<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>Mutuals\xd5  Redeemable Shares Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>23/7/2013</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 43" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Lords" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Cover>
<CoverTitle>EXPLANATORY NOTES</CoverTitle>
<CoverPara><Text><?start-line?>Explanatory notes to the Bill, prepared by the [Name to be replaced], are published <?new-line?>separately as ...</Text></CoverPara>
<CoverTitle>EUROPEAN CONVENTION ON HUMAN RIGHTS</CoverTitle>
<CoverPara><Text><?start-line?>[Name to be replaced] has made the following statement under section 19(1)(a) of the <?new-line?>Human Rights Act 1998:</Text></CoverPara>

<CoverPara><Text><?start-line?>In my view the provisions of the <?start-line?>Mutuals’ Redeemable Shares Bill [HL]<?start-line?> are <?new-line?>compatible with the Convention rights.</Text></CoverPara>
</Cover><Contents>
<Rubric TemplateVersion="4.2.002" xmlns="" /><Rubric xmlns="" /><ContentsTitle>Contents</ContentsTitle>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00007">
<ContentsNumber>1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Power to permit the use of a new class of redeemable shares</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00009">
<ContentsNumber>2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Redeemable shares</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00010">
<ContentsNumber>3</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Terms and manner of redemption</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00013">
<ContentsNumber>4</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Restriction on voting rights</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00014">
<ContentsNumber>5</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Definitions</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00015">
<ContentsNumber>6</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Short title, commencement and extent</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
</Contents>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Enable the law relating to societies registered under the Industrial and <?new-line?>Provident Societies Act 1965 or the Friendly Societies Act 1992 and certain <?new-line?>mutual insurers to be amended to permit and facilitate the use of a new and <?new-line?>additional class of redeemable share capital; to provide consequential rights to <?new-line?>members of such societies or insurers; and to restrict the voting rights of <?new-line?>certain members who hold such shares.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<P1group id="p00007">
<Title><?start-line?>Power to permit the use of a new class of redeemable shares</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2 id="p00008">
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State may, by regulations, amend the Industrial and Provident <?new-line?>Societies Act 1965, hereafter called “the 1965 Act”, the Friendly Societies Act <?new-line?>1992, hereafter called “the 1992 Act”, the Companies Act 2006 and any <?new-line?>legislation governing a mutual insurer to permit and facilitate the use of a new <?new-line?>and additional class of redeemable share in a society or mutual insurer.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This subsection applies to redeemable shares referred to in subsection <InternalLink id="i00001" Ref="p00008">(1)</InternalLink>—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a redeemable share in a society registered under the 1965 Act may be <?new-line?>transferable but may not be withdrawable;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a redeemable share in a society registered under the 1992 Act shall have <?new-line?>such characteristics as may be provided by amendments made to that <?new-line?>Act by regulations made under this section but shall not be <?new-line?>withdrawable;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a redeemable share in a mutual insurer shall have such characteristics <?new-line?>as are specified in regulations made under this Act and shall be subject <?new-line?>to such provisions of the Companies Act 2006 (whether or not they are <?new-line?>amended or inserted by regulations under this Act) as are applied to <?new-line?>them by such regulations;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>d</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>regulations made under this Act shall ensure, in respect of redeemable <?new-line?>shares whose use is permitted or facilitated by any such regulations, <?new-line?>that every holder of such shares is or becomes—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>a member of the society or mutual insurer;</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<?new-page?><P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>entitled to only one vote as a member regardless of the value or <?new-line?>number of shares that they hold and regardless of any <?new-line?>entitlement they may have as a result of their participation in <?new-line?>the society or mutual insurer otherwise than as a holder of such <?new-line?>shares;</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>iii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>entitled to only the level of remuneration payable under the <?new-line?>rules of the society or the constitution of the mutual insurer;</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>iv</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>entitled to repayment of the nominal value of the share on <?new-line?>redemption of the share, or the earlier solvent liquidation of the <?new-line?>society or the mutual insurer and to no other bonus or part of <?new-line?>any surplus.</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The power to make regulations under this Act is exercisable by statutory <?new-line?>instrument and must not be made unless a draft of it has been laid before and <?new-line?>approved by resolution of each House of Parliament.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00009">
<Title><?start-line?>Redeemable shares</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Regulations made under section 1(1) may provide for a society or mutual <?new-line?>insurer to issue either—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>shares that will be redeemed on a fixed or ascertainable date stated in <?new-line?>the terms of issue of the share, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>shares that can be redeemed on a date chosen either by the society or <?new-line?>mutual insurer or by the member who holds the share in accordance <?new-line?>with the terms of issue of the share.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The memorandum or rules of any society or constitution of any mutual insurer <?new-line?>may exclude or restrict the issue of redeemable shares.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A society or mutual insurer may only issue redeemable shares if it is authorised <?new-line?>to do so by its memorandum or rules.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A society or mutual insurer with share capital may only redeem a redeemable <?new-line?>share if it has, at the time of redemption, at least one issued share which is <?new-line?>neither redeemable nor withdrawable.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00010">
<Title><?start-line?>Terms and manner of redemption</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2 id="p00011">
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Regulations made under section 1 may permit the directors or committee of a <?new-line?>society or mutual insurer to determine the terms, conditions and manner of <?new-line?>redemption of shares if they are authorised to do so—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>by the society’s or mutual insurer’s rules or other constitutional <?new-line?>document, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3 id="p00012">
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>by a resolution of the society or mutual insurer.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Regulations made under section 1 may provide that, notwithstanding any <?new-line?>provision of any legislation or of the society’s rules or the mutual insurer’s <?new-line?>constitution, a resolution under subsection <InternalLink id="i00002" Ref="p00011">(1)</InternalLink><InternalLink id="i00003" Ref="p00012">(b)</InternalLink> may be an ordinary <?new-line?>resolution, even if it amends the society’s rules or the mutual insurer’s <?new-line?>constitution.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where the directors, committee or committee of management can be <?new-line?>authorised by regulations, in accordance with subsection <InternalLink id="i00004" Ref="p00011">(1)</InternalLink>, to determine the <?new-line?>terms, conditions and manner of redemption of shares, regulations shall <?new-line?>provide—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>that they must do so before the shares are allotted, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>that any obligation of the society or mutual insurer to state in a <?new-line?>statement of capital the rights attached to the shares extends to the <?new-line?>terms, conditions and manner of redemption.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where directors, committee or committee of management are not so <?new-line?>authorised, the terms, conditions and manner of redemption of any <?new-line?>redeemable shares must be stated in the society’s rules or the mutual insurer’s <?new-line?>constitution.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Regulations made under section 1 may apply sections 658 to 737 of the <?new-line?>Companies Act 2006, with such modifications as the Treasury may think fit, to <?new-line?>any society or mutual insurer to be permitted by those regulations to issue <?new-line?>redeemable shares.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00013">
<Title><?start-line?>Restriction on voting rights</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>No holder of a redeemable share, who is a member of a society or mutual <?new-line?>insurer only by virtue of holding such a share, shall be entitled to propose, or <?new-line?>vote in respect of, any resolution under section 50, 51 or 52 of the Industrial and <?new-line?>Provident Societies Act 1965, or section 85, 86 or 91 of the Friendly Societies Act <?new-line?>1992 (amalgamation, transfer of engagements or conversion into a company) or <?new-line?>any resolution or proposal to similar effect in the case of a mutual insurer, <?new-line?>including a compromise or arrangement proposed at a meeting called under <?new-line?>section 896 of the Companies Act 2006 or, in any case, a proposed transfer or <?new-line?>sale of business or property under section 110 of the Insolvency Act 1986.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00014">
<Title><?start-line?>Definitions</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>In this Act—</Text>
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>a “society” is—</Text>
<OrderedList Decoration="parens" Type="alpha">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>a society registered under the 1965 Act other than a credit union <?new-line?>registered under that Act by virtue of the Credit Unions Act <?new-line?>1979; or</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>a friendly society incorporated and registered under the <?new-line?>Friendly Societies Act 1992; or</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>a body which is a co-operative or mutual undertaking of such <?new-line?>description as HM Treasury may specify by order and which is <?new-line?>established or operates in accordance with the laws of an EEA <?new-line?>State or any of the Channel Islands or the Isle of Man;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</OrderedList>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>a “mutual insurer” is a body corporate, other than a society, which has no <?new-line?>share capital and which has permission to effect or carry out contracts <?new-line?>of insurance pursuant to the Financial Services and Markets Act 2000;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“the 1965 Act” includes the Industrial and Provident Societies Acts 1965 <?new-line?>to 2003, all later Acts amending or replacing them and any secondary <?new-line?>legislation made under any such Acts;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“the 1992 Act” includes the Friendly Societies Act, all later Acts amending <?new-line?>or replacing it, and any secondary legislation made under any such <?new-line?>Acts.</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00015">
<Title><?start-line?>Short title, commencement and extent</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the Mutuals’ Redeemable Shares Act 2013.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act shall come into force on such day as the Secretary of State may by <?new-line?>order made by statutory instrument appoint, and different days may be <?new-line?>appointed for different purposes.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act extends to England and Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Body>
</Primary>
</Legislation>