<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>BBC (Trustee Election and Licence Fee) Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>31/7/2013</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 47" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Lords" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Make provision for election of the trustees of the BBC by licence fee payers; <?new-line?>and in relation to civil enforcement of non-payment of TV licence fees.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<Part>
<Number><?start-line?>Part 1</Number>
<Title><?start-line?>Trustees of the BBC: elections</Title>
<P1group id="p00001">
<Title><?start-line?>Election of trustees of the BBC</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2 id="p00002">
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Notwithstanding anything in any enactment or charter, the British <?new-line?>Broadcasting Corporation (referred to in this Act as the “BBC”) must put in <?new-line?>place arrangements for individual licence-fee payers to vote in an election for <?new-line?>appointment to the role of Trustee of the BBC.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State may be regulations made by statutory instrument, <?new-line?>subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of <?new-line?>Parliament, set out how such an election is to be conducted.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State must recommend the people elected in an election held <?new-line?>under subsection <InternalLink id="i00001" Ref="p00002">(1)</InternalLink> for appointment to the role of Trustee of the BBC.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Trustees shall nominate one of their number to be recommended for <?new-line?>appointment as Chairman of the BBC Trust.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Part>
<Part>
<Number><?start-line?>Part 2</Number>
<Title><?start-line?>TV licence fees</Title>
<P1group id="p00003">
<Title><?start-line?>Civil penalties for non-payment of TV licence fee</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Communications Act 2003 is amended as follows.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Subsections (2) to (4) of section 363 (licence required for use of TV receiver) are <?new-line?>omitted.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2 id="p00004">
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 366 (powers to enforce TV licensing)—</Text>
<P3 id="p00005">
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>omit subsections (1) to (12);</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>at end insert—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P2 id="p00006">
<Pnumber>13</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State shall make provision by regulations for or <?new-line?>in connection with—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the imposition of penalty charges in respect of—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>installation or use of a television receiver in <?new-line?>contravention of section 363(1),</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>possession or control of a television receiver <?new-line?>with intent to install or use it in contravention of <?new-line?>section 363(1), and</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>iii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>possession or control of a television receiver <?new-line?>with knowledge, or reasonable grounds to <?new-line?>believe, that another person intends to install or <?new-line?>use it in contravention of section 363(1);</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the payment of such penalty charges.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>14</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations shall include provision specifying the person or <?new-line?>persons by whom a penalty charge in respect of a contravention <?new-line?>is to be paid (who may be the owner of the television receiver <?new-line?>involved in the contravention, its operator at the time of the <?new-line?>contravention, the owner or tenant of the property in which it is <?new-line?>installed, or any other appropriate person).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>15</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations shall include provision in respect of any <?new-line?>description of conduct for which a penalty charge may be <?new-line?>imposed—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>prohibiting criminal proceedings or the issuing of a <?new-line?>fixed penalty notice in respect of conduct of that <?new-line?>description, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>securing that a penalty charge is not required to be paid, <?new-line?>or is refunded, where the conduct is the subject of <?new-line?>criminal proceedings or of a fixed penalty notice.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>16</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may include provision prohibiting the <?new-line?>imposition of a penalty charge except on the basis of—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a record produced by an approved device, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>information given by a civil enforcement officer as to <?new-line?>conduct observed by him.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>17</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>specify exemptions from penalty charges, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>make provision for discounts or surcharges, or both.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>18</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations shall specify the BBC as the enforcement <?new-line?>authority for contraventions set out in subsection <InternalLink id="i00002" Ref="p00006">(13)</InternalLink>.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</BlockAmendment>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>After section 366, insert—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>  Civil enforcement officers</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>366A</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The BBC may provide for the enforcement of contraventions for which <?new-line?>it is the enforcement authority by individuals to be known as civil <?new-line?>enforcement officers.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A civil enforcement officer must be—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>an individual employed by the BBC, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>where the BBC have made arrangements with any person for <?new-line?>the purposes of this section, an individual employed by that <?new-line?>person to act as a civil enforcement officer.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Civil enforcement officers—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>when exercising specified functions must wear such uniform as <?new-line?>may be determined by the BBC in accordance with guidelines <?new-line?>issued by the Secretary of State, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>must not exercise any of those functions when not in uniform.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In subsection <InternalLink id="i00003" Ref="p00004">(3)</InternalLink><InternalLink id="i00004" Ref="p00005">(a)</InternalLink> “specified” means specified by regulations made by <?new-line?>the Secretary of State.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Setting the level of penalty charges</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>366B</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The BBC shall set the level of charges applicable in the case of <?new-line?>contraventions for which they are the enforcement authority.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Different levels of charges may be set for different parts of the United <?new-line?>Kingdom and for different cases or classes of case.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The levels of charges set under this section must (subject to subsection <?new-line?>(5)) accord with guidelines appended to an order made by the Secretary <?new-line?>of State.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Different guidelines may be given by the Secretary of State for different <?new-line?>cases or classes of case.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The BBC may, with the permission of the Secretary of State, depart from <?new-line?>any such guidelines.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The BBC shall publish, in such manner as the Secretary of State may <?new-line?>determine, the levels of charges set under this section.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Notification of penalty charge and confiscation of television receiver</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>366C</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Lord Chancellor may make regulations for and in connection with <?new-line?>the notification of penalty charges.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may provide for notification of a penalty charge to be <?new-line?>given in respect of a television receiver—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>by a notice affixed to the property in which the receiver is kept,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>by a notice given to a person appearing to be in charge of the <?new-line?>receiver, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>in such other manner as may be specified by the regulations.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may provide that, if it appears to the BBC that both the <?new-line?>operator of a television receiver and the owner or tenant of the property <?new-line?>in which the television receiver is kept are liable to a penalty charge, </Text><?new-page?><?start-line?>  <Text>they may give notice to the operator requiring him to provide them <?new-line?>with the name and address of the owner or tenant of the property at the <?new-line?>time of the alleged contravention.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may include provision creating criminal offences to be <?new-line?>triable summarily and punishable with a fine not exceeding level 5 on <?new-line?>the standard scale or such lower amount as may be specified.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2 id="p00007">
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State may make provision by regulations for or in <?new-line?>connection with a power of removal of a television receiver which is <?new-line?>being possessed or used, or has been installed, in contravention of <?new-line?>section 363(1) by a person whom the BBC have reasonable grounds to <?new-line?>believe has previously been issued with a penalty charge under section <?new-line?>366(13).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Regulations made under subsection <InternalLink id="i00005" Ref="p00007">(5)</InternalLink> may provide—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>that on any occasion when a television receiver is removed in <?new-line?>accordance with the regulations, the person removing the <?new-line?>receiver shall fix in its place a notice—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>indicating that the television has been removed;</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>specifying the steps to be taken in order to secure its <?new-line?>release; and</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>iii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>giving such other information as may be specified by the <?new-line?>regulations; and</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>that a notice fixed in place in accordance with the regulations <?new-line?>shall not be removed or interfered with except by or under the <?new-line?>authority of—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>the owner or operator of the television receiver, or</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>the BBC,</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<Text><?start-line?>and that a person contravening that prohibition commits an <?new-line?>offence and is liable on summary conviction to a fine not <?new-line?>exceeding level 2 on the standard scale.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Representations and appeals</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>366D</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Lord Chancellor may make provision by regulations entitling a <?new-line?>person—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>who is or may be liable to pay a penalty charge, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>who secures the return of a television receiver from the BBC on <?new-line?>payment of an amount in accordance with regulations under <?new-line?>section 336C,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<Text><?start-line?>to make representations to the BBC and to appeal to an adjudicator if <?new-line?>his representations are not accepted.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may make such provision in connection with the rights <?new-line?>conferred as appears to the Lord Chancellor to be appropriate, and may <?new-line?>in particular make provision—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>requiring the BBC to give a person notice of the rights conferred <?new-line?>by the regulations,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>as to the grounds on which, and time within which, <?new-line?>representations may be made,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>requiring supporting evidence in such circumstances as may be <?new-line?>specified,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>d</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>as to the duties of the BBC when representations are received,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>e</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>as to the circumstances in which there is a right of appeal to an <?new-line?>adjudicator,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>f</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>generally as to the making, determination and effect of, and <?new-line?>procedure in connection with, appeals, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>g</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>enabling an adjudicator to review any decision made on, or in <?new-line?>the course of, an appeal.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may provide that, as respects a ground on which <?new-line?>representations may be made, the adjudicator’s function on an appeal <?new-line?>is to decide whether to direct the BBC to consider or re-consider (as the <?new-line?>case may be) any representations relating to that ground.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may include provision—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>authorising an adjudicator to require a person—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>to attend to give evidence at the hearing of an appeal, <?new-line?>and</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>to produce any documents in his custody or under his <?new-line?>control relating to any matter relevant for the purposes <?new-line?>of the appeal, and</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>making it a criminal offence triable summarily and punishable <?new-line?>with a fine not exceeding level 2 on the standard scale to fail to <?new-line?>comply with such a requirement.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may provide that a person who makes a representation <?new-line?>that is false in a material particular, and does so recklessly or knowing <?new-line?>it to be false, commits an offence triable summarily and punishable <?new-line?>with a fine not exceeding level 5 on the standard scale.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may include provision authorising an adjudicator to <?new-line?>make an order for the payment of costs and expenses by a party to an <?new-line?>appeal in such circumstances as may be specified.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Adjudicators</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>366E</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Lord Chancellor may make provision by regulations for and in <?new-line?>connection with the appointment of adjudicators for the purposes of <?new-line?>this Part.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The following provisions apply in relation to the office of adjudicator—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>to be qualified for appointment as an adjudicator, a person must <?new-line?>satisfy the judicial appointment eligibility condition on a 5-year <?new-line?>basis;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>an adjudicator is appointed for a term, not exceeding five years, <?new-line?>specified in his instrument of appointment;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>on the expiry of a term of appointment an adjudicator is eligible <?new-line?>for re-appointment;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>d</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>an adjudicator may be removed from office only for misconduct <?new-line?>or on the ground that he is unable or unfit to discharge his <?new-line?>functions, but otherwise holds and vacates office in accordance <?new-line?>with the terms of his appointment.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations shall provide—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for adjudicators to be appointed by the BBC on such terms as <?new-line?>the BBC may decide;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the consent of the Lord Chancellor to be required for any <?new-line?>decision by the BBC to appoint a person as an adjudicator; and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the consent of the Lord Chancellor and the Lord Chief <?new-line?>Justice to be required for any decision by the BBC—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>not to re-appoint a person as an adjudicator, or</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>to remove a person from his office as an adjudicator.</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may provide for the Lord Chief Justice to nominate a <?new-line?>judicial office holder (as defined in section 109(4) of the Constitutional <?new-line?>Reform Act 2005) to exercise any of his functions under the regulations.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The BBC shall—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>provide, or make arrangements for the provision of, <?new-line?>accommodation and administrative staff and facilities for <?new-line?>adjudicators, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>determine the places where adjudicators are to sit,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<Text><?start-line?>and shall defray all the expenses of the adjudication process and, in <?new-line?>particular, expenses in relation to the remuneration of adjudicators.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations shall provide—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for each adjudicator to make an annual report to the BBC in <?new-line?>accordance with such requirements as may be imposed by the <?new-line?>BBC, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the BBC to make and publish an annual report to the <?new-line?>Secretary of State on the discharge by the adjudicators of their <?new-line?>functions.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2 id="p00008">
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The expenses of the BBC under this section shall be defrayed by them <?new-line?>in such proportions—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>as they may decide, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3 id="p00009">
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>in default of a decision by them, as may be determined in <?new-line?>accordance with regulations made by the Secretary of State.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Regulations under subsection <InternalLink id="i00006" Ref="p00008">(7)</InternalLink><InternalLink id="i00007" Ref="p00009">(b)</InternalLink> may, in particular, provide—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the matter to be determined by an arbitrator appointed by a <?new-line?>body specified in the regulations, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the giving of directions by the Secretary of State in order to <?new-line?>secure that the matter is referred to arbitration.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Enforcement of penalty charges</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>366F</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Lord Chancellor may make regulations for or in connection with <?new-line?>the enforcement of penalty charges issued under section 366(13).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>These regulations may include provision—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>creating criminal offences to be triable summarily and <?new-line?>punishable with a fine not exceeding level 5 on the standard <?new-line?>scale or such lower amount as may be specified;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3 id="p00010">
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for amounts payable under or by virtue of any provision of this <?new-line?>Part to be recoverable, if any county court so orders, as if they <?new-line?>were payable under a country court order,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<Text><?start-line?>an amount to which paragraph <InternalLink id="i00008" Ref="p00010">(b)</InternalLink> applies that is so recoverable is <?new-line?>referred to below as a “TV licence contravention debt”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2 id="p00011">
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Lord Chancellor may by order make provision—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for warrants of execution in respect of TV licence contravention <?new-line?>debts, or such class or classes of TV licence contravention debts </Text><?new-page?><?start-line?>  <Text>as may be specified in the order, to be executed by certificated <?new-line?>bailiffs;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>as to the requirements that must be satisfied before a person <?new-line?>takes any other step of a kind specified in the order, with a view <?new-line?>to enforcing the payment of—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>a TV licence contravention debt, or</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>such class or classes of TV licence contravention debts as <?new-line?>may be so specified.</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any such order may make such incidental and supplementary <?new-line?>provision (including modifications of any enactment other than this <?new-line?>Act) as the Lord Chancellor considers appropriate in consequence of <?new-line?>the provision made by the order.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of subsection <InternalLink id="i00009" Ref="p00011">(3)</InternalLink> a person is a certificated bailiff if he <?new-line?>is authorised to act as such by a certificate signed—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>by a judge assigned to a county court district, or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>in such circumstances as may be specified in regulations made <?new-line?>by the Lord Chancellor, by a district judge.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Lord Chancellor may be regulations make provision in connection <?new-line?>with the certification of bailiffs under this section and the execution of <?new-line?>warrants of execution by such bailiffs.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulations may, in particular, make provision—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>as to the security (if any) to be required from certificated bailiffs,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>as to the fees and expenses payable with respect to execution by <?new-line?>certificated bailiffs, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the suspension of cancellation of certificates issued under <?new-line?>this section and with respect to the effect of any such suspension <?new-line?>or cancellation.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A person who is not a certificated bailiff but who purports to levy a <?new-line?>distress as such a bailiff, and any person authorising him to levy it, shall <?new-line?>be deemed to have committed a trespass.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</BlockAmendment>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00012">
<Title><?start-line?>Short title, commencement and extent</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the BBC (Trustee Election and Licence Fee) Act 2013.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act shall come into force on 1 January 2017.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act extends to England and Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Part>
</Body>
</Primary>
</Legislation>