<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>High Cost Credit Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>9/7/2013</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 12" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Commons" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Contents>
<Rubric TemplateVersion="4.2.002" xmlns="" /><Rubric xmlns="" /><ContentsTitle>Contents</ContentsTitle>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00010">
<ContentsNumber>1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Financial Conduct Authority (“FCA”) duty to define high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements and make rules</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00011">
<ContentsNumber>2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>FCA rules to set out penalties for contravention</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00012">
<ContentsNumber>3</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Duty to review effectiveness and power to make additional rules beyond <?new-line?>those specified</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00013">
<ContentsNumber>4</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Power to place a levy on the high-cost credit sector to fund additional debt <?new-line?>advice services</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00014">
<ContentsNumber>5</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Duty to consider a cap on the total cost of high-cost credit agreements</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00015">
<ContentsNumber>6</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Commencement, implementation and transitional powers</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00016">
<ContentsNumber>7</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Short title</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsSchedules>
<ContentsSchedule ContentRef="p00017">
<ContentsNumber>Schedule 1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Prohibited features of high-cost credit agreements</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsSchedule>
<ContentsSchedule ContentRef="p00019">
<ContentsNumber>Schedule 2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Required behaviours of authorised persons entering into high-<?new-line?>cost credit agreements</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsSchedule>
</ContentsSchedules>
</Contents>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Make provision for regulating high-cost credit arrangements and providers of <?new-line?>such arrangements; to provide for controls on advertising, information and <?new-line?>communications associated with such arrangements; to make measures to <?new-line?>address the cost and affordability of such credit arrangements and their <?new-line?>associated charges; to regulate matters concerning repayments under such <?new-line?>arrangements; to make provision on advice and advice services in relation to <?new-line?>debt arising from such arrangements; and for connected purposes.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<P1group id="p00010">
<Title><?start-line?>Financial Conduct Authority (“FCA”) duty to define high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements and make rules</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In this Act—</Text>
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“high-cost credit agreement” means a regulated credit agreement as <?new-line?>defined by section 137C of the Financial Services and Markets Act 2000 <?new-line?>(as inserted by the Financial Services Act 2012) that provides for—</Text>
<OrderedList Decoration="parens" Type="alpha">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>the payment by the borrower of charges of a description from <?new-line?>time to time specified by the FCA; or</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>the payment by the borrower over the duration of the <?new-line?>agreement of charges that, taken with the charges paid under <?new-line?>one or more other agreements which are treated by the FCA’s <?new-line?>rules as being connected with it, exceed, or are capable of <?new-line?>exceeding, an amount specified by the FCA;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</OrderedList>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“charges” means charges payable, by way of interest or otherwise, in <?new-line?>connection with the provision of credit under the regulated credit <?new-line?>agreement, whether or not the agreement itself makes provision for <?new-line?>them and whether or not the person to whom they are payable is a <?new-line?>party to the regulated credit agreement or an authorised person;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“authorised person” has the same meaning as in the Financial Services <?new-line?>and Markets Act 2000.</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The FCA shall make rules prohibiting specific features of high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements and those rules shall, for the purposes of section 137D of the <?new-line?>Financial Services and Markets Act 2000 (as amended by the Financial Services <?new-line?>Act 2012) be deemed to have been made under that section.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The specific features of high-cost credit agreements to be prohibited by those <?new-line?>FCA rules are those contained in Schedule 1 (“the prohibited features”).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The FCA shall also make rules requiring any authorised person entering into a <?new-line?>high-cost credit agreement to undertake or refrain from certain activities and <?new-line?>those rules shall, for the purposes of section 137A of the Financial Services and <?new-line?>Markets Act 2000 (as amended by the Financial Services Act 2012) be deemed <?new-line?>to have been made under that section.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The specific activities to be the subject of those FCA rules are those contained <?new-line?>in Schedule 2 (“the required behaviours”).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00011">
<Title><?start-line?>FCA rules to set out penalties for contravention</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any rules established by the FCA pursuant to this Act shall specify the <?new-line?>penalties for contravention, and shall include provisions—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for high-cost credit agreements containing any of the features set out in <?new-line?>Schedule 1—</Text>
<P4>
<Pnumber>i</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>to be unenforceable against the borrower; and/or</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>ii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the recovery of any money or other property paid or <?new-line?>transferred under the agreement by the borrower; and/or</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
<P4>
<Pnumber>iii</Pnumber>
<P4para>
<Text><?start-line?>for the payment of compensation for any loss sustained by the <?new-line?>borrower as a result of paying or transferring any money or <?new-line?>other property under the agreement or obligation; and</Text>
</P4para>
</P4>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>for authorised persons breaching the required behaviours set out in <?new-line?>Schedule 2 to be subject to any of the disciplinary measures contained <?new-line?>in Part XIV of the Financial Services and Markets Act 2000 (as inserted <?new-line?>by the Financial Services Act 2012) as the FCA shall deem appropriate.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00012">
<Title><?start-line?>Duty to review effectiveness and power to make additional rules beyond <?new-line?>those specified</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Nothing in this Act shall restrict the power of the FCA to make additional rules <?new-line?>beyond those set out in Schedules 1 and 2 in relation to high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The FCA shall keep the effectiveness of the rules made under this Act under <?new-line?>review and shall, if it considers it necessary, exercise any discretion provided <?new-line?>within Schedules 1 and 2 to change the rules relating to high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements and/or introduce additional rules relating to high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements beyond those specified in this Act.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00013">
<Title><?start-line?>Power to place a levy on the high-cost credit sector to fund additional debt <?new-line?>advice services</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>In addition to any powers provided to the FCA within the Financial Services and <?new-line?>Markets Act 2000 (as amended by the Financial Services Act 2012) to levy fees and <?new-line?>charges in order to fund the Money Advice Service, the FCA shall also have the power <?new-line?>to introduce an additional levy on authorised persons entering into high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements in order to fund debt advice services.</Emphasis></Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>When deciding whether to exercise this power, or the size of any such levy that may be <?new-line?>required, the FCA shall have regard to the number of people reported by high-cost credit <?new-line?>lenders to the FCA as referred to debt advice services by virtue of the requirement under <?new-line?>Schedule 2, paragraph 4(4)</Emphasis>.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>In setting the size of such a levy, the FCA may also have regard to any other indicators <?new-line?>of demand for debt advice amongst high-cost credit borrowers as it sees fit.</Emphasis></Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00014">
<Title><?start-line?>Duty to consider a cap on the total cost of high-cost credit agreements</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The FCA shall consider, on an annual basis, whether or not to use the powers <?new-line?>to cap the total cost of credit afforded to it in section 137C of the Financial <?new-line?>Services and Markets Act 2000 (as inserted by the Financial Services Act 2012).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In considering whether or not and how to use the powers referred to in this <?new-line?>paragraph, the FCA shall have regard to information contained on the <?new-line?>regulatory database referred to in Schedule 2, paragraph 4.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00015">
<Title><?start-line?>Commencement, implementation and transitional powers</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The provisions of this Act shall come into force on the day on which it is <?new-line?>passed.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The FCA shall put in place rules pursuant to this Act within three months of <?new-line?>the commencement of this Act.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The regulatory database referred to in Schedule 2, paragraph 5 of this Act shall <?new-line?>be established by the FCA within twelve months of the commencement of this <?new-line?>Act.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In advance of the regulatory database being established the FCA shall require <?new-line?>any authorised person entering into a high-cost credit agreement to use credit <?new-line?>reference services to determine whether or not a high-cost credit agreement <?new-line?>can be entered into in accordance with the rules established by the FCA under <?new-line?>this Act.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this Act the definition of credit reference services is the <?new-line?>same as that contained in the Financial Services and Markets Act 2000 (as <?new-line?>amended by the Financial Services Act 2012).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00016">
<Title><?start-line?>Short title</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the High Cost Credit Act 2013.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Body>
<?new-page?>
<Schedules>
<Title><?start-line?>SCHEDULES</Title>
<Schedule id="p00017" NumberFormat="default">
<Number><?start-line?>SCHEDULE 1</Number>
<TitleBlock>
<Title><?start-line?>Prohibited features of high-cost credit agreements</Title>
</TitleBlock>
<Reference>Sections 1 to 3</Reference>
<ScheduleBody>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Restrictions on the amount of high-cost credit that can be advanced</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2 id="p00018">
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>No high-cost credit agreement may be entered into if this would be <?new-line?>unaffordable for the borrower. The FCA shall specify how authorised <?new-line?>persons are expected to assess the affordability of high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements and may also specify limits in respect of—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the total amount of contractual liability that may be created; and/ or</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the total amount of repayments permitted to fall due in any such <?new-line?>period as the FCA may determine appropriate.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The FCA may express the limits referred to in this paragraph in absolute <?new-line?>terms or as a proportion of the borrower‘s income.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The limits referred to in this paragraph may be specified in respect of a <?new-line?>single high-cost credit agreement or the aggregate of all high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements entered into by a borrower.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Level of default charges to be restricted</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>No high-cost credit agreement may make provision for the payment by the <?new-line?>borrower of additional charges on default or in respect of the collection of <?new-line?>unpaid amounts unless the amounts contained in the agreement are beneath <?new-line?>the limits from time to time be specified by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>When setting the limits referred to in this paragraph the FCA shall have <?new-line?>regard to the duration of high-cost credit agreements and may set different <?new-line?>limits for agreements of different durations.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The limits referred to in this paragraph may include limits on the duration <?new-line?>for which default or collection charges can be incurred by the borrower in <?new-line?>respect of any high-cost credit agreement as well as limits on the amount of <?new-line?>those charges.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Prohibition on charges connected with the use of “continuous payment authority”</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>No high-cost credit agreement or connected agreement may create a liability <?new-line?>for any charge to the borrower for the collection of payments through the <?new-line?>use of a “continuous payment authority” or similar process as may be <?new-line?>specified by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this Act “continuous payment authority” means an <?new-line?>authorisation for the lender to collect payments directly from the borrower’s <?new-line?>bank or other transactional account.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<?new-page?><P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Restrictions on “rollover” and repeat lending</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>No high-cost credit agreement may make provision for the deferment of <?new-line?>contractual repayments on payment of additional fees or charges by the <?new-line?>borrower unless those fees or charges are beneath the limits from time to <?new-line?>time specified by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>No high-cost credit agreement may make provision for the deferment of <?new-line?>contractual repayments on payment of additional fees or charges by the <?new-line?>borrower on more occasions than shall be specified by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>No high-cost credit agreement may be entered into if this would cause the <?new-line?>borrower to exceed a limit as may be set by the FCA on the total number of <?new-line?>high-cost credit agreements that can be entered into in any “given period”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this paragraph “given period” means such period of <?new-line?>time as specified by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this paragraph the FCA may specify different limits on <?new-line?>the number of high-cost credit agreements that may be entered into in any <?new-line?>given period for high-cost credit agreements of different durations.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Requirements in respect of high-cost credit agreements and guarantors</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>No high-cost credit agreement may be entered into which imposes a liability <?new-line?>on a third party unless—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the liability that is being created to the third party has been <?new-line?>adequately explained to that party; and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the third party has provided a signature consenting to the creation of <?new-line?>the liability.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this paragraph “adequately explained” shall have the <?new-line?>meaning to be specified from time to time by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</ScheduleBody>
</Schedule>
<Schedule id="p00019" NumberFormat="default">
<Number><?start-line?>SCHEDULE 2</Number>
<TitleBlock>
<Title><?start-line?>Required behaviours of authorised persons entering into high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements</Title>
</TitleBlock>
<Reference>Sections 1 to 6</Reference>
<ScheduleBody>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Advertising of high-cost credit agreements</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2 id="p00020">
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>All authorised persons advertising high-cost credit agreements shall—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>contain within their advertising a warning, in a form and manner <?new-line?>from time to time specified by the FCA, that the agreements being <?new-line?>promoted are high-cost and that entering into any such an agreement <?new-line?>should be considered carefully;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>contain an illustration of the “typical cash cost” of the agreements <?new-line?>being promoted in a form and manner specified by the FCA;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>contain a clear statement of any default fees and charges that may be <?new-line?>included in a high-cost credit agreement in a form and manner <?new-line?>specified by the FCA;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>d</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>contain information on sources of free debt advice services in a form <?new-line?>and manner specified by the FCA;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>e</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>refrain from using content or advertising in such a way that breaches <?new-line?>the standards as shall from time to time be set for high-cost credit <?new-line?>advertising by the FCA following consultation with the Advertising <?new-line?>Standards Authority;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>f</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>refrain from promoting high-cost credit agreements through the use <?new-line?>of SMS text or picture messages to mobile phones;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>g</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>refrain from promoting high-cost credit agreements through the use <?new-line?>of phone calls.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this paragraph the advertising standards set by the FCA <?new-line?>may specify restrictions on the timing of television or other broadcast <?new-line?>advertising and the sponsorship of specific types of sporting or cultural <?new-line?>activities as may be determined inappropriate by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Requirement to disclose information concerning business practices to the FCA</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any authorised person entering into high-cost credit agreements may be <?new-line?>required by the FCA to disclose details of their marketing strategy and <?new-line?>methods of generating loans to the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this paragraph the terms “marketing strategy” and <?new-line?>“methods of generating loans” have the meanings specified from time to <?new-line?>time by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Requirement of credit brokers to provide lender details to the borrower</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any person engaging in credit brokerage shall be required to disclose details <?new-line?>of the lenders on whose behalf they are acting to a credit applicant in a form <?new-line?>and manner and at a time in the application process to be specified by the <?new-line?>FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this paragraph “credit brokerage” has the same meaning <?new-line?>as in the Consumer Credit Act 1974.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Requirement to register details of loans on a regulatory database and to consult this prior to <?new-line?>entering into agreements</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The FCA may require any authorised person entering into high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements to enter details of their agreements on a database as shall be <?new-line?>established for that purpose by the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this paragraph the agreement details to be entered on the <?new-line?>database shall be those as shall be specified by the FCA and shall include—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>details of borrower: including name, address, date of birth and <?new-line?>national insurance number or other unique identifiers as may be <?new-line?>specified by the FCA; and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>details of the loan agreement: including the amount advanced, the <?new-line?>interest and other fees contained in the agreement, the amount <?new-line?>repayable, and the contractual date on which repayment is due.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Persons entering details of high-cost credit agreements onto the database <?new-line?>shall also be required—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>to consult the database prior to making any high-cost credit <?new-line?>agreements in order to ensure that any limitations on the making of <?new-line?>high-cost credit agreements that may be set by the FCA pursuant to <?new-line?>this Act are observed; and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>to maintain up to date records of the performance of any high-cost <?new-line?>credit agreements entered on the database, including but not limited <?new-line?>to details of any missed contractual repayments, any deferments, <?new-line?>and the level of default fees or other charges imposed as a <?new-line?>consequence.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In the event that a high-cost credit agreement cannot be entered into as a <?new-line?>result of the limitations set by the FCA pursuant to this Act then authorised <?new-line?>persons required to use the database shall refer credit applicants to debt <?new-line?>advice services in a manner to be specified by the FCA and shall report any <?new-line?>such referral to the FCA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In so far as the FCA incurs any costs in establishing and maintaining the <?new-line?>database referred to in this paragraph, the FCA may recover these from <?new-line?>authorised persons entering into high-cost credit agreements by requiring—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a payment per agreement entered into the database by the <?new-line?>authorised person; or</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>an annual payment based on the overall size, as defined by the FCA, <?new-line?>of the high-cost credit lending business undertaken by the <?new-line?>authorised person; or</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a combination of these methods.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Requirements relating to use of “continuous payment authority”</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where an authorised person enters into a high-cost credit agreement which <?new-line?>provides for the collection of payment through the use of “continuous <?new-line?>payment authority”, the FCA may require the authorised person to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>provide information to the borrower about their right to cancel any <?new-line?>such authority with their bank account provider in a manner and <?new-line?>form as may be specified by the FCA;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>provide borrowers with three days notice of the date on which the <?new-line?>continuous payment authority is to be used;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>refrain from exercising the use of the continuous payment authority <?new-line?>in such circumstances as may be specified by the FCA.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Circumstances under which lenders must inform borrowers of sources of free debt advice</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Authorised persons entering into high-cost credit agreements shall be <?new-line?>required to inform borrowers of sources of free debt advice in a manner and <?new-line?>form to be specified by the FCA whenever—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a contractual repayment has been missed; or</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>there has been a deferment of a contractual repayment.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Requirement to put in place repayment plan for debtors</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where a debt advice service contacts an authorised person concerning a <?new-line?>high-cost credit agreement in relation to which a default has occurred then <?new-line?>the FCA shall require the authorised person to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>immediately cease any enforcement action against the borrower; and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>agree to a schedule of repayments (“a repayment plan”) based on the <?new-line?>ability of the debtor to pay as advised by the debt advice service; and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>waive any fees, charges or interest, which may otherwise have fallen <?new-line?>due under the agreement over the period of the repayment plan.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<?new-page?><P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Requirement to accept offers from third parties to settle outstanding debts</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where an authorised person is contacted by third parties as shall be <?new-line?>specified by the FCA, and the third party is acting with the consent of the <?new-line?>borrower and offers to make a payment to settle any outstanding high-cost <?new-line?>credit agreement then the FCA shall require the authorised person to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>co-operate fully with the third party to ensure that the settlement of <?new-line?>the agreement takes place as quickly as possible; and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>not add any interest, fees, or other charges to the amount <?new-line?>outstanding from the date on which the authorised person has been <?new-line?>contacted by the third party.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</ScheduleBody>
</Schedule>
</Schedules>
</Primary>
</Legislation>