<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>Public Services (Ownership and User Involvement) Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>27/2/2014</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 160" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Commons" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Contents>
<Rubric TemplateVersion="4.2.002" xmlns="" /><Rubric xmlns="" /><ContentsTitle>Contents</ContentsTitle>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00012">
<ContentsNumber>1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Obligation to consult prior to outsourcing or privatisation</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00013">
<ContentsNumber>2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Internal bids</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00014">
<ContentsNumber>3</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Contracts with relevant authorities and the promotion of organisations with <?new-line?>a social purpose</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00015">
<ContentsNumber>4</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Requirement for a break clause</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00016">
<ContentsNumber>5</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Transparency</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00017">
<ContentsNumber>6</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Freedom of information</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00018">
<ContentsNumber>7</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Orders and regulations</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00019">
<ContentsNumber>8</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Interpretation</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00020">
<ContentsNumber>9</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Financial provisions</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00021">
<ContentsNumber>10</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Short title, commencement and extent</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsSchedules>
<ContentsSchedule ContentRef="p00022">
<ContentsNumber>Schedule</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Contracts with relevant authorities and the promotion of <?new-line?>organisations with a social purpose</ContentsTitle>
<ContentsPart>
<ContentsNumber>Part 1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Proritising social enterprises, not for profit entities and public <?new-line?>sector bodies</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsPart>
<ContentsPart>
<ContentsNumber>Part 2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Contracts with relevant authorities</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsPart>
<ContentsPart>
<ContentsNumber>Part 3</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Amendment of Local Government Act 1988</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsPart>
</ContentsSchedule>
</ContentsSchedules>
</Contents>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Promote public ownership of public services; to introduce a presumption in <?new-line?>favour of service provision by public sector and not-for-profit entities; and to <?new-line?>put in place mechanisms to increase the accountability, transparency and <?new-line?>public control of public services, including those operated by private <?new-line?>companies.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<P1group id="p00012">
<Title><?start-line?>Obligation to consult prior to outsourcing or privatisation</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>If a relevant authority proposes to enter into a public services contract in <?new-line?>circumstances where those services were previously provided or secured by <?new-line?>that authority, or where it has an obligation to provide such services,  it must <?new-line?>consult on the proposed contract in accordance with subsections (2), (3) and (4).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Before starting the process of procurement for a public services contract, the <?new-line?>relevant authority must publicise its intention to enter into the proposed <?new-line?>contract in such a manner as the authority reasonably thinks it will bring the <?new-line?>proposal to the attention of the majority of people who would be affected by it.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any consultation held under subsection (1) must be open for response for at <?new-line?>least 28 days and must, in particular, allow consultees to express a view as to <?new-line?>whether they wish the services to be provided by the relevant authority.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where the proposed contract relates to an asset held by the relevant authority, <?new-line?>any consultation held under subsection (1) must allow consultees to express a <?new-line?>view as to whether they wish the asset to remain the property of the relevant <?new-line?>authority.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The relevant authority must, when deciding whether to proceed with the <?new-line?>process of procuring a public services contract, have regard to any responses <?new-line?>to the consultation that the authority has received.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<?new-page?><P1group id="p00013">
<Title><?start-line?>Internal bids</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where a relevant authority has held a consultation and decides to proceed with <?new-line?>the process of procurement for a public services contract, it must consider any <?new-line?>internal bid.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where the relevant authority determines that an internal bid is not practicable, <?new-line?>it is required to give reasons for this decision and publicise those reasons in <?new-line?>such a manner as the authority reasonably thinks it likely to bring them to the <?new-line?>attention of the majority of people who would be affected by the  outcome of <?new-line?>the procurement exercise.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00014">
<Title><?start-line?>Contracts with relevant authorities and the promotion of organisations with <?new-line?>a social purpose</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Schedule has effect.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In that Schedule—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>Part 1 requires the Secretary of State to make regulations prioritising <?new-line?>bids by public authorities, not for profit entities and social enterprises <?new-line?>and also makes consequential provisions;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>Part 2 provides that where a relevant authority is engaged in the <?new-line?>purchase, management, disposal and hire of goods or the carrying out <?new-line?>of works, it is required to consider how what is proposed to be <?new-line?>procured might improve the economic, social and environmental well-<?new-line?>being of the relevant area, and how, in conducting the process of <?new-line?>procurement, it might act with a view to securing that improvement;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>Part 3 amends provisions of the Local Government Act 1988 relating to <?new-line?>the exclusion of non-commercial considerations in the case of local and <?new-line?>other public authority contracts.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00015">
<Title><?start-line?>Requirement for a break clause</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where a relevant authority enters into a public services contract it must include <?new-line?>in that contract a break clause.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A relevant authority is entitled to exercise the break clause under a public <?new-line?>services contract and re-tender for the contract where the relevant conditions <?new-line?>are triggered.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State may by regulations define the  trigger conditions to be <?new-line?>included in a break clause under subsection (1).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In respect of a nationally provided public service, such regulations may in <?new-line?>particular require contracts for public services to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>require the relevant authority to provide a complaints procedure and <?new-line?>record the number of complaints received about the service provision;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>prescribe a defined threshold of complaints after which the relevant <?new-line?>authority is obliged to consider whether an adequate service is being <?new-line?>provided under the contract;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>prescribe that in circumstances where the threshold of complaints is <?new-line?>reached, and the relevant authority concludes that an adequate service <?new-line?>is not being provided under the contract, it is entitled to exercise the <?new-line?>break clause and re-tender for the contract.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In respect of a local or regionally provided public service, such regulations may <?new-line?>in particular require a contract for public services to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>require the relevant authority to provide a complaints procedure and <?new-line?>record the number of complaints received about the service provision;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>prescribe a defined threshold of complaints after which the relevant <?new-line?>authority is required to consider whether an adequate service is being <?new-line?>provided under the contract.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>prescribe that in circumstances where the threshold of complaints is <?new-line?>reached, and the relevant authority concludes that an adequate service <?new-line?>is not being provided under the contract, it is entitled to exercise the <?new-line?>break clause and re-tender for the contract.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>When a  break clause is exercised under section 4, regulations must preclude <?new-line?>the payment of any financial compensation under the contract.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00016">
<Title><?start-line?>Transparency</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where a relevant authority starts the process of procurement for a public <?new-line?>services contract, it must make available to the public details of all bids <?new-line?>received prior to the conclusion of the procurement exercise.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where a relevant authority enters into a public services contract, details of that <?new-line?>contract shall be made available to the public within 28 days of the <?new-line?>procurement decision.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00017">
<Title><?start-line?>Freedom of information</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State must designate as a public authority, pursuant to section <?new-line?>5(1)(b) of the Freedom of Information Act 2000, companies or other bodies <?new-line?>which enter into a public services contract.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>“Public services contract” has the meaning contained within section 8 of this <?new-line?>Act.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State shall maintain a list of companies designated under <?new-line?>section 6(1) of this Act.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Requests under the Freedom of Information Act 2000 in respect of such <?new-line?>companies or bodies can only be made in respect of information relevant to the <?new-line?>provision of a public services contract.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State must designate as a public authority, pursuant to section <?new-line?>5(1)(b) of the Freedom of Information Act 2000, any utility company subject to <?new-line?>regulation by regulatory authorities as defined in section 8.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00018">
<Title><?start-line?>Orders and regulations</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any power to make regulations under this Act is exercisable by statutory <?new-line?>instrument.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A statutory instrument containing regulations under this Act is subject to <?new-line?>annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament, save as <?new-line?>specified in subsection (3).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A statutory instrument containing regulations under section 3 may not be <?new-line?>made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before and approved by a <?new-line?>resolution of each House of Parliament.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<?new-page?><P1group id="p00019">
<Title><?start-line?>Interpretation</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>In this Act—</Text>
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“asset” means an asset worth in excess of £50,000;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“internal bid” means an in-house bid by public sector staff employed by <?new-line?>the relevant authority;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“public service contract” means all contracts for public services, whether <?new-line?>national or local, worth in excess of £50,000;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“regulatory authorities” includes Ofwat and Ofgem;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“relevant authority” means a person or body that is a contracting <?new-line?>authority for the purposes of the Regulations;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“the Regulations”, in the definition of “relevant authority”, means the <?new-line?>Public Contracts Regulations 2006 (<Citation id="c00101" Class="UnitedKingdomStatutoryInstrument" Year="2006" Number="0005">S.I. 2006/5</Citation>), or any regulations <?new-line?>replacing those regulations, as from time to time amended.</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00020">
<Title><?start-line?>Financial provisions</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>9</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>There is to be paid out of money provided by Parliament—</Emphasis></Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>any expenditure incurred under or by virtue of this Act by the Secretary of <?new-line?>State, a Minister of the Crown, a person holding office under Her Majesty or <?new-line?>by a government department, and</Emphasis></Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>any increase attributable to this Act in the sums payable under any other Act <?new-line?>out of money so provided.</Emphasis></Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00021">
<Title><?start-line?>Short title, commencement and extent</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>10</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the Public Services (Ownership and User <?new-line?>Involvement) Act 2014.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act comes into force at the end of the period of 2 months beginning with <?new-line?>the day on which it is passed.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act extends to England, Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Body>
<?new-page?>
<Schedules>
<Schedule id="p00022" NumberFormat="default">
<Number><?start-line?>Schedule</Number>
<TitleBlock>
<Title><?start-line?>Contracts with relevant authorities and the promotion of organisations with <?new-line?>a social purpose</Title>
</TitleBlock>
<Reference>Section 3</Reference>
<ScheduleBody>
<Part>
<Number><?start-line?>Part 1</Number>
<Title><?start-line?>Proritising social enterprises, not for profit entities and public sector bodies</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State shall make regulations, providing that where a <?new-line?>relevant authority contracts for a public services contract, it may reserve the <?new-line?>right to prefer a bid by a public sector body, a not for profit entity or a social <?new-line?>enterprise.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Such regulations may consider the circumstances in which the right to prefer <?new-line?>in paragraph 1 may be exercised, including consideration of a public benefit.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any regulations made under paragraph 1 of this Schedule may require the <?new-line?>Secretary of State to compile a list of bodies that would qualify as a not for <?new-line?>profit entity or a social enterprise for the purpose of this Act.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The bodies referred to in paragraph 3 shall  include, but are not limited to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>charities;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>industrial and provident societies;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>community interest companies;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>d</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>mutuals wholly owned by staff.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
</Part>
<Part>
<Number><?start-line?>Part 2</Number>
<Title><?start-line?>Contracts with relevant authorities</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Where a relevant authority is engaged in the purchase, management, <?new-line?>disposal and hire of goods or the carrying out of works the authority must <?new-line?>consider—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>how what is proposed to be done might improve the economic, <?new-line?>social and  environmental well-being of the relevant area, and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>how, in conducting the process of purchasing, managing, disposing, <?new-line?>hiring or carrying out works, it might act with a view to securing that <?new-line?>improvement.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The authority must consider under paragraph 5(b) only matters that are <?new-line?>relevant to the activities proposed under that paragraph and in doing so, <?new-line?>must consider the extent to which it is proportionate in all the circumstances <?new-line?>to take those matters into account.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The authority must consider whether to undertake any consultation as to the <?new-line?>matters that fall to be considered under paragraph 5.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>If an urgent need to arrange the activities proposed under paragraph 5 <?new-line?>makes it impractical to comply with the requirements in paragraphs 5, 6 and </Text><?new-page?><?start-line?>  <Text>7, a relevant authority may disregard the requirements to the extent that it is <?new-line?>not practical to comply with them.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>9</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Paragraph 8 does not apply to the extent that the time available is reduced <?new-line?>by undue delay on the part of the authority after this section has come into <?new-line?>force.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>10</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The “relevant area” for the purpose of paragraph 5(a) means the area <?new-line?>consisting of the area or areas of the one or more relevant authorities on <?new-line?>whose behalf the activities are intended to be conducted.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</Part>
<Part>
<Number><?start-line?>Part 3</Number>
<Title><?start-line?>Amendment of Local Government Act 1988</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>11</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 17 of the Local Government Act 1988 (exclusion of non-<?new-line?>commercial considerations in the case of local and other public authority <?new-line?>contracts), after subsection (11) insert—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P2>
<Pnumber>12</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This section does not prevent a public authority to which it applies <?new-line?>from exercising any function regulated by this section with reference <?new-line?>to a non-commercial matter to the extent that the authority considers <?new-line?>it necessary or expedient to do so to enable or facilitate compliance <?new-line?>with a duty imposed on it by the Public Services (Ownership and <?new-line?>User Involvement) Act 2014.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</BlockAmendment>
</P1para>
</P1>
</Part>
</ScheduleBody>
</Schedule>
</Schedules>
</Primary>
</Legislation>