<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>Communication Support (Deafness) Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>11/10/2013</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 24" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Commons" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Contents>
<Rubric TemplateVersion="4.2.002" xmlns="" /><Rubric xmlns="" /><ContentsTitle>Contents</ContentsTitle>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00006">
<ContentsNumber>1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Council for Communication Support on Deafness</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00007">
<ContentsNumber>2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Definition of deafness</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00008">
<ContentsNumber>3</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Objectives of the Council</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00009">
<ContentsNumber>4</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Short title, commencement and extent</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsSchedules>
<ContentsSchedule ContentRef="p00010">
<ContentsNumber>Schedule</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Council for Communication Support on Deafness</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsSchedule>
</ContentsSchedules>
</Contents>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Establish a body to assess provision of communication support for deaf <?new-line?>people and to make recommendations; and for connected purposes.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<IntroductoryText>
<P><Text>W<SmallCaps>hereas</SmallCaps> deafness does not in itself constitute a learning difficulty;</Text>

<?new-line?><Text><?start-line?>And whereas communications and language support is essential for social <?new-line?>communication for deaf people and their families and for education and employment;</Text>

<?new-line?><Text><?start-line?>And whereas there is a recognised attainment gap in the education achievements of <?new-line?>deaf children and young people;</Text>

<?new-line?><Text><?start-line?>And whereas there is variation in the level and quality of support provided across <?new-line?>the United Kingdom;</Text>

<?new-line?><Text><?start-line?>And whereas there is need for a minimum standard and promotion of best practice;</Text>

<?new-line?><Text><?start-line?>And whereas there is a case for independent monitoring of performance and <?new-line?>recommendations of best practice within education by schools inspectorates:-</Text>

</P>
</IntroductoryText>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<P1group id="p00006">
<Title><?start-line?>Council for Communication Support on Deafness</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>There shall be established an independent body known as the Council for <?new-line?>Communication Support on Deafness (referred to in this Act as “the Council”).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Schedule makes provision about the Council.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00007">
<Title><?start-line?>Definition of deafness</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>For the purposes of this Act, deafness shall relate to persons with a hearing loss <?new-line?>who are classified as—</Text>
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>having a severe hearing loss,</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<?new-page?><ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>profoundly deaf,</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>hard of hearing,</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>deafened, or</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>deafblind.</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The definition under subsection (1) is intended to reflect the social model of <?new-line?>disability and cultural model of deafness.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00008">
<Title><?start-line?>Objectives of the Council</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council’s main objective is to assess provision of language and <?new-line?>communication support for people experiencing deafness and to make <?new-line?>recommendations. This assessment of provision should include all forms of <?new-line?>language and communications support including but not limited to lip <?new-line?>speaking, British Sign Language and other sign languages used both in person <?new-line?>and remotely, and deafblind communication including deafblind manual and <?new-line?>tactile methods for deafblind people.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council’s main objective is supported by the following subsidiary <?new-line?>objectives—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>to establish a British Sign Language Board which shall have the <?new-line?>function of promoting and facilitating the use of British Sign Language;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>to produce Accessible Language and Communications Action Plans <?new-line?>with measurable outcomes and deadlines to set out how the Strategy <?new-line?>will be implemented;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>to set up an Accessible Language and Communications Stakeholders’ <?new-line?>Panel, made up of deaf people (covering the whole spectrum of <?new-line?>language and communication needs), and engage them fully in the <?new-line?>production of the Strategy and Action Plan and its implementation and <?new-line?>follow-up.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The members appointed to the Panel established in subsection (2)(c) shall not <?new-line?>be paid for their membership of the Panel.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council shall carry out research and make recommendations for <?new-line?>legislative, policy and practice improvements, including but not limited to <?new-line?>addressing the following issues—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>availability of sufficient appropriately qualified and regulated <?new-line?>language and communication professionals for deaf and deafblind <?new-line?>service users;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>use of these professionals by public bodies, including private <?new-line?>companies contracted to provide a public service, with a view to <?new-line?>ensuring language and communication support is provided whenever <?new-line?>required, both in person and remotely;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>use of these professionals by all bodies serving the public with a view <?new-line?>to ensuring that they provide alternative language and communication <?new-line?>support for deaf users whenever required, both in person and <?new-line?>remotely;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>d</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>recognition of British Sign Language as an indigenous language of the <?new-line?>United Kingdom;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>e</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>consideration to the role of other Sign Languages within the United <?new-line?>Kingdom;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>f</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>provision of adequate language and communication support for deaf <?new-line?>children and their families;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>g</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>current overall provision of language and communication support and <?new-line?>consider whether it would be more efficient and cost-effective to <?new-line?>devolve control of language and communication support budget to <?new-line?>individual users.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State may by regulations provide for the Council to have an <?new-line?>additional function if it appears to the Secretary of State that it is necessary or <?new-line?>expedient for the Council to have the function in relation to any of its <?new-line?>objectives.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Regulations under subsection (5) shall be made by statutory instrument and no <?new-line?>regulations shall be made unless a draft has been laid before, and approved by <?new-line?>resolution of, each House of Parliament.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council shall aim to pursue, and to have regard to, its objectives when <?new-line?>exercising a function that is relevant to it.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council must exercise its functions effectively and efficiently.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00009">
<Title><?start-line?>Short title, commencement and extent</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the Communication Support (Deafness) Act 2013.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act shall come into force on such day as the Secretary of State shall by <?new-line?>order appoint.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act extends to England and Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Body>
<?new-page?>
<Schedules>
<Schedule id="p00010" NumberFormat="default">
<Number><?start-line?>Schedule</Number>
<TitleBlock>
<Title><?start-line?>Council for Communication Support on Deafness</Title>
</TitleBlock>
<Reference>Section 1</Reference>
<ScheduleBody>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Membership</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council is to consist of a member to chair it and six other members, <?new-line?>appointed by the Secretary of State following a pre-appointment hearing by, <?new-line?>and with the consent of, the Work and Pensions Committee of the House of <?new-line?>Commons.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council’s membership shall consist of a majority of people defined as <?new-line?>deaf in section 2(1) of this Act, including at least one deaf person fluent in <?new-line?>British Sign Language.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Annual report</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council must prepare a report of the performance of its functions <?new-line?>annually.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The report must be sent to the Department of Work and Pensions.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State must lay the report before Parliament.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Accountability and reporting</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>It will be the responsibility of the Secretary of State to lay before Parliament <?new-line?>responses to reports of the Council in Parliament.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Finance</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>The budget of the Council will be agreed by the Secretary of State.</Emphasis></Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>The Department of Work and Pensions may make to the Council such payments out <?new-line?>of money provided by Parliament as it considers appropriate for the purpose of <?new-line?>enabling the Council to meet its expenses.</Emphasis></Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>Payments are to be made at such times, and subject to any such conditions, as the <?new-line?>Department of Work and Pensions considers appropriate.</Emphasis></Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Accounts and audit</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council must—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>Keep proper accounts and proper records in relation to its accounts, <?new-line?>and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>prepare in respect of each financial year a statement of accounts.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Each statement of accounts must comply with any directions given by the <?new-line?>Work and Pensions Select Committee as to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the information to be contained in it and the manner in which it is to <?new-line?>be presented;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the methods and principles according to which the statement is to be <?new-line?>prepared, and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the additional information (if any) which is to be provided for the <?new-line?>information of Parliament.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Council must send a copy of each statement of accounts to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the Secretary of State, and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the Comptroller and Auditor General,</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<Text><?start-line?>before the end of the month of June next following the financial year to <?new-line?>which the statement relates.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</ScheduleBody>
</Schedule>
</Schedules>
</Primary>
</Legislation>