<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><HansardDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print file:/C:/Users/edwardsc/Desktop/LordsHansard_Print2008.xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print"><House name="Lords"><System type="Cover"><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/Cover/34F2C6BEA39049040ED8CC901179BB30A513F193" __version__="1.5"><Cover-wrapper><Cover bcoveruri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/Cover/CC901179BB30A513F19334F2C6BEA39049040ED8" cdate="1" cday="Friday" cmonth="November" cyear="2013" date="25" day="Friday" htmlBackCoverUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/Html_Index/34F2C6BEA330A513F1939049040ED8CC901179BB" htmlIndexUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/Html_Index/CC901179BB34F2C6BEA39049040ED830A513F193" indexuri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/Index/9049040ED8CC901179BB30A513F19334F2C6BEA3" issue="59" maxparts="1" month="October" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" type="back" volume="748" year="2013"><Contents><hs_FPNormal>Voting
Age (Comprehensive Reduction) Bill
[HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>1275</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Medicinal
Labelling Bill [HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>1296</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Equality
(Titles) Bill [HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>1310</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Written
Statements<I>WS 114</I></hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormal>Written
Answers<I>WA
203</I></hs_FPNormal></Contents></Cover></Cover-wrapper></Fragment></System><System type="Debate" ColStart="1275"><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/211D8A3C4CECC0E91E0FAE70F93247B6E482C30C" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AA-AB1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_Venue UID="13102540000369" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000369">House
of Lords</hs_Venue><hs_date UID="13102540000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000001">Friday, 25 October
2013<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:07:11"></hs_TimeCode></I>.</hs_date><hs_time UID="13102540000284" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000284">10
am</hs_time><hs_Procedure UID="13102540000359" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000359">Prayers—read
by the Lord Bishop of
Guildford.</hs_Procedure><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102540000356" alt="Voting Age Bill [HL]" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000356">Voting
Age (Comprehensive Reduction) Bill
[HL]<a href="http://services.parliament.uk/bills/2013-14/votingagecomprehensivereduction.html" title="Voting Age (Comprehensive Reduction) Bill [HL]  "></a></hs_DebateHeading>
<hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13102540000285" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000285">10.06
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13102540000366" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000366">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Tyler" PimsId="4859" UID="13102540000317" xid="1879" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000317">Lord
Tyler</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102540000314" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000314">That the Bill be
read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102540000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000005"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Tyler" PimsId="4859" UID="13102540000318" xid="1879" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000318">Lord
Tyler (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I pay tribute to those from all
parts of the House who have encouraged me to introduce the Bill. The
noble Lord, Lord Lucas, from the Conservative Benches, who
is going to be here shortly, has pioneered discussion of the issue in
your Lordships’ House. Then there is the noble Baroness, Lady
Young of Hornsey, from the Cross Benches, who is on the speakers list,
and the noble Lord, Lord Adonis, a very distinguished Member
from the Labour Benches who is, unfortunately, not able to be here
today, but has indicated to me his strong
support<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:07:02"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:06:50"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:06:50"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:06:50"></hs_TimeCode>.
I am very encouraged to see a number of colleagues from all sides of
the House who intend to speak in this debate, most notably the noble
Baroness, Lady Royall. I
am<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:07:21"></hs_TimeCode> very
grateful, given her very busy life, that she is able to be here today.
No doubt she will be able to report to your Lordships’ House
that our Bill, with cross-party support, has also now the official
support of the official
Opposition<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:07:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000006">I
do not intend to speak at great length, not least because I am very
well aware that esteemed colleagues on all sides of the House are
anxious to make progress on the two important Bills that follow. I hope
that we can complete this stage of our Bill as quickly as possible, for
that reason. I am especially encouraged by the presence of my noble
friend Lord Wallace of Saltaire, who will give the ministerial response
to our debate. He has an enviable reputation for integrity, logic and
rational analysis, which may stem more from his academic background
than from his political allegiance. He will, I am sure, be the first to
see the inevitable case for this
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:08:27"></hs_TimeCode>.
Whatever<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:08:32"></hs_TimeCode>
ministerial brief he has been handed, I invite him to apply these
invaluable assets to the situation that we find ourselves
in.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000007">Whatever<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:08:52"></hs_TimeCode>
others may say, my noble friend will recognise that the Government have
in principle accepted the case for the extension of the franchise to 16
and 17 year-olds. I pay tribute to my right honourable
friend the Prime Minister—and I never thought that in
50 years of public life I could say that—and to my
right honourable friend Michael Moore, for their role in achieving the
Edinburgh agreement. The proper role of these young people to decide on
the future of Scotland was accepted in that agreement; they will now be
entitled to vote in next year’s
referendum<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:09:08"></hs_TimeCode>. It
was acknowledged by the coalition Government that 
<?notus-xml column=1276?>in such far-reaching decisions, which could affect their whole lives,
the whole nation would benefit from their opportunity to
participate.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000008">Of
course, as those of us who are committed to the maintenance of the
union must agree, it would intolerable if our citizens in different
parts of the United Kingdom were to enjoy totally different basic civic
rights or civic responsibilities. That would not be a united kingdom.
Other minor matters—some quite important, perhaps—may be
devolved; but surely we cannot sustain the argument that the franchise,
the most basic building block of our representative democracy in the
UK, should not be approached on a coherent and cohesive basis? The
Constitution Committee of your Lordships’ House has frequently
urged the Government to be consistent and to avoid ad hoc change in
this field. I trust that it will itself be consistent in this
respect<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:10:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000009">In
our debate in the Grand Committee in the Moses Room on 27
February, I quoted a specific recommendation from our Constitution
Committee entitled, “Agreement on a Referendum on Independence
for Scotland”, where it was said that relevant authorities must
act—and this is the
quote,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13102540000278" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000278">“in
accordance with their constitutional responsibilities of fairness and
equal
treatment”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13102540000254" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000254">If
that applies north of the border, it must surely also apply south of
the border<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:11:08"></hs_TimeCode>. I
very much hope that we will see that recommendation if the Constitution
Committee of your Lordships’ House looks again at this
issue<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:11:21"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13102540000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000010">Let
us suppose this enfranchisement is denied to 16 and 17
year-olds in future referendums—for example, on the continued
membership of this country in the European Union. I cannot think of any
issue with more long-term implications for this age group than that. If
that happened, I suspect that the Joint Committee on Human Rights would
have something to say. It will surely be bad enough for this age group
in England, Wales and Northern Ireland to be disfranchised in the
general election in 2015, but what will Ministers say to 17 year-olds
who have voted in 2014 in Scotland but cannot do so a year later? And
what if there is a local, Scottish Parliament or even Westminster
by-election in a Scottish area on the same day as the independence
referendum? How could the Minister’s impeccable logic explain to
this group that it was mature enough for one decision but not for the
other<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:12:28"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000011">I
am delighted to see a number of noble friends on all sides of the
House—and I mean that sincerely—who are going to speak
today. I am sure that they will be able to spell out the extent to
which that age group has become much better informed and able to deal
with decisions of this
sort<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:12:29"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:13:18"></hs_TimeCode>.
That was very much the theme of our debate in the Moses Room on 27
February. I hope that the copious evidence that was produced there on
all sides gives strong support to this point. Since then, of course,
the Labour Party has specifically endorsed our
campaign<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:13:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000012">A
number of other organisations have also made general or specific
recommendations in support of this change: for example, the British
Youth Council, Bite the Ballot and the All-Party Parliamentary Group on
Voter Registration. That last group is especially relevant. As I
pointed out at Question Time yesterday, 
<?notus-xml column=1277?>it was found in Northern Ireland, when the new system of individual
electoral registration was piloted there, that the anticipated
catastrophic collapse in registration among younger age groups was
averted by attaching preparatory processing of registration to the
citizenship syllabus in secondary schools. I hope that that will occur
in this part of the United Kingdom. It is surely a natural and
practical end product of these courses in schools and colleges that
when students achieve that greater understanding they can then have
greater impact in practical terms as they will be prepared for
registration to be full electoral citizens in our country. It is far
easier to do that at that age group than when many people have left
their home environment for work or further education at
18<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:14:22"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000013">I
have in mind particularly a very interesting conclusion of the
so-called Kenny report entitled <I>How </I><I>D</I><I>o
</I><I>P</I><I>olitics and </I><I>E</I><I>conomics </I><I>A</I><I>ffect
</I><I>G</I><I>angs and </I><I>S</I><I>erious </I><I>Y</I><I>outh
</I><I>V</I><I>iolence</I> <I>A</I><I>cross the UK</I><I>?</I>. When it
was published, its author Kenny Imafidon, who has direct
personal experience of that side of life in south-east London, came to
see me and drew my attention to the following recommendation. Under the
heading, “Lowering the voting age for young people from 18 to
16”, it
states:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13102540000266" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000266">“Why
is it possible for young people to go to prison at 10, give full
consent to medical treatment at 16, leave school and enter work or
training at 16, pay income tax and National Insurance at 16,
obtain tax credits and welfare benefits in their own right
at 16, consent to sexual relationships at 16, get married or
enter a civil partnership at 16, change their name by deed poll at 16,
join the armed forces at 16, but they cannot vote at 16? …
Because there is no right to vote at the age of 16, many young people
are disenfranchised before they even get a chance to vote. The
political system is weighted in favour of those who are eligible to
vote at the expense of young people who cannot. The impact of young
people not being able to vote regarding critical services that affect
their life chances are highlighted in the recommendations
below”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13102540000255" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000255">Of
course, this Bill will not solve all those problems. How could it? It
is not a cure-all for such deep and formidable difficulties in our
civil society, but it could make a useful contribution. It is in those
terms that I and colleagues from other parts of the House wish to make
progress on this issue. The Kenny report sums up that case
admirably.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13102540000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000014">In
the interests of brevity I will say no more except to add that this is
a very modest, brief and positive Bill, so I trust that my noble
friend’s response can be all those things too, and that he will
just say yes. I beg to
move<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:16:41"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/00CB2B2519821AA76596EF06740EB81D8818B2BA" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AB2-AC1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000286" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000286">10.16
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:16:41"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000015"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Lexden" PimsId="5893" UID="13102540000319" xid="2107" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000319">Lord
Lexden (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, when I had the
honour of joining your Lordships’ House nearly three years ago,
I rapidly discovered that it possessed no stronger advocate of the need
to enhance the extent and quality of our democratic processes than my
noble friend Lord Tyler. He is known above all for his desire to extend
the blessings of democracy to this unelected
House<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:19:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000016">An
election manifesto, produced jointly by the Conservatives and the
Liberals, states
that,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13102540000279" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000279">“it
will be one of the objects of the Government to create a Second Chamber
which will be based upon direct contract with the people, and will
therefore be representative enough adequately to perform its
functions”.</hs_quotefo> 
<?notus-xml column=1278?><hs_parafo UID="13102540000256" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000256">The
manifesto in which these words appear provided the platform on which
Lloyd George and the Conservative leader, Andrew Bonar Law, fought the
1918 election together in coalition. It was written by one the great
20th century historians, HAL Fisher. If my noble friend had
been around at the time to assist him, the course of British
constitutional history might conceivably have been different. Today my
noble friend keeps the formidable cause of radical Lords reform
constantly before him while seeking other more immediate means of
improving our democratic system. His Bill, about which he has spoken so
powerfully today, would bring about a significant enlargement of our
electorate<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:18:11"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13102540000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000017">The
arguments for and against the lowering of the voting age to 16 have
been amply rehearsed both in Parliament and outside it. Both the
Liberal Democrats and the Labour Party have committed themselves to
making this immensely significant change. Some in the Labour
Party believe that it should be made compulsory for newly enfranchised
young people to vote at their first election. This would be in open
defiance of our established democratic traditions in this
country<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:18:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000018">Even
more deeply unsatisfactory has been the unilateral decision by the
Scottish National Party to enfranchise 16 year-olds for the referendum
on independence next year. This disreputable initiative springs solely
from a desire to increase support for independence. I hope very much
that it rebounds on those responsible for it when the referendum comes,
with the votes of young people helping to reinforce the union.
Conceived in opportunism and expediency, it represents entirely the
wrong approach to profound democratic change. It is often said that the
irresponsible Scottish decision has reignited debate on this subject.
Debate is indeed what we need, but the proper basis for it is my noble
friend’s Bill, founded on respect for democratic
principle.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000019">There
is at present no widespread public clamour for change in our country. A
recent opinion poll found that just one person in every five supported
a voting age of 16. After detailed consultations, the Youth
Citizenship Commission, established by the last Government, included no
recommendation in its report of June 2009 for a reduction in the voting
age. It found that while,</hs_para>
<hs_quotefo UID="13102540000280" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000280">“a majority
of 16 and 17-year-olds were in favour ... all categories from the age
of 18 upwards were opposed to change”.</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="13102540000257" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000257">Subsequent surveys
have produced similar results.</hs_parafo>
<hs_para UID="13102540000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000020">As<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:09:59"></hs_TimeCode>
regards the population as a whole, my noble friend’s Bill would
seem to embody an idea whose time has not yet come. Even among young
people interest in the idea would not seem to be matched by enthusiasm
for actually exercising the right to vote. Enfranchised 16 year-olds
could be expected to follow the example of their immediate seniors who
have the vote. According to this year’s <I>Audit of Political
Engagement</I> by the Hansard Society, of which I have just had the
honour to become a trustee, the proportion of young people between the
ages of 18 and 24 who are certain to vote at the next election now
stands at 12%, down 10 points in one year. The Hansard Society poses
the central question:</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000021">“Given the
degree to which the current cohort of young people are increasingly
turned off by the idea of using their vote, what exactly is going to be
different 
<?notus-xml column=1279?>about voting and politics generally that is going to engage their
younger 16 and 17 year old brothers and sisters?”.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000022">This is the heart of
the matter, which is so familiar to all those who share my noble friend
Lord Tyler’s dedication to the cause of democracy and, at the
same time, so difficult to address successfully.
Young<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:21:27"></hs_TimeCode> people and
politics today seem to inhabit different worlds. Long gone are the
merry, colourful days of organisations such as the Young Conservatives,
with a membership of close to 1 million in the 1950s, which combined
politics and fun. Today, far-sighted reformers such as my noble friend
and the noble Lord, Lord Adonis, look to schools to play a central part
in helping to rebuild political commitment among the young, without
which the good government of our country will be impaired. If the young
do not vote—whether at 16, 18 or 24—policies
in a democracy will favour unduly the older sections of society who
turn out in substantial numbers; and I very much agree with what my
noble friend said about the importance of action in schools.
Citizenship education introduced as a statutory subject in the national
curriculum by the previous Government could mark the beginning of a
significant change of attitudes if it is taught with flair and
imagination. Carefully prepared debates on the principal issues of the
day and mock elections could prepare the way for registration at 18 or
even 16, and then participation in real
elections.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000023">In
addition, it is tempting to think that efforts to promote a change in
attitudes among the young might be assisted by some powerful new
initiative. Do we need to make the issue far more prominent in the
consciousness of the nation? Could there be a case for convening a
Speaker’s Conference to stimulate national debate on the
implications of my noble friend’s Bill and galvanise ideas to
secure its successful implementation? Mr Speaker Bercow has often
proclaimed the deep fervour he feels for associating the young with the
processes of politics and government. A conference might be a suitable
sphere for his not inconsiderable energies. It was, after all, a
Speaker’s Conference in the mid-1960s which prepared the way for
the reduction in the voting age from 21 to
18.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000024">No
responsible Tory should reject out of hand for all time the case for
votes at 16. Disraeli declared famously that,</hs_para>
<hs_quotefo UID="13102540000281" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000281">“the Youth of
a Nation are the trustees of Posterity”.</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="13102540000258" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000258">If this extraordinary
timeless character were alive today he would be deeply shocked at the
state of political interest and commitment among the nation’s
youth in the democracy that Britain has become since his death. We
should work towards the day when, in a phrase much used in the 19th
century, young people could be brought fully within the pale of the
constitution by being given the right to vote from the age of 16, as
long as the nation had confidence that they would exercise it. My noble
friend may find at some future point that his Bill’s time has
come<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:24:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/716B36DC7D1DAD88CC39947B17801C2ED4842960" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AC2-AD</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000287" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000287">10.24
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000025"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Smith of Basildon" PimsId="5786" UID="13102540000320" xid="2058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000320">Baroness
Smith of Basildon (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, I welcome the fact that
the noble Lord, Lord Tyler, has brought forward the Bill. It is a rare
and giddy moment 
<?notus-xml column=1280?>that we find ourselves on the same side of a debate, and I suspect the
mood will pass. However, today I am pleased to support his Bill. I come
to this debate with perhaps the zeal of a
convert<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:24:53"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000026">The right of citizens
to vote at the age of 16 is an issue about which I have become
passionate, and I was delighted that the Labour Party’s leader,
Ed Miliband, made his and our party’s commitment so clear. That
said, I do not agree with all the arguments often made in favour of
such a move. The claim that it will somehow improve, for example, the
percentage turnout is not at all relevant to the debate—I have
no idea whether it will do so. I suspect that initially a significant
proportion of 16 and 17 year-olds will not take up that right, but it
is a matter of principle as to whether it is the right thing to give
them that right. I should like to make three points that changed my
view and convinced me that this is the appropriate way
forward<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:25:36"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000027">First were the views of
young people themselves. As a member of the other place, I would
regularly engage with school-aged students and young people. At one
particular event with around 60 or 70 school students of around 15, 16
and 17 years they quizzed me and discussed a whole range of issues: the
environment, jobs, education, the economy, animals, and local, national
and international issues. The students were of different ages and
abilities, and from different parts of town but few did not engage in
some way in that discussion. They were interested and knowledgeable
about issues that affected them, and in issues that involved their
families, neighbours and communities. Some were involved in and were
members of local and national groups and organisations.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000028" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000028">Perhaps most important
for this debate, they were really interested in issues that affected
their futures. If it does not sound too grand to say this, I sensed
that they were interested in the future of the country and
the world—in the decisions that were being taken now that would
affect the world in their lifetimes. It was a lengthy wide-ranging
discussion. I then asked if they thought they should be able to vote at
16, and noble Lords may expect me to say that they said that they
should be able to do so. I certainly expected that response. However, I
was staggered that the overwhelming majority said that they did not
think that they should have the vote at 16. Given the debate that we
had been having, I thought that I should probe and challenge that view.
What were their reasons for not wanting the vote? They said, “We
don’t think we know enough about it”, and that they were
not interested in politics, despite having discussed a range of
political issues, because they did not have enough information, hardly
ever read a newspaper, and did not know much or much liked political
parties.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000029">All<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:27:37"></hs_TimeCode>
those views could equally apply to many people who already have the
vote, so I found myself playing devil’s advocate. These bright,
lively, some slightly stroppy, kids were engaged with issues and
interested in their communities but were not at all confident about how
much they knew. Yet they had views—often strong and some not yet
fully formed—but were working their way through them, like the
rest of us do. They were worried about not being able to vote at 16 not
because they did not care about issues but because 
<?notus-xml column=1281?>they cared too much. They thought they should know
more, have more information and engage more before they voted. How
impressive is that? If only every voter would want to be as well
informed and concerned about issues that affected
them.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000030" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000030">Political
engagement is not just about voting and then leaving it to those who
are elected for the next four or five years. These young people were
engaged but had not yet connected that engagement—that
campaigning and caring about issues—with voting. Too often the
young think they cannot engage or contact their elected representatives
because they do not vote. In 1958, Eddie Cochran said in his hit
“Summertime Blues”:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000267" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000267">“I’m
gonna take my problem</hs_quote>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000268" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000268">To the United
Nations.</hs_quote>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000269" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000269">Well I called my
congressman</hs_quote>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000270" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000270">And he said,
whoa</hs_quote>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000271" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000271">I’d like to
help you son</hs_quote>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000272" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000272">But you’re too
young to
vote”.</hs_quote><hs_para UID="13102540000031" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000031">Perhaps
more Members of your Lordships’ Chamber will recognise that than
would Members of the other place. Politicians should always try to be
consistent. It would be completely inconsistent to encourage voting at
an earlier age, want to increase the number of people
engaged enough with their communities to recognise the value of voting,
and then support the Government’s appalling lobbying—or
gagging—Bill, which seeks to disengage campaigning from the
political process of elections. We want young people to engage and we
should oppose measures that then put inappropriate and undemocratic
boundaries on that
engagement<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:29:45"></hs_TimeCode>. Many
people I meet start to engage in politics, even if they do not
recognise it as such, through campaigns and issues, and we should
encourage, not curtail,
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:29:54"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000032">The second experience
that led me to think that this was a way forward occurred in May on
local election day. I was out and about in part of my former
constituency doing what the politicians call “knocking
up”—encouraging voters to come out and vote. Some did, as
always, but some preferred to stay at home. I met a young woman who was
walking along the street. She was about 18 or 19 and she had a baby in
a pushchair. I asked her whether she was going to vote. She recognised
me as I had spoken at her school a few years prior to that, and I think
that she felt confident that she knew me and was able to talk to me.
Her comments were ones that I have heard before and I think that they
are very relevant to this debate. She said, “I want to go and
vote. I’ve been looking at such and such, and I’ve seen
this in the paper. I want to go and vote but I’ve never done it
before. I don’t know what to do”. It was not that she did
not have views or was not engaged but she did not know, practically,
what to do in order to vote. That was all that was holding her back.
She did not know whether her friends would vote and she did not have
anyone to go with. It struck me that if, at the age of 16, young people
were given the right to vote while still at school, collectively they
would engage and find out what to do. Schools could support them with
that basic knowledge in, for example, citizenship classes. I am not
talking about how to vote or necessarily why they should vote but the
simple mechanics of what to do and how to
<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:31:20"></hs_TimeCode>do it.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1282?><hs_para UID="13102540000033" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000033">The third reason is
perhaps the one used most often. It is a nonsense that young
people of 16 can go out to work, pay taxes, join the Armed Forces and
have children, with all the responsibility that that
entails, but that they cannot have a say in their own future
when it comes to choosing their Member of Parliament, their
Government or members of their local
council<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:31:38"></hs_TimeCode>.
Yesterday, I spoke to councillor Andrew Gordon of Basildon. He said to
me, “If you can pay taxes at 16, you should be allowed to say
how those taxes are spent”. Andrew is the councillor
for Nethermayne ward on Basildon Council. He is the first Labour
councillor in that ward for 20 years, and that in itself is
something of an achievement. He lives in the ward he represents. The
very first time he voted it was for himself, and he won that
election. Andrew was only 18. Did he suddenly, on his 18th
birthday, become interested in issues that affected his community? Did
he suddenly, at the age of 18, decide that he wanted a bigger role
politically? Of course he did not, but like many young people he had
views, he cared and he wanted to do
something<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:32:31"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000034" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000034">If I am honest, despite
the fact that he won the seat, there were those in his community who
were sceptical that one so young could represent them. However, when he
spoke out recently at a public meeting, supporting more than 200 people
on a very important local issue, it was clear that they had made the
right choice. Whether or not they agreed with his politics, here was a
young man fully engaged with the community and understanding local
issues, and he did a first-rate job of representing them. He got a
standing ovation at that meeting—the only councillor who
did<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:33:04"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000035" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000035">I am not advocating a
whole council of 18 year-olds any more than I would advocate a whole
council or parliament of 50 year-olds or 70 year-olds, but
too often councils and parliaments are full of older people
like us. Decisions taken today affecting our futures include the
futures of 16 year-olds, and they will be here long after I have gone.
Therefore, should we not be engaging people under the age of 16 and
those of 16, 17 and 18 in the democratic process and
decision-making<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:33:32"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000036" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000036">There is a lot of
discussion and there are many press reports about politics being more
representative, and that usually refers to women and black and Asian
people, but there are two issues that we have shied away from for too
long—class and age. Now we have the opportunity to rectify one
of those. The Bill has my total support.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13102540000288" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000288"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:33:53"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.33
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:33:53"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000037"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Coussins" PimsId="5193" UID="13102540000321" xid="1949" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000321">Baroness
Coussins (CB):</Member></B> My Lords, I, too, strongly support the Bill
and am delighted to take the opportunity today to put some of the
reasons on
record.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000038">In
fact, it is not the only radical reform in our voting system that I
would like to see. I should also like us to adopt the Australian system
of compulsory voting, accompanied by the ability to exercise a positive
abstention on the ballot paper. It may not seem at first sight that
this has any connection with reducing the voting age to 16, but I
believe they are linked. I have never been persuaded by the argument
that the reason the turnout among young people is low is that they are
apathetic about politics. I think that a much more likely explanation
is that their non-voting is a rational 
<?notus-xml column=1283?>expression of dislike of all the options on offer and that, if they had
the chance to put a cross beside a box that said “None of the
above”, a great many of them would. That itself would be a
genuine form of political engagement and would send an important
message to all the political parties that they had some serious
thinking to
do.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000039" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000039">I assure
the noble Lord, Lord Tyler, that I have absolutely no intention of
spoiling the simplicity and brevity of his Bill by seeking to amend
it—not that I would even expect a measure such as compulsory
voting to qualify as an amendment to the straightforward proposal to
give the vote to 16 year-olds. However, I hope that I can add to, or at
least support, the arguments as to why the Government should look
favourably on the Bill and make the most positive and progressive
change to the electoral system since the voting age was reduced to 18
in 1969.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000040">The
first argument of course—and we have heard it already—is
consistency. Why should a 16 year-old be regarded as capable of
consenting to medical treatment, be old enough to fight and die for his
or her country, or be required to pay income tax and national
insurance, but not have the right to vote for a representative in
Parliament?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000041" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000041">Secondly,
despite assertions that 16 and 17 year-olds know nothing and have too
little experience to contribute their say as to who runs the country,
we should remember, as the noble Lord, Lord Lexden, pointed out, that
since 2002 we have had compulsory citizenship education in schools, so
we could argue that this age group is likely to be better informed,
better educated and more thoughtful about this issue than some older
segments of the population. As well as citizenship on the curriculum,
85% of secondary schools have school councils. There are also 600
elected members of the Youth Parliament, which was established in 2000,
and each member serves for 12 months and is voted in by
their peers. I think that not having the vote at 16 undermines
compulsory citizenship education at key stages 3 and 4 and that it is
unfair to make school leavers wait for what could be several years
before they are allowed to exercise their right to vote for the first
time. I certainly know from my experience of speaking to teenagers at
schools through the Peers in Schools programme that very many of them
have a level of understanding and a wish to participate and engage in
the democratic process, which signals to me that they are more than
ready when they are
16.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000042">Thirdly<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:37:05"></hs_TimeCode>,
given that the general demographic is an ageing one, you could argue
that young people have more of a stake in participating in elections.
It could be said that 16 and 17 year-olds should have the vote in order
to balance out the interests being expressed at the ballot box. Some
studies have shown that 16 and 17 year-olds are more likely to vote
than certain other age groups—for example, the over-70s and
those between 18 and 30. Therefore, the argument that the UK would end
up being embarrassed by an even lower turnout if we gave the vote to 16
year-olds cannot necessarily be substantiated. Even if it could, I
agree with what the Power commission said in 2006: that the potential
embarrassment of politicians is no reason to reject reform.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1284?><hs_para UID="13102540000043" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000043">One objection that we
sometimes hear is that 18 is the most common voting age around the
world and that there is no public support in the UK for going out of
line with that norm. All I can say to that is that not so long ago the
norm was that only men could vote, so keeping things as they are rather
than making a logical and progressive change cuts absolutely no ice in
a sensible political
debate.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000044" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000044">A case
study of Austria, where the voting age was reduced to 16 in 2007,
concluded that democratic quality was not jeopardised by extending the
franchise and that the votes of the under-18s reflected a range of
political preferences just as much as those of the over-18s. However,
the study also pointed out—I think that this is an important
general point—that voter turnout in elections is by no means the
only expression of political engagement, and that under-18s
demonstrated just as much engagement as the under-30s when it came to
activities such as contacting politicians on specific issues,
collecting signatures on petitions, campaigning, going on
demonstrations or working for an NGO, to give a few
examples.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000045">The
right to vote at 16 is supported by a huge range of organisations. It
would take far too long to list them this morning but they include the
British Youth Council, the Children’s Rights Alliance for
England, the NUS and the Scottish Youth Parliament. I, for one,
sincerely hope that the Government will take their head out
of the sand on this issue and do the right thing for 16 year-olds and
the right thing for
democracy.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/EF529D78A189B49F816FDFEB578DE57368AC96A9" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AE-AF1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000289" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000289"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:39:18"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:39:27"></hs_TimeCode>10.39
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000046" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000046"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Goodhart" PimsId="3491" UID="13102540000322" xid="1169" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000322">Lord
Goodhart (LD):</Member></B> I believe that young people should be
allowed to vote at the ages of 16 and 17, a view which I came to some
years ago. Elections were on the way and as a candidate I went to
school meetings about those elections. Most of those schools were state
schools. I went to the constituencies where I had a political
interest—first, North Kensington and, later, Oxford West and
Abingdon. With the exception of just one of these schools, boys and
girls at these meetings were interested, sharp-minded and challenging.
In one school, one of the politicians talked as if the boys and girls
were 12 years old. The 16 and 17 year-olds simply took that
candidate
apart<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:40:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000047" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000047">Very
few of the young school people were old enough to vote in the then
current election. In later years, when they had left school and were
old enough to vote, probably not many of them voted for several years.
But if the boys and girls aged 16 and 17 at the meetings at their
schools had been allowed to vote in the next few days, a large number
of them would have voted. Having voted once, they would have continued
to do so in elections which occurred after they had left
school.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000048" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000048">As<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:41:42"></hs_TimeCode>
it is, most of the young who have reached the age of 18 do not vote for
several years to come. I believe that if young people aged 16 and 17
are allowed to vote, most would do so in a justifiable way. They will
not vote simply as they are told to vote by their parents. I have a
granddaughter aged almost 16. It is very likely that her judgment would
be better than mine at the age of 80, although of course I have no
power to vote in a parliamentary election.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1285?><hs_para UID="13102540000049" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000049">When<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:42:21"></hs_TimeCode>
I was young, no one could vote until they were 21 years old. It is now
unthinkable to go back to that age to start voting. Nowadays, the young
of 16 and 17 are independent enough to be voters
and should be allowed to vote in order to be
so<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:42:50"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13102540000290" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000290"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:42:47"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.42
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000050" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000050"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Young of Hornsey" PimsId="4702" UID="13102540000323" xid="1796" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000323">Baroness
Young of Hornsey (CB):</Member></B> My Lords, I thank the noble Lord,
Lord Tyler, for bringing us to the point of a Second Reading of this
admirably focused Private Member’s Bill. I do not want to
rehearse the various anomalies regarding the age at which it is
possible to marry and to join the Armed Forces, et cetera, as these
have been covered. Examples of countries with a voting age of 16 were
given in a very good speech by my noble friend Lady
Coussins.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000051" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000051">I
shall focus on maturity and political understanding. A number of noble
Lords have mentioned the lowering of the voting age from 21 to 18. In
1969, Lord Somers, speaking to his proposed amendment to the
Representation of the People Bill and arguing against this move, made
the following interesting comments. He
said:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13102540000273" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000273">“Mental
maturity can come only from experience. Recently we have seen some of
the efforts of those who are 18 and over at the London School of
Economics. I wonder how many of your Lordships would feel that they
would be suitable electors for the Government of our country. I
certainly do not. I do not think that they are more mature mentally.
They are far more ready to voice their opinions; they are far more
ready to question the wisdom of those who are older and wiser than they
are. But that does not mean that they are more
mature”.—[<I>Official Report</I>, 6/2/69; col.
214.]</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13102540000259" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000259">Those
are very telling remarks, which underpin a lot of people’s
opposition to giving 16 year-olds the vote. As a number of noble Lords
have suggested, maturity does not necessarily come with age and can
diminish as we get older. It is unhelpful to generalise on the basis of
age in this context.</hs_parafo>
<hs_para UID="13102540000052" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000052">For<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:44:35"></hs_TimeCode>
those noble Lords who have not seen it, perhaps I may recommend viewing
an interview on YouTube with a 12 year-old Egyptian boy, Ali Ahmed. To
date, it has had more than 3 million viewers. A reporter asked him to
explain why he was participating in a demonstration last October. He
stuns the reporter by referring to his opposition to a “fascist
theocracy”. When asked by the interviewer to define this term
because she did not know what it meant, he gives a critical analysis of
the Muslim Brotherhood, the party at that time in power. He does not
mince his words. He said that he was there to, “protest the
confiscation of the constitution by one single party”.
When<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:45:13"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:45:10"></hs_TimeCode>
asked about the progress the country has made, he asks right back,
“Do you mean politically or
socially<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:45:20"></hs_TimeCode>?”.
After a critique of the lack of equality for women, Ali Ahmed states
that he has read the country’s draft constitution on the
internet and declares that, “what is built on falsehood is false
itself”. When asked how he knows all this, his reply is telling
and simple. He says, “I listen to people a lot and I use my own
brain. Plus I read newspapers, watch tv and search in the
internet”.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000053">Even
if noble Lords have not seen that impressive interview, or watched a 14
year-old Kenyan, Richard Turere, explain on a TED talk how he developed
a 
<?notus-xml column=1286?>device that uses solar power to prevent lions from attacking his
community, or missed 16 year-old Jack Andraka responding to a family
death by inventing a cheap, effective test for pancreatic cancer, they
surely will be familiar with the hugely impressive 16 year-old Malala
Yousafzai, a nominee for the Nobel Peace Prize and a heroine and role
model for young people
everywhere.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000054" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000054"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:46:29"></hs_TimeCode>Of
course, I am not trying to argue that these young people are the norm
for their age. However, what they, and many more, have in common is the
good sense not to think that because they are young, they have nothing
to say about their world, the way it works and, importantly, how to
improve it. Unsurprisingly, the internet is an important factor.
Without it, awareness of their skills, knowledge and activism would
have taken much longer to penetrate our consciousness and the capacity
to spread the word on their achievements would be so much less. But,
importantly, for many of them it is a learning
tool<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:46:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000055" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000055">As
we all know, trawling the internet does not necessarily give the surfer
wisdom. Often the opposite is true but newspapers and other older media
do not always confer wisdom or knowledge on the reader or viewer
either. However, the internet and social media offer the opportunity
and the potential to gain an in-depth knowledge of the world around us
across national and cultural borders that was unimaginable 20 years
ago. Instead of putting down our young people for being glued to
screens in what we might see as unproductive, harmful ways, we could
harness the power of social media to encourage them to engage with the
democratic process and to transform it, for it surely is in need of
change.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13102540000056" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000056">Like
many other noble Lords have said today, my experience of visits to
schools is that most young people will profess to be ignorant of and
uninterested in politics. As the noble Baroness, Lady Smith, said, we
need to challenge that view rather than throw our hands in the air and
claim that all is lost. I have found that they are not interested in
party politics, which again echoes what other noble Lords have said,
and the stale, rehashed speeches and positions that are constantly
presented to them. If you get the right subject and teach it well, help
them to learn about it in a way that enables them to see the relevance,
and to develop their confidence, they will get involved, even if
initially it is about very local or even personal issues. That is not a
problem either. I do not see that level of activity as a problem at
all.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13102540000057" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000057">As my
noble friend Lady Coussins has said, many 16 year-olds are familiar
with our political structures through citizenship studies,
participation in mock elections at school, schools councils, the UK
Youth Parliament and so on. There are more than 1.5 million 16 and
17 year-olds in the UK, many of whom feel very strongly
about the issues that directly affect them, as well as educational
opportunities, and poverty here and overseas. We often refer to young
people as being disfranchised and alienated. In terms of driving the
agenda for enhancing their lives, they are. But are we seriously
suggesting that they should not have a say in shaping their, and our,
world? Many would say that they do not want to have the vote and would
agree that 
<?notus-xml column=1287?>they should not be allowed to do so. But we are not suggesting that they
should be compelled to vote, or at least some of us are not; simply
that they are enabled to. Enabling entails enhancing their education in
civic responsibility and improving their understanding of how power
works through political processes and mechanisms.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000058">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:49:46"></hs_TimeCode>
noble Lord, Lord Adonis, was emphatic about this issue during the
Question for Short Debate we had earlier this year. He made what I
think is an interesting point:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000274" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000274">“Every school
with a sixth form and every further education and sixth-form college
should have a polling station, and young people should be registered to
vote there—instead of there being the perversity that some
schools are actually closed on polling day so that the adults can vote
undisturbed”.—[<I>Official Report</I>, 27/2/13; col.
GC181.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13102540000260" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000260">I
heartily agree with that. Young people should be involved in a
meaningful way in the political process as early as possible in order
to create a basis for greater political engagement in later life.
Though it should not be regarded as a universal panacea for our
political culture and the state that it is in, votes at 16 could be
just the impetus we need to reinvigorate that political culture. Once
we have left education, few of us, young or old, are likely to be
exposed to a discussion as to why it is so important to vote, and those
leaving school at 16 may have to wait six or eight years before they
can cast their vote. When the voting age was lowered to 18, to my
frustration I had to wait for several years until I could exercise that
right.</hs_parafo>
<hs_para UID="13102540000059" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000059">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:50:57"></hs_TimeCode>
lament of Lord Somers in that earlier quotation from <I>Hansard</I> is
a familiar one and is often at the heart of arguments about the voting
age. Yes, young people will challenge our habits, thinking and actions,
as well as our judgment of what is right for the country and what is
wrong. That is their job and I hope that, through agreeing to progress
this Bill, we will let them get on with it.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13102540000291" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000291"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:51:15"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.51
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:51:15"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000060" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000060"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Kidron" PimsId="7000" UID="13102540000324" xid="2166" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000324">Baroness
Kidron (CB):</Member></B> My Lords, as others have said, central to
this debate is the question of maturity: whether a young person of 16
or 17 is mature enough to take on the mantle of independent thought and
wise enough to play their part in the democratic process. I will not
repeat what has already been said in the debate, but it seems that we
have not categorically decided when a child becomes an adult, and
therefore it is of little surprise that the interests of the young are
woefully unrepresented.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000061" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000061">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:46:21"></hs_TimeCode>
reality of the current political process is that the concerns of those
who vote become the concerns of the political class. As a result, the
young are suffering the worst employment rates, have a full-time wage
that cannot meet the ever increasing costs of housing, utilities and
transport. They have become burdened with debt for their education. We
have consigned them to be poorer, to live at home for longer, and to
look forward to bearing greater responsibilities for looking after the
old. They endure a lack of representation that is positively deforming
of their interests, so unless all of our citizens participate in the
political process, the “political market” will always
favour those with votes to spend. And yet we ask this under-represented

<?notus-xml column=1288?>group to make life-defining choices before the age at which they can
vote, choices that tacitly require investment in a future over which
they have no purchase. In doing so, we demand high levels of those same
qualities that we doubt they own, those of maturity, commitment and
wisdom. If we demand so much, perhaps we also owe them the tools to
help shape the future we are asking them to invest
in<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:53:25"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000062" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000062">The noble Lord, Lord
Tyler, referred to the positive relationship between citizenship
lessons and registering to vote in Ireland, while others have also
talked about citizenship. However, in September this year the statutory
requirement to provide citizenship education was, I think, disapplied.
The only formal entry point to the democratic process was loosened from
the statutory offer in our schools. Next spring will see the
introduction of individual electoral registration, legislation that
disproportionately affects young people as many of them move to
educational institutions and new towns and cities in search of work.
Would it not be a much more equitable state of affairs if every young
person left school with a full set of jabs, a national security number,
a decent education, already registered to vote and—as other
noble Lords have commented—confident to
vote<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:54:33"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000063" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000063">The habits that are
formed in youth “stick”, whether they are smoking or
reading, sports or debating. A voting habit in the next generation
would be transforming to our democracy. We are leaving it too late to
invest political power in the young, to make participation a norm, and
to give them agency over their investment in the future. We are leaving
it too late for them to have the right to demand a world that meets
their needs adequately. Some people assert that a 16 year-old is not
mature enough to vote, but the right to vote, as others have suggested,
is not contingent on maturity or wisdom. If it were, many of us adults
might be considered unfit. Voting well or correctly is not a
consideration
here.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000064" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000064">In the
Library note that has provided us with the background to this debate, I
was amused by the ever changing statistics on the voting patterns for
“Britain’s Got Talent” and “The X
Factor” versus electoral turnout. Having a right and
exercising it are not material; they are two separate issues. In my
capacity as co-founder of an educational charity, which is declared on
the register of interests, I have been privileged to have visited
scores of schools and talked to hundreds of young people over the past
decade. Scratch the surface and they display wisdom, energy and
foresight in copious quantities. The arguments about introducing an
unfit cadre into the electoral equation sounds suspiciously like other
arguments of exclusion made at other times.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000065" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000065">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:56:25"></hs_TimeCode>
question that should frame this debate is not about their suitability,
but ours. We have allowed a crisis to develop—a lack of
engagement and faith in the political process that threatens its
legitimacy. We have failed to deal with many of the most intractable
issues of the day and we have left for the next generation a multitude
of fiscal, environmental and political debts. Lowering the voting age
is not a question of our altruism. The political class needs some votes
to spend 
<?notus-xml column=1289?>on behalf of the long-term interests of the young, and for that we need
to allow young people to participate in our
democracy.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/57825ED3BB140BDEC7DA6245B0A805ADEFC7D765" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AF2-AG1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13102540000292" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000292"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:57:14"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.57
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:57:14"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time>
<hs_para UID="13102540000066" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000066"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13102540000325" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000325">Lord
Cormack (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, speaking in the gap, I should
like briefly to turn this into a debate. We have had a series of
speeches extolling the virtues of my noble friend Lord Tyler’s
measure. We heard half a speech expressing some equivocation from my
noble friend Lord Lexden—eloquently expressed, but certainly not
opposed to the Bill. I am surprised that no one has mentioned Malala
Yousafzai, that extraordinary young
woman<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:57:46"></hs_TimeCode>—</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000067"><B><Member ContinuationText="Noble Lords" PimsId="0" UID="13102540000326" xid="2182" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000326">Noble
Lords:</Member></B> Young of
Hornsey<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:57:47"></hs_TimeCode>!</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000068" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000068"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13102540000327" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000327">Lord
Cormack:</Member></B> If someone mentioned her, I apologise for missing
the reference. She is an extraordinary young woman of great courage. I
was born in Grimsby, where one of the great heroes of the First World
War died. He was Jack Cornwell, who was awarded a posthumous VC at the
age of 16 for his incredible bravery at the Battle of Jutland. And yet
I believe that the case is not as simple as has been suggested. It is
not a question of wisdom or maturity, although it is a question of some
degree of experience. I believe that to have a cohort of voters who are
still under the influence of their schoolteachers is perhaps something
that one ought to question a little more than some colleagues have
today.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000069" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000069"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:58:47"></hs_TimeCode>I
also believe in the rites of passage. There are certain things that one
should be aspiring towards. Yesterday I had the great privilege of
taking a group of Members of your Lordships’ House from the two
major parties and the Cross Benches to discuss with my noble friend
Lord Nash the desirability of better citizenship education, in
particular a ceremony when young people become citizens, based on the
ceremony that those who obtain British nationality now go through.
There is a great deal to be said for that, but I strongly suggest to
noble Lords that it is not as simple as my noble friend Lord Tyler has
been seeking to
suggest<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T10:59:28"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000070" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000070">My noble friends Lord
Tyler and Lord Lexden both referred to the decision that young people
of 16 will be able to vote in the Scottish referendum next year. I have
a granddaughter who will be among them. That was, as my noble friend
Lord Lexden said, a bit of shameless expediency on the part of the
leader of the Scottish National Party. When it was raised in this
House, I made the point that a precedent would have been created that
it would be difficult to argue against. The noble Lord, Lord Tyler,
made that point in his speech. However, I believe that it is incumbent
on those of us who have real reservations to argue at least for
caution.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000071" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000071">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:08:49"></hs_TimeCode>
do not speak as somebody who has no contact with the young: I was a
schoolmaster for 10 years before I entered the other place and have
maintained my contacts with schools and universities throughout those
years. I conduct seminars in this place for young people from America
who come over. I have a passionate 
<?notus-xml column=1290?>belief in the young. But to argue that because the referendum on Europe
will affect 16 year-olds more than others is a false—a
specious—argument. It will affect 14 year-olds and 12 year-olds
more than others. There has to be a right age and I believe that 18 is
the time. Although many are, of course, going on to universities and
colleges, full-time education is over and they are outside
the confines of the school. It is the time when they are allowed to buy
alcohol and cigarettes. It would be a pretty odd situation if
16 year-olds could vote but could not smoke or
drink.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000072" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000072">It<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:01:22"></hs_TimeCode>
is wrong to exploit the gap, but I believe that there are issues here
that noble Lords ought to
consider<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:01:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/D8A0060137E6221AA9B9C47A3DB8EC17279604AD" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AG2-AH1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000293" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000293">11.01
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000073" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000073"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Royall of Blaisdon" PimsId="485" UID="13102540000328" xid="1719" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000328">Baroness
Royall of Blaisdon (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, I do
not doubt the noble Lord’s passion for the young or his
experience. However, he is adamant that 18 is the right age to vote and
I believe very strongly that 16 is the right age to vote. The noble
Lord cited the importance of experience. I suggest that there are many
people in our country now over the age of 18 who have very limited
experience of life. Equally, we all come across extraordinary young
people, some of them cited by the noble Baroness, Lady Young, who face
the most enormous challenges in their lives. There are hundreds or even
thousands of them. They have wider life experience than I will ever
have, in terms of the difficulties that they confront in their lives. I
believe that those young people, at the age of 16, should have the
right to
vote.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000074" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000074">I often
disagree with the noble Lord, Lord Tyler, but as he lives in Stroud,
where the excellent David Drew, who is a believer in votes at 16, is
our prospective parliamentary candidate, I thought that there must be
other issues on which the noble Lord and I could agree.
Votes at 16 is, indeed, one of them. I am very grateful to
the noble Lord for introducing what I believe is an excellent short
Bill, which has my full
support.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000075" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000075">Like
my noble friend Lady Smith, I did not used to be in favour of votes at
16 but, over the past few years, I have met and exchanged views with
hundreds and hundreds of young people, the majority of whom I found to
be in favour of votes at 16. More importantly, those who are not in
favour express concern that they do not have enough knowledge to equip
themselves to vote and do not want the media—whether written
media, television or social media—to be their only guide. If
only many of the millions of people who do vote had the same
concern.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000076" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000076">I am
proud that my own party is now in favour of votes at 16. The policy was
not plucked from the air, as some have suggested—not in
today’s debate, I hasten to add—but is the result of a
clear policy-making process by which it was agreed that the voting age
should be reduced but that it must, in parallel, be accompanied by
improved citizenship education, including active
citizenship.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000077" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000077">The
noble Baroness, Lady Coussins, spoke of compulsory voting, which would
be an interesting issue to debate on another day. One idea that is
currently being discussed by some people inside and outside political
parties, inspired by a very good IPPR paper, is whether first-time
votes should be compulsory. 
<?notus-xml column=1291?>Habits formed in youth, as has been said, do stick and there is clear
evidence that once a person votes, they are likely to continue voting.
Does the Minister have a view on
that?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000078" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000078">The
noble Baroness, Lady Northover, told the House yesterday that we should
look forward to what she regarded as the wonderful new citizenship
syllabus. I hope it will be wonderful, but one of my concerns is that
there are not enough teachers who are qualified to teach citizenship.
The noble Lord, Lord Gardiner of Kimble, wrote me a helpful letter on
21 October in which he informed me
that:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13102540000275" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000275">“Data
published in the School Workforce Census in January 2013
shows that in November 2012 there were around 8,200 Citizenship
teachers teaching in publicly funded schools in England. Of these 7.7
per cent were recorded as having a post A level qualification in the
subject. The School Workforce Census showed that there were around
10,000 citizenship teachers of whom 6.2% had a qualification in the
subject”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13102540000261" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000261">That
was in 2010. I must ask the Minister why there has been such a huge
decrease. What are the Government going to do to ensure that there are
more qualified citizenship teachers and who is going to teach the new
citizenship syllabus? I hope that the aspiration of my Government will
be for at least one teacher in every secondary school to be qualified
to teach citizenship as well, perhaps, as some other subject. I have
seen some shining examples of best practice in citizenship
teaching—for example, in the Bethnal Green Academy—but it
is usually where there is at least one teacher with the appropriate
qualifications.
Citizenship<hs_TimeCode time="2000-01-01T00:00:00"></hs_TimeCode>
lessons should enable our young people to understand politics, but not
just in an academic way. They want to know how to vote and what
policies are being pursued and developed by political parties.
On<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:09:35"></hs_TimeCode> the issue of
how to vote, there was a salutary example during the local elections
earlier this year when a UKIP candidate standing for election went to
the polling station and had to ask the council official present how to
vote.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13102540000079" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000079">Young<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:09:35"></hs_TimeCode>
people want to have an input into politics. In the past, too many
schools have been wary about inviting politicians into schools to talk
politics, but the young people I meet want that. They do not just want
to hear from me, they want to hear from the Conservatives and the Lib
Dems and from local councillors, MPs and MEPs. It can be no surprise
that they have got strong views about health, transport, EMAs,
policing, crime, their communities and
poverty.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000080" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000080">A<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:06:58"></hs_TimeCode>
few weeks ago, I was in a primary school in Bradford, talking to a
small group of nine and 10 year-olds who face challenges in
their lives that you or I could never imagine. I asked them what one
thing they would like to happen to make their lives better. One of them
talked about broken bottles in her street, which made it difficult to
play. After a chat, she decided to write to her local councillor, but
the group also decided to ask the fantastic Joshua Project, a
community project for young people, to help them sweep the
streets in question, get rid of broken glass and nettles, and plant
flowers. I have no doubt that this is now happening. That is what
citizenship is all about: understanding where power lies—in this
case, with the council—and how to influence it but also being
active in shaping communities. That is why we are in favour not only of
good citizenship teaching but also active citizenship. 
<?notus-xml column=1292?>I could cite many examples but draw special attention to the
Prendergast-Ladywell Fields College in Lewisham, where the students
have been instrumental in creating the CitySafe Haven, and to the
Bethnal Green Academy again, where, having undertaken local surveys,
the students worked with local police to cut crime in the immediate
area. Both schools work closely with London Citizens, which does a
stunning
job.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000081" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000081">These
young people are now active citizens who want, or will want, to take an
active part in our democracy by voting at 16, and they should do so. I
agree with all that the noble Baroness, Lady Kidron, said this morning
and in her speech during the Second Reading of the Transparency of
Lobbying, Non-Party Campaigning and Trade Union Administration Bill. We
demand much of our young people and should give them the tools to do
what they need to do. Young people are often involved in single-issue
campaigns, which can be the start of a broader political understanding
and a journey towards democratic engagement. So why are the Government
seeking to stifle the voices of campaigners and curb their capacity to
campaign in the year before an election? The noble Lord, Lord Lexden,
whose involvement in the Hansard Society I warmly welcome, gave us some
dreadful figures about democratic engagement. I suggest that that is
exactly why campaigning is so important to young people and why it must
not be constrained in any
way.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000082" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000082">The noble
Lord, Lord Tyler, mentioned Bite the Ballot. I am a huge supporter of
that organisation, and of Michael Sani and his colleagues, who do a
brilliant job. They aspire to reverse the pattern of poor electoral
turnout—a shameful 44% of 18 to 24 year-olds at the last
election—and, in giving young people a voice, they
hope to make their votes and opinions count in the political arena.
Having seen Bite the Ballot in action, I want to clone its
energy and inspirational work. I was present at one session with my
noble friend Lord Bassam and my honourable friend Tristram
Hunt MP, before he became our shadow Secretary of State for Education.
We were at the Brighton Hove and Sussex Sixth Form College, where
citizenship is thriving. However, at the start of the session, only two
or three students had registered to vote. At the end of the session,
students were clamouring for voter registration forms so that they
could ensure that their voices were heard at the next
election.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000083" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000083">This<hs_TimeCode time="2000-01-01T00:00:00"></hs_TimeCode>
is not about hunting for votes or telling young people how to
vote—I have no doubt that many of those students will vote
Conservative, Lib Dem or Green at the next election—but it is
important that young people are equipped to vote. What plans do the
Government have to make registration forms available in schools, sixth
form colleges, FE colleges and universities as a matter of course? Like
the noble Baroness and my noble friend Lord Adonis, I am very much in
favour of having polling stations at all schools and colleges where
people should be eligible to
vote.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000084" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000084">As we
know, the introduction of individual electoral registration will
disproportionately affect your people, so I am delighted that Bite the
Ballot is collaborating with many organisations and educational
establishments to ensure a robust and reliable electoral register
before the transition to IER in 2014.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1293?><hs_para UID="13102540000085" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000085">We all have a
responsibility, from all political parties and none, to
ensure that as many people as possible are registered to vote so that
they can exercise their democratic right. One of our biggest democratic
challenges in this country is lack of trust in the political system, a
strong anti-politics feeling and apathy. It is a lethal combination in
a democracy, and it means that, too often, those
who most need a voice do not have a voice. Votes at 16 is a great way
of energising the debate, ensuring that all young people, not just the
privileged few, are informed and empowered. It is also the right thing
to do.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000086" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000086">In<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:11:29"></hs_TimeCode>
a debate last night at the Oxford Labour Club, everyone recognised that
this Government’s policies have had a profoundly negative effect
on the lives of young people. It is therefore right that young people
should have a say in who makes and implements those
policies<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:10:00"></hs_TimeCode>. I am
very pleased to support this
Bill.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/FA2B050E91DA00E56C91F34CD21FBE7D34C6ECB4" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AH2-AJ1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000294" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000294">11.12
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:10:00"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000087" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000087"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13102540000329" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000329">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, this has been a
high-quality debate and I thank all those who have taken part. I have
to say that there is no consensus within the Government on this change.
This reflects differing views in society at large and the divergent
positions on the topic within and across political parties. Having said
that, let me bring one of the underlying issues out into the open; let
us all be a little honest: the reason why the Greens, the Liberal
Democrats and the Labour Party are in favour of votes at 16 is not
completely unconnected with the hope and belief that young people are
more likely to vote for those sorts of party, and the position of the
Conservative Party for various reasons is not entirely the same. The
noble Lord, Lord Lexden, is an enthusiast for making it easier for
those who live overseas to vote. That again is an important issue in
terms of democratic participation. It is not completely unconnected
perhaps with the belief that those people might just be a little more
inclined to vote Conservative. So we need a cross-party consensus on
the franchise and we need to approach this as carefully and
consensually as
possible<hs_TimeCode time="2000-01-01T00:00:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000088" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000088">I
thank the noble Lord, Lord Tyler, for continuing to push for this
change; it is very much a debate that we need to continue to have. I
was rather struck by the report of the youth council saying that there
was a severe lack of evidence that there is a demand for votes at 16,
so it is a discussion that we need to
continue<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:13:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000089" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000089">The
debate has gone rather more widely than this issue. We have
discussed the decline in participation in party politics, the shift to
single-issue politics and disengagement and alienation from politics.
Those are issues that all of us in political parties need to be
concerned about. It is a long-term shift, having started in the late
1960s with disillusionment with the then Labour Government, and it
creates real problems for all of us who are involved in the trade-offs
which politicians, particularly those in government, have to
address<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:14:07"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000090" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000090">Single-issues
campaigns always want 100% of what they go for. I recall one of my
Liberal Democrat colleagues, a lawyer, saying, “When you give a
particular group 80% of what they wanted, they attack you that
you didn’t give the other 20%”.
Government is very often about compromise and about realising that you 
<?notus-xml column=1294?>cannot spend everything on everything, and
single-issue campaigning can to some extent deteriorate politics. I do
not want to edge over in the Transparency of Lobbying Bill beyond
saying that I have a particularly painful awareness this morning of the
new political technologies and the extent to which singe-issue
campaigning can go into that area, because the Electoral Reform Society
successfully crashed my computer last night in attack which was worthy
of Russian technology in the way that it took
place<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:15:07"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000091">Perhaps
I may comment on some of the issues that have been raised. To the noble
Lord, Lord Tyler, I say that the precedent in Scotland is one that has
been brought about by the Scottish Government for the
Scottish referendum; it does not necessarily affect where we go from
here in the rest of the United Kingdom.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000092" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000092">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:15:28"></hs_TimeCode>
noble Lord, Lord Lexden, listed the social dimension of party youth
wings. The particularly close nature of that social dimension among
young people of one sort or another is something that I remember well;
indeed, I met my wife at a Young Liberal
conference<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:15:47"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000093" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000093">How
to re-engage young people in politics and how far citizenship education
relates to that seem to me to be at the core of this debate. My own
personal view is that the need to make sure that citizenship education
is taken more seriously in schools, with all the other pressures on the
curriculum, is in many ways the most powerful argument for considering
lowering the voting age. We are all of us here, I am sure, committed to
more effective citizenship education and encouraging young people to
vote. I am not myself persuaded, nor are the Government, that making
the first vote compulsory would help in this regard. I was wondering,
as the noble Baroness was suggesting it, how we would enforce it. Would
we impose fines on young people for not voting or would we send them to
prison? Would we have compulsory service of some sort? There are real
problems in insisting on compulsory voting if we want to put penalties
on
it<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:16:50"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000094" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000094">I
strongly share the noble Baroness’s views about active
citizenship. As I have said previously, having started as an initial
sceptic about the citizen service scheme which the Conservatives
initiated, I have become a convert. I have found that through that
young people find that working within their own community and promoting
projects to help others within it is something which 15 and 16
year-olds are capable of and can enjoy, and it gives them a sense of
local engagement. I suspect that we need to spend more time working on
community councils—really local councils, which we have
lost—if we are to re-engage an awful lot of people with
politics. There is a whole host of issues there which are not within
the frame of this
debate<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:17:36"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000095" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000095">I
think that I heard the noble Baroness, Lady Kidron, say that every
young person should be equipped with a national security
number<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:17:42"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000096" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000096"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Kidron" PimsId="7000" UID="13102540000330" xid="2166" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000330">Baroness
Kidron:</Member></B> I meant social
security<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:17:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000097" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000097"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13102540000331" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000331">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> All thoughts of shadows of the
dominant state emerged there. For those of us who are concerned about
the debate on data sharing, data protection and data privacy, I note
that that is not a phrase that one would want to use
lightly<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:18:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1295?><hs_para UID="13102540000098" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000098">I
have touched on citizenship education. The noble Baroness, Lady Smith,
raised the delicate issue of taxpaying and voting. That relates
particularly to the participation of overseas voters. We are unclear
about the principles which would apply to voting as
such<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:18:28"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000099">Having
welcomed the debate, the Government have no agreed view on how we
should respond. I wish the noble Lord, Lord Tyler, well. I am glad to
hear that the policy is in the Labour Party manifesto, and I hope that
it will follow through on that commitment in its manifesto as
vigorously as it did its commitment to Lords reform in its previous
manifesto<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:18:47"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13102540000295" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000295"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:18:47"></hs_TimeCode></I>11.18
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000100" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000100"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Tyler" PimsId="4859" UID="13102540000332" xid="1879" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000332">Lord
Tyler:</Member></B> My Lords, this has been a very high-quality debate,
and I am enormously grateful to all those who have spoken, and indeed
those who have attended. I do not know whether this is the normal
attendance on a Friday morning, but I think that all those who have
listened to the debate as well as contributed will agree that this has
been the House of Lords at its
best<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:19:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000101" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000101">We
are sometimes slightly complacent about the quality of our debates, so
I should perhaps draw to your Lordships’ attention that the
other place on 24 January voted by 119 MPs to 46 in support
of a similar Motion to this—so they are not quite as retrograde
as we sometimes think.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000102" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000102">Your Lordships have
demonstrated a maturity of judgment this morning, but also that we are
young at heart. I am grateful to all those who have taken part. I do
not propose to comment on all the contributions, because there are
other important Bills to follow, but I want to take up one or two
points very quickly. I am delighted that my noble friend Lord Lexden is
joining the team at the Hansard Society, in which I am also involved.
The noble Baroness, Lady Kidron, and my noble friend Lord Goodhart
pointed out that one of our problems about disengagement is that people
get out of the habit of voting before they even start. That is a strong
argument for combining this proposal with the natural thread of the
citizenship
programme.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000103" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000103">I
am particularly grateful to the noble Baroness, Lady Royall, for her
commitment. She said honestly that she had changed her mind on this
issue through a combination of principle and practical experience. Many
of us are in the same position. I must say to my noble friend Lord
Wallace that I suspect that his official brief was rather less
equivocal than he was, because he is obviously having to tread a very
careful path. I say to him, as a fellow historian, imagine if the great
Whig Government of 1832 had said in preparing for the Reform Bill,
“We will seek a consensus”. A very distinguished
constitutional historian in my former college, Exeter College, Oxford,
said recently apropos of the Lords reform process—I paraphrase,
because I do not have his book before me, but I recommend
it—that the search for consensus is a shortcut to a dead end. My
noble friends should beware of the idea that we must always go at the
speed of the slowest, with the lowest common
denominator<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:21:42"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000104" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000104">I
shall not say more. I am very grateful to all those who have
contributed but, in the interests of brevity and those who are to speak
in the later debates, I now invite your Lordships’ House to give
the Bill a Second Reading.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1296?><hs_Procedure UID="13102540000360" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000360">Bill read a second
time and committed to a Committee of the whole
House.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/FEFA6AEFA8F276A50398C398B6F9858CA0D42C81" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AJ2-AK1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102540000357" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000357">Medicinal
Labelling Bill
[HL]<a href="http://services.parliament.uk/bills/2013-14/medicinallabelling.html" title="Medicinal Labelling Bill [HL]"></a></hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13102540000296" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000296">11.22
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13102540000367" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000367">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Winston" PimsId="4649" UID="13102540000333" xid="1499" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000333">Lord
Winston</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102540000315" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000315">That the Bill be
read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102540000105" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000105"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Winston" PimsId="4649" UID="13102540000334" xid="1499" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000334">Lord
Winston (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, first, I am so pleased to see the
noble Baroness sitting on the Front Bench, but so sad that the noble
Earl, Lord Howe, is not fit at the moment. We agree that he is a most
loved and respected Member of this House and wish him well. We fully
understand that it is far more important that he recovers completely to
good health than that he deal with the issues that I want to raise in
the Bill. I know that the noble Baroness will give an excellent answer
to the questions that I will raise. Secondly, it is rather sad that the
Bill is being read on a Friday. A large number of Members of the House
have told me personally that they support it, and many of my scientific
friends, who are working, have been unable to come in on a Friday but
have certainly been very
supportive<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:23:33"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000106" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000106">Why
do we need a Bill of this kind? There is no question but that animal
research in the United Kingdom has been considerably under threat
repeatedly for a long time. Experimenters such as me who hold licences
often find it difficult to do research which we regard as an ethical
necessity. The biggest single area where animal research is needed is
in the development of pharmaceuticals and, to a lesser extent, the
development of vaccines. It is true, of course, that with reverse
vaccinology and the ability to use genomic medicine, we can often
design vaccines on a piece of paper, without the need for such
research, but even there, vaccines have always been tested using at
least eggs, so anyone using a vaccine is effectively benefiting from
that research. As your Lordships will be aware, in terms of public
health, the area in which we often lag behind in this country, despite
the excellence of our research, vaccines are one of the most important
means of protection of ourselves, our children and the population. They
will always be particularly important with the rising risk of pandemic
infections across the globe. Indeed, many people feel that that is a
more serious threat than that of climate
change.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000107" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000107">It is
a fact that virtually every drug, every medicine that we take, with the
possible exception of aspirin and digitalis for the heart, which is
hardly ever used nowadays, was developed as a result of animal
research. The pharmaceutical industry in this country is one of our
most important and critical industries. It is under considerable
threat. We have seen a diminution of the pharmaceutical companies in
this country. For example, it is very sad for the United Kingdom that
Pfizer has moved offshore its research establishment in Sandwich, in
Kent. We have lost a great deal of R&amp;D, which is important for that
work, and, with it, the trials that might be done.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1297?><hs_para UID="13102540000108" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000108">I fear that one issue is
that although the pharmaceutical companies desperately need that work,
they have been very reluctant to put their heads above the parapet.
Despite repeated suggestions to the Association of British
Pharmaceutical Industries that the industry should engage the public
much more readily to say why that research is necessary, on the whole
it has been reluctant to make any waves which might cause more public
concern about what is going on with drugs. I have to say that in
medicine in general, as I am sure that your Lordships are aware, a huge
number of developments could not have been possible without animal
research. I am sure that everyone in the Chamber agrees that it would
have been unthinkable for us to have transferred a human embryo to the
uterus of an infertile patient without first making sure
that an embryo transferred in the mouse and then in other mammals was
not made abnormal by the culture in vitro. That is a given and we
accept it and benefit from it in all sorts of ways. Medicine has always
benefited from
that.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000109">The work
that is done in this field is very strictly regulated by the Home
Office. It is increasingly difficult to obtain a licence. I have just
had a letter from the Home Office to renew my licence and I am told by
my institution that unless I sign up very quickly for that process it
will take me at least six months to get a licence. That is a
problem for research in universities, particularly when a PhD student
wants to start a
project<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:28:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000110" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000110">Of
course, we all espouse the idea of the three Rs—reduction,
refinement and replacement of animals—but the truth is that the
figures show that the number of transgenic mice used in research is
increasing, and has been steadily over some years, as it must continue
to do. A transgenic mouse is a mouse that has been genetically modified
in a humane way, usually by tampering with the embryo, although there
are other ways to do it. These mice are important models used in the
drug industry and every research establishment where animals are used
in biology. The need for animal research in drugs will probably
increase rather than decrease. Often we do not state that clearly
enough<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:29:08"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000111">Let
me give one example. The most successful area in drug development at
the moment is unquestionably in the treatment of cancer. It is a fact
that at least one-third of us in this Chamber will eventually develop
cancer as we age—unless we are thrown out of the Chamber in due
course by a cull. The incidence of cancer will rise. As a
result of genomic medicine, we are now able to make targeted
therapies that are specific to the individual genome of that particular
cancer.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13102540000112" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000112">As we
go through life and as we age, from the egg through to the final stages
of life, cell division results and more and more mutations. There are
at least 100,000 mutations believed to be responsible for cancer in
different cells. So far, the drug companies have managed to manufacture
and target therapies for about 297 mutations. They are greatly accorded
but in fact they do not work particularly well because we need to do
more research. However, they often work better than any other therapy,
and of course they are much more humane to the patient because the side
effects are much more controlled; they do not cause the 
<?notus-xml column=1298?>severe injury that patients suffer from. This is a very important
example of where mouse models will be essential in medicine and in drug
companies in
future<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:30:39"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000113" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000113">In my view, a packet
that is clearly labelled so that the public understand that animal
research is necessary for the development of the drug that they are
taking or the vaccine that they are using is really important as a part
of public debate, and as a recognition that this research is not only
necessary but that it is done properly and humanely and is entirely
ethical. The alternatives, I think, are
not<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:31:05"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000114" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000114">What
are those alternatives? Cell culture has been posited but it does not
work because it does not have the intact animal, the cell signalling is
quite different in cell cultures and we cannot replace the sort of work
that we do in physiology by culturing cells. Computer modelling has
also been posited but is a way off what is required. Organ culture is
slightly better, but often the best way of doing organ culture might
well be with modified organs from animals, which would of course
require animal research where we had modified the genes in those organs
so that they could mimic what was going on. For example, the piece of
research that I am doing at Imperial College involves modifying
kidneys, livers and hearts so that we can potentially look at organs
that have been humanised—for example, from the pig. That area
will be increasingly important, as xenotransplantation might possibly
be in due
course<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:32:08"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:32:02"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000115" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000115">I
am afraid that we have failed to recognise just how humane our laws
actually are. Last night I got home at about
1.30<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:32:15"></hs_TimeCode> am from a
visit to Keele University, whose medical school uses animal research.
The vice-chancellor said, “Of course, we keep quiet about our
animal house. It has only small animals”. However, every
institution should be saying that these animal houses are essential to
the progress of the research that is needed for humanity. At Imperial
College, where I work, there is a very large animal facility, but
pretty well every university that has biological research going on must
and does use animal models, as does the entire pharmaceutical industry.
It makes sense that we are open about that, but for far too long we
have sheltered behind the parapet because we have been frightened of
threats. My friend Colin Blakemore has had firebomb threats; indeed, so
have I in the past. However, although I am in the public eye and am
known to be doing animal research, in the past few years I have not
seen any evidence of antagonism from the public. That openness is an
advantage, because if you do it properly you will be
trusted<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:33:32"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000116" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000116">What
are the disadvantages of a Bill such as this? First, there is the
question of what the attitude of the drug companies might be. Will this
be costly to add to the packet? Given that, for example, for a cancer
drug it might cost £600 million to £900 million to
develop a single targeted molecule, it does not seem unreasonable to
put a message on the packet for a few extra coppers. So why should the
drug companies not do that? If you talk to scientists at these drug
companies, which I have done in various companies throughout the
country, they universally applaud this measure; they think that it is a
good thing to be considered. What about patients? Would it actually
prevent them taking their medication? I do not think so. We eat meat
but people do not 
<?notus-xml column=1299?>destroy butchers’ shops. In fact, when you think about it, animal
farming is a good deal less humane than the restrictive and thoroughly
humane work done in laboratories looking at animal research. Indeed,
those noble Lords who have visited an abattoir will know
full well how unpleasant that is compared with the cleanliness and
scrupulousness of how we conduct our work with animals—for
example, in a
university<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:34:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000117" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000117">The
issue is therefore not only the attitude of patients, who I do not
believe would present a problem, but also the attitude of researchers.
In my view, it is very important for young people not to feel that the
work they are doing is reprehensible. Noble Lords may not always
understand this, not being in that community, but it is amazing that so
many researchers who I have had as junior staff have felt very
threatened—for example, by authorities who argue that their work
is reprehensible or unethical. For example, I do not want to rail
against the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Authority, but it is
extraordinary how many of my staff were reluctant to work
with human embryos because they felt that somehow that work was not
regarded as being proper and appropriate. That is certainly true of
animal research.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000118" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000118">The Bill is being
introduced because I believe that in our society we need more
transparency in, and recognition of, the need for this valuable
activity, which is essential for human health and in my view will
remain so in the future. I beg to
move<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:36:09"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/4E97DD24A0EDB4E5E1190C37F8634A455131BF63" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AK2-AL</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000297" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000297">11.36
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:36:07"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000119" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000119"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Willis of Knaresborough" PimsId="5783" UID="13102540000335" xid="2056" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000335">Lord
Willis of Knaresborough (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I rise with a
little trepidation following the noble Lord, Lord Winston. I think that
all of us who heard that remarkable speech recognise someone who has a
real passion not only for his Bill but also for the whole of the
medical science that he has been involved with. We are very grateful
indeed to him for introducing the Bill.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000120" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000120">I welcome my noble
friend to the Front Bench. This is the first time that she has replied
to a debate that I have taken part in. She always agreed with me when
she was on the Back Benches; I trust that she will do the same on this
occasion<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:36:59"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000121" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000121">I
speak in the debate not as a scientist—indeed, I think that all
of us here feel rather humble and inadequate compared with the noble
Lord, Lord Winston—but as chairman of the Association of Medical
Research Charities, which represents some 127 medical research
charities. Our members raise about £1.3 billion a year for
medical research, which is roughly equivalent to what the Government
put into medical research. This is therefore an incredibly pertinent
subject for our members. If people are going to donate to medical
research charities, they need to have an understanding of what it is
that they are donating to, and to have confidence that their donations
are going to ethical research.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000122" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000122">As a group of
charities, we are spending a significant amount of our time at our
board meetings and with our members discussing the whole question of
the use of animals in science, and what the grants we are making to
researchers are being used for. While we are hugely supportive of the
three Rs, the reality is that 
<?notus-xml column=1300?>that is not enough. A campaign by Animal Aid, an organisation aimed at
disrupting medical science, has not been effective but has been
disturbing. Targeting major charities like Cancer Research UK, Diabetes
UK, the British Heart Foundation and the Alzheimer’s Society, it
has tried to persuade individuals that donating to these charities
means donating to the evil vivisection of animals, and it is therefore
wrong and they should stop donating. That is an important issue,
because if we were to cut off a significant supply of resources, we
would be doing a lot of
damage<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:39:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000123" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000123">The
noble Lord has introduced an innovative idea in his Bill, which I am
very supportive of, but there are a couple of major questions. First,
would it raise awareness about animal research? Secondly,
would it have any other impacts that we might not want, such as the
ones the noble Lord referred
to?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000124" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000124">Labelling
is not new. In fact, successive Governments have supported the
labelling of tobacco products. When they brought that in, they must
have thought that it was an effective way of communicating to the
public that there are some pretty harmful effects when you buy a packet
of cigarettes or cigars. If you are taking a drug that has been
prescribed by your GP, approved by NICE and funded by the Government,
there is an undeniable logic in having a simple message on it which
states, “This is not only okay but has been appropriately tested
on animals”. That must be right. But the reality is that simply
having a message on the packet is not enough. You need to know what is
behind that, and we need to do a great deal more. I am pretty sure that
the noble Lord, Lord Winston, would agree with
that.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000125" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000125">The
second issue is whether the provision would have any other impact.
Quite frankly, that issue worries me more than the first one. There is
a real problem here. The NHS spends around £9 billion a year on
its drug bill but hundreds of millions of pounds is wasted because
people do not take the drugs they are prescribed or do not complete the
course. There is a real challenge as to whether this labelling would
lead to people saying, “I will not take that because
it has been tested on animals”. You would have to do some market
research on the issue. I suspect that it would have a pretty low impact
but the research would need to be
done<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:41:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000126" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000126">Are the public attuned
with this issue? BIS, using Ipsos MORI, regularly looks at the
public’s attitude to using animals in medical research. The
majority of the public seem to accept that research using animals is
necessary. However, the latest poll, in April 2012, shows a slight drop
in public support for research. The last time the research was done, in
2010, about 73% said that they supported the use of animals
in research if certain conditions were met. That number dropped to 63%
in 2012, with the number of those objecting to the use of animals in
medical science increasing from about 35% to 37%.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000127" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000127">I support the Bill
introduced by the noble Lord, Lord Winston, because of those figures.
There is clearly a slight shift in the public’s attitude which
needs to be addressed; it cannot simply be ignored as a
blip. Although the number of those wanting an outright ban
has consistently decreased every time a new poll is taken, the number
of those who want to know more is 
<?notus-xml column=1301?>nevertheless increasing. I think that that is healthy. If people are
saying, “I don’t know how to answer your question because
I don’t know what animals are being used for”, it is an
important statement.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000128" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000128">It is important that
all of us involved in this area of science—whether we be
scientists or charitable funders, as in my case—try to do more.
The public are very supportive of medical research charities but our
members have to do more. It is not good enough simply to give grants to
scientists to carry out important research; we should also be telling
our members what those grants are being used for. In fact, many of our
grants are being used to research key conditions such as cancer and
Parkinson’s and to find cures for arthritis. We are funding all
those key areas. We have therefore been encouraging our charities to be
much more open and to ensure that they explain their role, and they
have been very effective indeed in doing so.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000129" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000129">For instance,
Alzheimer’s Research UK has produced an interesting leaflet,
<I>Why </I><I>R</I><I>esearch using </I><I>A</I><I>nimals can help
defeat </I><I>Dementia</I>, which clearly
states:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13102540000276" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000276">“Flies
and mice bred to develop amyloid and tau in their brains have been
vital for helping scientists understand these hallmark
Alzheimer’s proteins, tracking how they build up and finding
clues to why this could be so damaging in people”.</hs_quote>
<hs_parafo UID="13102540000262" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000262">Almost every family
in the land who includes an elderly person will have somebody involved
with dementia or Alzheimer’s. It is important to tell people
that by using animals we are on a journey to finding at least
amelioration, which we hope will lead to cures at some time in the
future.</hs_parafo> <hs_para UID="13102540000130" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000130">The
British Heart Foundation has produced some marvellous publicity showing
how vital medicines using ACE inhibitors are allowing people to live
longer. Again, that is directly relevant to the reasons for
using it on animals. The foundation also had a marvellous campaign
using zebra fish. It had large billboards illustrating that
the use of zebra fish has had a significant impact in improving our
understanding of how the heart works; indeed, it has been able to look
at regrowing proteins to effect cures. A significant number of our
members have had similar campaigns that I could mention.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000131" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000131">AMRC can, however, do
more. We have established an animal research working group of all our
members to ensure that every one of them that funds animal research
talks about it and makes clear to their members what they are doing. We
also recognise that we have to work with the bioscience industry to
develop openness. In 2012, some 40 organisations within the charitable
sector of the bioscience industry that are involved in funding animal
research for medical science came together to launch their
<I>Declaration </I><I>on Openness o</I><I>n Animal Research</I>, which
committed all signatories to agreeing principles and practical steps
for the whole community.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000132" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000132">All these steps are
important in driving forward the idea. Interestingly, over
the past few months the International Debate Education Association has
been posing the question in universities on whether, “This House
would ban all forms of animal research”. I think that the
debating society at the university where the noble Lord is the
chancellor debated that target. Of the 24
universities that held a debate among their 
<?notus-xml column=1302?>young, intelligent people, every single one rejected the proposal that
we should ban animal science. If you bring this debate to people and
give them proper, educated, adult reasoning, the result is a buy-in and
understanding of what you are trying to
do.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000133" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000133">I am sad
to say, however, that there is a real issue with the Department of
Health. I understand that the department does not itself fund research
using animals. At this point, I should say that I could not compliment
the Government more for their funding of science, particularly medical
science. The Medical Research Council had an above- inflation grant
from the last spending round while the NIHR, which looks at medical
research within the NHS, has constantly had increased funding. I have
no gripes at all in that area. When it comes to recognising that
animals are used to develop scientific cures both in pharmaceuticals
and in the procedures used in the NHS, however, the NHS is silent.
There is nothing on the NIHR website which supports the use of animals
in science but there is a bold statement which basically says,
“We do not use and do not fund the use of animals in
science”.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000134" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000134">In order for the noble
Lord’s Bill to have real success, it needs a buy-in from the
department. The department must lead on this. It cannot simply say that
it is BIS or another department that does science using animals and
that, “It’s nothing to do with us, gov”. It has to
be a standard bearer and say that patients are treated because animals
have been used quite humanely and quite superbly in terms of finding
cures for a host of diseases. I hope that the Bill receives a Second
Reading and that the Government will give it a fair wind as it moves
through the
House.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/1002AB49A6E5818984860911F2EAF37682E5642F" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AM-AN1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000298" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000298"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T11:50:20"></hs_TimeCode>11.50
am</hs_time>
<hs_para UID="13102540000135" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000135"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Turnberg" PimsId="4356" UID="13102540000336" xid="1473" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000336"><B>Lord
Turnberg (</B><B>Lab</B><B>):</B></Member> My Lords, I am very pleased
to support my noble friend’s Bill. I believe it is timely and
important. He introduced the Bill with his usual panache which I find
difficult to emulate. It is a pleasure to follow my friend the noble
Lord, Lord Willis. I welcome coming after him, even though he has
stolen much of what I had to say. It will not stop me, of course, but I
enjoyed listening to
him.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000136" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000136">I should
express my interests as a medical researcher in a previous life and now
as scientific adviser to the AMRC, in which organisation I work very
closely with the noble Lord, Lord Willis. In the more recent past, I
was chairman of NC3Rs—the National Centre for the Replacement,
Reduction and Refinement of Animals in Research. All the 120 or so
members of the AMRC sign up to support animal research where that is
essential to improve human health and cure disease and where it is
performed under strictly regulated conditions. It is worth remembering
that AMRC members represent a huge variety of patient groups, from
Parkinson’s disease to cancer, from Alzheimer’s disease
to asthma and from diabetes to leukaemia. So a very wide section of
society who suffer these diseases or care for those suffering from them
recognise the value of animal research where that is essential for
improvements in their
care.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000137" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000137">In
chairing the NC3Rs, it has become clear that it is also important in
the context of this Bill. NC3Rs was set up by the Government to support
research that 
<?notus-xml column=1303?>would lead to ways of replacing animals in research by the use of
non-animal techniques, such as those that my noble friend Lord Winston
described, or if that is not possible, to reduce the number of animals
needed to do a piece of research and in all circumstances
to refine research to minimise the suffering of animals.
Chairing that body was an interesting experience since it had
representatives from not only the scientific community but industry,
animal welfare organisations and the Home Office animal inspectorate.
Despite those different backgrounds, there was unanimity of
purpose in what we did. It turned out that neither the pharmaceutical
industry nor the basic scientists were at all resistant to the idea of
replacing animals or reducing the numbers of animals used. In fact, the
pharmaceutical industry would be relieved of the considerable expense
of animal research and would be able to avoid the opprobrium that is
sometimes heaped on it for doing
it.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000138">The fact
is that animal research is absolutely essential in many circumstances,
and although we in NC3Rs supported some excellent work that had an
impact on the use of animals, as I will describe in a moment, it
remains the case that research in animals is vital in the basic
science, the discovery of new treatments and the testing safety of
drugs before they can be given to patients. A very high proportion of
all animal research is done to test the toxicity of new treatments.
Huge numbers of animals are used. The industry does not like doing it.
The expense and the unpleasant publicity surrounding it does not make
it easy, but it has to do it because of the strict rules of the
regulators. The MHRA in the UK, the EMA in Europe and the
FDA in the USA would not allow a drug to be sold unless they were
convinced that it was safe for human use, as demonstrated by toxicity
studies in animals. We, in NC3Rs, were able to show how the number and
the range of animals used in these tests could be reduced, and the
industry was very happy to take those recommendations on board, but at
the end of the day the regulators have to be satisfied, quite rightly,
that any new drug is safe. Of course, Home Office inspectors make sure
that the conditions under which animal research is carried out are
strictly controlled and standards of animal care are maintained, but it
has to be accepted that research in animals is
essential.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000139">In
any debate on animal research there is always going to be a wide range
of views from the extreme animal rights groups at one end to the
scientific community at the other, but the vast majority of people
somewhere in the middle will always be concerned for the welfare of
animals and be unhappy if they are treated badly or inhumanely. They
certainly are concerned if there are reports of animal maltreatment and
want to be reassured that systems are in place to minimise suffering
and that animal use is essential for the discovery and use of new cures
for their
ills.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000140" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000140">I
believe that labelling all drugs with a note indicating that animals
have been used in their testing, as they always have been used, would
go a considerable way to opening up the public’s knowledge of
how drugs have to be tested for their safety and, equally importantly,
point to the care and attention that is given to controlling the
conditions under which such research is carried out. I cannot see that
any rational person would be put off taking their medicines by such a
provision.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1304?><hs_para UID="13102540000141" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000141">This
Bill is one step, but I hope it will open up the discussion and bring
some sense and reality to a debate that is too often
surrounded by
misinformation.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13102540000299" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000299">11.57
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000142" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000142"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Wheeler" PimsId="5797" UID="13102540000337" xid="2066" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000337">Baroness
Wheeler (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, on behalf of these
Benches, I send our best wishes to the noble
Earl, Lord Howe, and welcome the noble Baroness, Lady Jolly,
to the government Front Bench role. We welcome the opportunity
presented by my noble friend Lord Winston in this Bill to
address the important issue of animal research. There are high levels
of general acceptance among the public for scientific animal research
which leads to vital breakthroughs and improvements in the
understanding and treatment of a wide range of human diseases and
conditions.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000143" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000143">This
public support depends on the humane treatment of animals and research
being carried out only if there is clear benefit and there are no other
means of achieving it. It is therefore right that today’s focus
is on both what information is supplied to the public to raise
awareness and its possible impact and how we assess and step up
progress on the overall work the Government are undertaking in this
area.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000144" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000144">My noble
friend Lord Winston argues his case, in his usual fascinating and
expert way, for the need to make clear to the public the important,
indeed vital, role played by animal research in physiological medical
research in almost every field. He is absolutely right in citing
developments in his own field of in vitro fertilisation and
reproductive biology and in other key areas such as cancer treatments
and vaccines. We heard of other convincing examples from the other
noble Lords who spoke.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000145" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000145">My noble
friend’s Bill proposes, as a key way of raising public awareness
and understanding, making it mandatory for medicines to make it clear
on the label that a drug has been made possible for human consumption
only because of animal testing. We believe there is a compelling case
for looking at how the information on drugs supplied to the user can be
improved in this respect and in a number of ways. The MHRA guidance on
labelling and packaging of medicines needs to be reviewed and updated.
Can the Minister advise the House on the work that is being undertaken
on this?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000146" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000146">The
noble Lord, Lord Willis, and my noble friend Lord Turnberg referred to
the Association of Medical Research Charities of which they are leading
members. AMRC is clear and up front about why its members support the
use of animals in research, where it is necessary and there is no
alternative, and strongly encourage as best practice the widespread use
of leaflets and blogs when members talk about research breakthroughs
where animals were
used.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000147" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000147">We are
also having this debate hotfoot on the inclusion in the Care Bill
earlier this week of a key government amendment on promoting
transparency in research. That was essentially about clinical
trials, but the principles of transparency in the
registration, publication and dissemination of research
findings and data access apply to what we are
discussing
today.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000148" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000148">My
noble friend Lord Winston expressed his concern and disappointment at
the reluctance and failure of the pharmaceutical industry and many of
the research 
<?notus-xml column=1305?>universities to engage in raising public awareness. I am sure that he is
right that much more has to be done by them to move this agenda
forward. However, we share the AMRC’s cautions, as set out by
the noble Lord, Lord Willis, that before a big step such as labelling
medicines is taken we need to have clearer evidence about what the
impact on public opinion and awareness would be, and how any negative
impacts on patients and their health are to be
addressed.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000149" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000149">The
Government are committed to reducing the use of animals in scientific
research and ending the testing of household products on animals. We
know that this is a complex issue, and I look forward to hearing from
the Minister on the progress being made, although I realise that we are
ranging across the responsibilities of both the Department of Health
and the Home Office, and those of other departments, in this debate and
the issues arising from it. The recent article from the NC3Rs chief
executive, Dr Vicky Robinson, shows just how difficult it currently is
to measure progress on the three Rs principles on animal research, and
how we need to look behind Home Office headline animal testing figures,
as well as to measure key other areas such as improvements
to the welfare and care of animals that are used—surely vital
information that the public want to be reassured about. They want
to know how research animals are housed, cared for and
treated.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000150" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000150">Can<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:01:14"></hs_TimeCode>
the Minister tell the House how the Government will ensure that the
data collected across departments measure the information that is
needed to assess the overall picture, not just the numbers of animals
tested? Are there plans to change the way data are collected in the
future<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:01:29"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000151" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000151">It
is also worth reminding ourselves in the context of today’s
discussions about the new EU directive covering animal research. I hope
that the Minister will be able to advise the House on how the
consultation on the directive is progressing following transposition,
and how the Department of Health and the Home Office in particular are
working together on the issues covered in this debate. That is, again,
particularly important given the reference of the noble Lord, Lord
Willis, to the Department of Health’s position on research
funding.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000152" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000152">The
Government have given welcome assurances that they want the new
regulations in the directive to be transposed in a way that will
promote public confidence in humane animal research, and maintain and
improve existing standards and rigour of inspections of research
premises and laboratories. Do the Government remain committed to this?
What is the implementation timetable and when will the results of the
consultation be
published?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000153" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000153">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:02:23"></hs_TimeCode>
aim of my noble friend’s Bill, as he has made clear today and in
press interviews, is to emphasise that animal research is an essential
part of producing safe and effective ethical medicine. It gets to the
heart of the debate about animal research and the need to maintain
public consensus on its use, which will only continue if we ensure that
it is effectively regulated, transparent about research methods and
data, and that animals are treated humanely and well and are not
subject to unacceptable levels of cumulative suffering.
We must also ensure that the vital work of the
NC3Rs 
<?notus-xml column=1306?>in funding innovation and technological development that replace or
reduce the need for animals in research testing continues to have our
full support. I was grateful to my noble friend Lord Turnberg for
underlining the importance of its
work.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/713F3000A3DA983606609FBE377DED4CA90FBA04" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AN2-AO</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13102540000300" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000300">12.03
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:03:14"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000154" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000154"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Jolly" PimsId="5895" UID="13102540000338" xid="2109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000338">Baroness
Jolly (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I congratulate the noble Lord, Lord
Winston, on securing a Bill that draws attention to the important
information contained on the labelling and packaging of medicines. I
need to reassure him that, although the noble Earl, Lord Howe, is not
here, he and I were exchanging emails late last night as to the content
of this speech. He is here in spirit if not in
person<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:03:39"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000155" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000155">The noble Lord’s
reputation as one of the world’s foremost medical scientists is
acknowledged both in academia and in the nation’s sitting rooms.
I was fascinated by his contribution today. He recognises that the
importance of information which accompanies medicine is all too often
underestimated, so I am grateful to him for providing the opportunity
to highlight this important subject and for finding the time to talk to
me yesterday about the
issue<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:04:09"></hs_TimeCode>. As noble
Lords would expect from the contributors to the debate, it has been
commendable in terms not only of standard but of breadth and depth, for
which I am
grateful<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:04:24"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000156" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000156">I should start by
making clear that the Government’s commitment to a continuing
need for properly regulated and ethically conducted research using
animals where no practicable alternative exists is strong. The
coalition agreement included a commitment to work to reduce the use of
animals in scientific research. We believe that scientific advances
present significant opportunity. All noble Lords have mentioned the
three Rs: replace, reduce and
refine<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:04:59"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000157" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000157">To this end, we are
pressing ahead with a delivery plan to work towards reducing the use of
animals in research which has three strands: a domestic programme, an
international programme and a programme to promote understanding and
awareness about the use of animals where no alternative exists. This
last strand would therefore seem to be entirely aligned with the aims
of the noble Lord, Lord
Winston<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:05:24"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000158" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000158">Central to the
Government’s work on openness and transparency is the review of
Section 24 of the Animals (Scientific Procedures) Act 1986. This
provides for the protection of confidential information provided in
connection with regulatory activities. A breach of Section 24 can
result in criminal sanctions. The requirements of Section 24 are now
completely out of step with our policy on openness and transparency,
and with the approach taken in other legislation such as the Freedom of
Information Act 2000. The solution we develop will improve the overall
transparency surrounding research using animals while protecting
personal identities, intellectual property and commercial
competitiveness. The principle is of fundamental importance to the life
sciences sector; we have heard this today. Factors such as the rapid
pace of global travel, the looming threat of widespread antimicrobial
resistance and an increasingly ageing world population all present
challenges in dealing with many conditions which noble Lords have
mentioned
today<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:06:41"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:06:39"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1307?><hs_para UID="13102540000159" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000159">Improved research models
will be required to deal with these challenges, and animal research
will play a vital role in their delivery. To retain public confidence
in our work we must be open and transparent about our use of animals.
In relation to the labelling of medicines, the House might find it
helpful if I explain the rationale for requirements for information
which accompanies medicines, particularly labelling, and the
legislation which pertains to these requirements. The label on the
medicine, along with the packaging and the product information are the
public face of the product. The law governing the labelling of
medicines is set out in European law, in title 5 of council directive
2001/83/EC, which specifies what information must appear on the label.
This is replicated within Part 13 of the Human Medicines Regulations
2012, which recast the Medicines Act 1968. This European and national
framework requires that some 14 items of information must appear on
what are often small packages, already crowded. The legislation also
states that where the information provided complies with the
requirements, member states cannot refuse to authorise such packaging.
A statement on animal research is not currently required as part of the
information
set<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:08:10"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000160" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000160">The primary purpose of
the medicine label is to identify unambiguously the product and to
alert users to any important safety messages. Clear labelling ensures
that healthcare professionals and patients can select and use medicines
safely and to best effect. Although no particular size of text is
specified in legislation as regards information on the label, the
European Commission has published guidance which recommends text of a
size not smaller than 7-point. Those of us who are ageing will
appreciate that, but also note that they often miss it by a
mile<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:08:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000161" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000161">Many pharmaceutical
companies struggle with three considerations: legibility of information
on the packaging; keeping packaging to a minimum; and supplying packs
which are easy to read. Increasing the amount of information which is
required to appear on the label and the packaging is likely to have a
detrimental effect on text size. This would result in all the
information appearing in a smaller text size on the package, having a
negative impact on users’ ability to find and assimilate key
messages. In high-pressure environments such as pharmacies, this could
make safe selection of the correct medicine difficult to carry out
quickly.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13102540000162" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000162">I
certainly have a personal anecdote about this. A pharmacist was unable
to read clearly the different labels on two medicines that were side by
side on the counter. My mother was not given the medicine prescribed
for her but the neighbouring one, and as a consequence she was very
poorly for a very long time. Of course, more information can be and is
accommodated within the patient information leaflet that comes in the
packaging of all medicines. However, again, the legislation covering
those does not specify the need to include anything about whether the
product or its ingredients have been subject to animal research. The
focus here is safe and effective use of the product to help patients
manage their
disease<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:10:19"></hs_TimeCode>. Where
the patient information meets the legislative provisions, national
competent authorities in the UK and the Medicines and Healthcare
products Regulatory Agency cannot refuse to accept
these<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:10:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1308?><hs_para UID="13102540000163" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000163">On the key issue of
European medicines licensing, there are more fundamental points at
issue here than the problem of adding more material to the packaging of
medicines. These are to do with the way we regulate medicines to
safeguard public health. More and more medicines are now authorised
through European licensing procedures. These arrangements enable a
pharmaceutical company to market a product in all member states across
the Community. As part of this licensing arrangement, the labelling and
product information, which is approved, must be identical across the
Community. This leaves no opportunity for the United Kingdom to require
specific labelling statements concerning animal testing to appear.
Therefore the UK is not able to act unilaterally in seeking to add new
labelling requirements in an area covered by EU
legislation—which is a key point. Legislative obstacles to the
inclusion of this information were previously explored at European
level, but proposals in this area were
rejected<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:11:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000164">At
a meeting of the Pharmaceutical Committee, the European
Commission’s senior pharmaceutical policy body, the UK sought
clarification of the labelling provisions. The outcome was that there
should be no additions to the labelling spec. Any additional
information on the label included even that added voluntarily
by pharmaceutical companies, and is unlikely to be
acceptable. Indeed, such a voluntary arrangement could not be enforced,
and a level playing field could not be ensured. This could cause
confusion and uncertainty to patients and healthcare professionals
alike.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000165" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000165">Let<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:12:22"></hs_TimeCode>
us take into consideration the patient. Including a statement about
animal testing on medicines labelling could impact adversely on patient
compliance and health outcomes. Prescribers must weigh up
the fine balance between the possibility of benefit from a particular
medicine against any possibility of harm. The inclusion of a statement
about animal testing could inadvertently shift this balance and would
require additional explanation. Doctors, pharmacists, nurses and other
healthcare professionals might see a significant impact on their
workload, as they would need to take time to explain and reassure
patients about the safety of the medicine and their rationale for
prescribing a
product<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:13:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000166" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000166">A further difficulty in
ensuring compliance with such a legal responsibility would be to define
the extent of animal research that would require relevant labelling. It
is likely that all medicines currently on the UK market will have one
or more ingredient that has at some point in its development been the
subject of animal research. This begs the question of how to make any
such requirement meaningful, whether a timescale or threshold should be
used, or a proportion of the active ingredient and/or any excipients.
That challenge is likely to make the framing of any such requirement
extremely
difficult<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:13:46"></hs_TimeCode>. In
conclusion, I am grateful to the noble Lord for raising the issue, and
to those noble Lords who spoke so thoughtfully in
today<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:14:02"></hs_TimeCode>’s
Second Reading
debate.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000167" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000167">I will
respond to questions from noble Lords. The noble Lord, Lord Willis,
raised the issue of Department of Health funding of research. As the
noble Lord will know, BIS funds annual research, but the National
Institute of Healthcare Research, which is in fact an 
<?notus-xml column=1309?>arm’s-length body of the Department of Health, builds upon that
initial research, and the Department of Health is fully supportive of
this<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:14:25"></hs_TimeCode>. The noble
Baroness, Lady Wheeler, asked about guidance on packaging and
labelling. The MHRA guidance on packaging and labelling is updated
regularly to reflect the latest research and learning on how the risks
and benefits of medicines are communicated.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000168" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000168">While<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:15:27"></hs_TimeCode>
I share the view that it is important to explain the need for and the
value of research on animals and what the Government are doing to play
their part, I cannot share the view that the labelling of medicines is
the right vehicle to achieve those ends. The legislation on medicines
labelling, which is European in origin, does not require such a
statement. The UK cannot act alone in the area of medicines labelling.
The potential for a statement about animal testing causing worry to
patients and resulting in them failing to take their medicines as
intended could lead to treatment failure and disease progression. For
these reasons the Government cannot support the Bill. However, I
sincerely hope that noble Lords may find a way to help the
Government’s programme to promote a national understanding and
awareness of the use of animals in testing where no such alternatives
exist<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:15:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13102540000301" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000301">12.15
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:15:44"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000169" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000169"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Winston" PimsId="4649" UID="13102540000339" xid="1499" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000339">Lord
Winston:</Member></B> My Lords, I am very grateful to all Members of
the House who have been kind enough to speak in this debate. I am not
entirely convinced by the arguments that I have heard; I will need to
read the Minister’s response to my Motion in more detail before
I make a considered reply to it. I am a little unhappy with my noble
friend on the Front Bench on this side, who seemed to imply that it is
better not to discuss things that should be open and transparent. That
is a real risk here. If animal research is being used, we should state
it clearly; that is a very important ethical consideration. To know
that will not put people off taking their drugs; there is no evidence
for
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:16:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000170" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000170">The
noble Lord, Lord Willis, made a very cogent point about the support or
lack of it in some aspects of the Department of Health, and the
concern. The Department of Health has not, at the moment, shown the
right way forward. It has certainly not been helpful to people such as
myself, who do this research and are in the firing line. Far too often
we have seen evidence that, for example, companies that supply or
transport animals have been under great threat because they have not
been thoroughly supported in the way they should
have<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:17:17"></hs_TimeCode>
been.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000171" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000171">It is
important that this measure is considered seriously. I very much take
the point made by the noble Lord, Lord Willis, with his usual accuracy,
about the need for research about public opinion. Governments do not do
that very well. It is, for example, rather shocking that social science
is not very prevalent in the Department of Health. We should think
about that very clearly, along with the assessment of these
issues<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:17:46"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000172" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000172">I
am obviously very grateful to my noble friend Lord Turnberg. Both he
and the noble Lord, Lord Willis, have spoken from the aspect of the
medical 
<?notus-xml column=1310?>research charities, which do such valuable work in supporting the sort
of things that we are trying to do. I am very grateful for this debate;
I do not intend to detain the House any longer on a Friday afternoon,
as it now is. I ask the House to give the Bill a Second
Reading.</hs_para><hs_Procedure UID="13102540000361" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000361">Bill
read a second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/C7B1F3D57676B81C74138723D5F880360B199A47" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AP-AQ1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102540000358" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000358">Equality
(Titles) Bill
[HL]<a href="http://services.parliament.uk/bills/2013-14/equalitytitles.html" title="Equality (Titles) Bill [HL]"></a></hs_DebateHeading>
<hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13102540000302" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000302">12.19
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:19:16"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13102540000368" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000368">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Lucas" PimsId="1570" UID="13102540000341" xid="1324" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000341">Lord
Lucas</Member></B></hs_TabledBy><hs_Question UID="13102540000316" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000316">That
the Bill be read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102540000173" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000173"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13102540000340" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000340">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I have it in command
from Her Majesty the Queen to acquaint the House that Her Majesty,
having been informed of the purport of the Equality (Titles) Bill [HL],
has consented to place her prerogative, so far as affected by the Bill,
at the disposal of Parliament for the purposes of the
Bill.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000174" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000174"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Lucas" PimsId="1570" UID="13102540000342" xid="1324" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000342">Lord
Lucas (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, I beg to move
that this Bill be now read a second time. That I am doing so, with at
least some small hope of success, would have delighted the first holder
of my title, Mary Lucas, who was a most successful and energetic woman,
who took on her husband’s derelict estates and created a basis
of great prosperity, which lasted for 200 years—sadly, only 200
years—after her. It would have delighted even more her aunt,
Margaret Lucas, later Margaret Cavendish, who was an author, a
scientist, and a regular part of the debates around the Royal Society,
as it was being founded. She ended up buried in Westminster Abbey. But
the dents that they made in the carapace of male supremacy were soon
forgotten. It has only been the progress that we have seen in the past
150 years that has made, gradually and steadily, enough of a difference
for us to stand today at a position where Margaret Cavendish is in
print again, in Penguin. There is an International Margaret Cavendish
Society, with professors from more than 70 countries, many of them men.
One day—says I, looking firmly to the north-east—we will
have a female Lucasian professorship of
mathematics.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000175" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000175">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:21:51"></hs_TimeCode>
find myself looking at my daughters with great pleasure, knowing that
they can stand in this world as equal in any way to a man, that they
see that in themselves, and that in many parts of our society that is
fully acknowledged. But there is a lot left to
do<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:21:51"></hs_TimeCode>. I am
conscious of how hard it is for women in particular to return to their
careers having taken time out to look after children. At the other end
of the spectrum is the old ogre of the Royal and Ancient. One day that
will fall—my father played his part in the MCC admitting women.
I am sure that we will get around to golf. A fascinating study was done
the other day by Harvard Business School on gender equity among its
students, which showed how much of a problem we still
have<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:22:29"></hs_TimeCode>. I know
that this House concerns itself with the representation of women on
boards of major
companies<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:22:41"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:21:33"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1311?><hs_para UID="13102540000176" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000176">There<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:23:05"></hs_TimeCode>
is a lot left to do but, as with the past, this will be a slow process
of small, persistent but absolutely determined progress. In that
context, this Bill has an important part to play, because history,
symbols, respect and, to some extent, privilege, go with titles. It is
important that we should play our part in the progress of the equality
of men and women and should not shrink from following the example set
by Her Majesty the Queen in making the succession to titles an equal
thing between men and
women<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:23:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000177" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000177">This
is a permissive Bill. It does not seek to compel Peers to change the
pattern of inheritance of their titles. Peerages are complicated
things. In many families, there is a pattern of legitimate expectation
that a younger son will be the one to inherit. He may have settled his
life on the expectation that he will take on the rights and obligations
that go with a particular title. Still in many families there is a
pattern of property and the arrangements made for the preservation and
succession of that property, which would be disrupted by a Bill that
was sudden and compulsory. My noble friend Lord
Jopling<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:24:27"></hs_TimeCode> has
written to me saying that he would very much prefer the idea of
compulsion. I see the advantage of it, but if it was to be part of a
Bill like this it would have to be long delayed. Eventual certainty
would be liveable with. If one knew that this Bill would be compulsory
in 100 years’ time, people could plan towards it and we would
get there in the end. But for the moment, in order not to cause great
disruption to already settled lives, we are best to respect the slow
march of history and say that making this Bill permissive rather than
compulsory is the best way to go about
things<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:25:21"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000178" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000178">My
noble friend also raised the question of whether the arrangements in
the Bill would lead to family quarrels. Clauses 3 and 4 require that a
Peer apply for permission to make changes to the pattern of inheritance
and that he carries his family with him in doing so. Looking at my own
family, I can see that we will have some interesting discussions on how
the pattern of inheritance should be organised, should this Bill go
through. That is not something that we should shrink from. We have a
greater responsibility to make the world a more equal place. Having to
take a decision is not beyond most of us, even if it is a difficult
one. Many of us have taken harder decisions in our
lives<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:26:22"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:23:39"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000179" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000179">There
is also a provision in the Bill for special remainder—that a son
with expectations can be allowed to succeed on the basis that, after
his succession, any future succession will be to the oldest
child<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:26:41"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:26:13"></hs_TimeCode>.
For many families that will provide a way in which the reasonable
expectations of living children can be properly accommodated while
allowing the whole family to make the change which I think it is time
to
make<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:26:57"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000180" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000180">I
am sure this Bill could do with some polishing despite the best efforts
of Megan Conway and Simon Burton in the Legislation Office, for whose
help I am immensely grateful. I hope for support from the Government
and that they will be willing to see this Bill taken forward. In that
case, I shall be very grateful for the opportunity that that will
provide to gain their expert help in polishing some of the corners of
inheritance such as heraldry in a way which will not upset the college
too
much<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:27:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1312?><hs_para UID="13102540000181" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000181">I
also have great pleasure in including in the Bill Clause 10, which to
my mind rights an old inequity which it is high time we
dealt with. Why should the wives of Peers have the right to
a courtesy title when the husbands of Baronesses do not? That proposal
came from my honourable friend Oliver Colvile in another
place. He had his own Bill on the subject and with his
permission I have picked up his wording. I am persuaded that it is
perfect as it is. However, I should be interested to hear what noble
Lords have to say about that. I beg to
move<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:28:31"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13102540000303" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000303">12.28
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:28:31"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000182" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000182"><B><Member ContinuationText="Viscount Simon" PimsId="702" UID="13102540000343" xid="1434" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000343">Viscount
Simon (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, the noble Lord, Lord Lucas, has set
in motion a change in the way that hereditary titles and various other
matters are passed from the male route to the first born. Of course,
only a few hereditary Peers are still Members of this House and any
change will have little effect in this Chamber.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000183" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000183">So<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:29:03"></hs_TimeCode>
what effect will this measure have? A Peer whose titles might go back
many centuries might not have a son and, in order to find the closest
male relative, it might be necessary to proceed to, let us say, a
seventh cousin twice removed who is totally unknown to the immediate
family. However, that Peer might have a daughter who could succeed and
in this modern age this would make so much more
sense.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000184" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000184">Family
heirlooms often have a sentimental value rather than a monetary one.
They can be passed from one generation to another regardless of the
gender of the recipient. Following the House of Lords reform and the
reduction in the number of hereditary Peers who sit in this House, a
family title is now often no more than an heirloom—however, one
that the custodian has no choice in who to pass it on to. In addition,
when there is a monetary value gained through the land, property and
chattels, why should this not be passed to the next generation in the
immediate
bloodline?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000185" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000185">My
title dies with me, but I have a child, a daughter. Should she inherit
my title? Most definitely. I am going to get personal. My daughter has
risen to the top of her career in an age when we are encouraging more
gender equality in the boardroom. Her experience has included working
in government departments in countries where there are distinct
segregated societies where women have only recently been allowed to
have formal education, drive a car and have the right to vote. She is
often asked whether she has faced any issues based on her
gender during her international work. She has the skills and expertise
and can rightly say that she has not. The only place where she faces
equality issues based on her gender is here, in this
House.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000186" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000186">However,
we now have female MPs and Ministers of the Crown and have had a female
Prime Minister. The successor to the Crown can now be a female if she
is the first born of the monarch, and it was announced only this week
that a stumbling block has been removed for women thinking of applying
to be part-time High Court judges. Things change and the succession to
hereditary titles needs to catch up in the name of equality. I look
forward to seeing this Bill being
passed<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:31:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/B24D4929F027121B0B67A023E6E7AD004BE8B8CD" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AQ2-AS1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13102540000304" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000304">12.32
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:31:56"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000187" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000187"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Addington" PimsId="3590" UID="13102540000344" xid="1045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000344">Lord
Addington (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, any hereditary Peer who speaks
on this Bill probably has to declare a series of interests. My interest
is that my only child is a 
<?notus-xml column=1313?>daughter. I have checked under all the beds and cannot find anybody else
in the house; and she is definitely a
daughter<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:32:18"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000188" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000188">Would
I like my daughter to inherit my title? Yes, I would. Do I think my
younger brother, or either of his two sons would do a particularly bad
job if, by some miracle, the hereditary peerage process is still going
by the time it comes round to them? I touch wood in saying
that and will ensure that I cross the road carefully when I leave the
Chamber. Would they be any good at the job? Who knows? My two nephews
are still far too young to even consider this as a realistic prospect
as you cannot sit in this Chamber before attaining the age of 21. But,
would my daughter be any worse? I do not think so. Would my older
sister have performed worse than me, had she sat in this Chamber? She
would have done things differently, but would she have been worse than
me? I doubt it. However, we are talking about history here. I am a
direct descendant of the first Lord Addington through the younger
sons’ line. Had this Bill become an Act in an earlier era and
been implemented, I would be very surprised if there had not been a few
females succeeding to the title. The fact that it has always been done
and chance has always worked in that way is not a good
reason for carrying on with the present system. The fact that things
can change and there is a pool of talent out there that could add to
this place is something we should
embrace<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:33:46"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000189" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000189">If hereditary
Peers’ automatic right to sit in this Chamber is cut within the
next few years—we have been waiting a decade and a half and
there does not seem to be any great hurry to reduce it—it would
be merely a courtesy that should be carried on in the fairest way to
reflect society. It is a bit of history that does not hurt very much.
We should
embrace<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:34:25"></hs_TimeCode> the fact
that history is living and changing.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000190" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000190">I have a good memory
for previous arguments on this issue that I have listened to, and my
noble friend has probably found a way forward that will allow us to
take that important step. It may not be the end of the argument but it
is a step forward. In embracing the idea I suggest that if we pass this
measure the world will carry on turning. There will probably be a few
family squabbles but there always will be, some of which are quite
entertaining, provided that you are out of punching and throwing range
at the time. We should take on this part of our history, make it
slightly more up to date and let it carry on. While we still have an
entrance into this House, it is absurd not to do this, given that we
have the opportunity. This measure will not hurt anyone and I totally
support it.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13102540000305" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000305"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:35:24"></hs_TimeCode>12.35
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000191" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000191"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Deech" PimsId="4986" UID="13102540000345" xid="1903" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000345">Baroness
Deech (CB):</Member></B> My Lords, there are two elements to this Bill.
I am personally affected by only one but there is a common thread that
joins the two parts and lies at the root of this very welcome Bill,
introduced by the noble Lord, Lord Lucas—the equality of men and
women. We in this House are very ready to impose equality obligations
on others and must therefore be equally ready to accept them ourselves.
The origin of this debate goes back further than the recent change that
gives royal girls equality with royal boys in the 
<?notus-xml column=1314?>succession. For a long time now there have been well founded concerns
about primogeniture, title and inheritance of estates; and for more
than 50 years the husbands of noble Baronesses, Ladies fortunate enough
to be seated in this House, have received second-class treatment
compared with the wives of noble Lords. What a contrast that makes with
the egalitarian behaviour accorded in practice in this House.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000192" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000192">All women in positions
created by birth or elevation to a status should be treated as well as
the royals and as well as their male peers. If titles matter—and
they certainly do when linked to the inheritance of an
estate—they must be inheritable by women. If they do not matter,
if as no doubt some will say they are trivial and snobbish, then for
the sake of equality the only answer would be the removal of the titles
borne by the wives of knights and Peers. I rather think there would be
something of an outcry if that were to be done, which proves my
point.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000193" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000193">In
relation to primogeniture and estates, there is no reason to think that
women are any less capable of managing estates than men, and noble
Lords will forgive me for mentioning the alleged incompetence or
spendthrift traits sometimes said to have been found in their male
ancestors. The dilemma of “Downton Abbey” should be
fiction only and not real life, for women’s livelihoods and the
future of great estates may depend on inheritance. Moreover, equality
in succession would have the welcome side effect of bringing some more
women into hereditary Peer positions in this House. So the changes
proposed in the Bill must be supported by the
Government.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000194" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000194">The
other part of the Bill that is close to my heart is about an issue that
I have addressed before—namely, that the husbands or partners of
dames and noble Ladies do not have a courtesy title, while the wives of
knights and noble Lords do. Dames and noble Ladies have earned their
titles, not inherited them. Yet they receive worse treatment than the
Ladies who are married to noble Lords. If a male Peer’s wife is
always a Lady, and his divorced wife retains that title, should not the
same courtesy be extended to the husband of a woman Peer? Husbands will
have done as much, if not more, to support and partner their wives as
the women married to noble Lords. When I brought this issue up in 2009
many noble Lords treated it as amusing, but there is a serious point.
It is discrimination that a man may confer on his wife an honour that a
wife may not confer on her husband or civil
partner.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000195" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000195">Thus
all members of our Supreme Court are Lords with Lady wives, save the
one female Supreme Court justice whose husband remains
“Mr”. Thus we have the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge,
Lord and Lady but Mr and Baroness or, in my case, Dr and Baroness.
There are two possible theories behind this anomaly. One is that there
is support of one spouse by another—as they used to say, behind
every great man is a great woman—but surely what is sauce for
the goose is sauce for the gander. Support works both ways. I guess
that many is the husband of a noble Lady who has gone out of his way to
help her do her work, support her and manage without her company, maybe
even more so than the other way round, and they deserve equality of
treatment.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1315?><hs_para UID="13102540000196" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000196">The only other possible
reason for retaining discrimination is that women, but not men, derive
their position in life from their spouses. Indeed, many women have
given up the title “Mrs”, preferring “Ms”,
precisely because it is the married woman who is marked out by title as
the dependant of her husband and not the other way round.
Unfortunately, many elements of our family law treat wives as having a
place in life wholly dependent on their husbands conferring that place
on them, as though the women were piggybacking through life. In many
respects, our unreformed family law suggests that a woman is not
expected to make her own achievements in life but to rely on her
husband or partner for status and financial support. That cannot remain
the case. As Aretha Franklin
sang:</hs_para><hs_newline10 UID="13102540000002" url="13102540000002">“Sisters
are doin’ it for themselves,</hs_newline10>
<hs_newline10 UID="13102540000003" url="13102540000003">Standin<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:40:08"></hs_TimeCode>’
on their own two feet ...</hs_newline10>
<hs_newline10 UID="13102540000004" url="13102540000004">We<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:40:08"></hs_TimeCode>
got doctors, lawyers, politicians
too”.</hs_newline10><hs_para UID="13102540000197" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000197">The
truth is one of mutual support and so the titles must be equal. In
these times of change, gender equality is a given, and it should not
have taken 55 years for this to be recognised by and in this House. I
urge the Government to take up this worthy Bill, which will do a great
deal of good and no
harm<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:41:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/3ECF843DD139655289BA8A300A9C407A9F889ED9" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AS2-AT1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000306" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000306">12.42
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:41:56"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000198" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000198"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Northbrook" PimsId="2139" UID="13102540000346" xid="1366" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000346">Lord
Northbrook (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, first, I must declare an
interest as a hereditary Peer, and the father of three daughters and no
sons, whose title will become extinct after my death as I am the last
male descendant in the male line of the first Baron. Should my eldest
daughter inherit the title? Certainly,
yes<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:42:25"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000199" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000199">I congratulate my noble
friend Lord Lucas both on this Bill and on his previous attempt under
the Hereditary Peerages (Succession) Bill. It is clear to me that in
the 21st century the fact that a daughter, except in a few peerages,
may not inherit a title is an anomaly and completely wrong.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000200" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000200">On researching my noble
friend’s ancestors, I discovered with interest the history of
his title and noted how a Lucas barony has been created twice—of
Shenfield and Crudwell—and how the Lucases of Crudwell have
descended through the female line no less than five times since its
creation.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000201" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000201">I
note that a key principle of my noble friend’s permissive Bill
is that in Clause 1, by petition of the incumbent, a female heir may
inherit a hereditary title. Knowing hereditary Peer friends who have
very able daughters but no sons, what is being proposed is in many ways
an interesting evolution of our current system, which the popular TV
series “Downton Abbey” has put under the
spotlight.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000202" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000202">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:41:35"></hs_TimeCode>
method set out in Clause 3 is certainly ingenious, and the method of
objection is also set out in Clause 4. However, I can see
problems in Clause 4. A major issue will arise if the family situation
gets nasty. Then the light shines upon Clause 4(3) and (4), where the
reasons and the Lord Chancellor’s consideration of the objection
are set out. Clause 4(4)(b) says that the Lord Chancellor,</hs_para>
<hs_quotefo UID="13102540000282" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000282">“shall have
regard to whether it would be grossly inequitable to allow the
provisions of section 1 to apply to the peerage or title … and
in particular to … the financial consequences of so doing for 
<?notus-xml column=1316?>the child making the objection; and … whether
or not the succession had previously been promised to the child making
the objection”.</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="13102540000263" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000263">I am no lawyer but I
can see that the vagueness of the phrases “grossly
inequitable”
and,</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="13102540000283" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000283">“whether
or not the succession had previously been promised to the child making
the
objection”,</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13102540000264" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000264">could
cause all manner of problems, which I am sure the noble Lord, Lord
Lucas, would have swooped on had some someone else promoted the
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:44:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13102540000203" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000203">As
I read it, Clause 8, “Provision for special remainder”,
states that special remainder can be granted for one generation to
override the provisions of the Bill. From what my noble friend Lord
Lucas has said, I think I now understand that the purpose of this
clause is to not upset existing family arrangements. Clauses 9 and 10
are sensible changes to existing law to recognise the role of partners
or civil partners with courtesy
titles<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:45:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000204" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000204">In conclusion, rather
than the solely female inheritance proposed by the lobby group the
Hares, I am rather more attracted by a change from a Salic to a
semi-Salic solution whereby if all relevant males become extinct then
the closest female heir inherits, but that if she has a son it then
reverts to male succession. I believe that this could be implemented in
statute by the simple procedure of allowing peerages to alter their
letters patent so that heirs general rather than heirs male can
succeed, as in the cases of the titles of my noble friend Lord Lucas
and a few others. An individual peerage precedent exists for this in
statute, the Duke of Marlborough Annuity Act
1706.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000205" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000205">Another<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:46:18"></hs_TimeCode>
possibility which I like much less would be to follow the recent
Succession to the Crown Act principles; namely, that the eldest child
inherits regardless of sex. Do Her Majesty’s Government plan to
legislate similarly to the Succession to the Crown Act with regard to
encouraging or supporting a Private Member’s Bill on this theme?
A practical influence on future legislation may be Article 14 of the
European Convention on Human Rights, which prohibits discrimination
based on sex. I have discussed this informally with the noble Lord,
Lord Pannick, and he suggested that the way forward would be a petition
by a relevant potential female
heir.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000206" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000206">If we
are to preserve the peerage system then it needs to adapt to modern
times. Allowing a form of female inheritance, although not necessarily
the form in this Bill, would show that we are in touch with the reality
of equal opportunities for females that still do not exist in everyday
life. At the very top level, Her Majesty the Queen has shown a shining
example throughout her reign. The great strength of our British system
is its ability to evolve with the times and thus be relevant. These
qualities which are inherent in our system have allowed us to avoid the
type of shocks that have left such an enduring mark among noble
families in many continental European
nations<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:47:59"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/E7541862F65F52525D43B3B685F0F3BA6012F2E4" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AT2-AU</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13102540000307" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000307"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:47:59"></hs_TimeCode></I>12.47
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000207" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000207"><B><Member ContinuationText="The Earl of Clancarty" PimsId="2608" UID="13102540000347" xid="2038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000347">The
Earl of Clancarty (CB):</Member></B> My Lords, I am grateful to the
noble Lord, Lord Lucas, for allowing us to speak on this
matter today. I have two interests to declare. First, I have a daughter
who could inherit a title if the law was changed; and, secondly, my
wife, the journalist Victoria Lambert, is a leading
light in the group 
<?notus-xml column=1317?>largely but not wholly made up of women who are campaigning for equality
for women in the peerage and the baronetcy. They have called themselves
the Hares after the comment made by the noble Lord, Lord Trefgarne, in
April during Third Reading of the Succession to the Crown Bill. He
said:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="13102540000277" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000277">“This Bill has
also set running the hare of what happens to the hereditary peerage
with regard to the succession arrangements for hereditary
Peers”.—[<I>Official Report</I>, 22/4/13; col.
1229.]</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13102540000265" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000265">He
is right: it
has.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13102540000208" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000208">It will
not be a surprise to many of your Lordships to hear that I am no great
fan of the aristocratic system, male primogeniture of course being a
component of that. Part of me thinks that perhaps what is required is
more fundamental social reform in the interests of a more classless
society than we have at present. Of course, I am not alone in this
House in thinking that, even perhaps among hereditary Peers. But, and
this is a big but, as long as the Queen and the Royal Family command
such a central role in our society—the last Ipsos MORI poll in
November of last year gave the monarchy a 79% popularity
rating—this is not going to happen since the Royal Family is the
core of the aristocratic system.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000209" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000209">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:49:36"></hs_TimeCode>
public do a very good job of mentally separating the Royal Family from
the rest of the aristocracy but that is not the reality, something
which constitutional experts and republicans equally recognise. That is
why I support equality for women in the peerage, however much the
peerage itself represents an inequality within wider society—and
perhaps arguably now not even the main one.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000210" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000210">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:54:26"></hs_TimeCode>
feel that there are two principal arguments to be
made<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:50:09"></hs_TimeCode>. The most
powerful argument is, as the noble Lord, Lord Dubs, has said, that
there should not be gender discrimination in Britain, full stop. The
Equality Act 2006 created a public duty to promote equality on the
ground of gender. Modern British law states clearly that men and women
are equal in every aspect of life. Male primogeniture is the
cornerstone of old-fashioned patriarchy. No duke or earl should
consider that he is a special case; we are not. Gender equality should
mean that you have the potential to inherit from birth regardless of
gender, and that that should automatically come into effect as soon as
the Bill becomes an Act so that a living heir of whatever age may
inherit without any permission being necessary. The Bill would not be
retrospective, as I think we all agree that no current substantive
titles should be dispossessed. In these respects, the Bill before us
today is perhaps a little too modest and could be simpler, because
contrary to what some people have said, in principle this is not a
complex issue. A single blanket law to cover all families is what is
required.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000211" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000211">The
second argument I would make is that if the aristocracy remains at
least socially, and indeed still to some extent politically, a
significant source of influence in this country, it should be reformed
just as its core part has been. It may be argued that that has happened
so that the Royal Family has been brought more into the 21st century,
but it is also true that the Royal Family and the aristocratic system
as a whole should together be the best model of
behaviour possible, 
<?notus-xml column=1318?>giving the right signal to those non-aristocratic
families who still believe that the eldest males ought to inherit the
estate, whatever size it may be. There is no doubt, even in these
generally more enlightened times, that this is still so.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000212" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000212"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:52:25"></hs_TimeCode>Only
two of the 92 hereditary seats in this House are held by women, a
significant argument of course for removing the hereditaries, which
will happen, whether in the longer or shorter term. Nevertheless, it is
worth mentioning that campaigners have calculated that with a change in
the law, if you go forward just one generation, there would be 41 men
to 51 women occupying hereditary seats, a considerably better ratio
indeed than either House has at present, or indeed for the conceivable
future, and an effect that no doubt would be replicated throughout the
aristocracy as a whole.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000213" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000213">If this Bill were to be
refined further, I think the Hares’ recommendation that one
should not reach back more than one generation—that is, to the
generation before the deceased—to find the next heir is a very
good one. In this, I perhaps differ rather from the opinion
of the noble Viscount, Lord Simon. It is unacceptable that some distant
relative should inherit a title and an estate which that person had
perhaps hardly known about let alone visited, displacing close family,
as has indeed happened. In the memorable words of campaigner Liza
Campbell, “No more cousins from
Pluto”.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000214" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000214">It
is in these various ways that this issue is of greater significance for
the public than many people realise. A call for a change in the law has
wide cross-party support in both Houses. In May, Mary Macleod MP
introduced a ten-minute rule Bill in the other place to remove male
primogeniture. It is an issue that is not going to go away, and the
Government would be wise to deal with it. Indeed, it has this year
already generated a huge amount of coverage in the press, on the radio
and television both here and abroad, including front page coverage in
the <I>New York Times</I>. The issue has been championed by the
<I>Independent</I>, the <I>Daily Telegraph</I> and the <I>Sunday
Times</I>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000215" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000215">A<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:54:04"></hs_TimeCode>
number of potential beneficiaries of this change in the law have now
written to the Crown Office stating their intention to take their cases
to Strasbourg. I think that the Government should accept the underlying
principle of this Bill or bring in their own legislation. After all, it
is simply logical that what the Government have done quite rightly with
the Succession to the Crown Bill were to be extended to the rest of the
same system of which the Royal Family is a
part.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/90A0C3835E30AC3D2A0C376B28ED67670B976D1B" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AV-AV</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13102540000308" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000308">12.55
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000217" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000217"><Member ContinuationText="The Lord Bishop of Guildford" PimsId="3684" UID="13102540000348" xid="2022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000348"><B>The
Lord Bishop of </B><B>Guildford</B><B>:</B></Member> My Lords, I am
grateful for the courtesy of the House in allowing me to slip into the
gap, as it were. I shall, I hope, be courteous in return by being very
brief in so doing.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000218" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000218">Members<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:54:49"></hs_TimeCode>
on this Bench have no direct interest in the content of the Bill, for
obvious reasons.
Nevertheless<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:54:47"></hs_TimeCode>, I
express support in principle and, indeed, in practice for the Bill
before your Lordships’ House and hope to hear that the
government Front Bench is also sympathetic. I will not rehearse what
has already been said in the House in support of the Bill, which I
fully agree with, but am sorely tempted to slip in an amendment to the
effect that women bishops could be ordained in the Church of
England<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:55:15"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1319?><hs_para UID="13102540000219" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000219"><B><Member ContinuationText="Noble Lords" PimsId="0" UID="13102540000349" xid="2182" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000349">Noble
Lords:</Member></B> Hear,
hear<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:55:15"></hs_TimeCode>!</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000220" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000220"><B><Member ContinuationText="The Lord Bishop of Guildford" PimsId="3684" UID="13102540000350" xid="2022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000350">The
Lord Bishop of Guildford:</Member></B> That would allow the noble
Baroness, Lady Deech, to add bishops to her
list<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:55:26"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:55:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13102540000309" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000309">12.56
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000221" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000221"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Thornton" PimsId="4281" UID="13102540000351" xid="1466" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000351">Baroness
Thornton (Lab):</Member></B> Hear, hear to that. First, I thank the
noble Lord, Lord Lucas, for his introduction of the Bill. No one is
more qualified than the noble Lord to raise the issue of male
primogeniture and the related matters in the Bill.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000222" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000222">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:55:43"></hs_TimeCode>
intend to be brief.
As<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:55:52"></hs_TimeCode> the party
that has, for more than 50 years, introduced almost all of the
legislation that addresses inequality and discrimination, how could
Labour be anything but in support of the principle behind this Private
Member’s Bill? I agree that it is really quite a modest Bill and
I agree with the noble Lord, Lord Addington, when he says that the
world will not stop turning if the Bill is agreed. My own personal
views definitely lean towards those of the noble Earl, Lord Clancarty,
when it comes to this whole
issue.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000223" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000223">The
Equality Act 2006 created a public duty to promote equality on the
grounds of gender. Can the Minister explain why our UK aristocracy
should be allowed a special or protected status? Surely the law is the
law for all of us. Male primogeniture is simply unacceptable. There is
no justification for gender discrimination in our society. Other noble
Lords have delved into the history of wealth and property that has led
us to the unfairness of the current old-fashioned inheritance
practices. Surely, after the successful passage of the Succession to
the Crown Bill, which introduced gender equality into the succession
for the head of state, this Bill’s objectives are most timely.
Indeed, this issue peppered the debates on the Bill as it went through
the House earlier this
year.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000224" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000224">I thank
Victoria Lambert and others who have written to me about the Bill. I
received a lot of letters from fathers and daughters about it and
thought it might be worth putting on the record the names of some of
those who have written, as it is a very impressive Bill. I thank Lady
Willa Franks, Lady Daisy Fane, Sir Michael Leighton, Sir
Nicholas Stuart Taylor and Virginia Stuart-Taylor, my noble friend Lord
Simon and Fiona Simon, Liza Campbell, the Earl of Westmorland, the
honourable Amanda Murray, the Duke of Leinster, Lady Francesca
Fitzgerald, Aliki Currimjee—neé Boothby—and Rose
Baring, to name but a few.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000225" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000225">In the letters, the
fathers explain that they wish their daughter, as the oldest child, to
inherit the title and the female oldest children say that it is time to
end this archaic practice. All intend to contest male primogeniture in
the European Court of Human Rights under Article 14 of the European
Convention on Human Rights, which prohibits discrimination on the
grounds of gender, and Article 1 of Protocol 1, which confers the right
to peaceful enjoyment of one’s possessions. I would be
interested to know whether the Minister has considered these statutes
and how they might apply under the circumstances.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1320?><hs_para UID="13102540000226" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000226">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:59:19"></hs_TimeCode>
am the oldest daughter, albeit of a plumber, it has to be said. I think
that my younger brother, who is the next one down of the seven of
us—six girls and one boy—would find the idea that he
would take precedence above me as ridiculous an idea as I would. I
might therefore claim to be an honorary member of the Hares. I am told
that the Hares have attracted some attention in high places and been
told to desist from what they are doing. As a lifelong feminist, all I
can say to them is, “Sisters, you are probably right and the
ruder the opposition gets, the more right you probably are. Stick with
it<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:59:44"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000227" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000227">I
wish the noble Lord, Lord Lucas, success with this issue and will be
interested to hear from the Minister whether the Government will
support him in this matter of equal
rights.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/0AB9047AD4843D18E1E1F905E43FFE22E1162C35" __version__="1.6"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>AW-AX</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13102540000310" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000310"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:59:59"></hs_TimeCode></I>1
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T12:59:59"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000228" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000228"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13102540000352" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000352">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, perhaps I might start
with one or two personal remarks. I was interested to hear the noble
Baroness, Lady Thornton, say that she is opposed to male primogeniture
as a principle. Speaking as a third child, I am not entirely an
enthusiast for primogeniture as such. Sitting and listening to the
debate, I have been ruminating on other forms of inheritance,
particularly among aristocratic and ruling families. The Salic law has
been quoted—we all remember that passage in Shakespeare in which
the discussion about the Salic law and whether women can inherit comes
up. In early Viking kingdoms, as I recall, it was the roughest and
toughest who inherited, and the others just had to put up with it. The
Ottoman succession went further than that: the most successful
inherited and then killed off most of his brothers. The Saudi
succession is extremely interesting: the family has now created a
council to consider who shall succeed to the Saudi
kingdom<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:01:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000229" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000229">The
modernisation of hereditary peerages is an interesting concept.
Hereditary peerages are inherently non-modern. The whole series of
grants and different rules for succession contained in ancient Scottish
titles, some United Kingdom titles and elsewhere is part of
the glory of the peculiar history of the British Isles and
of our partly unwritten and considerably unmodernised constitution.
When I receive letters talking about appeals to the European Court of
Human Rights in order to modernise this principle, I feel slightly the
same as I did when read on the front page of the <I>Daily Mail </I>on
one day an attack on the European Court of Human Rights and a demand
that Britain should leave, and seeing only two days later the <I>Daily
Mail </I>join other newspapers in appealing to the European Court of
Human Rights against the new press charter. There is something
contradictory in the whole
approach<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:02:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000230" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000230">Belgian
aristocratic succession, as I recall, has all sons of a baron with the
courtesy title, baron, which is why so many people you meet in the
Belgian diplomatic service are barons. There are all sorts of ways in
which one might play around with all this; I am not sure that in a
modern society we should be in favour of the proliferation of titles to
which this might lead
us<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:02:36"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000231" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000231">However,
the Government are committed to equality of treatment before the law,
as evidenced by the legislation that they have already taken through
this House, 
<?notus-xml column=1321?>including the Succession to the Crown Act. The
Government are therefore sympathetic to the motives behind the Bill,
but they suggest that there are a number of areas where its approach
does not present the best way to address equalities.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000232" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000232">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:02:57"></hs_TimeCode>
Bill would not eliminate differences in treatment of the sexes, as
discretion rests with the
incumbent<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:03:07"></hs_TimeCode>.
Title-holders may therefore decide not to petition, and the practice of
male heirs taking precedence would then continue—it is at the
incumbent’s discretion whether to initiate any action. In taking
such an approach, we would risk creating a patchwork of different
treatment across the peerage and introducing uncertainty for those who
currently expect or hope to
inherit<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:03:32"></hs_TimeCode>. The
noble Lord, Lord Lucas, raised a number of questions about property and
inheritance which I shall not go into here, but I just mark that this
is all part of a very complex
picture<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:03:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000233" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000233">While
the Succession to the Crown Act could be given effect without
disturbing the legitimate expectations of anyone in line for the
throne, the same could not be said for any similar change of the rules
governing the descent of hereditary titles. Clause 7 provides that,
once a female heir has been allowed to succeed, females will be allowed
to succeed in all future successions of that peerage and title. Is it
right for the present Peer to make that decision for all future
generations? If we were to make this minor constitutional change,
surely it should be a conscious decision expressed through the will of
Parliament rather than a decision left in the hands of each incumbent
Peer. Before embarking on such a change, we would certainly want to
undertake a full consultation—the pages of the <I>Daily
Telegraph</I> would be full of letters for weeks, I suggest—and
public discussion to ensure that the changes had no unintended
consequences.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000234" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000234">There
are also a number of difficulties with the role envisaged for the Lord
Chancellor. Reference is made to having regard to whether it would be
grossly inequitable to allow a petition. However, it does not prescribe
that the Lord Chancellor must grant that position unless that is the
case. If the Lord Chancellor is not so confined, the basis for that
decision is unclear, which could in turn put the Lord Chancellor in an
invidious
position.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000235" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000235">Further,
the Bill is not clear on what should happen where a Peer has a daughter
and a son and the son has died, leaving his son in his place. Whether
the daughter would displace the grandson is not entirely clear. There
is also no provision for the daughter to make representations to the
Lord Chancellor.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000236" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000236">There were a number of
interesting interventions on Clauses 9 and 10, including one from the
noble Baroness, Lady Deech. There is strength in the argument 
<?notus-xml column=1322?>that it is inequitable for the wives of those honoured to be able to use
courtesy titles while husbands and civil partners, whatever their
gender, cannot. In terms of equality, there is an argument to dispense
with that long-standing convention and to bring husbands and civil
partners in line with wives of those receiving honours. I am interested
that the noble Baroness, Lady Thornton, did not suggest that the way to
make them equal is to remove courtesy titles altogether, but we will
leave that for another time.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102540000237" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000237">However,
parliamentary legislation is not the traditional route to pursue any
change, either extension or diminution, of courtesy titles. Courtesy
titles are traditionally dealt with under the royal prerogative by way
of royal licences. For example, the royal licence signed by
the Queen on 30 April 2004 was the means by which courtesy titles were
extended to adopted children of Peers. A royal licence was also the
means by which justices of the Supreme Court were permitted to use the
courtesy title of Lord or Lady in instances where they have not been
created a Peer. So Clauses 9 and 10, while interesting, are not
necessarily needed in the Bill. That is a question for the monarchy
itself.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000238" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000238">Having
said that, the Government are studiously neutral on the Bill. We look
forward to hearing from the noble Lord, Lord Lucas, and seeing how far
he will take it. We shall watch with interest how it
proceeds<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:06:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13102540000311" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000311"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:07:03"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:05:00"></hs_TimeCode>1.07
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:05:00"></hs_TimeCode></I><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:05:00"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13102540000239" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000239"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Lucas" PimsId="1570" UID="13102540000353" xid="1324" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000353">Lord
Lucas:</Member></B> My Lords, I am very grateful to all who have
spoken, with<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:07:03"></hs_TimeCode>
some modification of that as regards the Minister. None the less, I
take heart from the guidance he has given on the Government’s
aversion to uncertainty in these matters. I think it is possible to
look more along the lines that my noble friend Lord Jopling proposed of
producing certainty in these matters. It may be useful to consider that
in Committee to see whether there is interest on the part of the
Government and the House generally in pursuing a Bill which made these
matters certain but perhaps took longer to introduce that certainty
than this Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2013-10-25T13:08:06"></hs_TimeCode>
would.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102540000240" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000240">I am
interested in what my noble friend said about courtesy titles. I very
much hope that he will find the opportunity to encourage change in that
direction. It seems to me the right time to make such change. I hope
that in giving advice to Her Majesty—or whatever is necessary to
bring the matter forward—the Government will not be slow to
suggest that this has the general assent of Lords Temporal and
Spiritual. They might usefully consider making progress on that.
However, for now, I commend the
Bill.</hs_para><hs_Procedure UID="13102540000362" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000362">Bill
read a second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure><hs_Procedure UID="13102540000363" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-0001.htm#13102540000363">House
adjourned at 1.09
pm.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment></System><System type="WMS" ColStart="113"><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/729593DCBBC24A58982E01B36607CCBE1984AD57" __version__="1.2"><Header><House>0</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date="25 October 2013">Friday
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>Header-9-522</Section><TransformationVersion>0.5</TransformationVersion></Header><Body><hs_HoL UID="13102543000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000002">Written
Statements</hs_HoL><hs_date UID="13102543000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000001"><I>Friday 25 October
2013</I></hs_date></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/5B02D0D916B2748999AF92121D905726AF62C797" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>3</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>LordsWMSSection</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102543000041" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000041">Afghanistan</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102543000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000003"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Warsi" PimsId="5263" UID="13102543000036" xid="1971" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000036">The
Senior Minister of State, Department for Communities and Local
Government &amp; Foreign and Commonwealth Office (Baroness Warsi)
(Con):</Member></B> My right honourable friend the
Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs (William Hague)
made the following Written Ministerial Statement in
September.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000004">I
wish to inform the House that the Foreign and Commonwealth Office,
together with the Ministry of Defence and the Department for
International Development, is today publishing the thirty-first
progress report on developments in Afghanistan since November
2010.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000005">I
announced drawdown plans for the Helmand Provincial Reconstruction Team
(PRT) in a written statement on 9 September. The PRT has already begun
to decrease in size. By December 2013 we envisage a small PRT political
and governance team moving to Camp Bastion, followed by the final
closure of the PRT in March
2014.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000006">On 3
September, the Independent Election Commission co-chaired a meeting of
the ELECT II Project Board with UNAMA. The IEC provided an update on
voter registration and preparations for the elections, and donors
pledged additional funds to support the electoral preparations. Overall
donors pledged USD$134m.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000007">The UN High
Commissioner for Human Rights, Navi Pillay, visited Afghanistan 15-17
September. Her visit focussed on three key areas – the
importance of ensuring gains made on human rights are consolidated, the
issue of violence against women and the future of the Afghan
Independent Human Rights Commission.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000008">On 1 September,
President Karzai appointed Omar Daudzai, the previous Afghan Ambassador
to Pakistan, as Acting Interior Minister, replacing Mujtaba
Patang.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13102543000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000009">The
Home Secretary visited Afghanistan 22 – 24 September, meeting
President Karzai, the Ministers of Interior and Refugees, the Head of
the National Directorate of Security (NDS), Afghanistan’s
Intelligence Agency, and international ambassadors. The visit focused
on a range of security and criminal issues affecting the UK
(principally terrorism, drugs and
migration).</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000010">On
1 September, the UK assumed lead nation status at the Afghan National
Army Officer Academy. The Academy, which is designed to develop the
future leaders of the Afghan National Army, will begin training by the
end of
October.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000011">On 27
September, the Prime Minister announced that the UK will host the 2014
NATO Summit in what will be the final year of the ISAF combat mission
in Afghanistan. The precise date for the Summit has yet to be finalised
but its themes will be discussed in greater detail at the October NATO
Defence Ministerial meeting in Brussels.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=114?><hs_para UID="13102543000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000012">I am
placing the report in the Library of the House. It will also be
published on the gov.uk website
(www.gov.uk/government/publications/afghanistan-progress-reports).</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102543000042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000042">Contingent
Liabilities</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102543000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000013"><B><Member ContinuationText="Viscount Younger of Leckie" PimsId="4709" UID="13102543000037" xid="2037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000037">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Business,
Innovation and Skills (Viscount Younger of Leckie) (Con):</Member></B>
My Rt. Hon. Friend the Secretary of State for
Business, Innovation and Skills (Vince Cable) has made the following
statement.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13102543000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000014">It
is normal practice when a Government department proposes to undertake a
contingent liability in excess of £300,000 for which there is no
specific statutory authority, for the Minister concerned to present a
departmental minute to Parliament giving particulars of the liability
created, explaining the circumstances and to refrain from incurring the
liability until fourteen parliamentary sitting days after the issue of
the statement, except in cases of special urgency and/or
confidentiality.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000015">During the preparatory
phase of the Royal Mail transaction, there was a need for strict
confidentiality as to the content of the preparatory work, including
the scope of the Royal Mail transaction liabilities and the transaction
timetable.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13102543000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000016">On
10th September 2013, following the “non-standard
notification” procedure outlined in Managing Public Money (Annex
5.4), I wrote to the Chairs of the Public Accounts Committee and the
Business, Innovation and Skills Select Committee outlining the proposal
to provide certain indemnities on behalf of Government.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000017">As a matter of record I
have placed a departmental Minute in the libraries of both Houses
explaining the procedure followed and containing a description of the
liabilities
undertaken.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102543000043" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000043">Mental
Health Act
2007</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102543000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000018"><B><Member ContinuationText="Earl Howe" PimsId="1035" UID="13102543000038" xid="1749" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000038">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department of Health (Earl
Howe) (Con):</Member></B> My hon Friend the Minister
of State, Department of Health (Norman Lamb) has made the following
written ministerial
statement.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000019">We
have today laid before Parliament Post-Legislative Scrutiny of the
Mental Health Act 2007: Response to the Health Committee of the House
of Commons (Cm
8735).</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000020">The
response addresses the specific recommendations in the
Committee’s report. These include (in the Mental Health Act
1983) the important issues of independent mental health advocate
services, supervised community treatment, places of safety and (in the
Mental Capacity Act 2005) the Deprivation of Liberty
Safeguards.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000021">The Department will
feed consideration of all the recommendations into future work
programmes, including the revision of the “Code of Practice
Mental Health Act 1983” in
2014.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000022">I would
like to put on record my thanks to the Committee for their thoughtful
comments.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement">

<?notus-xml column=115?><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102543000044" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000044">Railways:
InterCity East Coast
Franchise</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102543000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000023"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Kramer" PimsId="5891" UID="13102543000039" xid="2104" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000039">The
Minister of State, Department for Transport (Baroness Kramer)
(LD):</Member></B> My Honourable friend the Parliamentary Under
Secretary of State for Transport (Stephen Hammond) has made the
following Ministerial
Statement:</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102543000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000024">Today
I have published the InterCity East Coast Prospectus, pre-qualification
documents and submitted for publication an OJEU Notice. These steps
mark the start of the formal competition to find a new private sector
partner to run passenger rail services on InterCity East Coast The
Prospectus explains the current business as it stands today and sets
out the opportunities it presents to a new operator. It also provides
some indications of how we will be specifying InterCity East Coast when
we release the Invitation to Tender (ITT) which is planned for February
2014. The Prospectus will provide potential applicants with a large
amount of information that will help them decide whether they can be
the right partner for this vital and historic railway.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000025">I am also publishing
the InterCity East Coast Consultation Summary Report that brings
together the responses we received to the consultation conducted in
2012. This report is being published now to enable those who responded
to the consultation; potential bidders for the franchise; and other
interested parties to see the key concerns and issues raised in advance
of the publication of the ITT.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000026">We have seen great
improvements on our railways since privatisation, with unprecedented
growth in passenger numbers and the best safety record in Europe and
this Government is committed to the principle that partnership between
the public and private sector works. We want to further strengthen our
partnership with the private sector and continue to build on this
growth so as to deliver world class railways for passengers and best
value for the taxpayer. Private sector partnership on this route will
deliver, amongst other things, the investment in the design, build and
maintenance contract for the new Class 800/801 trains procured through
the intercity express programme.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=116?><hs_para UID="13102543000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000027">I am confident that
through the partnership approach the Department for Transport is
taking, combined with the skills, investment and innovation of the
private sector, we can deliver a new railway for the InterCity East
Coast. One that meets the Secretary of State’s three objectives
for franchising across the network: that the passenger gains; the
industry thrives; and the taxpayer
benefits.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102543000045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000045">Taxation:
Avoidance</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13102543000028" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000028"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Deighton" PimsId="7002" UID="13102543000040" xid="2168" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000040">The
Commercial Secretary to the Treasury (Lord Deighton)
(Con):</Member></B> My honourable friend the Exchequer Secretary to the
Treasury (David Gauke) has today made the following Written Ministerial
Statement.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000029">This Government is
committed to delivering a progressive tax system that is affordable,
fair and encourages growth.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000030" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000030">As announced by the
Chief Secretary to the Treasury (Danny Alexander) on 17 September 2013
the Government will introduce legislation to stop people avoiding tax
by using rules known as compensating adjustments.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000031" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000031">The rules are being
exploited in two areas. In the first, partnerships pay companies for
services at cost price and use the tax rules to create a mark-up which
is not actually paid, but which reduces the income tax bill of
individual partners.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000032">In the second type of
case individuals lend money to a company in which they are a
shareholder, charging excessive interest payments on which they do not
pay full income tax.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000033" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000033">The Government has
consulted on technical detail and will introduce in the next Finance
Bill legislation, effective from today, to stop this exploitation by
denying compensating adjustments for transactions between income tax
payers and connected companies.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000034" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000034">In certain
circumstances the compensating adjustment will be treated for tax
purposes as a distribution of profits.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13102543000035" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025-wms0001.htm#13102543000035">Further details on
these measures are contained in a Technical Note published today,
together with the draft
legislation.</hs_para></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Writtens" ColStart="203"><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/37E61A6968B8D8239C506E5CA32AA67E6919B6B5" __version__="1.2"><Header><House>0</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date="25 October 2013">Friday
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>Header-10-417</Section><TransformationVersion>0.5</TransformationVersion></Header><Body><hs_HoL UID="13102544000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000002">Written
Answers</hs_HoL><hs_date UID="13102544000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000001"><I>Friday 25 October
2013</I></hs_date></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/3156E04A0BD8590F9CFC7132093AFCB513F18DA6" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>1</System><Sitting short-date=" 25 October 2013">Friday,
25 October
2013</Sitting><Section>Section</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102544000040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000040">Armed
Forces:
Aircraft</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Questions</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000047" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000047">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord West of Spithead" PimsId="5250" UID="13102544000022" xid="1966" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000022">Lord
West of Spithead</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000013">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether the Ministry of Defence has
established a Royal Naval study team to establish the best way of using
satellites, drones, passive sonar, helicopters and ships to fill or
improve on the cover historically provided by large fixed-wing
land-based
aircraft.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2639]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000003"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Astor of Hever" PimsId="3811" UID="13102544000023" xid="1721" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000023">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Ministry of Defence (Lord Astor
of Hever) (Con):</Member> The Ministry of Defence (MOD) has not
established a Royal Navy study team for this purpose. However both Navy
Command and Joint Forces Command are undertaking work studies to
consider the use of small, medium and large manned platforms, hybrid
air vehicles, unmanned aircraft systems and space assets to inform
resource decisions ahead of and as part of the Strategic Defence and
Security Review planned for 2015. MOD is also planning to explore how
rotary wing UAS might be used to fill a range of maritime roles when
operating from a frigate or destroyer-sized
vessel.</hs_para><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000048" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000048">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord West of Spithead" PimsId="5250" UID="13102544000024" xid="1966" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000024">Lord
West of Spithead</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000014">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government how much work has been undertaken to
utilise further Merlin ASW helicopters in the north-west approaches and
the Greenland, Iceland and United Kingdom gaps partly filling the loss
of cover historically provided by large fixed-wing land-based
aircraft.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2641]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000004"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Astor of Hever" PimsId="3811" UID="13102544000025" xid="1721" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000025">Lord
Astor of Hever:</Member> The Royal Navy has a contingent ASW Merlin
capability in the UK to react to any requirement to operate in the
North Atlantic. Work is underway to incorporate Nimrod MRA4 ASW
technology in the Merlin Mk2. Once completed, the ASW Merlin will be
better placed to provide further mitigation for the loss of the UK
Maritime Patrol Aircraft programme. A number of assets such as
Type 23 Frigates, C-130 Hercules and support from allies are
also used to supply this
capability.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102544000041" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000041">Drones</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000049" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000049">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord West of Spithead" PimsId="5250" UID="13102544000026" xid="1966" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000026">Lord
West of Spithead</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000015">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether there are any plans for the Royal
Navy to own and use shore- or sea-based drones for wide area ocean
surveillance.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2640]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000005"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Astor of Hever" PimsId="3811" UID="13102544000027" xid="1721" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000027">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Ministry of Defence (Lord Astor
of Hever) (Con):</Member> No decision has been made on whether the
Royal Navy should own and use shore- or sea-based drones for wide area
ocean surveillance. However, Navy Command is 
<?notus-xml column=204?>developing a Maritime Unmanned Air Systems (UAS)
Strategy paper describing the requirement to 2050. The Navy is also
working with UK industry to establish whether operational unmanned
systems can provide maritime surveillance from ships including from the
Queen Elizabeth Class Aircraft Carrier as part of the UAS
Strategy.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102544000042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000042">Government
Departments:
Expenditure</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Questions</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000050" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000050">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Davies of Stamford" PimsId="5785" UID="13102544000028" xid="2057" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000028">Lord
Davies of Stamford</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000016">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what is their estimate of the total
expenditure of the Ministry of Defence in the current financial year
(1) on current items, and (2) on capital
items.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2620]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000006"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Astor of Hever" PimsId="3811" UID="13102544000029" xid="1721" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000029">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Ministry of Defence (Lord Astor
of Hever) (Con):</Member></B> The Ministry of Defence's current
estimate of spending on both current items and capital items in
Financial Year 2013-14 was published in the Department's Main Estimates
in April 2013. The Department will publish an update on our in-year
financial position for 2013-14 in the Supplementary Estimates. We
currently expect this to be during February
2014.</hs_para><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000051" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000051">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Davies of Stamford" PimsId="5785" UID="13102544000030" xid="2057" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000030">Lord
Davies of Stamford</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000017">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether there have been negotiations
between the Ministry of Defence and HM Treasury with a view to securing
an exemption for the Ministry of Defence from the normal Treasury rules
on departmental spending; and, if so, what has been the
result.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2623]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000007"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Astor of Hever" PimsId="3811" UID="13102544000031" xid="1721" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000031">Lord
Astor of Hever:</Member> The Treasury has agreed to exceptional budget
flexibility for the Ministry of Defence; and has agreed that the full
amount of the underspend against the core budget in 2012-13 can be
carried forward to subsequent
years.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102544000043" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000043">Government
Departments:
Procurement</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000052" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000052">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Methuen" PimsId="1890" UID="13102544000032" xid="1346" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000032">Lord
Methuen</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000018">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether the Treasury Solicitor's Office is
paying its small suppliers within the time recommended by Government
guidelines; and, if not, why
not.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2619]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000008"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13102544000033" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000033">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member> The Treasury Solicitor's Department
(TSo1) has made a commitment to pay all suppliers promptly and within
30 days. Over the past three years 85% to 90% of supplier invoices and
fee notes were paid within this time
frame.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13102544000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000009">The
TSo1 systems do not capture information on the circumstances that
result in payment after 30 days. However, over 50% of payments relate
to fee notes received from barrister's chambers. These detail the work
completed, the agreed hourly rate and any additional charges such as
travel. The amount on a fee note is considered negotiable and where
negotiations take place payment can take more than 30
days.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question">

<?notus-xml column=205?><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102544000044" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000044">Railways:
Luggage
Space</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000053">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Bradshaw" PimsId="2261" UID="13102544000034" xid="1089" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000034">Lord
Bradshaw</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000019">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government, further to the Written Answer by Baroness
Kramer on 21 October (WA 136), whether either of the current franchises
have been consulted about the design of seating and luggage
space on the new Intercity Express
Trains.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2824]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000010"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Kramer" PimsId="5891" UID="13102544000035" xid="2104" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000035">The
Minister of State, Department for Transport (Baroness Kramer)
(LD):</Member> First Great Western and East Coast have been, and
continue to be, heavily involved in the design of all aspects of the
IEP
design.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102544000045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000045">Railways:
Signalling</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000054" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000054">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Truscott" PimsId="4343" UID="13102544000036" xid="1691" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000036">Lord
Truscott</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000020">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what costs in terms of signalling will be
required to permit classic compatible trains to run north of Lichfield
to Glasgow and
Edinburgh.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2722]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question>

<?notus-xml column=206?><hs_para UID="13102544000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000011"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Kramer" PimsId="5891" UID="13102544000037" xid="2104" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000037">The
Minister of State, Department for Transport (Baroness Kramer)
(LD):</Member> The HS2 Phase 1 cost estimate includes an allowance of
circa £15m for signalling works to permit classic compatible
trains to run north of
Lichfield.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13102544000046" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000046">Social
Mobility</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13102544000055" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000055">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Scotland of Asthal" PimsId="615" UID="13102544000038" xid="1547" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000038">Baroness
Scotland of Asthal</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13102544000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000021">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what is their commitment to encourage
social
mobility.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL2746]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13102544000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000012"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13102544000039" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/131025w0001.htm#13102544000039">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member> Improving social mobility is the
principal goal of this Government’s social policy, which is why
we have introduced policies such as early education for two year-olds
from lower income families, the Pupil Premium, which will be worth
£2.5 billion by 2014-15, and the £1bn Youth Contract to
help young people who require extra help to get learning or earning. We
have also created the Social Mobility Business Compact which has the
specific goal of making sure that all young people have fair and open
access to employment
opportunities.</hs_para></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Index"><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/Index/9049040ED8CC901179BB30A513F19334F2C6BEA3" __version__="1.2"><Index cdate="1" cday="Friday" cmonth="November" cyear="2013" date="25" day="Friday" issue="59" maxparts="1" month="October" part="1" price="" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="748" year="2013"><tocdate col="WS113">Friday 25 October 2013</tocdate><title>ALPHABETICAL
INDEX TO WRITTEN
STATEMENTS</title><level1 col="WS113">Afghanistan</level1><level1 col="WS114">Contingent
Liabilities</level1><level1 col="WS114">Mental
Health Act
2007</level1><level1 col="WS115">Railways:
InterCity East Coast
Franchise</level1><level1 col="WS116">Taxation:
Avoidance</level1><tocdate col="WS113">Friday 25
October 2013</tocdate><title>ALPHABETICAL INDEX TO WRITTEN
ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA203">Armed Forces:
Aircraft</level1><level1 col="WA203">Drones</level1><level1 col="WA204">Government
Departments:
Expenditure</level1><level1 col="WA204">Government
Departments:
Procurement</level1><level1 col="WA205">Railways:
Luggage
Space</level1><level1 col="WA205">Railways:
Signalling</level1><level1 col="WA206">Social
Mobility</level1><title>NUMERICAL INDEX TO WRITTEN
ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA204">[HL2619]</level1><level1 col="WA204">[HL2620]</level1><level1 col="WA204">[HL2623]</level1><level1 col="WA203">[HL2639]</level1><level1 col="WA203">[HL2640]</level1><level1 col="WA203">[HL2641]</level1><level1 col="WA205">[HL2722]</level1><level1 col="WA206">[HL2746]</level1><level1 col="WA205">[HL2824]</level1></Index></Fragment></System><System type="Back_Cover"><?date 2013-10-25?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_10_25_PT_1/Cover/CC901179BB30A513F19334F2C6BEA39049040ED8" __version__="1.2"><Contents cdate="1" cday="Friday" cmonth="November" cyear="2013" date="25" day="Friday" issue="59" maxparts="1" month="October" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="748" year="2013"><citicont1 col="1275">Voting
Age (Comprehensive Reduction) Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="1296">Medicinal
Labelling Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="1310">Equality
(Titles) Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="WS 113">Written
Statements</citicont1><citicont1 col="WA 203">Written
Answers</citicont1></Contents></Fragment></System></House></HansardDoc>