<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>2 September</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>BACKBENCH BUSINESS</OrderTitle>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>public bodies</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Public Bodies (Abolition of the Registrar of Public Lending Right) Order 2013, which was laid before this House on 9 May, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <OrderTitle>regulatory reform</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Regulatory, Enforcement and Sanctions Act 2008 (Amendment of Schedule 3) Order 2013, which was laid before this House on 24 June, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <OrderTitle>free movement of workers</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House takes note of European Union Document No. 9124/13 and Addenda 1 and 2, a draft Directive of the European Parliament and of the Council on measures facilitating the exercise of rights conferred on workers in the context of freedom of movement for workers; notes that the proposal seeks to prevent discrimination against EU nationals when seeking work in another Member State; further notes that this proposal is intended to facilitate the exercise of existing rights, in particular by requiring Member States to provide adequate judicial or administrative means of redress, to designate a body or bodies for promotion and support of equal treatment of workers and their family members, to encourage social dialogue and to disseminate information on free movement rights; and supports the Government’s approach of seeking to ensure that no EU legislation is adopted that creates new free movement rights or imposes unnecessary bureaucratic burdens.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Charitable support work for Romanian orphanages</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>