<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date> </Date>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
				
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to grant certain duties, to alter other duties, and to amend the law relating to the National Debt and the Public Revenue, and to make further provision in connection with finance.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
			
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make further provision about banking and other financial services, including provision about the Financial Services Compensation Scheme; to make provision for the amounts owed in respect of certain deposits to be treated as a preferential debt on insolvency; to make provision about the accounts of the Bank of England and its wholly owned subsidiaries; and for connected purposes.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
				
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make provision for the marriage of same sex couples in England and Wales, about gender change by married persons and civil partners, about consular functions in relation to marriage, for the marriage of armed forces personnel overseas, and for connected purposes.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
				
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make provision for the setting of a decarbonisation target range and duties in relation to it; for or in connection with reforming the electricity market for purposes of encouraging low carbon electricity generation or ensuring security of supply; for the establishment and functions of the Office for Nuclear Regulation; about the government pipe-line and storage system and rights exercisable in relation to it; about the designation of a strategy and policy statement; about domestic supplies of gas and electricity; for extending categories of activities for which energy licences are required; for the making of orders requiring regulated persons to provide redress to consumers of gas or electricity; about offshore transmission of electricity during a commissioning period; for imposing fees in connection with certain costs incurred by the Secretary of State; and for connected purposes.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
				
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make provision about children, families, and people with special educational needs; to make provision about the right to request flexible working; and for connected purposes.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
			
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make provision about pensions and about benefits payable to people in connection with bereavement; and for connected purposes.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
			
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make provision about anti-social behaviour, crime and disorder, including provision about recovery of possession of dwelling-houses; to make provision amending the Dangerous Dogs Act 1991, Schedules 7 and 8 to the Terrorism Act 2000 and the Extradition Act 2003; to make provision about firearms and about forced marriage; to make provision about the police, the Independent Police Complaints Commission and the Serious Fraud Office; to make provision about criminal justice and court fees; and for connected purposes.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
				
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make provision about the licensing and advertising of gambling.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
				
			
				<Text>
			<p>Bill to make provision about donations, loans and related transactions for political purposes in connection with Northern Ireland; to amend the Northern Ireland Assembly Disqualification Act 1975 and the Northern Ireland Act 1998; to make provision about the registration of electors and the administration of elections in Northern Ireland; and to make miscellaneous amendments in the law relating to Northern Ireland.</p>
					</Text>
				</Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle/>
				<Text>
			
			
			<p>Most Gracious Sovereign,</p>
					</Text>
				
				<Text>
			<p>We, Your Majesty&#8217;s most dutiful and loyal subjects, the Commons of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland in Parliament assembled, beg leave to offer our humble thanks to Your Majesty for the Gracious Speech which Your Majesty has addressed to both Houses of Parliament.</p>
      <subp>Line 5, at end add &#8216;but respectfully request that your Government recognise that its programme fails to address either the worsening climate crisis or that austerity is failing; call on your Government to heed warnings that urgent and radical cuts in emissions are needed to prevent global temperature rises of 4℃ or more by the end of the century; urge your Government to recognise that, to fulfil its own commitment to keep warming below 2 degrees, around 80 per cent of known fossil fuel reserves must stay in the ground; further call on your Government to end austerity and instead reduce the deficit through an economic programme that prioritises investment in jobs, especially in labour-intensive green sectors and that pursues a goal of 100 per cent renewable energy by 2050, with policies for rapid deployment of renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies; and further call on your Government to lift the council borrowing cap to promote council house building, to tackle the cost of public transport starting with bringing the railways back into public ownership, to end cuts to welfare and take other steps to build a resilient and stable economy.</subp></Text>
   </Item>
</op>