<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>Unsolicited Telephone Calls (Caller Line Identification) Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>21/2/2014</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 126" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Commons" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Require disclosure of caller line identification by non-domestic callers; to <?new-line?>require Ofcom to consider applications for exemption from such disclosure; to <?new-line?>provide that telephone providers may not make a charge for providing caller <?new-line?>line identification; and for connected purposes.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<P1group id="p00001">
<Title><?start-line?>Amendment of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) <?new-line?>Regulations 2003</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 <?new-line?>(<Citation id="c00101" Class="UnitedKingdomStatutoryInstrument" Year="2003" Number="2426">S.I. 2003/2426</Citation>) (“the Regulations”) are amended as follows.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?new-line?>In regulation 2(1), between the definitions of “the Directive” and “electronic <?new-line?>communications network”, insert—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“domestic caller” means any subscriber or user, other than a non-<?new-line?>domestic caller, who uses a public electronic communications <?new-line?>service for the purpose of making a call;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</BlockAmendment>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In regulation 2(1), between the definitions of “location data” and “OFCOM”, <?new-line?>insert—</Text>
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>““non-domestic caller” means—</Text>
<OrderedList Decoration="parens" Type="alpha">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>a corporate subscriber that uses a public electronic <?new-line?>communications service for the purpose of making calls; or</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>any other subscriber or user who uses a public electronic <?new-line?>communications service for the purpose of making unsolicited <?new-line?>calls for direct marketing purposes;”</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</OrderedList>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In regulation 10(1), after the words “to outgoing calls” insert the words “made <?new-line?>by a domestic caller”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>After regulation 10, insert—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Provision of calling and connected line identification - outgoing calls</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>10A</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This regulation applies to outgoing calls made by a non-domestic <?new-line?>caller.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?new-line?>The provider of a public electronic communications service shall <?new-line?>provide users originating a call by means of that service with a facility <?new-line?>to enable the presentation of calling line identification and connected <?new-line?>line identification to the recipient of the call.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?new-line?>Non-domestic callers shall ensure that calling line identification and <?new-line?>connected line identification is presented to the recipient of an outgoing <?new-line?>call, unless the recipient makes use of a facility provided under <?new-line?>regulation 11(2).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?new-line?>Where OFCOM determines that there are reasonable grounds to <?new-line?>exempt a non-domestic caller or group of non-domestic callers from the <?new-line?>requirements in paragraph (3), it may issue a notification under this <?new-line?>regulation.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A notification under paragraph (4) is one which—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>states that the non-domestic caller or group of non-domestic <?new-line?>callers is exempt from the requirements in paragraph (3);</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>specifies the period during which the exemption applies;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>imposes any conditions on the exemption that OFCOM believes <?new-line?>are appropriate.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>OFCOM must arrange for the publication of any notifications made <?new-line?>under paragraph (4) in such form and manner as it considers <?new-line?>appropriate.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>OFCOM must consider an application for a notification under <?new-line?>paragraph (4) made by a non-domestic caller or group of non-domestic <?new-line?>callers.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>OFCOM may prepare and issue guidance (including altered or <?new-line?>replacement guidance) in relation to notifications under paragraph (4), <?new-line?>including as to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>factors that might affect whether a notification under paragraph <?new-line?>(4) is or is not given; and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the procedure that OFCOM will adopt in considering <?new-line?>applications made under paragraph (7).</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>9</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>OFCOM must arrange for the publication of any guidance issued under <?new-line?>paragraph (8) in such form and manner as it considers appropriate.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>10</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In this regulation “recipient” means a subscriber whose line is the called <?new-line?>line or connected line with regard to an outgoing call made by a non-<?new-line?>domestic caller.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</BlockAmendment>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>After regulation 11(1), insert—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>(1A) The provider of a public electronic communications service <?new-line?>shall provide subscribers to the service with a facility enabling <?new-line?>the presentation of the calling line identification and connected <?new-line?>line identification of incoming calls to the subscriber’s line.</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<?new-page?><ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>  (1B) The facility to be provided under paragraph (1A) shall be <?new-line?>provided free of charge.</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</BlockAmendment>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In regulation 11(2), delete the words “Where a facility enabling the <?new-line?>presentation of calling line identification is available”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In regulation 11(3), delete the words—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>“Where a facility enabling the presentation of calling line identification <?new-line?>prior to the call being established is available”; and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>“where the presentation of the calling line identification has been <?new-line?>prevented by the calling user or subscriber”.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>9</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In regulation 11(4), delete the words “Where a facility enabling the <?new-line?>presentation of connected line identification is available”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>10</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In regulation 12, for the words “Where a provider of a public electronic <?new-line?>communications service provides facilities for calling or connected line <?new-line?>identification, he shall provide information to the public regarding the <?new-line?>availability of such facilities” substitute the words “A provider of a public <?new-line?>electronic communications service shall provide information to the public <?new-line?>regarding the availability of calling or connected line identification facilities”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00002">
<Title><?start-line?>Short title, commencement and extent</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the Unsolicited Telephone Calls (Calling Line <?new-line?>Identification) Act 2014.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The provisions of this Act shall come into force on such day as the Secretary of <?new-line?>State may appoint by order made by statutory instrument.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>An order under subsection (2) may appoint different days for different <?new-line?>purposes.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act has the same extent as the Regulations.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Body>
</Primary>
</Legislation>