<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill52(a))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 153, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Protection arrangements for children and dependents</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Criminal Justice Act 2003 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 174 (duty to give reasons for, and explain effect of, sentence) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;174A Duty to ask about children etc left behind</quote>
         <quote>(1) Any court passing a custodial sentence on an offender who was on bail when awaiting sentence must ask what the arrangements are for the care of any children of the offender or any vulnerable adult who is dependent on the offender while the offender is in custody.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If the court considers the arrangements are not satisfactory the court must make a referral to the relevant local authority social care team.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Any person or body having statutory responsibilities for children or vulnerable adults must co-operate with the court in securing that arrangements are made for their safety in the circumstances to which subsection (1) refers.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Bail Act 1976 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In section 5 (supplementary provisions about decisions on bail), after subsection (5), there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5A) Where a court withholds bail in criminal proceedings from a person to whom section 4 of this Act applies, the court must ask what the arrangements are for the care of any children of the defendant or any vulnerable adult who is dependent on the defendant while the defendant is on remand in custody.</quote>
         <quote>(5B) If the court considers the arrangements are not satisfactory the court must make a referral to the relevant local authority social care team.</quote>
         <quote>(5C) Any person having statutory responsibilities for children or vulnerable adults must co-operate with the court in securing that arrangements are made for their safety in the circumstances to which subsection (5A) refers.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(5) This section shall come into force two months after enactment.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 3, page 3, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) the anti-social behaviour in which the respondent has engaged, or threatens to engage, consists of intentional or deliberate anti-social behaviour of a potentially persistent nature&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 11, leave out &#8220;or&#8221; and insert &#8220;and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 12, after the first &#8220;that&#8221; insert &#8220;some or all of the activities referred to in paragraph (a)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 12, leave out &#8220;a public place within that area&#8221; and insert &#8220;that public place&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 15, leave out &#8220;persistent&#8221; and insert &#8220;repetitive&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 25, leave out &#8220;reasonable&#8221; and insert &#8220;necessary&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 27, leave out &#8220;, occurring&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 29, leave out &#8220;, occurrence&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 30, leave out subsection (6)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 33, leave out &#8220;, or at all times except those specified&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(6A) A prohibition or requirement framed under the provisions of subsection (6) must not discriminate directly or indirectly against any person or group of persons on the grounds of age, race, religious beliefs, gender or sexual orientation.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 41, leave out paragraph (b)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 42, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) the county council where the restricted area that is being proposed is in an area where there is both a county and a district council;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) a parish council or a Welsh community council where the restricted area that is being proposed is wholly or partly within its area.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 32, line 42, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7A) A local authority making a public spaces protection order must before doing so&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) advertise the proposal in such ways as it thinks appropriate to bring it to the attention of those in the locality and of persons who visit or use the restricted area that is proposed or might reasonably be expected to do so, including on the authority&#8217;s website;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) make a copy of the proposal available at its offices and in at least one location that is as local as possible to the restricted area that is being proposed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) allow a reasonable period for comments on and objections to the proposal to be made to the authority;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) allow any person to make representations in person to the authority as part of its decision-making process.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7B) A local authority must consider each decision on whether to make or amend a public spaces protection order in a committee of the authority meeting in public.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 33, line 5, leave out from &#8220;in&#8221; to end of line 6 and insert &#8220;such ways as the authority considers appropriate which must include on the authority&#8217;s website&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 55, page 33, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A local authority must make a public spaces protection order available for inspection at its offices.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>