<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill52_V(a))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Fifth Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 132</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56YJ&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56YJ&#042;:</B> After Clause 132, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report by Secretary of State</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall, no later than three months after the coming into force of section 132, report to Parliament his or her recommendations&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) for the introduction of safeguards in respect of legally privileged material, excluded material and special procedures material in respect of a person detained under Schedules 7 or 8 of the Terrorism Act 2000, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for the introduction of a statutory bar to the introduction in a criminal trial of admissions made by a person detained under Schedules 7 or 8 of the Terrorism Act 2000.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56YK&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56YK&#042;:</B> After Clause 132, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Further amendment of Terrorism Act 2000</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall by order make any amendments to Schedule 7 or Schedule 8 of the Terrorism Act 2000 recommended by the Independent Reviewer of Terrorism Legislation to limit the scope of its application.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 138</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>81A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>81A&#042;:</B> Clause 138, page 106, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In section 2 of that Act (Part 1 warrant and certificate), after subsection (7) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7A) But in the case of a Part 1 warrant containing the statement referred to in subsection (3), the designated authority must not issue a certificate under this section if it is clear to the designated authority that a judge proceeding under section 21A would be required to order the person&#8217;s discharge on the basis that extradition would be disproportionate.</quote>
         <IndentOne>In deciding that question, the designated authority must apply any general guidance issued for the purposes of this subsection.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7B) Any guidance under subsection (7A) may be revised, withdrawn or replaced.</quote>
         <quote>(7C) The function of issuing guidance under subsection (7A), or of revising, withdrawing or replacing any such guidance, is exercisable by the Lord Chief Justice of England and Wales with the concurrence of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Lord Justice General of Scotland, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Lord Chief Justice of Northern Ireland.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 148</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95ZB&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95ZB&#042;:</B> After Clause 148, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Electronic transmission of European arrest warrant etc</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 204 of the Extradition Act 2003 (warrant issued by category 1 territory: transmission by electronic means), in subsection (5)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) for &#8220;subsection (1), a&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;subsection (1)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) a&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) at the end there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(b) information contained in the warrant is treated as being received by the designated authority in a form in which it is intelligible if the authority receives&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) a summary of that information in English, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the text of the warrant itself,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>in a form in which it is legible.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 149</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95ZC&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95ZC&#042;:</B> After Clause 149, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Discount on sentence for time spent in custody awaiting extradition: Scotland</quote>
         <quote>(1)  Section 210 of the Criminal Procedure (Scotland) Act 1995 (consideration of time spent in custody) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2)  In subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a)  in paragraph (a), after &#8220;United Kingdom&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;otherwise than from a category 1 territory&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b)  in paragraph (c)(ii), for &#8220;for the purposes of this section&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;who was extradited to the United Kingdom otherwise than from a category 1 territory&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (1) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A)  Subsection (1B) applies where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a)  a court is passing a sentence of imprisonment or detention on a person for an offence, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b)  the person is an extradited prisoner who was extradited to the United Kingdom from a category 1 territory.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(1B)  The court shall specify&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the period of time spent in custody awaiting extradition, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b)  the date of commencement of the sentence in accordance with subsection (1C).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(1C)  The date of commencement of the sentence is to be a date the relevant number of days earlier than the date the sentence would have commenced had the person not spent time in custody awaiting extradition.</quote>
         <quote>(1D)  In subsection (1C), &#8220;the relevant number of days&#8221; means the number of days in the period specified under subsection (1B)(a).&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(4) After subsection (2) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) In this section, &#8220;category 1 territory&#8221; means a territory designated under the Extradition Act 2003 for the purposes of Part 1 of that Act.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(5)  Subsection (3) is repealed.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95ZD&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95ZD&#042;:</B> After Clause 149, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Discount on sentence for time spent in custody awaiting extradition: Northern Ireland</quote>
         <quote>(1) In section 38 of the Prison Act (Northern Ireland) 1953 (arrest, etc, of persons unlawfully at large), for subsection (3) there is substituted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) The provisions of subsection (2) shall not apply to any period during which any such person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is detained in pursuance of any other sentence of any court in the United Kingdom in a prison or other institution, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is kept in custody in a category 1 territory before, and only for the purpose of, being extradited to the United Kingdom to serve the term of imprisonment or detention referred to in that subsection,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>but shall apply in addition to any other provisions of this Act imposing any punishment for an escape.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3A) In subsection (3) &#8220;category 1 territory&#8221; means a territory designated under the Extradition Act 2003 for the purposes of Part 1 of that Act.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 26 of the Treatment of Offenders Act (Northern Ireland) 1968 (duration of sentence), at the end of subsection (2A) there is inserted &#8220;; or</quote>
         <IndentOne>(c) any period during which he was in custody in a category 1 territory with a view to his being extradited to the United Kingdom to be tried or sentenced for that offence (and not for any other reason).</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>In paragraph (c) &#8220;category 1 territory&#8221; means a territory designated under the Extradition Act 2003 for the purposes of Part 1 of that Act.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>98A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>98A&#042;:</B> Schedule 9, page 197, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Prison Act (Northern Ireland) 1953 (c. 18)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In section 38 of the Prison Act (Northern Ireland) 1953 (arrest, etc, of persons unlawfully at large), in subsection (4), for &#8220;the last foregoing sub-section&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;subsection (2)&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>98B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>98B&#042;:</B> Schedule 9, page 199, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) Section 204 of that Act (warrant issued by category 1 territory: transmission by electronic means) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsections (1)(c) and (2)(c), for &#8220;a qualifying form&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;a form in which it is intelligible and which is capable of being used for subsequent reference&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (6)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the end of paragraph (a) there is inserted &#8220;and&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) paragraph (c) and the word &#8220;and&#8221; before it are omitted.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 157</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>100A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>100A&#042;:</B> Clause 157, page 126, line 6, after &#8220;Act&#8221; insert &#8220;or under section (Further amendment of Terrorism Act 2000)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 159</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104A&#042;:</B> Clause 159, page 127, line 21, leave out &#8220;and&#8221; and insert &#8220;to&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104B&#042;:</B> Clause 159, page 127, line 23, leave out &#8220;Section 109 extends&#8221; and insert &#8220;Sections 109 and (Discount on sentence for time spent in custody awaiting extradition: Scotland) extend&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104C&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104C&#042;:</B> Clause 159, page 127, line 24, leave out &#8220;Section 120 extends&#8221; and insert &#8220;Sections 120 and (Discount on sentence for time spent in custody awaiting extradition: Northern Ireland) extend&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>