<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill52_III(a)(Rev))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Revised Third Marshalled
List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 99</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS GALE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS SMITH OF BASILDON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 99, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Dog control notice</quote>
         <quote>(1) Where an authorised officer has reasonable cause to believe that a dog is not under sufficient control and requires greater control in any place, as a preventative measure to protect the public, the dog itself, or another protected animal, he or she may serve on the owner, and if different, person for the time being in charge of the dog, a written control notice which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) states that he or she is of that belief;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) specifies the respects in which he or she believes the owner, and if different, the person for the time being in charge of the dog, is failing to keep the dog under sufficient control;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) specifies the steps he or she requires the owner, and if different, the person for the time being in charge of the dog, to take in order to comply with the notice;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) specifies the date by which the terms of the notice must be complied with; and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) specifies the date that the notice expires which will not be for a period which exceeds six months.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In a control notice pursuant to subsection (1)(c), an authorised officer must require a dog to be microchipped (if not already done) and the owner, and if different, the person for the time being in charge of the dog, register the dog with a microchip database, and may require the following steps, where appropriate, but not limited to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) keeping the dog muzzled as directed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) keeping the dog on a lead when in public or under control as directed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) requiring the owner, and if different, the person for the time being in charge of the dog, to seek and implement expert advice about training and behaviour for the dog;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) having the dog neutered where appropriate; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) keeping the dog away from particular places or persons.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Failure to comply with the steps required in a control notice within the time period specified, to the satisfaction of the authorised officer, may lead to a complaint to a magistrates&#8217; court under section 2 of the Dogs Act 1871.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The provisions of section 2 of the Dogs Act 1871 shall have effect if the owner, and if different, the person for the time being in charge of a dog, fails to comply with the steps required in a control notice within the time period specified in accordance with subsection (3) as they would apply if a dog was dangerous and not kept under proper control.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An &#8220;authorised officer&#8221; is a person that has been appointed by the local authority or police for the purposes of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(6) A &#8220;protected animal&#8221; is one that is commonly domesticated in the British Islands, is under the control of man whether on a permanent or temporary basis, or is not living in a wild state.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 100</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS SMITH OF BASILDON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 100, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Firearms licences: assessing public safety</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Firearms Act 1968 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 28A (certificates: supplementary) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;28B Assessing public safety</quote>
         <quote>(1) When assessing the threat to public safety under sections 27, 28, 30A, 30B or 30C the chief police officer must ensure that a range of background checks are performed.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Where these checks uncover substantiated evidence of violent conduct, domestic violence, mental illness or drug or alcohol abuse, the presumption is that the chief police officer should refuse the licence application unless exceptional evidence can be brought forward by the applicant as to their suitability to possess a weapon.</quote>
         <quote>(3) When assessing public safety within this section the chief police officer must follow any guidance issued by the Secretary of State.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) After section 113(1) (power of Secretary of State to alter fees) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) Before making an order under this section the Secretary of State must consult with chief police officers to ensure the level of fees collected by the police under sections 32 and 35 are appropriate after considering the costs they incur through the administration and assessment of firearms&#8217; licences made under this Act.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 103</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS SMITH OF BASILDON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 103, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Control of new psychoactive substances</quote>
         <quote>(1) Any person supplying, or offering to supply, a synthetic psychoactive substance including but not restricted to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a powder;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a pill;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a liquid; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) a herbal substance with the appearance of cannabis, which is likely to be consumed by a person for the purpose of causing intoxication,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>will be subject to a synthetic psychoactive product order prohibiting its supply.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Any subsequent breach of that order will be an offence.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A person guilty of an offence under this section shall be liable on summary conviction to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding level 5 on the standard scale.</quote>
         <quote>(4) This section does not apply to alcohol, tobacco or any drug currently scheduled under the Misuse of Drugs Act 1971 or the Medicines Act 1968.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 103, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Review of effect of legal highs on anti-social behaviour</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall carry out a review no more than 12 months following the passing of this Act to assess the effect of legal psychoactive drugs on&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) anti-social behaviour offending rates; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) NHS, policing and local authority resources dedicated to tackling anti-social behaviour.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>BARONESS SMITH OF BASILDON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD BEECHAM</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 103, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Proxy purchasing of tobacco products on behalf of children</quote>
         <quote>(1) A person commits an offence if he or she buys or attempts to buy a tobacco product or cigarette papers on behalf of a person under the age of 18.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A person guilty of an offence under subsection (1) is liable on summary conviction to a fine not exceeding level 5 on the standard scale.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 121</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HENIG</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HARRIS OF RICHMOND</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENS OF KIRKWHELPINGTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 121, page 90, line 25, after &#8220;person&#8221; insert &#8220;who is licensed and who works for a company licensed by the Security Industry Authority and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 147</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HENIG</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HARRIS OF RICHMOND</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENS OF KIRKWHELPINGTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 147, page 119, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In making an order under subsection (1), the Secretary of State must include in the specification a requirement that the person be licensed and work for a company that is licensed by the Security Industry Authority.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>