<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Care_(HLBill1_III)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58A:</B> Clause 97, page 80, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The HRA shall also have the function of encouraging the translation of research into innovative practice.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 97, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 97 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58B:</B> Clause 98, page 81, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the Medical Royal Colleges;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58C:</B> Clause 98, page 81, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the General Medical Council, the General Dental Council and the Nursing and Midwifery Council;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>59</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>59:</B> Clause 98, page 81, line 28, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the Chief Nursing Officer of the Department of Health&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>60</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>60:</B> Clause 98, page 81, line 38, after &#8220;research&#8221; insert &#8220;, including that undertaken by the research and development committees of NHS trusts&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>60A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>60A:</B> Clause 98, page 81, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In promoting the co-ordination and standardisation of practice in the United Kingdom relating to the regulation of health and social care research, as defined in section 97(2) and (3) above, of any changes proposed in the system for setting pharmaceutical prices.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>61</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>61:</B> Clause 98, page 82, line 11, after &#8220;2006&#8221; insert &#8220;, providers commissioned to deliver services for the NHS&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>61A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>61A:</B> Clause 98, page 82, line 12, leave out from &#8220;must&#8221; to end and insert &#8220;follow guidance under subsection (6) unless there is good reason not to do so&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62:</B> Clause 98, page 82, line 12, leave out &#8220;have regard to&#8221; and insert &#8220;comply with&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>63</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>63:</B> Clause 98, page 82, line 14, at end insert &#8220;and transparency in reporting clinical trials&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64:</B> After Clause 104, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Human Tissue and Embryo Authority</quote>
         <quote>(1) There shall be a body corporate called the Human Tissue and Embryo Authority.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Authority shall consist of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a chairman and deputy chairman, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) such number of other members as the Secretary of State appoints.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The Authority shall keep proper accounts and proper records in relation to the accounts and shall prepare for each accounting year a statement of accounts.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The annual statement of accounts shall comply with any direction given by the Secretary of State, with the approval of the Treasury, as to the information to be contained in the statement, the way in which the information is to be presented or the methods and principles according to which the statement is to be prepared.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Not later than five months after the end of an accounting year, the Authority shall send a copy of the statement of accounts for that year to the Secretary of State and to the Comptroller and Auditor General.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Comptroller and Auditor General shall examine, certify and report on every statement of accounts received by him under subsection (5) and shall lay a copy of the statement and of his report before each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The Secretary of State and the Comptroller and Auditor General may inspect any records relating to the accounts.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In this section &#8220;accounting year&#8221; means the period beginning with the day when the Authority is established and ending with the following 31st March, or any later period of twelve months ending with the 31st March; and Schedule 1 to this Act (which deals with the membership of the Authority, etc) shall have effect.</quote>
         <quote>(9) The Authority shall prepare&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a report for the period beginning with the 1st August preceding the day when the Authority is established (or if that date is a 1st August, beginning with that date) and ending with the next 31st March, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a report for each succeeding period of 12 months ending with 31st March.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) The Authority shall send each report to the Secretary of State as soon as practicable after the end of the period for which it is prepared.</quote>
         <quote>(11) A report prepared under subsection (9) for any period shall deal with the activities of the Authority in the period and the activities the Authority proposes to undertake in the succeeding period of twelve months.</quote>
         <quote>(12) The Secretary of State shall lay before each House of Parliament a copy of every report received by him under subsection (10).</quote>
         <quote>(13) The following provisions of the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 are repealed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) sections 5 to 10, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section 11(1)(a) and (aa).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(14) Save for the provision in subsection (13), references in the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 to &#8220;the Authority&#8221; shall be taken to be references to the Human Tissue and Embryo Authority.</quote>
         <quote>(15) The Care Quality Commission may grant the following licences&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) licences under paragraph 1 of Schedule 2 to the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 authorising activities in the course of providing treatment services,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) licences under paragraph 1A of that Schedule authorising activities in the course of providing non-medical fertility services.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(16) Sections 12, 13 and 13A of, and paragraph 4 of Schedule 2 to, the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 have effect in the case of all licences granted under subsection (15) as they would do for licences granted under that Act.</quote>
         <quote>(17) Section 13 of the Human Tissue Act 2004 is repealed.</quote>
         <quote>(18) Save for the provision in subsection (17), references in the Human Tissue Act 2004 to &#8220;the Authority&#8221; shall be taken to be references to the Human Tissue and Embryo Authority.</quote>
         <quote>(19) In Schedule 5 (power to modify or transfer functions) to the Public Bodies Act 2011 omit&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the entry for the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Authority, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the entry for the Human Tissue Authority.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64A:</B> Clause 74, page 62, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) &#8220;Significant improvement&#8221; is to be defined in regulations.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>65</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>65:</B> Clause 74, page 62, line 17, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) send a copy of the warning notice to Monitor in the case of an NHS foundation trust and the Trust Development Authority in the case of an NHS trust&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66:</B> Clause 74, page 62, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) must in the case of an NHS trust require the Trust Development Authority to consider advising the Secretary of State to appoint a trust special administrator to run the trust and ensure high quality sustainable services for the future&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66ZA</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66ZA:</B> Clause 74, page 62, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Commission must ensure that there is consistency in&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the assessment of different NHS trusts and NHS foundation trusts; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the approach to tackling quality failures between different providers.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66ZB</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66ZB:</B> Clause 74, page 62, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Commission must define how the process of assessing the quality of health care for the purpose of a warning notice under section 29A is to apply to multi-site trusts offering a wide range of services.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66ZC</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66ZC:</B> Clause 74, page 62, line 28, leave out paragraph (a)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66ZD</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66ZD:</B> Clause 75, page 62, line 43, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2B) Where Monitor issues a licence condition following a warning notice under section 29A of the Health and Social Care Act 2008, it must set out the criteria which have guided its issuing of such a licence condition.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66ZE</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66ZE:</B> Clause 75, page 62, line 43, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2C) Where Monitor issues a licence condition following a warning notice under section 29A of the Health and Social Care Act 2008, the relevant NHS foundation trust shall have a right to appeal that licence condition.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 75, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 75 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66ZF</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66ZF:</B> Clause 76, page 63, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) After that subsection insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The regulator and the Care Quality Commission must follow a transparent and evidence-based process in making judgments under this section.</quote>
         <quote>( ) Either body will be required to publish on request the criteria which have informed a decision under this section.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66ZG</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66ZG:</B> Clause 76, page 63, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) After that subsection insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The regulator must ensure that there is a well-publicised appeals process available in the event of any disagreement with a proposed appointment of a trust special administrator under this section.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66A:</B> Clause 76, page 63, line 37, leave out &#8220;regulator&#8221; and insert &#8220;Secretary of State&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67:</B> Clause 76, page 63, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Commission and the Trust Development Authority must act in accordance with equivalent arrangements to those for foundation trusts when appointing a trust special administrator to run an NHS trust.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67A:</B> Clause 76, page 63, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In subsection (4) of that section, for &#8220;the reference in subsection (1) to the Secretary of State is to be read as a reference&#8221; substitute &#8220;the references in subsections (1) and (3A) to the Secretary of State are to be read as references&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>( ) In paragraph 24 of Schedule 14 to the Health and Social Care Act 2012 (abolition of NHS trusts in England: consequential amendments to section 65N of the National Health Service Act 2006), after sub-paragraph (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) In subsection (3A), for &#8220;the Secretary of State&#8221; substitute &#8220;the regulator&#8221;.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 76, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 76 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68:</B> Clause 77, page 64, line 8, leave out &#8220;(2A)&#8221; and insert &#8220;(5)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>69</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>69:</B> Clause 77, page 64, line 11, leave out &#8220;(2AA) Nor&#8221; and insert &#8220;(5A) Nor, in the case of an NHS foundation trust,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>70</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>70:</B> Clause 77, page 64, line 16, leave out &#8220;(2B)&#8221; and insert &#8220;(6)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>71</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>71:</B> Clause 77, page 64, line 18, leave out &#8220;(2A) or (2AA)&#8221; and insert &#8220;(5) or (5A)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>72</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>72:</B> Clause 77, page 65, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In paragraph 15(4) of Schedule 14 to the Health and Social Care Act 2012 (abolition of NHS trusts in England: consequential amendments to section 65F of the National Health Service Act 2006)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the new subsection (2A) to be inserted by paragraph 15(4), in paragraph (a), for &#8220;65DA&#8221; substitute &#8220;65DA(1)(a)&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after that new subsection, insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(2AA) Nor may the administrator provide the draft report to the regulator under subsection (1) without having obtained from the Care Quality Commission a statement that it considers that the recommendation in the draft report would achieve that part of the objective set out in section 65DA(1)(aa).&#8221;, and</quote>
         <IndentOne>(c) in the new subsection (2B) to be inserted by paragraph 15(4)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) after &#8220;Where the Board&#8221; insert &#8220;or the Care Quality Commission&#8221;,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) for &#8220;to that effect&#8221; substitute &#8220;to the effect mentioned in subsection (2A) or (2AA)&#8221;, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) after &#8220;, the Board&#8221; insert &#8220;or (as the case may be) the Commission&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 77, lord Warner gives notice of his intention to oppose the Question that Clause 77 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73:</B> Clause 79, page 66, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) a Chief Inspector of Hospitals,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) a Chief Primary and Community Care Inspector,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73A&#042;:</B> After Clause 79, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;National Reporting and Learning System</quote>
         <IndentOne>The National Reporting and Learning System shall come under the control of the Care Quality Commission.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73B&#042;:</B> After Clause 79, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Staffing numbers and skills mix</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Care Quality Commission shall, in carrying out its functions, have regard to any official guidance on staffing numbers and skills mix.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74:</B> Clause 80, page 67, line 19, at end insert &#8220;including their integration with other relevant services&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74A&#042;:</B> Clause 80, page 67, line 26, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) that reviews and performance assessment will also apply to commissioners of healthcare services, specifically Clinical Commissioning Groups and NHS England&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>75</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>75:</B> Clause 80, page 67, line 33, at end insert &#8220;including their integration with other relevant services&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76:</B> Clause 80, page 67, line 43, at end insert &#8220;providing such indicators as enable fair comparisons to be made on the performance of providers of similar classes of services&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76ZA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76ZA&#042;:</B> Clause 80, page 68, line 12, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) use an indicator to measure the adequacy of health and wellbeing support for staff by registered service providers in respect of regulated activities&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76ZB&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76ZB&#042;:</B> Clause 80, page 68, line 29, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Before the commencement of this section, a pilot of review and performance assessments must be conducted in numbered regions and for a fixed duration to be determined in regulations.</quote>
         <quote>( ) The pilot shall be independently evaluated, with the evaluation report laid before Parliament and approved by resolution of both Houses of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 80, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 80 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[In substitution for Amendment 93]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76A:</B> Before Clause 81, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Review by the Office for Budget Responsibility</quote>
         <IndentOne>Before enactment of Part 1 or the provisions in section 80 relating to performance ratings for local authorities, the Secretary of State must ask the Office for Budget Responsibility to complete by the end of 2014 a review of the funding of adult social care that assesses&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) the adequacy of current public funding of these services;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the proposals for funding the provisions in this Act; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the implications of the Act and its funding for the NHS over the next five years.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76B&#042;:</B> Before Clause 81, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty of candour</quote>
         <quote>Every organisation registered with the Care Quality Commission to provide health or social care services must be honest, open and truthful in all their dealing with patients and the public.</quote>
         <quote>Organisational interests of those so registered must never be allowed to outweigh the duty to be honest, open and truthful.</quote>
         <quote>Where death or serious harm has been or may have been caused to a patient by an act or omission of the organisation or its staff, the patient (or any lawfully entitled personal representative or other authorised person) should be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) informed of the incident;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) given full disclosure of the surrounding circumstances; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) be offered an appropriate level of support,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>whether or not the patient or representative has asked for this information.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>77</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>77:</B> Clause 81, page 69, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Under the terms of registration the Commission must require a care provider to ensure that all personnel exercise a duty of candour in their contacts with patients, service users and their families or representatives.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>77A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>77A&#042;:</B> Clause 81, page 69, line 31, leave out subsection (6)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>78</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>78:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State in making regulations or issuing guidelines under this Part must have regard to the general duty of local authorities, in exercising a function under this Part in the case of an individual, to promote that individual&#8217;s well-being.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>79</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>79:</B> Clause 1, page 2, line 31, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In exercising any function under this Part, the Secretary of State shall also have regard to the principles of well-being for individuals in subsection (2).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>80</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>80:</B> Clause 2, page 3, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the importance of identifying housing options required to exercise that duty&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>81</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>81:</B> Clause 3, page 3, line 32, after &#8220;provision&#8221; insert &#8220;and housing provision&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>82</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>82:</B> Clause 3, page 3, line 41, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In pursuit of integrating care and support with other relevant services, a local authority is enabled to participate in any form of joint working or funding with such services without let or hindrance.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>83</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>83:</B> Clause 4, page 4, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A local authority must only offer a financial product to pay for care to people who have received regulated financial advice or are customers who have opted out of taking regulated financial advice.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>83A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>83A:</B> Clause 4, page 4, leave out lines 19 to 21 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) the range of financial support and advice available independently of the local authority that is likely to be relevant to adults who have needs for care and support or are making plans for meeting needs for care and support that might arise and, for all care self-funders, a referral to regulated financial advice on matters related to paying for their care,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>84</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>84:</B> Clause 4, page 4, line 19, leave out &#8220;independent financial&#8221; and insert &#8220;information and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>85</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>85:</B> Clause 4, page 4, line 21, after &#8220;arise,&#8221; insert &#8220;including mandatory regulated financial advice for those taking out a care-related financial product, and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>86</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>86:</B> Clause 4, page 4, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) available housing options, and the choice of providers, available in the authority&#8217;s area&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87:</B> Clause 5, page 5, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) housing options for meeting adults&#8217; needs for care and support.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87ZA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87ZA&#042;:</B> Clause 6, page 6, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) ensuring the early and co-ordinated assessment of an adult who may have care and support needs following discharge from hospital or other acute care setting.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87A:</B> Clause 7, page 7, line 15, leave out &#8220;adult&#8221; and insert &#8220;individual&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87B:</B> Clause 7, page 7, line 16, after &#8220;carer,&#8221; insert &#8220;a carer of a child or a young carer,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87C:</B> Clause 7, page 7, line 22, leave out &#8220;adult&#8221; and insert &#8220;individual&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87D:</B> Clause 7, page 7, line 23, after &#8220;carer,&#8221; insert &#8220;a carer of a child or a young carer,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87E</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87E:</B> Clause 7, page 7, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) &#8220;Carer of a child&#8221; means a person who is a carer for the purposes of section 57.</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) &#8220;Young carer&#8221; has the same meaning as in section 60.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>88</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>88:</B> Clause 9, page 8, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(e) housing options to contribute to the achievement of those outcomes&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>89</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>89:</B> Clause 13, page 12, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In making regulations under this section, the Secretary of State must have regard to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the well-being principles in section 1,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) preventing the need for NHS services,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) establishing criteria for service provision that applies to all local authorities in England without variation in charging policies between areas,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) making available funding to meet the requirements of paragraph (c).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>90</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>90:</B> Clause 15, page 13, line 46, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State has a duty to make people aware of the terms of the cap on the cost of care through a national public awareness campaign.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>90A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>90A&#042;:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 2, leave out &#8220;earnings&#8221; and insert &#8220;care costs&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>90B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>90B&#042;:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 11, leave out &#8220;earnings&#8221; and insert &#8220;care costs&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>90C&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>90C&#042;:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 12, leave out &#8220;earnings&#8221; and insert &#8220;care costs&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>91</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>91:</B> Clause 17, page 15, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The regulations must provide that where the financial resources of a carer who has needs for support or of the adult needing care (whether in terms of income, capital or a combination of both) as calculated in accordance with the regulations exceed the financial limit, payments by the local authority shall be tapered in such a way that each complete increase of £500 in resources held by the carer or adult over and above the financial limit shall result in a reduction of annual payments of £1.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92:</B> Clause 17, page 15, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(10A) The regulations must provide that where the financial resources of a carer who has needs for support or of the adult needing care (whether in terms of income, capital or a combination of both) as calculated in accordance with the regulations exceed the financial limit, a reduction of annual payments of £1 shall be made for each complete increase by a sum that the Secretary of State may from time to time specify in resources held by the carer or adult over and above the financial limit.</quote>
         <quote>(10B) When specifying a sum for the purposes of subsection (10A), the Secretary of State must ensure that any such sum is greater than £250.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92A:</B> After Clause 46, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Corporate responsibility for neglect</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where a person registered under Chapter 2 of Part 1 of the Health and Social Care Act 2008 (a &#8220;registered care provider&#8221;) in respect of the carrying on of a regulated activity (within the meaning of that Part) has reasonable cause to suspect that an adult in their care is experiencing, or is at risk of, abuse and neglect.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The registered care provider must make (or cause to be made) whatever enquiries it thinks necessary to enable it to decide whether any action should be taken in the adult&#8217;s case and, if so, what and by whom.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Where abuse or neglect is suspected, the registered care provider is responsible for informing the Safeguarding Adults Board in its area and commits an offence if (without reasonable cause) it fails to do so.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A registered care provider is guilty of an offence if the way in which its activities are managed or organised by its board or senior management neglects or is a substantial element in the existence and or possibility of abuse or neglect occurring.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92B:</B> Clause 55, page 43, leave out lines 20 to 24 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) When a child receiving services reaches the age of 14, or a local authority receives a request from the child, or a parent or carer of the child, to assess the child&#8217;s needs for care and support (whichever is sooner), the authority must, if the consent condition is met, assess&#8212;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92C:</B> Clause 55, page 43, line 40, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) &#8220;Child receiving services&#8221; means a child&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) for whom, or for whose family or for a member of whose family, services are being provided under section 17 of the Children Act 1989,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for whom services are being provided under arrangements made under section 2 of the Chronically Sick and Disabled Persons Act 1970 (welfare services),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) for whom services are being provided under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 (after-care services),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) for whom care is being provided under the National Health Service Act 2006,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) for whom, or for whose family or for a member of whose family, services are being provided under such enactment as may be specified in regulations.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92D:</B> Clause 55, page 44, line 12, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The child&#8217;s needs assessment must be completed before the child reaches the age of 16, or within two years of the commencement of services being provided to the child, whichever is later.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>93</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>93:</B> After Clause 56, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>94</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>94:</B> After Clause 56, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Transition plans</quote>
         <quote>(1) When a local authority has completed an assessment under this section and is satisfied that the child has needs for care and support, is likely to have needs for care and support after becoming 18, and has determined what those needs are likely to be, the local authority must, before the child reaches 16 or within two years of the child beginning to receive services (whichever is later)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) secure that a transition plan is prepared for the child or young person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) once a transition plan has been prepared, it must maintain the plan.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of this Part, a transition plan is a plan specifying, for the proceeding five years of the child or young person&#8217;s life&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any health care and social care provision reasonably required by him or her;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the outcomes sought for him or her, including intentions to enter further or higher education, enter the workplace or move to independent or assisted living;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the housing provision required by him or her.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) &#8220;Health care provision&#8221; means the provision of health care services as part of the comprehensive health service in England continued under section 1(1) of the National Health Service Act 2006.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Regulations may make provision about the preparation and content of transition plans.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Where a local authority is required to secure that a transition plan is prepared for a child or young person, it must consult the child&#8217;s parent or the young person about the content of the plan during the preparation of a draft of the plan.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The local authority must then send the draft plan to the child or parent or carer.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The local authority must send a copy of the finalised transition plan to the child or parent or carer.</quote>
         <quote>(8) A transition plan shall be maintained until the young person reaches the age of 25.</quote>
         <quote>(9) A local authority in England and its partner commissioning bodies must make arrangements about the health, care and housing provision to be secured for children and young people for whom a transition plan is prepared and maintained.</quote>
         <quote>(10) Where an education, health and care plan (&#8220;EHC plan&#8221;) is being prepared for a child or young person by a local authority under Part 3 of the Children and Families Act 2013, and a transition plan is already maintained for the child or young person, the transition plan must become part of the EHC plan.</quote>
         <quote>(11) Where an EHC plan is already maintained for a child or young person by a local authority and a child&#8217;s needs assessment is undertaken under section 55(1), the local authority must ensure that the child or young person&#8217;s EHC plan includes the transition plan as set out under subsection (2).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95:</B> After Clause 56, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Continuity of a transition plan when a child moves</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a child&#8217;s needs assessment has been carried out by a local authority (&#8220;the first authority&#8221;) under section 55(1) and a transition plan under section (Transition plans) (1) is being maintained;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the child or parent or carer of the child notifies another local authority (&#8220;the second authority&#8221;) (or that authority is notified on the child&#8217;s behalf) that the child intends to move to the area of the second authority, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the second authority is satisfied that the child or parent or carer intention is genuine.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The second authority must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) provide the child or parent or carer with such information as it considers appropriate, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) notify the first authority that it is satisfied as mentioned in subsection (1)(c).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The first authority, having received the notification under subsection (2)(b), must provide the second authority with&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a copy of any transition plan prepared for the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a copy of the most recent child&#8217;s needs assessment in the child&#8217;s case; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) such other information relating to the child as the second authority may request.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The second authority must undertake a child&#8217;s needs assessment.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In carrying out an assessment under subsection (4), the second authority must have regard to the transition plan provided under section (Transition plans).</quote>
         <quote>(6) This Part applies to an assessment under subsection (4) as it applies to a child&#8217;s needs assessment.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Where the child&#8217;s needs identified by a child&#8217;s needs assessment under subsection (6) carried out by the second authority are different from those specified in the transition plan provided under subsection (3)(a), the second authority must provide a written explanation of the difference to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the child,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the parent,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the carer, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) any other person to whom the child asks the authority to provide the explanation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) Regulations may specify steps which a local authority must take for the purpose of being satisfied as mentioned in subsection (1)(c).</quote>
         <quote>(9) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a reference to moving to an area is a reference to moving to that area with a view to becoming ordinarily resident there, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a reference to remaining in an area is a reference to remaining ordinarily resident there.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>96</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>96:</B> After Clause 56, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Case where assessments not complete on day of move</quote>
         <quote>(1) If, on the day of the intended move as mentioned in section (Continuity of a transition plan when a child moves) (1)(b), the second authority has yet to carry out the assessment under section (Continuity of a transition plan when a child moves) (4), or has done so but has yet to take the other steps required under this Part in the child&#8217;s case, it must maintain the transition plan which the first authority has been maintaining.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The second authority must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) provide the child or parent or carer with such information as it considers appropriate, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) notify the first authority that it is satisfied as mentioned in section (Continuity of a transition plan when a child moves) (1)(c).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The first authority is not required to maintain the child&#8217;s transition plan for so long as the second authority is subject to the duty under subsection (1).</quote>
         <quote>(4) Where, having complied with the duty under subsection (1), the second authority is not required to maintain the child&#8217;s transition plan under section (Transition plans) because the child is still ordinarily resident in the area of the first authority, the second authority may recover from the first authority the costs it incurs in complying with the duty under subsection (1).</quote>
         <quote>(5) Regulations may specify matters to which the second authority must have regard in deciding how to perform the duty under subsection (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>97</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>97:</B> After Clause 56, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Disputes about ordinary residence or continuity of care</quote>
         <quote>(1) Any dispute about where a child is ordinarily resident for the purposes of this Part, or any dispute between local authorities under section (Continuity of a transition plan when a child moves) about the application of that section, is to be determined by&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Secretary of State, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the Secretary of State appoints a person for that purpose (the &#8220;appointed person&#8221;), that person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State or appointed person may review a determination under subsection (1), provided that the review begins within three months of the date of the determination.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Having carried out a review under subsection (2), the Secretary of State or appointed person must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) confirm the original determination, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) substitute a different determination.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Regulations may make further provision about resolution of disputes of the type mentioned in subsection (1); the regulations may, for example, include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) provision for ensuring that care and support is provided to the child while the dispute is unresolved;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provision requiring the local authorities in dispute to take specified steps before referring the dispute to the Secretary of State or (as the case may be) the appointed person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provision about the procedure for referring the dispute to the Secretary of State or appointed person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) where a review of a determination has been carried out under subsection (2) and a different determination substituted, provision requiring a local authority to take specified steps (including paying specified amounts) in relation to the period before the determination was substituted.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>98</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>98:</B> Clause 57, page 45, leave out lines 6 to 10 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) When a child receiving services reaches the age of 14, or a local authority receives a request from a carer of a child to assess the carer&#8217;s needs for support (whichever is sooner), the authority must assess&#8212;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>99</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>99:</B> Clause 57, page 45, line 16, leave out from &#8220;support&#8221; to end of line 19 and insert &#8220;the authority must assess&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>100</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>100:</B> Clause 57, page 46, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment must be completed before the child reaches the age of 16, or within two years of the commencement of services being provided to the child, whichever is later.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>101</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>101:</B> Clause 59, page 47, line 3, leave out &#8220;may&#8221; and insert &#8220;must&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>102</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>102:</B> Clause 59, page 47, line 5, leave out &#8220;power&#8221; and insert &#8220;duty&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>103</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>103:</B> Clause 59, page 47, line 8, leave out &#8220;whether or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104:</B> Clause 59, page 47, line 8, leave out &#8220;exercise the power&#8221; and insert &#8220;comply with the duty&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104A&#042;:</B> Schedule 3, page 102, line 37, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) specify matters which the local authority and relevant partners must have regard to in carrying out an assessment of a person who may have care needs following discharge from a hospital or other acute care setting.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>105</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>105:</B> Clause 68, page 56, leave out lines 4 to 11 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>(5) In this section, &#8220;after-care services&#8221; means services to reduce the likelihood of the person requiring admission to a hospital again for treatment for mental disorder.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>