<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill59_II(d))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Second Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 51</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HUGHES OF STRETFORD</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS JONES OF WHITCHURCH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 51, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Single point of appeal: review</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State will, within a year of this Act coming into force, carry out a review to assess the feasibility of enabling a child&#8217;s parent or a young person to appeal to the First Tier Tribunal in relation to the healthcare or social care provision specified in an EHC plan.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In undertaking a review under subsection (1), the Secretary of State will pay particular regard to the need for an integrated appeals process.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Secretary of State will publish, and lay before both Houses of Parliament, a report setting out the conclusions of the review.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 73</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD NORTHBOURNE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 73, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;School policies to prepare children and young people for the opportunities, challenges and responsibilities of adult life</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 78 of the Education Act 2002 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;78A Duty of schools to promote the personal and social development of pupils, and to prepare them for the responsibilities of adult life and parenthood</quote>
         <quote>(1) All schools shall make explicit to parents, school governors and pupils how they deliver&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) guidance to young people as they explore the opportunities and challenges of the adult life which lies ahead of them;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) help for children and young people who are pupils at the school to develop the personal, social and communication skills that they are likely to need in their adult life;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) help for children and young people who are pupils at the school to discuss and understand the responsibilities, duties and challenges of parenthood;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) provision of activities and other opportunities for pupils at the school to develop interpersonal, leadership and teamwork skills as a preparation for their adult life.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The above shall be delivered as appropriate to the age, readiness and needs of pupils in the school.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 4</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HUGHES OF STRETFORD</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS JONES OF WHITCHURCH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 4, page 171, line 15, after &#8220;agency&#8221; insert &#8220;, or any individual childminder registered at the agency,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 4, page 171, line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Chief Inspector must at such intervals as may be prescribed inspect all early years provision registered with an early years childminder agency.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 76</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HUGHES OF STRETFORD</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS JONES OF WHITCHURCH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 76, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 76 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>