<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill32_VI(a))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>267D&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>267D&#042;:</B> After Clause 97, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Parental bereavement leave</quote>
         <IndentOne>In the Employment Rights Act 1996, after section 57A insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;57AA Parental bereavement leave</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State must make regulations entitling an employee who satisfies specified conditions&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) as to duration of employment, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) as to relationship with a child,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>to be absent from work on leave under this section in consequence of the death of a child.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Regulations under subsection (1) shall secure that, where an employee has a right to leave under this section, he or she is entitled to a leave period of at least 2 weeks.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Regulations under subsection (1) shall secure that an employee who exercises his or her right under subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is entitled, for such purposes and to such extent as may be prescribed, to the benefit of the terms and conditions of employment which would have applied if he or she had not been absent,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is bound, for such purposes and to such extent as may be prescribed, by any obligations arising under those terms and conditions (except in so far as they are inconsistent with subsection (1)), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is entitled to return from leave to a job of a prescribed kind.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (3)(a) &#8220;terms and conditions of employment&#8221; includes&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) matters connected with an employee&#8217;s employment whether or not they arise under his or her contract of employment; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) terms and conditions about remuneration.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>