<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Energy_(Bill48(b))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENT TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 137</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CAMPBELL-SAVOURS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 137, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Rising block tariff energy supply scheme</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State shall have regard to the desirability of establishing specifications for the introduction of a rising block tariff scheme governing electricity and gas prices and shall consult representatives of the gas and electricity supply industries prior to the establishment of such regulations.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A rising block tariff system of energy pricing is one in which there is a basic threshold price for electricity and gas and an additional percentage price premium applicable to each block of units above that threshold.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A national standard for rising block tariffs shall cover the following matters&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the number of units of gas or electricity to be provided by the supplier of the basic threshold price annually;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the number of units comprised in each subsequent block of units;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the additional price premium payable per unit applicable to each block;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the calculation for the purposes of setting the minimum number of units to be applied at the basic threshold price quarterly;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) the arrangements for the setting of standing charges.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Nothing in this Act permits the Secretary of State to determine the basic threshold price of electricity where a rising block tariff is in force.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Secretary of State shall report to Parliament on the operation of the scheme within 12 months of the coming into force of this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>