<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Energy_(Bill48_II)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>59A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>59A&#042;:</B> Clause 43, page 27, line 18, leave out &#8220;may&#8221; and insert &#8220;shall&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>60</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>60:</B> Clause 44, page 28, line 6, at end insert &#8220;; and the Secretary of State must exercise that power and the power to make regulations under section 45 so as to ensure that a power purchase agreement scheme begins to operate no later than the time at which the first CFD is awarded&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>61</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>61:</B> Clause 44, page 28, line 14, at end insert &#8220;at a discount to a prevailing market price&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[As an amendment to Amendment 61]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>61A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>61A&#042;:</B> Clause 44, after &#8220;discount&#8221; insert &#8220;not exceeding 5 per cent.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62:</B> Clause 44, page 28, line 16, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In determining the provision to be made under this section and section 45, the Secretary of State must have regard, in particular, to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the desirability of ensuring that every electricity generator who is a party to a CFD is able to borrow money commercially for its business purposes at adequate levels, reasonable cost and over a reasonable period;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) accordingly, the need to ensure that the terms of every power purchase agreement made under the scheme, and the level of the associated strike price, are such that every such agreement is demonstrably viable for the electricity generator who is party to it.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>63</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>63:</B> Clause 44, page 28, line 24,  at end insert &#8220;(including provision for determining a market price and the amount of a discount at any time)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64:</B> Clause 44, page 28, line 29, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Provision under subsection (1) (including provision of the kind mentioned in subsection (4)) must be such as to ensure that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) every electricity generator who is eligible to become a party to a CFD is eligible to enter into a power purchase agreement under the scheme;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an electricity generator who is so eligible may, by notice in writing, require the Authority (or such other person on whom regulations under section 45 confer the relevant functions) to secure, within no later than seven days after the notice is given, that a licensed supplier enter into a power purchase agreement with the generator under the scheme;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the terms of each power purchase agreement entered into under the scheme, including its duration, are such that the agreement is demonstrably viable for the electricity generator who is party to it;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the price at which electricity is purchased under each power purchase agreement entered into under the scheme is set, for the duration of the agreement, by reference to a fixed discount from the strike price or reference price under the associated CFD, at a level that enables the generator to maintain adequate borrowings for its business purposes at reasonable cost.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>65</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>65:</B> Clause 44, page 28, line 44, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Provision of the kind mentioned in subsections (5) and (6) must be such as to ensure that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) every electricity generator is entitled to have the question which licensed supplier or suppliers is or are to be required or permitted to enter into an agreement with that generator determined swiftly and at minimal cost by one of the persons mentioned in subsection (6)(a);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where a process of the kind mentioned in subsection (6)(a) is made available, it is no more onerous for an electricity generator than a process of the kind mentioned in subsection (6)(b).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66:</B> Before Clause 49, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Closure of support under the renewables obligation</quote>
         <quote>(1) After section 32L of EA 1989 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;32LA  Renewables obligation closure order</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may make a renewables obligation closure order.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A renewables obligation closure order is an order which provides that no renewables obligation certificates are to be issued under a renewables obligation order in respect of electricity generated after a specified date.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Provision made under subsection (2) may specify different dates in relation to different cases or circumstances.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The cases or circumstances mentioned in subsection (2) may in particular be described by reference to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) accreditation of a generating station, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the addition of generating capacity to a generating station.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) A renewables obligation closure order may include provision about&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the meaning of &#8220;accreditation&#8221; and &#8220;generating capacity&#8221; in subsection (4);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) when generating capacity is to be treated as added to a generating station for the purposes of that subsection.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) References in this section to a renewables obligation order are references to any renewables obligation order made under section 32 (whenever made, and whether or not made by the Secretary of State).</quote>
         <quote>(7) Power to make provision in a renewables obligation order (and any provision contained in such an order) is subject to provision contained in a renewables obligation closure order; but this section is not otherwise to be taken as affecting power to make provision in a renewables obligation order of the kind mentioned in subsection (2).</quote>
         <quote>(8) Section 32K applies in relation to a renewables obligation closure order as it applies in relation to a renewables obligation order (and subsection (3) above is not to be taken as limiting the application of that section).</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;32LB Renewables obligation closure orders: procedure</quote>
         <quote>(1) Before making a renewables obligation closure order, the Secretary of State must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Authority,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Council,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) such generators of electricity from renewable sources as the Secretary of State considers appropriate, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) such other persons, if any, as the Secretary of State considers appropriate.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The requirement to consult may be satisfied by consultation before, as well as consultation after, the passing of the Energy Act 2013.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A renewables obligation closure order is not to be made unless a draft of the instrument containing it has been laid before and approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 32M(1) of EA 1989 (interpretation of sections 32 to 32M)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) for &#8220;32L&#8221; substitute &#8220;32LB&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after the definition of &#8220;renewables obligation order&#8221; insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;renewables obligation closure order&#8221; is to be construed in accordance with section 32LA;&#8221;;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(c) in the definition of &#8220;specified&#8221;, after &#8220;renewables obligation order&#8221; insert &#8220;or a renewables obligation closure order&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In section 106 of EA 1989 (regulations and orders), in subsection (2)(b) after &#8220;32,&#8221; insert &#8220;32LA,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In Article 56(1) of the Energy (Northern Ireland) Order 2003 (S.I. 2003/419 (N.I. 6)) (power to amend Part 7 of that Order to take account of amendments of corresponding Great Britain provisions), the reference to amendments made to sections 32 to 32C of EA 1989 includes a reference to subsections (1) and (2) of this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67:</B> Clause 49, page 42, leave out lines 45 to 47</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68:</B> Clause 49, page 44, line 46, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;32XA  Certificate purchase orders: corresponding provision </quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where the Secretary of State exercises a listed power in the making of a certificate purchase order.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) so far as the order is made for a GB purpose, exercise the listed power in the way that the Secretary of State considers will replicate the effect of provision contained in a renewables obligation order (whenever made, and whether or not made by the Secretary of State) by virtue of the equivalent GB power;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) so far as the order is made for a NI purpose, exercise the listed power in the way that the Secretary of State considers will replicate the effect of provision contained in an order under Article 52 of the 2003 NI Order (whenever made) by virtue of the equivalent NI power.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The duty in subsection (2) to exercise any listed power in the way mentioned in that subsection applies only to the extent that it appears to the Secretary of State that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) it is reasonably practicable to exercise the listed power in that way, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) exercising the power in that way is not inconsistent with other duties or requirements of the Secretary of State (whether arising under this Act or another enactment, by virtue of any EU obligation or otherwise).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In the Table&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a &#8220;listed power&#8221; is any power specified in the first column;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the &#8220;equivalent GB power&#8221;, in relation to a listed power, is the power specified in the corresponding entry in the second column;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the &#8220;equivalent NI power&#8221;, in relation to a listed power, is the power specified in the corresponding entry in the third column, and in that column references to an Article are to an Article of the 2003 NI Order.</IndentOne>
         <Table columns="3">
            <tablehead>
               <r>
                  <c>Listed power</c>
                  <c>Equivalent GB power</c>
                  <c>Equivalent NI power</c>
               </r>
            </tablehead>
            <tablebody>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32O(2)(a)</c>
                  <c>Sections 32A(2)(a) and 32G(2)(a)</c>
                  <c>Articles 53(2)(a) and 55(2)(a)</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32O(2)(b)</c>
                  <c>Sections 32A(2)(b) and 32G(2)(c)</c>
                  <c>Articles 53(2)(b) and 55(2)(c)</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32O(2)(c)</c>
                  <c>Section 32G(2)(e)</c>
                  <c>Article 55(2)(e)</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32O(2)(f) </c>
                  <c>Section 32A(2)(c) </c>
                  <c>Article 53(2)(c) </c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32S</c>
                  <c>Section 32B</c>
                  <c>---</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32T</c>
                  <c>---</c>
                  <c>Article 54</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32U(5) and (6)</c>
                  <c>Section 32C(5) and (6)</c>
                  <c>Article 54A(5) and (6)</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32V(1) </c>
                  <c>Section 32D(1) </c>
                  <c>Article 54B(1) </c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32W(5) to (8)</c>
                  <c>Section 32E(4) to (6) and (8)</c>
                  <c>Article 54C(4) to (7)</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32X</c>
                  <c>Section 32J</c>
                  <c>Article 55C</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32Z1(2) (so far as relating to definition of &#8220;renewable sources&#8221;) and (3)</c>
                  <c>Section 32M (so far as relating to that definition) and (2)</c>
                  <c>Article 55F(1) (so far as relating to that definition) and (2)</c>
               </r>
               <r>
                  <c>Section 32Z1(9)</c>
                  <c>Section 32M(7)</c>
                  <c>Article 55F(3)</c>
               </r>
            </tablebody>
         </Table>
         <quote>(5) The duty in subsection (2), so far as it has effect in relation to the exercise of the listed power under section 32V(1) to specify different amounts of electricity in relation to different cases or circumstances, applies only to the first exercise of that listed power.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The relevant part of Great Britain to which a renewables obligation order relates may be ignored for the purposes of subsection (2)(a).</quote>
         <quote>(7) It does not matter for the purposes of subsection (2) whether or not a renewables obligation order, or an order made under Article 52 of the 2003 NI Order, is in force at the time when the listed powers in question are being exercised.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;2003 NI Order&#8221; means the Energy (Northern Ireland) Order 2003 (S.I. 2003/419 (N.I. 6));</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;GB purpose&#8221; means the purpose of imposing the certificate purchase obligation on the purchasing body of GB certificates;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;NI purpose&#8221; means the purpose of imposing the certificate purchase obligation on the purchasing body of NI certificates.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>69</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>69:</B> Clause 49, page 45, line 37, after &#8220;Part)&#8221; insert &#8220;, and by section 123(2) of the Energy Act 2013 (duties in relation to strategy and policy statement),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>70</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>70:</B> Clause 49, page 48, line 25, leave out &#8220;&#8220;32,&#8221;&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8220;32LA,&#8221; (as inserted by section (Closure of support under the renewables obligation)(3))&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>71</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>71:</B> Clause 50, page 49, line 1, leave out &#8220;Until (and including) 2044,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>72</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>72:</B> Clause 50, page 49, line 1, leave out &#8220;2044&#8221; and insert &#8220;2029&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73:</B> Clause 50, page 49, line 1, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) The statutory rate of emissions set in subsection (2) must be reviewed every three years in line with the decarbonisation reporting process required under the Energy Act 2010.</quote>
         <quote>(2B) The statutory rate of emissions will apply to new fossil fuel plants at the point at which they are consented.</quote>
         <quote>(2C) The Secretary of State may by regulations, and following the approval of Parliament, change the statutory rate of emissions following a review made under subsection (2A).</quote>
         <quote>(2D) The statutory rate of emission applying to a fossil fuel plant will remain at the rate which was applied when consented for its lifetime.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73A:</B> Clause 50, page 49, line 11, after &#8220;to&#8221; insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) section (Introduction of carbon capture and storage: exemption from emissions limit), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73B:</B> After Clause 50, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Introduction of carbon capture and storage: exemption from emissions limit</quote>
         <quote>(1) The emissions limit duty does not apply during the exemption period in relation to fossil fuel plant for which there is a complete CCS system.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For this purpose, a complete CCS system, in relation to fossil fuel plant, is a system of plant and facilities for&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) capturing some or all of the carbon dioxide (or any substance consisting primarily of carbon dioxide) that is produced by, or in connection with, generation of electricity by the generating station comprised in the fossil fuel plant,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) transporting the carbon dioxide (or substance) captured, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) disposing of it by way of permanent storage.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The exemption period for any fossil fuel plant is the period&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) beginning with the first day on which the fossil fuel plant and its complete CCS system are ready for use, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) ending with&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the expiry of 3 years beginning with that day, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) 31 December 2027,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>whichever is earlier.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (3), &#8220;use&#8221; includes testing in connection with the generation of electricity on a commercial scale.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Subsection (1) is subject to any provision made by regulations under section 50(6)(b).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74:</B> Schedule 4, page 130, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(iii) substantial pollution abatement equipment dealing with oxides of sulphur, oxides of nitrogen, heavy metal emissions or particles is fitted to the generating station.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74A:</B> Schedule 4, page 130, line 16, at end insert &#8220;, or the exemption in section (Introduction of carbon capture and storage: exemption from emissions limit),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74B:</B> Schedule 4, page 130, line 26, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Modifications where carbon capture and storage process used in relation to part of generating station</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>3A (1) Regulations under section 50(6)(b) may provide for the exemption in section (Introduction of carbon capture and storage: exemption from emissions limit) to apply with modifications in cases where the complete CCS system for the fossil fuel plant relates to only part of the generating station.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For this purpose&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a complete CCS system relates to part of a generating station if it is a system for capturing some or all of the carbon dioxide (or any substance consisting primarily of carbon dioxide) that is produced by, or in connection with, generation of electricity by that part of the generating station, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;complete CCS system&#8221; has the same meaning as in section (Introduction of carbon capture and storage: exemption from emissions limit).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74C:</B> Schedule 4, page 130, line 29, leave out from &#8220;where&#8221; to end of line 32 and insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the generating station is used for the first time, or permanently ceases to be used, for the generation of electricity,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any period during which the emissions limit duty does not apply in relation to the plant by virtue of section (Introduction of carbon capture and storage: exemption from emissions limit) begins or ends, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the generating station, or any CCS plant comprised in the fossil fuel plant, is altered.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74D:</B> Clause 53, page 52, line 5, after second &#8220;plant&#8221; insert &#8220;, or a system of plant and facilities,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74E</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74E:</B> Clause 53, page 52, line 37, after &#8220;&#8220;year&#8221;&#8221; insert &#8220;, except in section (Introduction of carbon capture and storage: exemption from emissions limit),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>75</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>75:</B> Clause 53, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76:</B> After Clause 58, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reduction of landfilling of organic waste</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must, as soon as reasonably practicable, set out a plan and timeframe for the reduction and eventual elimination of landfilling of organic waste in order to make it available for 100% renewable energy generation and other appropriate uses consistent with the waste hierarchy as defined in The Waste (England and Wales) Regulations 2011.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76A&#042;:</B> Clause 60, page 57, line 14, after &#8220;persons&#8221; insert &#8220;and the environment&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>77</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>77:</B> Clause 60, page 57, line 16, at end insert &#8220;their&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>78</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>78:</B> Clause 60, page 57, line 37, after &#8220;site&#8221; insert &#8220;(its &#8220;associated site&#8221;)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>78A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>78A&#042;:</B> Schedule 7, page 137, line 17, leave out sub-paragraph (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) At least one non-executive member must have experience of, or expertise in&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) matters relevant to nuclear safety management;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) representation of employees in health and safety;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) matters relevant to the ONR&#8217;s nuclear security purposes.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>78B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>78B&#042;:</B> After Clause 70, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Approval of design and construction of nuclear installations</quote>
         <quote>(1) In relation to the design and construction of nuclear installations under section 60(1)(a) of this Act, the ONR in conjunction with the Environment Agency shall have responsibility for the approval of the design and construction process for all nuclear installations.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In approving such designs, the ONR shall ensure the highest technological and safety standards are met and the most cost effective measures taken in the construction plans.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>79</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>79:</B> Clause 71, page 64, line 20, leave out &#8220;with the consent of the Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;in accordance with section (Procedure for issue, revision or withdrawal of codes of practice)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>80</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>80:</B> Clause 71, page 64, line 23, leave out from beginning to &#8220;revise&#8221; and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(b) &#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>81</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>81:</B> Clause 71, page 64, line 25, leave out subsections (3) to (5)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>82</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>82:</B> After Clause 71, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Procedure for issue, revision or withdrawal of codes of practice</quote>
         <quote>(1) The ONR may&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) issue or revise a code of practice under section 71 only in accordance with subsection (8);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) withdraw a code of practice under that section only in accordance with subsection (11).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Before issuing, or revising or withdrawing, a code of practice, the ONR must submit a proposal to the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Before submitting a proposal to the Secretary of State the ONR must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any government department or other person that the Secretary of State has directed the ONR to consult, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any other government department or other person that the ONR considers it appropriate to consult,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>about the proposal.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A direction under subsection (3)(a) may be general or may relate to a particular code, or codes of a particular kind.</quote>
         <quote>(5) A proposal for issuing or revising a code of practice must include a draft code of practice or, as the case may be, proposed revisions of a code of practice.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Where the ONR submits a proposal for issuing or revising a code of practice to the Secretary of State, the Secretary of State may approve the draft code of practice, or proposed revisions, as the case may be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) without modification, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) with the consent of the ONR, with modifications.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) If the Secretary of State approves the draft code or proposed revisions, the Secretary of State must lay before Parliament the draft code or proposed revisions in the form approved.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Secretary of State has laid a draft code or proposed revisions of a code before Parliament, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) no negative resolution is made within the 40-day period,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>the ONR may issue the code in the form of the draft laid before Parliament or, as the case may be, make the proposed revisions in the form so laid.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) For the purpose of subsection (8)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a &#8220;negative resolution&#8221;, in relation to a draft code or proposed revisions, means a resolution of either House of Parliament not to approve the draft code or proposed revisions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the &#8220;40-day period&#8221;, in relation to a draft of a code or proposed revisions, means the period of 40 days beginning with the day on which the draft is laid before Parliament (or, if it is not laid before each House of Parliament on the same day, the later of the 2 days on which it is laid).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) For the purposes of calculating the 40-day period, no account is to be taken of any period during which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) Parliament is dissolved or prorogued, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) both Houses are adjourned for more than 4 days.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(11) Where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the ONR submits to the Secretary of State a proposal for the withdrawal of a code of practice, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Secretary of State approves the proposal,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>it may withdraw the code.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(12) The ONR must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) publish any code of practice issued under section 71;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) when it revises such a code, publish&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) a notice to that effect, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) a copy of the revised code;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(c) when it withdraws such a code, publish a notice to that effect.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>83</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>83:</B> Schedule 9, page 157, line 9, leave out &#8220;or an&#8221; and insert &#8220;, an inspector or a health and safety&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>84</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>84:</B> Schedule 10, page 164, line 27, leave out &#8220;or under&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>85</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>85:</B> Clause 104, page 83, line 39, after &#8220;containing&#8221; insert &#8220;(whether alone or with other provision)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>86</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>86:</B> Clause 104, page 83, line 40, leave out from &#8220;regulations&#8221; to &#8220;or&#8221; in line 42 and insert &#8220;which fall within subsection (2A)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87:</B> Clause 104, page 83, line 45, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) Nuclear regulations fall within this subsection if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) they are the first nuclear regulations to be made,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) they include provision amending or repealing any provision of&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the Nuclear Installations Act 1965, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the Nuclear Safeguards Act 2000, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(c) they include provision creating a new offence by virtue of section 67;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and for this purpose nuclear regulations which revoke and re-enact an offence are not to be regarded as creating a new offence.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>88</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>88:</B> Clause 105, page 84, line 30, after &#8220;as&#8221; insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>(i) &#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>89</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>89:</B> Clause 105, page 84, line 32, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(ii) regulations under section 76, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) regulations under section 92.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>90</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>90:</B> Clause 105, page 84, line 43, leave out &#8220;section 15 of the 1974&#8221; and insert &#8220;section 14 of the 1974 Act (power to direct investigations and inquiries);</quote>
         <IndentOne>(ba) section 15 of that&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>91</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>91:</B> Schedule 11, page 172, line 9, after &#8220;A&#8221; insert &#8220;property transfer&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92:</B> Schedule 12, page 177, line 47, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) Section 82 (general provisions as to interpretation and regulations) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (3)(b), after &#8220;subsection&#8221; insert &#8220;(3A) or&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (3) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) In the case of a statutory instrument which also contains regulations under section 66 of the Energy Act 2013 (nuclear regulations), subsection (3) is subject to section 104 of that Act (subordinate legislation).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>93</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>93:</B> Clause 123, page 92, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Authority must demonstrate that it has complied with its general environmental duties as stipulated in national and international legislation.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>94</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>94:</B> Clause 123, page 92, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State shall issue guidance on social and environmental policies to which the Authority shall have regard in carrying out its functions.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95:</B> Clause 125, page 94, line 36, at end insert &#8220;and in accordance with any guidance issued under this section&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>96</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>96:</B> Clause 125, page 94, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State must issue guidance about arrangements for wider public engagement including consultation on social and environmental matters.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>97</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>97:</B> Clause 130, page 100, line 16, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(ba) require information to be provided in a form that is clear and easy to understand;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>98</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>98:</B> Clause 130, page 100, line 18, leave out from &#8220;information&#8221; to &#8220;about&#8221; in line 23</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>99</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>99:</B> Clause 130, page 100, line 24, after &#8220;terms&#8221; insert &#8220;to be provided&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>100</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>100:</B> Clause 130, page 100, line 24, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) make provision about the way in which information is to be provided, which may in particular require information to be provided&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) by means of a code or otherwise using a format readable by an electronic device, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) in a way which facilitates processing of the information by means of an electronic device.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>101</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>101:</B> Clause 130, page 102, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(13) A statutory instrument containing an order under subsection (10) is subject to annulment in pursuance of an order of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>102</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>102:</B> After Clause 130, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Transparency for consumers</quote>
         <IndentOne>The power under section 130 to modify energy supply licences may be exercised so as to make provision requiring a licence holder to provide information on a consumer bill that breaks down the total cost charged to the consumer by showing each of&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) the amount that goes to Government environmental levies or programmes;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the amount that goes to administration costs;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the amount that goes to wholesale energy costs;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the amount for raw energy costs; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) any other categories of cost.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>103</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>103:</B> Clause 131, page 102, line 13, leave out paragraph (a)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104:</B> Clause 131, page 102, line 21, leave out subsections (3) and (4) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) Before making modifications under section 130(1) the Secretary of State must lay a draft of the modifications before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(3B) If, within the 40-day period, either House of Parliament resolves not to approve the draft, the Secretary of State may not take any further steps in relation to the proposed modifications.</quote>
         <quote>(3C) If no such resolution is made within that period, the Secretary of State may make the modifications in the form of the draft.</quote>
         <quote>(3D) Subsection (3B) does not prevent a new draft of proposed modifications being laid before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(3E) In this section &#8220;40-day period&#8221;, in relation to a draft of proposed modifications, means the period of 40 days beginning with the day on which the draft is laid before Parliament (or, if it is not laid before each House of Parliament on the same day, the later of the 2 days on which it is laid).</quote>
         <quote>(3F) For the purposes of calculating the 40-day period, no account is to be taken of any period during which Parliament is dissolved or prorogued or during which both Houses are adjourned for more than 4 days.</quote>
         <quote>(3G) The Secretary of State must publish details of any modifications made under section 130(1) as soon as reasonably practicable after they are made.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104A:</B> After Clause 132, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Carbon monoxide detection</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may make regulations to ensure&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any particular class of residential premises is fitted with an appropriate carbon monoxide alarm where any carbon burning appliance is in situ,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the supply, sale and fitting of a carbon monoxide alarm may be undertaken by any registered carbon burning appliance engineer, smart meter installer or by local authority fire and rescue service personnel.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Regulations under this section shall be contained in a statutory instrument which shall be laid before Parliament and subject to annulment by resolution of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>105</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>105:</B> After Clause 137, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Rising block tariff energy supply scheme</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State shall have regard to the desirability of establishing specifications for the introduction of a rising block tariff scheme governing electricity and gas prices and shall consult representatives of the gas and electricity supply industries prior to the establishment of such regulations.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A rising block tariff system of energy pricing is one in which there is a basic threshold price for electricity and gas and an additional percentage price premium applicable to each block of units above that threshold.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A national standard for rising block tariffs shall cover the following matters&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the number of units of gas or electricity to be provided by the supplier of the basic threshold price annually;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the number of units comprised in each subsequent block of units;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the additional price premium payable per unit applicable to each block;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the calculation for the purposes of setting the minimum number of units to be applied at the basic threshold price quarterly;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) the arrangements for the setting of standing charges.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Nothing in this Act permits the Secretary of State to determine the basic threshold price of electricity where a rising block tariff is in force.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Secretary of State shall report to Parliament on the operation of the scheme within 12 months of the coming into force of this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>106</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>106:</B> After Clause 141, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendment of Electricity Act 1989: generating station and overhead line development by non licence-holders</quote>
         <IndentOne>In Schedule 9 to Electricity Act 1989 (preservation of amenity and fisheries), after paragraph 4 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;4A (1) Sub-paragraph (2) applies where a person who is neither a licence holder nor authorised by exemption to generate, distribute, supply or participate in the transmission of electricity applies for the consent of the Secretary of State under section 36 or 37 of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Paragraphs 1 and 3 above apply to the making and consideration of the application as they apply to the making and consideration of relevant proposals made by a person who is a licence holder or so authorised by exemption.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>107</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>107:</B> Clause 145, page 113, line 1, leave out sub-paragraph (iv) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section 49 (transition to certificate purchase scheme);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>108</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>108:</B> Clause 145, page 113, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Section (Closure of support under the renewables obligation)(4) extends to Northern Ireland only.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>109</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>109:</B> Clause 146, page 113, line 32, leave out paragraph (c) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section 49 (transition to certificate purchase scheme);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>110</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>110:</B> Clause 146, page 114, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Closure of support under the renewables obligation) (closure of support under the renewables obligation);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>