<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Equality_Titles_(HLBill12(c))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD JOPLING</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) No petition under section 2 may be made in respect of any person living at the time this Act is passed.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 4</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD LUCAS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, leave out Clause 4 and insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Petitioning procedure</quote>
         <quote>(1) The petition procedure set out in section 3 shall only apply if all relevant people have notified the Lord Chancellor in writing of their agreement for the petition to be presented.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A relevant person under subsection (1) shall be defined as&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any sibling, child or descendant of the incumbent who could reasonably consider themselves in line to the title, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any person who is able to satisfy the Lord Chancellor that they have a reasonable expectation of succeeding to the title.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The Lord Chancellor shall publish his decision within six months of a petition being lodged.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Lord Chancellor&#8217;s assessment of a relevant person is final and is not subject to a right of appeal.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 7</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD LUCAS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 7, page 4, line 2, at end insert &#8220;subject to the provisions set out in this section&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 7, page 4, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) Nothing in this Act shall apply automatically to any person living at the time this Act is passed.</quote>
         <quote>(2B) Any person covered by subsection (2A) who wishes part or all of this Act to apply to them may opt-in to the relevant provisions by notifying the Lord Chancellor in writing.</quote>
         <quote>(2C) The provisions of this Act shall apply automatically to any person born after this Act is passed.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TREFGARNE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 10, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Baronetcies</quote>
         <IndentOne>For the avoidance of doubt, the provisions of this Act do not extend to baronetcies.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 12</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TREFGARNE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 12, page 4, line 39, leave out &#8220;the United Kingdom&#8221; and insert &#8220;England&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>