<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Financial_Services_Banking_Reform_(Bill62_I)</billtitle>
      <headertext>MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON THIRD READING</headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 8</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1:</B> Clause 8, page 24, line 23, leave out &#8220;4&#8221; and insert &#8220;2&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 8</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2:</B> After Clause 8, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;PRA review of proprietary trading</quote>
         <quote>(1) The PRA must carry out a review of proprietary trading engaged in (whether or not as a regulated activity) by relevant authorised persons, for the purpose of considering whether further restrictions on any kind of proprietary trading ought to be imposed.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The review must begin before the end of the 12 months beginning with the first day on which section 142G of FSMA 2000 is fully in force.</quote>
         <quote>(3) On completion of the review, the PRA must make a written report to the Treasury on&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the extent to which relevant authorised persons engage in proprietary trading;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) whether proprietary trading engaged in by relevant authorised persons gives rise to any risks to their safety and soundness;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) whether any kinds of proprietary trading are particularly likely to give rise to such risks;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) anything done by the PRA to minimise risks to the safety and soundness of relevant authorised persons arising from proprietary trading engaged in by them;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) any difficulties encountered by the PRA in seeking to minimise such risks.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The report must include an assessment by the PRA of each of the following&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) whether the PRA&#8217;s powers under FSMA 2000 are, and might be expected to continue to be, sufficient to enable it to advance its objectives in relation to relevant authorised persons who engage in proprietary trading;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the effectiveness of restrictions imposed in countries or territories outside the United Kingdom on proprietary trading by banks (so far as experience in those countries or territories appears to the PRA to be of relevance to the United Kingdom).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The report must be made within 9 months of the beginning of the review.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The PRA must publish the report in such manner as it thinks fit.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The functions of the PRA under this section are to be taken for the purposes of FSMA 2000 to be functions under that Act.</quote>
         <quote>(9) This section is to be read with the interpretative provisions in section (Reviews of proprietary trading: interpretation).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3:</B> After Clause 8, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Independent review of proprietary trading</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Treasury must, after receiving the report of the PRA under section (PRA review of proprietary trading) but before the end of the initial period, appoint one or more persons (&#8220;the review panel&#8221;) to carry out a review of proprietary trading engaged in (whether or not as a regulated activity) by relevant authorised persons.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The initial period is the period of 2 years beginning with the first day on which section 142G of FSMA 2000 is fully in force.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The members of the review panel must be persons&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) who appear to the Treasury to be independent of the PRA, the FCA, the Bank of England and the Treasury, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) who do not appear to the Treasury to have any financial or other interests that could reasonably be regarded as affecting their suitability to serve as members of the review panel.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In appointing the members of the review panel, the Treasury must have regard to the need to ensure that the review panel (considered as a whole) has the necessary experience to undertake the review.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Before appointing the members of the review panel, the Treasury must consult the chair of the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The reference in subsection (5) to the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the name of that Committee is changed, is a reference to that Committee by its new name, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the functions of that Committee (or substantially corresponding functions) become functions of a different Committee of the House of Commons, is to be treated as a reference to the Committee by which the functions are exercisable;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) If the review panel consists of two or more members, the Treasury must appoint one of them to be the chair of the panel.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The review panel must, within a reasonable time after the end of the initial period, make a written report to the Treasury&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) stating whether the panel agrees with the conclusions reached by the PRA in its report under section (PRA review of proprietary trading),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) stating whether the panel recommends any further restrictions on any kind of proprietary trading in relation to relevant authorised persons, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) making such other recommendations as the panel thinks fit.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) The Treasury must&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) lay a copy of the report before Parliament, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) publish the report in such manner as they think fit.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) Any expenses reasonably incurred in the conduct of the review are to be paid by the Treasury out of money provided by Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(11) This section is to be read with the interpretative provisions in section (Reviews of proprietary trading: interpretation).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>4:</B> After Clause 8, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reviews of proprietary trading: interpretation</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section has effect for the interpretation of sections (PRA review of proprietary trading) and (Independent review of proprietary trading).</quote>
         <quote>(2) A person engages in &#8220;proprietary trading&#8221; where the person trades in commodities or financial instruments as principal.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (2)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;commodity&#8221; includes any produce of agriculture, forestry or fisheries, or any mineral, either in its natural state or having undergone only such processes as are necessary or customary to prepare the produce or mineral for the market;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;financial instrument&#8221; includes anything specified in Section C of Annex I to Directive 2004/39/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 21 April 2004 on markets in financial instruments.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) &#8220;Relevant authorised person&#8221; means a PRA-authorised person which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is a UK institution,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) meets condition A or B, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is not an insurer.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Condition A is that the UK institution has permission under Part 4A of FSMA 2000 to carry on the regulated activity of accepting deposits.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Condition B is that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the institution is for the purposes of FSMA 2000 an investment firm (see section 424A of that Act),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) it has permission under Part 4A to carry on the regulated activity of dealing in investments as principal, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) when carried on by it, that activity is a PRA-regulated activity.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) In subsections (4) to (6)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;UK institution&#8221; means an institution which is incorporated in, or formed under the law of any part of, the United Kingdom;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;insurer&#8221; means an institution which is authorised under FSMA 2000 to carry on the regulated activity of effecting or carrying out contracts of insurance as principal;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) &#8220;PRA-authorised person&#8221; and &#8220;PRA-regulated activity&#8221; have the same meaning as in FSMA 2000.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) Subsections (5), (6)(b) and (7)(b) are to be read in accordance with section 22 of FSMA 2000, taken with Schedule 2 to that Act and any order under that section.&#8221; </quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>5:</B> Clause 9, page 25, line 18, at end insert &#8220;or (Independent review of proprietary trading)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 14</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>6:</B> Clause 14, page 27, line 37, leave out from &#8220;particular&#8221; to &#8220;any&#8221; in line 38 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) enable the Bank of England, for the purpose of enabling it to exercise in relation to the business of a building society any of the powers exercisable as a result of the amendments made by this Part&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) to convert the building society into a company, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) to transfer the business of the building society to a company which immediately before the transfer is owned by the Bank or by a person of a description specified in the order;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) enable the Bank of England, in connection with the exercise of a power conferred by virtue of paragraph (a), to cancel membership rights or shares in the building society;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provide for any power exercisable as a result of the amendments made by this Part to be exercisable in relation to the company&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) into which the building society is converted, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) to which the business of the building society is transferred;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(d) enable the Bank of England, in a case where it has transferred the business of a building society by virtue of paragraph (a)(ii), to dissolve the building society at any time after the transfer;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) confer functions on the Treasury, the Bank of England, the FCA, the PRA or a bail-in administrator;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) make further amendments of Part 1 of the Banking Act 2009;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) amend or modify the effect of the Building Societies Act 1986 or&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>7</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>7:</B> Clause 14, page 28, line 5, after first &#8220;section&#8221; insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;bail-in administrator&#8221; is to be read in accordance with section 12B of the Banking Act 2009 (as inserted by paragraph 2 of Schedule 2);&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>8</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>8:</B> Clause 14, page 28, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;company&#8221; means a company as defined in section 1(1) of the Companies Act 2006 which is a public company limited by shares.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 18</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>9</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>9:</B> After Clause 18, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Vetting by relevant authorised persons of candidates for approval</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 60 of FSMA 2000 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;60A Vetting of candidates by relevant authorised persons</quote>
         <quote>(1) Before a relevant authorised person may make an application for a regulator&#8217;s approval under section 59, the authorised person must be satisfied that the person in respect of whom the application is made (&#8220;the candidate&#8221;) is a fit and proper person to perform the function to which the application relates.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In deciding that question, the authorised person must have regard, in particular, to whether the candidate, or any person who may perform a function on the candidate&#8217;s behalf&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) has obtained a qualification,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) has undergone, or is undergoing, training,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) possesses a level of competence, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) has the personal characteristics,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>required by general rules made by the regulator in relation to persons performing functions of the kind to which the application relates.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) For the meaning of &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221;, see section 71A.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>10</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>10:</B> After Clause 18, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Determination of applications for approval</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 61 of FSMA 2000 (determination of applications), in subsection (2)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) omit the &#8220;or&#8221; at the end of paragraph (b), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after paragraph (c) insert &#8220;or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) has the personal characteristics,&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 20</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>11</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>11:</B> After Clause 20, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty to notify regulator of grounds for withdrawal of approval</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 63 of FSMA 2000 (withdrawal of approval), after subsection (2) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) At least once a year each relevant authorised person must, in relation to every person in relation to whom an approval has been given on the application of the authorised person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) consider whether there are any grounds on which a regulator could withdraw the approval under this section, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the authorised person is of the opinion that there are such grounds, notify the regulator of those grounds.</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(For the meaning of &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221;, see section 71A.)&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 23</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>12</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>12:</B> After Clause 23, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Certification of employees by relevant authorised persons</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 63D of FSMA 2000 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Certification of employees</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>63E Certification of employees by relevant authorised persons</quote>
         <quote>(1) A relevant authorised person (&#8220;A&#8221;) must take reasonable care to ensure that no employee of A performs a specified function under an arrangement entered into by A in relation to the carrying on by A of a regulated activity, unless the employee has a valid certificate issued by A under section 63F.</quote>
         <quote>(2) &#8220;Specified function&#8221;&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in relation to the carrying on of a regulated activity by a PRA-authorised person, means a function of a description specified in rules made by the FCA or the PRA, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to the carrying on of a regulated activity by any other authorised person, means a function of a description specified in rules made by the FCA.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The FCA may specify a description of function under subsection (2)(a) or (b) only if, in relation to the carrying on of a regulated activity by a relevant authorised person of a particular description&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the function is not a controlled function in relation to the carrying on of that activity by a relevant authorised person of that description, but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the FCA is satisfied that the function is nevertheless a significant-harm function.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The PRA may specify a description of function under subsection (2)(a) only if, in relation to the carrying on of a regulated activity by a relevant PRA-authorised person of a particular description&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the function is not a controlled function in relation to the carrying on of that activity by a relevant PRA-authorised person of that description, but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the PRA is satisfied that the function is nevertheless a significant-harm function.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) A function is a &#8220;significant-harm function&#8221;, in relation to the carrying on of a regulated activity by an authorised person, if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the function will require the person performing it to be involved in one or more aspects of the authorised person&#8217;s affairs, so far as relating to the activity, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) those aspects involve, or might involve, a risk of significant harm to the authorised person or any of its customers.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) Each regulator must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) keep under review the exercise of its power under subsection (2) to specify any significant-harm function as a specified function, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) exercise that power in a way that it considers will minimise the risk of employees of relevant authorised persons performing significant-harm functions which they are not fit and proper persons to perform.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) Subsection (1) does not apply to an arrangement which allows an employee to perform a function if the question of whether the employee is a fit and proper person to perform the function is reserved under any of the single market directives or the emission allowance auctioning regulation to an authority in a country or territory outside the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;controlled function&#8221; has the meaning given by section 59(3);</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;customer&#8221;, in relation to an authorised person, means a person who is using, or who is or may be contemplating using, any of the services provided by the authorised person;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant PRA-authorised person&#8221; means a PRA-authorised person that is a relevant authorised person.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In this section any reference to an employee of a person (&#8220;A&#8221;) includes a reference to a person who&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) personally provides, or is under an obligation personally to provide, services to A under an arrangement made between A and the person providing the services or another person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is subject to (or to the right of) supervision, direction or control by A as to the manner in which those services are provided.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) For the meaning of &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221;, see section 71A.</quote>
         <quote>63F Issuing of certificates</quote>
         <quote>(1) A relevant authorised person may issue a certificate to a person under this section only if the authorised person is satisfied that the person is a fit and proper person to perform the function to which the certificate relates.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In deciding whether the person is a fit and proper person to perform the function, the relevant authorised person must have regard, in particular, to whether the person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) has obtained a qualification,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) has undergone, or is undergoing, training,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) possesses a level of competence, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) has the personal characteristics,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>required by general rules made by the appropriate regulator in relation to employees performing functions of that kind.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (2) &#8220;the appropriate regulator&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in relation to employees of PRA-authorised persons, the FCA or the PRA, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to employees of any other authorised person, the FCA.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A certificate issued by a relevant authorised person to a person under this section must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) state that the authorised person is satisfied that the person is a fit and proper person to perform the function to which the certificate relates, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) set out the aspects of the affairs of the authorised person in which the person will be involved in performing the function.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) A certificate issued under this section is valid for a period of 12 months beginning with the day on which it is issued.</quote>
         <quote>(6) If, after having considered whether a person is a fit and proper person to perform a specified function, a relevant authorised person decides not to issue a certificate to the person under this section, the authorised person must give the person a notice in writing stating&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) what steps (if any) the authorised person proposes to take in relation to the person as a result of the decision, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the reasons for proposing to take those steps.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) A relevant authorised person must maintain a record of every employee who has a valid certificate issued by it under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Expressions used in this section and in section 63E have the same meaning in this section as they have in that section.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 24</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>13</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>13:</B> Clause 24, page 37, line 45, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;64B Rules of conduct: responsibilities of relevant authorised persons</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where a regulator makes rules under section 64A (&#8220;conduct rules&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(2) Every relevant authorised person must&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) notify all relevant persons of the conduct rules that apply in relation to them, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) take all reasonable steps to secure that those persons understand how those rules apply in relation to them.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The steps which a relevant authorised person must take to comply with subsection (2)(b) include, in particular, the provision of suitable training.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In this section &#8220;relevant person&#8221;, in relation to an authorised person, means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any person in relation to whom an approval is given under section 59 on the application of the authorised person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any employee of the authorised person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) If a relevant authorised person knows or suspects that a relevant person has failed to comply with any conduct rules, the authorised person must notify the regulator of that fact.</quote>
         <quote>(6) In this section &#8220;employee&#8221;, in relation to an authorised person, has the same meaning as in section 64A.</quote>
         <quote>(7) For the meaning of &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221;, see section 71A.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 24</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>14</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>14:</B> After Clause 24, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Requirement to notify regulator of disciplinary action</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 64B of FSMA 2000 (inserted by section  above) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>24<quote>&#8220;64C Requirement for relevant authorised persons to notify regulator of disciplinary action</quote>
         <quote>(1) If&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a relevant authorised person takes disciplinary action in relation to a relevant person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the reason, or one of the reasons, for taking that action is a reason specified in rules made by the appropriate regulator for the purposes of this section,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>the relevant authorised person must notify that regulator of that fact.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) &#8220;Disciplinary action&#8221;, in relation to a person, means any of the following&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the issuing of a formal written warning;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the suspension or dismissal of the person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the reduction or recovery of any of the person&#8217;s remuneration.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) &#8220;The appropriate regulator&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in relation to relevant authorised persons that are PRA-authorised persons, the FCA or the PRA;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to any other relevant authorised persons, the FCA.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) &#8220;Relevant person&#8221; has the same meaning as in section 64B.</quote>
         <quote>(5) For the meaning of &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221;, see section 71A.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 25</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>15</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>15:</B> Clause 25, page 39, line 38, leave out &#8220;authorised&#8221; and insert &#8220;PRA-authorised&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>16</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>16:</B> Clause 25, page 40, line 11, leave out &#8220;authorised&#8221; and insert &#8220;PRA-authorised&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 26</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>17</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>17:</B> Clause 26, page 41, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) The Treasury may by order provide that authorised persons falling within any of the following descriptions are &#8220;relevant authorised persons&#8221; for the purposes of this Part&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) non-UK institutions (or non-UK institutions of a specified description) that are credit institutions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) non-UK institutions that are investment firms of a specified description.</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;Specified&#8221; means specified in the order.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3B) If the Treasury propose to make an order under subsection (3A) they must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the FCA,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the PRA,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any organisations that appear to them to be representative of interests substantially affected by the proposals, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) any other persons that they consider appropriate.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>18</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>18:</B> Clause 26, page 41, line 12, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) &#8220;non-UK institution&#8221; means an institution that is not a UK institution;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>( ) &#8220;credit institution&#8221; means any credit institution as defined in Article 4.1(1) of Regulation (EU) No 575/2013 of the European Parliament and of the Council;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 28</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WATSON OF INVERGOWRIE</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD BRENNAN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>19&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>19&#042;:</B> After Clause 28, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Obligations relating to anti-money laundering compliance: review</quote>
         <IndentOne>Within two weeks of the passing of this Act, the Chancellor of the Exchequer shall make a Written Statement to the House of Commons stating whether the provisions of this Act bind the Financial Conduct Authority to include anti-money laundering compliance as one of the obligations covered under the new personal responsibility mechanisms created by the material the Act inserts into FSMA 2000 including, but not limited to, the senior management functions, Banking Standard Rules and Senior Persons Regime.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 123</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>20</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>20:</B> After Clause 123, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty of FCA to make rules restricting charges for high-cost short-term credit</quote>
         <quote>(1) In section 137C of FSMA 2000 (FCA general rules: cost of credit and duration of credit agreements), after subsection (1) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) The FCA must make rules by virtue of subsection (1)(a)(ii) and (b) in relation to one or more specified descriptions of regulated credit agreement appearing to the FCA to involve the provision of high-cost short-term credit, with a view to securing an appropriate degree of protection for borrowers against excessive charges.</quote>
         <quote>(1B) Before the FCA publishes a draft of any rules to be made by virtue of subsection (1)(a)(ii) or (b), it must consult the Treasury.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) In Schedule 1ZA to FSMA 2000, in paragraph 11 (FCA&#8217;s annual report), in sub-paragraph (1), after paragraph (h) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(ha) any rules that it has made as a result of section 137C during the period to which the report relates and the kinds of regulated credit agreement (within the meaning of that section) to which the rules apply,&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The FCA must ensure any rules that it is required to make as a result of the amendment made by subsection (1) are made not later than 2 January 2015 and apply (at least) to agreements entered into on or after that date.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[Amendments 21 and 22 are amendments to Amendment 20]</clausetext>
   <proposer>LORD SHARKEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>21&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>21&#042;:</B> After Clause 123, line 9, at end insert &#8220;, and to preventing multiply sourced simultaneous loans and rollovers&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD EATWELL</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD MITCHELL</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS GREY-THOMPSON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>22&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>22&#042;:</B> After Clause 123, line 19, leave out &#8220;2 January 2015&#8221; and insert &#8220;1 October 2014&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>23</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>23:</B> After Clause 123, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Role of FCA Consumer Panel in relation to PRA</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 1Q of FSMA 2000 (the Consumer Panel), after subsection (5) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(5A) If it appears to the Consumer Panel that any matter being considered by it is relevant to the extent to which the general policies and practices of the PRA are consistent with the PRA&#8217;s general duties under sections 2B to 2H, it may communicate to the PRA any views relating to that matter.</quote>
         <quote>(5B) The PRA may arrange to meet any of the FCA&#8217;s expenditure on the Consumer Panel which is attributable to the Panel&#8217;s functions under subsection (5A).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 124</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>24</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>24:</B> After Clause 124, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty to meet auditors of certain institutions</quote>
         <quote>(1) Part 22 of FSMA 2000 (auditors and actuaries) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 339A insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;339B Duty to meet auditors of certain institutions</quote>
         <quote>(1) The FCA must make arrangements for meetings to take place at least once a year between&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the FCA, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the auditor of any PRA-authorised person to which section 339C applies.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The PRA must make arrangements for meetings to take place at least once a year between&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the PRA, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the auditor of any PRA-authorised person to which section 339C applies.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The annual report of each regulator must include the number of meetings that have taken place during the period to which the report relates between the regulator and auditors of PRA-authorised persons to which section 339C applies.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (3) &#8220;the annual report&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in relation to the FCA, every report which it is required by paragraph 11 of Schedule 1ZA to make to the Treasury, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to the PRA, every report which it is required by paragraph 19 of Schedule 1ZB to make to the Treasury.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section &#8220;auditor&#8221; means an auditor appointed under or as a result of a statutory provision.</quote>
         <quote>339C PRA-authorised persons to which this section applies</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies to a PRA-authorised person which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is a UK institution,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) meets condition A or B,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is not an insurer or a credit union, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) is, in the opinion of the PRA, important to the stability of the UK financial system.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Condition A is that the person has permission under Part 4A to carry on the regulated activity of accepting deposits.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Condition B is that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the person is an investment firm that has permission under Part 4A to carry on the regulated activity of dealing in investments as principal, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) when carried on by the person, that activity is a PRA-regulated activity.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;UK institution&#8221; means an institution which is incorporated in, or formed under the law of any part of, the United Kingdom;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;insurer&#8221; means an institution which is authorised under this Act to carry on the regulated activity of effecting or carrying out contracts of insurance as principal;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) &#8220;credit union&#8221; means a credit union as defined by section 31 of the Credit Unions Act 1979 or a credit union as defined by Article 2(2) of the Credit Unions (Northern Ireland) Order 1985.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Subsections (2), (3) and (4)(b) are to be read in accordance with Schedule 2, taken together with any order under section 22.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) The italic cross-heading before section 339A becomes &#8220;General duties of regulator&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 126</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>25</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>25:</B> Clause 126, page 99, line 5, after &#8220;procedure)&#8221; insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) after &#8220;55C,&#8221; insert &#8220;71A(3A),&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 129</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAYTER OF KENTISH TOWN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>26</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>26:</B> After Clause 129, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Recovery of expenditure incurred by Office for Legal Complaints</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Schedule to the Compensation Act 2006 (claims management regulations) is amended as set out in subsections (2) and (3).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The provision in paragraph 7 becomes sub-paragraph (1) of that paragraph.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In paragraph 7, after sub-paragraph (1) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) The fees that may be charged by the Regulator by virtue of sub-paragraph (1) include fees in respect of costs incurred by the Regulator for the purposes of meeting any leviable OLC expenditure.&#8220;Leviable OLC expenditure&#8221; has the meaning given by section 173(7) of the Legal Services Act 2007.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Legal Services Act 2007 is amended as set out in subsections (5) and (6).</quote>
         <quote>(5) After section 174 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;OLC expenditure relating to claims management services</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>174A OLC expenditure relating to claims management services</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section has effect at any time when no person is designated under section 5(1) of the Compensation Act 2006 (the Regulator in relation to claims management services).</quote>
         <quote>(2) In determining the leviable OLC expenditure for the purposes of section 173, any expenditure incurred, or income received, by the OLC in connection with the exercise of its functions in relation to claims management services is to be disregarded.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Lord Chancellor may by regulations charge periodic fees for authorised persons for the purposes of meeting any costs incurred by the Lord Chancellor in respect of relevant OLC expenditure.</quote>
         <quote>(4) &#8220;Relevant OLC expenditure&#8221; means the difference between&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any expenditure of the OLC incurred in connection with the exercise of its functions in relation to claims management services, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the aggregate of the amounts which the OLC pays into the Consolidated Fund under section 175(1)(g), (h) or (n), so far as relating to the exercise of its functions in relation to such services.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Regulations made under subsection (3) may, in particular&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) permit the charging of different fees for different cases or circumstances (which may, in particular, be defined wholly or partly by reference to turnover or other criteria relating to an authorised person&#8217;s business);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) enable the person exercising functions of the Regulator under section 5(9) of the Compensation Act 2006 to collect fees on behalf of the Lord Chancellor;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) specify the consequences of failure to pay fees (which may include anything which could be specified in regulations under section 9 of that Act as a consequence of a failure to pay fees charged under those regulations).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In this section &#8220;authorised person&#8221; and &#8220;claims management services&#8221; have the same meaning as in Part 2 of the Compensation Act 2006 (see section 4 of that Act).&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(6) In section 206 (Parliamentary control of orders and regulations), in subsection (4), after paragraph (o) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(oa) section 174A(3) (power to charge fees on persons providing claims management services);&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 131</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>27</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>27:</B> Clause 131, page 102, line 11, leave out &#8220;or the Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;, the Secretary of State or the Lord Chancellor&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>28</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>28:</B> Clause 131, page 102, line 15, leave out &#8220;or Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;, the Secretary of State or the Lord Chancellor&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>29</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>29:</B> Clause 131, page 102, line 18, leave out &#8220;Treasury or Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;person making the order or regulations&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 134</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>30</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>30:</B> Clause 134, page 103, line 19, leave out &#8220;or Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;, the Secretary of State or the Lord Chancellor&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>31</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>31:</B> Clause 134, page 103, line 21, leave out &#8220;Treasury or Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;person making the order&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 135</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>32</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>32:</B> Clause 135, page 103, line 31, leave out &#8220;or Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;, the Secretary of State or the Lord Chancellor&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>33</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>33:</B> Clause 135, page 103, line 32, leave out &#8220;Treasury or Secretary of State&#8221; and insert &#8220;person making the order&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 136</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>34</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>34:</B> Clause 136, page 103, line 41, leave out from &#8220;Ireland&#8221; to end of line 2 on page 104 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;This is subject to subsection (2).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The amendments made by the following sections have the same extent as the enactments amended&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 10 (preferential debts: Great Britain),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section 129 (power to impose penalties on persons providing claims management services), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) section (Recovery of expenditure incurred by Office for Legal Complaints) (recovery of expenditure incurred by Office for Legal Complaints).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 137</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>35</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>35:</B> Clause 137, page 104, line 5, at beginning insert &#8220;The following provisions&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>section (Duty of FCA to make rules restricting charges for high-cost short-term credit), and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>36</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>36:</B> Clause 137, page 104, line 8, leave out &#8220;Section 129 comes&#8221; and insert &#8220;Sections 129 and (Recovery of expenditure incurred by Office for Legal Complaints)(1) to (3) come&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>37</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>37:</B> Clause 137, page 104, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Section (Recovery of expenditure incurred by Office for Legal Complaints)(4) to (6) comes into force on such day as the Lord Chancellor may by order appoint.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 2</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>38</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>38:</B> Schedule 2, page 121, line 25, leave out from first &#8220;instrument&#8221; to &#8220;may&#8221; in line 26</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>39</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>39:</B> Schedule 2, page 125, line 39, after &#8220;41A(2)&#8221; insert &#8220;, or an associated supplemental property transfer instrument,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>40</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>40:</B> Schedule 2, page 125, line 41, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The reference in subsection (1) to an &#8220;associated&#8221; supplemental property transfer instrument is to a supplemental property transfer instrument in relation to which the original instrument (as defined in section 42(1)) is a property transfer instrument under section 12(2) or 41A(2).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>41</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>41:</B> Schedule 2, page 125, line 42, after &#8220;12(2),&#8221; insert &#8220;or a supplemental property transfer instrument in relation to which the original instrument is a property transfer instrument under section 12(2),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>42</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>42:</B> Schedule 2, page 126, line 42, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In section 52 (transfer to bridge bank), in subsection (3)(b), for &#8220;specified classes of creditor,&#8221; substitute &#8220;persons of a specified description,&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>43</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>43:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, line 4, at end insert &#8220;or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>44</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>44:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, line 5, leave out from &#8220;41A(2)&#8221; to end of line 6</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>45</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>45:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) before paragraph (za) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(zza) the Bank of England makes a supplemental share transfer instrument under section 26,&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>( ) after paragraph (za) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(zb) the Treasury makes a supplemental share transfer order under section 27,&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>( ) after paragraph (d) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(dza) the Bank of England makes a supplemental property transfer instrument under section 42,&#8221;;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, leave out lines 18 and 19</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>47</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>47:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;&#8220;( ) the Bank of England makes a supplemental resolution instrument under section 48U,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>48</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>48:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, line 23, at end insert &#8220;or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>49</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>49:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, line 25, leave out from &#8220;(3)&#8221; to end of line 27</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>50</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>50:</B> Schedule 2, page 127, line 27, at the end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in the heading, after &#8220;transfers&#8221; insert &#8220;etc&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51:</B> Schedule 2, page 128, line 4, after &#8220;require&#8221; insert &#8220;a resolution fund order,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>52</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>52:</B> Schedule 2, page 128, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) to depend in part upon the amounts which are or may be payable under a resolution fund order;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>53</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>53:</B> Schedule 2, page 134, line 32, leave out &#8220;that provides for a transfer of securities&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>54</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>54:</B> Schedule 2, page 134, line 33, leave out from &#8220;instrument&#8221; to end of line 35 and insert &#8220;; and in relation to a resolution instrument references in this section to a &#8220;transfer&#8221; are to a transfer of securities (whether made by that or another resolution instrument) and &#8220;transferor&#8221; and &#8220;transferee&#8221; are to be read accordingly.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55:</B> Schedule 2, page 134, line 36, leave out paragraph 16</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>In the Title</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEIGHTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56:</B>In the Title, line 7, leave out &#8220;for penalties to be imposed on&#8221; and insert &#8220;in relation to&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>