<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Immigration_(Bill84(d))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 2, line 16, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) paragraph 18B (detention of unaccompanied children);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH </proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Restriction on removal of children and their parents etc</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 78 of the Nationality, Immigration and Asylum Act 2002, insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;78A Restriction on removal of children and their parents etc</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies in a case where&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a child is to be removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an individual who&#8212;is also to be removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom (a &#8220;relevant parent or carer&#8221;).</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) is a parent of the child or has care of the child, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) is living in a household in the United Kingdom with the child,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>is also to be removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom (a &#8220;relevant parent or carer&#8221;).</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(2) During the period of 28 days beginning with the day on which the relevant appeal rights are exhausted&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the child may not be removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a relevant parent or carer may not be removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom if, as a result, no relevant parent or carer would remain in the United Kingdom.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The relevant appeal rights are exhausted at the time when&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) neither the child, nor any relevant parent or carer, could bring an appeal under section 82 (ignoring any possibility of an appeal out of time with permission), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) no appeal brought by the child, or by any relevant parent or carer, is pending within the meaning of section 104.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Nothing in this section prevents any of the following during the period of 28 days mentioned in subsection (2)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the giving of a direction for the removal of a person from the United Kingdom,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the making of a deportation order in respect of a person, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the taking of any other interim or preparatory action.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;child&#8221; means a person who is aged under 18;</quote>
         <quote>references to a person being removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom are to the person being removed or required to leave in accordance with a provision of the Immigration Acts.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Independent Family Returns Panel</quote>
         <IndentOne>Before section 55 of the Borders, Citizenship and Immigration Act 2009, insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;54A Independent Family Returns Panel</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Independent Family Returns Panel is established.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State must consult the Independent Family Returns Panel&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in each family returns case, on how best to safeguard and promote the welfare of the children of the family, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in each case where the Secretary of State proposes to detain a family in pre-departure accommodation, on the suitability of so doing, having particular regard to the need to safeguard and promote the welfare of the children of the family. </IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) A family returns case is a case where&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a child is to be removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an individual who&#8212;is also to be removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom (a &#8220;relevant parent or carer&#8221;); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) is a parent of the child or has care of the child, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) is living in a household in the United Kingdom with the child,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(c) the child and the relevant parent or carer have entered the United Kingdom within the meaning of section 11 of the Immigration Act 1971.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State may by regulations make provision about&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) additional functions of the Independent Family Returns Panel,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) its status and constitution,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the appointment of its members,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the payment of remuneration and allowances to its members, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) any other matters in connection with its establishment and operation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Regulations under this section must be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(6) An instrument containing regulations under this section is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote> &#8220;child&#8221; means a person who is under the age of 18;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;pre-departure accommodation&#8221; has the same meaning as in Part 8 of the Immigration and Asylum Act 1999;</quote>
         <quote>references to a person being removed from or required to leave the United Kingdom are to the person being removed or required to leave in accordance with a provision of the Immigration Acts.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH </proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 3, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Restrictions on detention of unaccompanied children</quote>
         <quote>(1) Schedule 2 to the Immigration Act 1971 (administrative provisions as to control on entry etc) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In paragraph 16, after paragraph (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) But the detention of an unaccompanied child under sub-paragraph (2) is subject to paragraph 18B.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) In paragraph 18, after sub-paragraph (1) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) But the detention of an unaccompanied child under paragraph 16(2) is subject to paragraph 18B.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(4) After paragraph 18A (as inserted by paragraph 2 of Schedule 1) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;18B (1) Where a person detained under paragraph 16(2) is an unaccompanied child, the only place where the child may be detained is a short-term holding facility, except where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the child is being transferred to or from a short-term holding facility, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) sub-paragraph (3) of paragraph 18 applies.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) An unaccompanied child may be detained under paragraph 16(2) in a short-term holding facility for a maximum period of 24 hours, and only for so long as the following two conditions are met.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The first condition is that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) directions are in force that require the child to be removed from the short-term holding facility within the relevant 24 hour period, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a decision on whether or not to give directions is likely to result in such directions.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The second condition is that the immigration officer under whose authority the child is being detained reasonably believes that the child will be removed from the short-term holding facility within the relevant 24 hour period in accordance with those directions.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An unaccompanied child detained under paragraph 16(2) who has been removed from a short-term holding facility and detained elsewhere may be detained again in a short-term holding facility but only if, and for as long as, the relevant 24 hour period has not ended.</quote>
         <quote>(6) An unaccompanied child who has been released following detention under paragraph 16(2) may be detained again in a short-term holding facility in accordance with this paragraph.</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) In this paragraph&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;relevant 24 hour period&#8221;, in relation to the detention of a child in a short-term holding facility, means the period of 24 hours starting when the child was detained (or, in a case falling within sub-paragraph (5), first detained) in a short-term holding facility;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;short-term holding facility&#8221; has the same meaning as in Part 8 of the Immigration and Asylum Act 1999;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;unaccompanied child&#8221; means a person&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(a) who is under the age of 18, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(b) who is not accompanied (whilst in detention) by his or her parent or another individual who has care of him or her.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 3, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Pre-departure accommodation for families</quote>
         <quote>(1) Part 8 of the Immigration and Asylum Act 1999 (removal centres and detained persons) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 147 (interpretation)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) after the definition of &#8220;custodial functions&#8221; insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;detained children&#8221; means detained persons who are under the age of 18;&#8221;;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(b) after the definition of &#8220;escort monitor&#8221; insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;pre-departure accommodation&#8221; means a place used solely for the detention of detained children and their families for a period of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) not more than 72 hours, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) not more than seven days in cases where the longer period of detention is authorised personally by a Minister of the Crown (within the meaning of the Ministers of the Crown Act 1975);&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in the definition of &#8220;removal centre&#8221;, after &#8220;facility,&#8221; insert &#8220;pre-departure accommodation,&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) in the definition of &#8220;short-term holding facility&#8221;, at the end insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;but which is not pre-departure accommodation.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 155 (custodial functions and discipline), in subsection (2), at the end insert &#8220;and in pre-departure accommodation&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) After section 157 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;157A Pre-departure accommodation</quote>
         <quote>(1) The following provisions of this Part apply to pre-departure accommodation as they apply to removal centres&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 149 (contracting out of certain removal centres);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section 150 (contracting out functions at directly managed removal centres);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) section 151 (intervention by Secretary of State).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In the application of those provisions to pre-departure accommodation&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) references to a removal centre contract are to be read as a contract made under section 149(1) for the provision or running of pre-departure accommodation;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) references to a contracted out removal centre are to be read as references to pre-departure accommodation in relation to which a contract under section 149(1) is in force;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) references to a directly managed removal centre are to be read as references to pre-departure accommodation in relation to which there is no contract under section 149(1) in force;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) references to removal centre rules are to be read as references to rules made under subsection (4).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The Secretary of State may by regulations extend to pre-departure accommodation any other provision made by or under this Part in relation to removal centres.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State may make rules for the regulation and management of pre-departure accommodation.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 14</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD PANNICK</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 14, page 13, leave out lines 5 to 11</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 14, page 13, leave out lines 23 to 39</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 14, page 13, line 40, leave out &#8220;(6)&#8221; and insert &#8220;(2)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 14, page 14, leave out lines 32 to 48</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 33</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS MEACHER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 33, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Domestic abuse and female genital mutilation</quote>
         <IndentOne>No charge may be imposed for health services&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) relating to injuries sustained as a result of domestic abuse as defined in Home Office Circular 003/2013 &#8220;New government domestic violence and abuse definition&#8221;, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) relating to injuries sustained as a result of female genital mutilation as defined in the Female Genital Mutilation Act 2003.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 34</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS CUMBERLEGE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 34, page 28, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) Notwithstanding subsection (1), any pregnant woman shall be treated as ordinarily resident.</quote>
         <quote>(1B) However, subsection (1A) shall not apply where there is evidence the woman has entered the UK for the purpose of obtaining health care.</quote>
         <quote>(1C) The Secretary of State shall provide guidance to relevant NHS bodies as to the identification of persons to whom subsection (1B) applies; and the relevant NHS bodies shall be required to comply with that guidance.</quote>
         <quote>(1D) Subject to the guidance provided under (1C), it shall be a matter for the discretion of the relevant NHS bodies to determine whether there is &#8220;evidence&#8221; within the meaning of subsection (1B).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 34</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS MEACHER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 34, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Guidance</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must provide information outlining details of the charges for health services applicable to any individual&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the point of their application for immigration permission as defined in section 33, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) upon request.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 9, page 103 , line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Special Immigration Appeals Commission Act 1997 (c. 68)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In section 2 of the Special Immigration Appeals Commission Act 1997 (jurisdiction: appeals), in subsection (2), after paragraph (c) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(ca) section 78A of that Act (restriction on removal of children and their parents),&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 9, page 104 , line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Prison Act 1952 (c. 52)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>(1) Section 5A of the Prison Act 1952 (appointment and functions of Her Majesty&#8217;s Chief Inspector of Prisons) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (5A)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) omit &#8220;and&#8221; at the end of paragraph (b);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after paragraph (b) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(ba) in relation to pre-departure accommodation within the meaning of that section, and&#8221;.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (5B)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), after &#8220;facilities&#8221; insert &#8220;, accommodation&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (b)(i), after &#8220;facilities&#8221; insert &#8220;, pre-departure accommodation&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 9, page 104 , line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Immigration Act 1971 (c. 77)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In Schedule 3 to the Immigration Act 1971 (supplementary provisions as to deportation), in paragraph 3, for &#8220;33&#8221; substitute &#8220;33A&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 9, page 104 , line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Northern Ireland Act 1998 (c. 47)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In section 69C of the Northern Ireland Act 1998 (investigations: places of detention), in subsection (3)(g), for &#8220;or short-term holding facility&#8221; substitute &#8220;, a short-term holding facility or pre-departure accommodation&#8221;.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Immigration and Asylum Act 1999 (c. 33)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>(1) The Immigration and Asylum Act 1999 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In Schedule 11 (detainee custody officers)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the heading above paragraph 3, at the end insert &#8220;and pre-departure accommodation&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph 3&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) in sub-paragraph (1), after &#8220;facility&#8221; insert &#8220;or in pre-departure accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) in sub-paragraph (2), after &#8220;facility&#8221; (in both places) insert &#8220;or accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(c) in paragraph 4(c), after &#8220;facility&#8221; insert &#8220;or in pre-departure accommodation&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) in paragraph 5(c), after &#8220;facility&#8221; insert &#8220;or in pre-departure accommodation&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In Schedule 12 (discipline etc at removal centres)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph 4 (assisting detained persons to escape)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) in sub-paragraph (1), for &#8220;or short-term holding facility&#8221; substitute &#8220;, a short-term holding facility or pre-departure accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) in the opening words of sub-paragraph (2), for &#8220;or short-term holding facility&#8221; substitute &#8220;, a short-term holding facility or pre-departure accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) in sub-paragraph (2)(a), for &#8220;or facility&#8221; substitute &#8220;, facility or accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iv) in sub-paragraph (2)(b), for &#8220;or facility&#8221; substitute &#8220;, facility or accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(v) in sub-paragraph (2)(c), for &#8220;or facility&#8221; substitute &#8220;, facility or accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph 8 (notice of penalties)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) in sub-paragraph (1), after &#8220;facility&#8221; insert &#8220;or contracted out pre-departure accommodation&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) in sub-paragraph (2), after &#8220;facility&#8221; insert &#8220;or pre-departure accommodation&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 9, page 104 , line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Nationality, Immigration and Asylum Act 2002 (c. 41)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In section 62 of the Nationality, Immigration and Asylum Act 2002 (detention by Secretary of State), in subsection (3), after paragraph (a) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(aa) a reference in paragraph 18B of that Schedule to an immigration officer shall be read as a reference to the Secretary of State,&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 9, page 104 , line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Safeguarding Vulnerable Groups Act 2006 (c. 47)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In section 59 of the Safeguarding Vulnerable Groups Act 2006 (vulnerable adults), in subsection (7)(d), after &#8220;facility&#8221; insert &#8220;or in pre-departure accommodation&#8221;.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Corporate Manslaughter and Corporate Homicide Act 2007 (c. 19)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In section 2 of the Corporate Manslaughter and Corporate Homicide Act 2007 (meaning of &#8220;relevant duty of care&#8221;)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in subsection (2)(b), for &#8220;or short-term holding facility&#8221; substitute &#8220;, a short-term holding facility or in pre-departure accommodation&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in subsection (7), for &#8220;and &#8220;short-term holding facility&#8221;&#8221; substitute &#8220;, &#8220;short-term holding facility&#8221; and &#8220;pre-departure accommodation&#8221;&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>UK Borders Act 2007 (c. 30)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>In section 48 of the UK Borders Act 2007 (establishment of border and immigration inspectorate), in subsection (2A)(a), after &#8220;facilities&#8221; insert &#8220;and in pre-departure accommodation&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>