<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Intellectual_Property_(HLBill5_I)</billtitle>
      <headertext>MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1&#042;:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 5, leave out subsection (1) to (4) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) In section 213(1) of the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 (unregistered design right: nature of design right), for &#8220;an original design&#8221; substitute &#8220;a design which is new and has individual character&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 213(2) of that Act for &#8220;the design of any aspect of the shape or configuration (whether internal or external) of the whole or part of an article&#8221; substitute &#8220;the appearance of the whole or a part of a product resulting from the features of, in particular, the lines, contours, colours, shape, texture and/or materials of the product itself or its ornamentation, or both&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 213(3) of that Act, for paragraphs (a) to (c) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) features of appearance of a product which are solely dictated by its technical function;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) features of appearance of a product which must necessarily be reproduced in their exact form and dimensions in order to permit the product in which the design is incorporated or to which it is applied to be mechanically connected to or placed in, around or against another product so that either product may perform its function;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a design which is contrary to public policy or to accepted principles of morality.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) For section 213(4) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) In determining whether a design is new and has individual character, the definitions contained in Articles 3, 4(2), 5(1)(a), 5(2), 6 and 7 of the Community Design Regulation, Regulation 6/2002 of 12 December 2001 (as amended), shall be applied.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(5) In section 51(3) of that Act (design documents and models), for the definition of &#8220;design&#8221; substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;design&#8221; has the meaning conferred on it by section 213(2);&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2&#042;:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 12, leave out paragraph (b) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(b) at the end insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In this section &#8220;qualifying country&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the United Kingdom; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) another member state of the European Economic Area.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 2</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3&#042;:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 31, at end insert &#8220;, or within a period of six months following commencement&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>4&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>4&#042;:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 31, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) For section 259 of the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 (joint designs) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Joint designs</quote>
         <quote>(1) Where two or more persons have jointly developed a design, design right shall vest in them jointly.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Where two or more persons are proprietors of unregistered design right or community unregistered design right, then, subject to the provisions of this section and subject to any agreement to the contrary&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) each of them shall be entitled, by himself or his agents, to do in respect of the design concerned, for his own benefit and without the consent of or the need to account to the other or others, any act which would apart from this subsection, amount to an infringement of the design right concerned; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any such act shall not amount to an infringement of the design right or unregistered community design right concerned.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Subject to any agreement for the time being in force, where two or more persons are proprietors of design right or unregistered community design right one of them shall not without the consent of the other or others grant a licence under the design right or assign or mortgage a share in the design right or in Scotland cause or permit security to be granted over it.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Where an article is disposed of by any of two or more proprietors of unregistered design right to any person, that person and any other person claiming through him shall be entitled to deal with the article in the same way as if it had been disposed of by a sole proprietor.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>5&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>5&#042;:</B> Clause 3, page 2, leave out lines 42 to 44 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(b) a person who has in any qualifying country a real and effective industrial or commercial establishment&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 5</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>6&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>6&#042;:</B> Clause 5, page 4, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In subsection (1), after paragraph (a) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(aa) in pursuance of an assignment or licence made or granted by a person who is the proprietor of unregistered design right or unregistered Community design right in a corresponding unregistered design or unregistered Community Design.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 5</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>7&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>7&#042;:</B> After Clause 5, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Infringement</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 226 of the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 (primary infringements of design right), for subsections (1) to (4) substitute&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) The owner of design right in a design has the exclusive right to reproduce the design and use reproductions of the design, in particular, the making, offering, putting on the market, importing, exporting or using of a product in which the design is incorporated or to which it is applied, or stocking such a product for those purposes.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For these purposes, reproducing the design means copying the design in a way which does not produce on the informed user a different overall impression.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In assessing the scope of protection, the degree of freedom of the designer in developing his design shall be taken into consideration.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 6</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>8&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>8&#042;:</B> Clause 6, page 4, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) Where a registered design or community registered design is granted to two or more persons, each of them shall, subject to any agreement to the contrary, be entitled to an equal undivided share in the design.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Where two or more persons are proprietors of a registered design, then, subject to the provisions of this section and subject to any agreement to the contrary&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) each of them shall be entitled, by himself or his agents, to do in respect of the design concerned, for his own benefit and without the consent of or the need to account to the other or others, any act which would apart from this subsection, amount to an infringement of the patent concerned; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any such act shall not amount to an infringement of the registered design concerned.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Subject to any agreement for the time being in force, where two or more persons are proprietors of a registered design one of them shall not without the consent of the other or others grant a licence under the registered design or assign or mortgage a share in the registered design or in Scotland cause or permit security to be granted over it.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Where a product falling within the scope of a registered design is disposed of by any of two or more proprietors of that design to any person, that person and any other person claiming through him shall be entitled to deal with the product in the same way as if it had been disposed of by a sole registered proprietor.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Nothing in subsection (3) or (4) above shall affect the mutual rights or obligations of trustees or of the personal representatives of a deceased person, or their rights or obligations as such.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>9&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>9&#042;:</B> Clause 6, page 4, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) This section does not apply to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any design created before the commencement of this section,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any design created after the commencement of this section in pursuance of a commission (irrespective of whether the design was commissioned before or after that commencement) provided that&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the designer and the commissioner of the design have entered into a contract relating to the commission of the design;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the contract was entered into before that commencement or within a period of six months following commencement.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 8</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>10&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>10&#042;:</B> Clause 8, page 5, line 35, leave out subsection (3)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>11&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>11&#042;:</B> Clause 8, page 5, line 41, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The first order under this section must be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>( ) A statutory instrument containing an order under this section may not be made unless a draft of the order has been laid before, and approved by resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>12&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>12&#042;:</B> Clause 8, page 5, line 42, leave out subsection (2) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) An order under this section may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>13&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>13&#042;:</B> Clause 8, page 6, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State will, within six months of the Act coming into force, report to both Houses of Parliament on plans to publicise changes to the law introduced under this provision and help educate holders of design rights.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>14&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>14&#042;:</B> Clause 9, page 6, leave out lines 20 to 25</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>15&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>15&#042;:</B> Clause 9, page 6, line 27, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The registrar may give directions specifying that Design Form DF12A shall include a statement indicating whether or not any associated unregistered design right has been assigned to the same assignee.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>16&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>16&#042;:</B> Clause 10, page 7, line 15, at end insert &#8220;or the Patents County Court&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 11</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>17&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>17&#042;:</B> Clause 11, page 9, leave out lines 30 to 33</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>18&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>18&#042;:</B> Clause 11, page 9, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) Regulations made under this section must be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A statutory instrument containing the first regulations under this section may not be made unless a draft of the regulations has been laid before, and approved by resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A statutory instrument containing other regulations under this section is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>19&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>19&#042;:</B> Clause 11, page 10, line 11, leave out subsection (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) An order under this section may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>20&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>20&#042;:</B> Clause 11, page 10, line 17, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A court shall take into account when awarding costs and damages whether either party, claimant or defendant in a dispute, has chosen to ignore the opinion given by the registrar.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 12</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD YOUNG OF NORWOOD GREEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>21&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>21&#042;:</B> Clause 12, page 11, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The registrar will ensure that, where possible, the use of online tools and digital platforms is encouraged.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>22&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>22&#042;:</B> Clause 12, page 11, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The registrar may give directions specifying that in Design Form DF2C the words &#8220;within one year&#8221; will be replaced with the words &#8220;within 30 months&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 13</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>23&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>23&#042;:</B> Clause 13, page 15, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;35ZE Offences committed by partnerships and body corporate</quote>
         <quote>(1) Proceedings for an offence under this Act alleged to have been committed by a partnership shall be brought against the partnership in the name of the firm and not in that of the partners; but without prejudice to any liability of the partners under subsection (4).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The following provisions apply for the purposes of such proceedings as in relation to a body corporate.</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any rules of court relating to the service of documents;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in England and Wales or Northern Ireland, Schedule 3 to the Magistrates&#8217; Court Act 1980 or Schedule 4 to the Magistrates&#8217; Courts (Northern Ireland) Order 1981 (procedure on charge of offence).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) A fine imposed on a partnership on its conviction in such proceedings shall be paid out of the partnership assets.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Where a partnership is guilty of an offence under this Act, every partner, other than a partner who is proved to have been ignorant of or to have attempted to prevent the commission of the offence, is also guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Where an offence under this Act committed by a body corporate is proved to have been committed with the consent, connivance or neglect of a director, manager, secretary or other similar office of the body, or a person purporting to act in any such capacity, he as well as the body corporate is guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 13</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>24&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>24&#042;:</B> After Clause 13, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Offence of unauthorised copying etc of a design protected by design right</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 235 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;235A Offence of unauthorised copying etc of a design protected by design right</quote>
         <quote>(1) A person commits an offence if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the course of a business, the person copies any design protected by design right so as to make a product exactly or substantially to that design, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the person does so&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) knowing or having reason to believe, that the design is protected by design right, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) without the consent of the owner of that design right.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(2) Subsection (3) applies in relation to a product where a design protected by design right has been copied so as to make the product exactly or substantially to the design.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A person commits an offence if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the course of a business, the person offers, puts on the market, imports, exports or uses the product, or stocks it for one or more of those purposes,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the person does so without the consent of the owner of the design right in that design, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the person does so knowing or having reason to believe, that a design has been copied without the consent of the owner of the design right in the design.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In this section &#8220;design right&#8221; includes an unregistered community design and a reference to the owner of the design right is also to be read as a reference to the owner of a community design right in a design.</quote>
         <quote>(5) A person guilty of an offence under this section is liable&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) on conviction on indictment, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding ten years or a fine or to both;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) on summary conviction in England and Wales or Northern Ireland, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding the statutory maximum or to both;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) on summary conviction in Scotland, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 12 months or to a fine not exceeding the statutory maximum or to both.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In section 235B (enforcement) substitute all references to &#8220;35ZA&#8221; for &#8220;235A&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In section 235C (forfeiture in England and Wales and Northern Ireland) substitute all references to &#8220;35ZA&#8221; for &#8220;235A&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In section 23ZC, in subsections (2) and (3), substitute all references to &#8220;registered design&#8221; for &#8220;design right subsisting in a design&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(6) In section 235D (forfeiture in Scotland), substitute all references to &#8220;35ZA&#8221; for &#8220;235A&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In section 235D substitute all references to &#8220;35ZC&#8221; for &#8220;235C&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(8) For section 235E (offences committed by partnerships and body corporate) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;235E Section 235E: offences committed by partnerships and body corporate</quote>
         <quote>(1) Proceedings for an offence under this Act alleged to have been committed by a partnership shall be brought against the partnership in the name of the firm and not in that of the partners; but without prejudice to any liability of the partners under subsection (4) below.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The following provisions apply for the purposes of such proceedings as in relation to a body corporate&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any rules of court relating to the service of documents;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in England and Wales or Northern Ireland, Schedule 3 to the Magistrates&#8217; Court Act 1980 or Schedule 4 to the Magistrates&#8217; Courts (Northern Ireland) Order 1981 (procedure on charge of offence);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a fine imposed on a partnership on its conviction in such proceedings shall be paid out of the partnership assets;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) where a partnership is guilty of an offence under this Act, every partner, other than a partner who is proved to have been ignorant of or to have attempted to prevent the commission of the offence, is also guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) where an offence under this Act committed by a body corporate is proved to have been committed with the consent, connivance or neglect of a director, manager, secretary or other similar officer of the body, or a person purporting to act in any such capacity, he as well as the body corporate is guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 14</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>25&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>25&#042;:</B> Clause 14, page 15, leave out lines 15 and 16 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(b) which directly displays clearly the product and its complete trade designation and associates the product with the number of the patent or patents which relate to it&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 20</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD JENKIN OF RODING</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>26&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>26&#042;:</B> Clause 20, page 18, line 2, after &#8220;growth&#8221; insert &#8220;arising from the creation and exploitation of intellectual property&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>27&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>27&#042;:</B> Clause 20, page 18, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State must make a statement to Parliament detailing the findings of the report referred to in subsection (1) and what actions he intends to take as a result of any recommendations of the report.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>28&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>28&#042;:</B> Clause 20, page 18, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In producing the report in subsection (1), the Secretary of State shall consider any responses collected by the Patent Office in response to consultations or investigations carried out for the purpose of the production of this report, including its assessment of the role of the effective operation and protection of IP rights licensing in promoting economic growth.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 21</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>29&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>29&#042;:</B> After Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Remote e-lending</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 5(2) of the Public Lending Right Act 1979 (interpretation) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) At the end of the definition of &#8220;lent out&#8221; omit &#8220;but (b) does not include being communicated by means of electronic transmission to a place other than library premises&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>30&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>30&#042;:</B> After Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Copyright in broadcast</quote>
         <IndentOne>Omit section 73 of the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 (reception and re-transmission of wireless broadcast by cable).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>31&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>31&#042;:</B> After Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Criminal liability</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 107(4A)(b) (Criminal liability for making or dealing with infringing articles, etc) delete &#8220;two&#8221; and insert &#8220;ten&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 198(5A)(b) (Criminal liability for making, dealing with or using illicit recordings) delete &#8220;two&#8221; and insert &#8220;ten&#8221;.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>