<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Local_Audit_and_Accountability_(HLBill42_I)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1&#042;:</B> After Clause 22, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Auditor&#8217;s right to documents and information of significant private contractors</quote>
         <quote>(1) A local auditor has a right of access at all reasonable times to audit documents from significant private companies that the local authority have contracted services to during the last financial year.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Local auditors only have a right of access to audit documents from private companies, under subsection (1), that relate to the service provided to the local authority by that company.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A local auditor must make available on request any audit documents, obtained under subsection (1), subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act 2000.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In this section &#8220;private company&#8221; shall be interpreted to mean any legal entity, including joint ventures, not-for-profit organisations, mutually-held organisations and charities.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Five years after the coming into force of this section, the Secretary of State must commission and publish a review of the effectiveness of subsections (1) to (3) and of the costs to local auditors, private companies and local authorities arising from it.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2&#042;:</B> After Clause 35, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Freedom of information</quote>
         <quote>(1) In the Freedom of Information Act 2000, at the end of Part 1 of Schedule 1 (public authorities), insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;7 A local auditor of a local authority.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) Five years after the coming into force of this section, the Secretary of State must commission and publish a review of the effectiveness of this section and of the costs to local auditors, private companies and local authorities arising from it.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3:</B> Schedule 12, page 88, line 37, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Omit sections 69 and 70 (transitional provision: local government bodies in Wales and Welsh NHS bodies).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>