<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Marriage_(Same_Sex_Couples)_(Bill34_I(Rev))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 5, at end insert &#8220;and shall be referred to as &#8220;marriage (same sex couples)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>( ) Marriage between opposite sex couples shall be referred to as &#8220;marriage (opposite sex couples)&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 6, leave out &#8220;The marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;A marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3:</B> Clause 1, page 2, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(6) Any duty of a person employed as a registrar of marriages on the date this Act comes into force (&#8220;relevant registrar&#8221;) to solemnize marriages is not extended by this Act to marriages of same sex couples if the relevant registrar has a conscientious objection to doing so.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Nothing in subsection (6) shall affect the duty of a relevant registrar to carry out any other duties and responsibilities of his employment.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The conscientious objection, under subsection (6), must be based on a sincerely held religious or other belief concerning only the marriage of same sex couples and in any legal proceedings the burden of proof of conscientious objection shall rest on the person claiming to rely on it.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>4:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Belief in traditional marriage</quote>
         <IndentOne>Nothing in this Act shall contradict the principle that a belief that marriage is the voluntary union of one man and one woman for life to the exclusion of all others is a belief worthy of respect in a democratic society.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[Amendments 5 and 6 are amendments to Amendment 4]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>5:</B> After Clause 1, line 4, leave out &#8220;for life to the exclusion of all others&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>6:</B> After Clause 1, line 5, leave out &#8220;in a democratic society&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>7</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>7:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Regulations</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by regulations make provision for the Registrar General to approve and permit organisations that are registered charities principally concerned with advancing or practising a non-religious belief to solemnise marriages according to their usages on the authority of a superintendent registrar&#8217;s certificate, and for related purposes.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The regulations shall specify that such marriages may not take place in register offices, but may in particular&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) define minimum requirements any such organisation must meet before it may be considered for such approval;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) define the procedures for the appointment of registering officers by such organisations, for the issue and custody of marriage register books, for the solemnisation and registering of marriages, and for related matters, and in these matters the regulations shall follow where convenient the several precedents to be found in the Marriage Act 1949;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) create criminal offences of a kind similar to, and with the same maximum penalties as, offences under Part IV of the Marriage Act 1949;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) include incidental or consequential provisions (which may include provisions amending an enactment);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) include transitional provision.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The regulations under subsection (2)(a) must include provisions concerning whether an organisation&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is a registered charity principally concerned with advancing or practising a non-religious belief;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) has been in continuous existence for at least 10 years;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) has been performing celebrations of marriage and other ceremonies for its members for at least five years, such ceremonies being rooted in its belief system;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) has in place written procedures for the selection, training and accreditation of persons to conduct solemnisations of marriages; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) appears to the Registrar General to be of good repute.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The regulations shall extend to England and Wales.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The regulations&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall be made by statutory instrument, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may not be made unless a draft has been laid before and approved by resolution of each House of Parliament.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The Secretary of State must lay these regulations before Parliament within six months of this Act coming into force.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>8</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>8:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Optional marriage declaration</quote>
         <quote>(1) Nothing in this Act takes away the right of a man and a woman to opt to make a declaration that they are entering into a traditional marriage.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A &#8220;traditional marriage&#8221; is one where the basis of the marriage is the voluntary union of one man and one woman for life, to the exclusion of all others.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A traditional marriage may be solemnized in accordance with&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) Part 2 of the Marriage Act 1949, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any other statutory provision authorising the marriage within a place of worship or in another place according to religious rites or usages, provided the ceremony contains a declaration by the parties in the following form, or words to that effect&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;I [name] take you [name] as my husband [or wife], and forsaking all others, to remain faithful to you as long as we both shall live.&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>9</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>9:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 10, after &#8220;compelled&#8221; insert &#8220;by any means (including by the enforcement of a contract or a statutory or other legal requirement)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>10</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>10:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 13, after &#8220;compelled&#8221; insert &#8220;by any means (including by the enforcement of a contract or a statutory or other legal requirement)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>11</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>11:</B> Clause 2, page 3, line 23, leave out &#8220;a registrar,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>12</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>12:</B> Clause 2, page 3, line 26, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>13</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>13:</B> Clause 2, page 3, line 42, leave out &#8220;of same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>14</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>14:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 7, leave out &#8220;the marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>15</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>15:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5AA) A does not contravene this section if A&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) does not undertake an opt-in activity, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) undertakes an opt-out activity.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>16</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>16:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 8, leave out &#8220;(5A) applies&#8221; and insert &#8220;(5A) and (5AA) apply&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>17</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>17:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 10, after &#8220;(5A)&#8221; insert &#8220;and (5AA)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>18</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>18:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) For the purposes of section 149 of the Equality Act 2010, no regard may be had by any public authority to the expression by a person of the opinion or belief that marriage is the union of one man with one woman.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>19</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>19:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) For the purposes of section 149 of the Equality Act 2010, no regard may be had by any public authority to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any decision by a person whether or not to opt-in, conduct, be present at, carry out, participate in, or consent to the taking place of, relevant marriages; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the expression by a person of the opinion or belief that marriage is the union of one man with one woman.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>20</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>20:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 22, leave out &#8220;the marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>21&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>21&#042;:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A person does not contravene section 29 only because the person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) does not undertake an opt-in activity, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) undertakes an opt-out activity</IndentOne>
         <quote>as defined by section 2 of the Marriage (Same Sex Couples) Act 2013.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>22</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>22:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) For the avoidance of doubt, in this section a person does not exercise a public function for the purposes of the Human Rights Act 1998, the Equality Act 2010, or judicial review, when the person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) refrains from undertaking an opt-in activity, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) undertakes an opt-out activity.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>23</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>23:</B> Clause 2, page 4, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) For the purposes of this Act &#8220;compelled&#8221; includes, but is not limited to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) less favourable treatment of a person by a public authority, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the imposition of any criminal or civil penalty,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>as a result of a decision not to opt-in, conduct, be present at, carry out, participate in, or consent to the taking place of, relevant marriages.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>24</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>24:</B> Clause 3, page 4, line 29, leave out from first &#8220;&#8221; to &#8220;&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8221;</quote>Marriagefor(same sex couples); marriage (opposite sex couples)</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>25</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>25:</B> Clause 3, page 4, line 33, leave out &#8220;of a man and a woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>26</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>26:</B> Clause 3, page 4, line 39, leave out &#8220;of a man and a woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>27</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>27:</B> Clause 3, page 5, line 1, leave out &#8220;between a man and a woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>28</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>28:</B> Clause 3, page 5, line 4, leave out &#8220;of a man and a woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>29</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>29:</B> Clause 3, page 5, line 8, leave out &#8220;of a man and a woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>30</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>30:</B> Clause 3, page 5, line 13, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>31</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>31:</B> Clause 4, page 5, line 20, leave out &#8220;&#8221; and insert &#8220;()&#8221;</quote>of same sex couplessame sex couples</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>32</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>32:</B> Clause 4, page 5, line 21, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>33</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>33:</B> Clause 4, page 5, line 40, leave out &#8220;of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>34</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>34:</B> Schedule 1, page 17, line 6, leave out &#8220;&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8221;</quote>marriage of same sex couplesmarriages (same sex couples)</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>35</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>35:</B> Schedule 1, page 18, line 39, leave out &#8220;marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>36</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>36:</B> Schedule 1, page 19, line 8, leave out &#8220;marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>37</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>37:</B> Schedule 1, page 19, line 11, leave out from beginning to end of line 32 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) The Secretary of State may by statutory instrument make regulations about the procedures to be followed and the fees payable&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) on registration applications;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to section 43B authorisations;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) on cancellation applications.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State may by statutory instrument make&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) regulations modifying the application of section 41 or 43 in relation to buildings that are already registered under section 43A;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) regulations about cases where a person makes applications under sections 41 and 43A, or gives or certifies authorisations under sections 43 and 43B, in respect of the same building at the same time (including provision modifying any requirement imposed by any of those sections or by regulations under subsection (1) of this section).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) A statutory instrument containing regulations made under this section is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;cancellation application&#8221; means an application under section 43C for the cancellation of the registration of a building;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;registration application&#8221; means an application under section 43A for the registration of a building;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;section 43B authorisation&#8221; means the authorisation of a person under section 43B to be present at the solemnization of marriages in a building registered under section 43A.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>38</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>38:</B> Schedule 1, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>39</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>39:</B> Schedule 1, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>40</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>40:</B> Schedule 1, page 19, line 34, leave out &#8220;&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8221;</quote>marriage of same sex couplesmarriages (same sex couples)</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>41</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>41:</B> Schedule 1, page 21, line 14, leave out from &#8220;&#8221; to end of line 24 and insert &#8220;</quote>sharedplaces of worship: registration and cancellation<quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by statutory instrument make regulations about&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) registration applications relating to other shared places of worship;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) cancellation applications relating to other shared places of worship;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the sharing churches&#8217; use of other shared places of worship (in cases where those places are registered under section 43A) for the solemnization of marriages of same sex couples.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The provision that may be made under subsection (1)(a) or (b) includes provision about the procedures to be followed on registration applications or cancellation applications.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In this section &#8220;other shared place of worship&#8221; means a shared building&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) which has been certified as required by law as a place of religious worship, but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to which sections 44A and 44B do not apply because the building is neither&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) subject to a sharing agreement, nor</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) used as mentioned in section 6(4) of the 1969 Act.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>42</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>42:</B> Clause 5, page 6, line 3, leave out &#8220;&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8221;</quote>of same sex couples(same sex couples)</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>43</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>43:</B> Clause 6, page 8, line 11, leave out &#8220;the marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>44</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>44:</B> Clause 6, page 8, line 16, leave out &#8220;the marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>45</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>45:</B> Clause 7, page 9, line 17, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46:</B> After Clause 7, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Protection of teachers</quote>
         <quote>(1) For the avoidance of doubt, nothing under or in consequence of this Act shall&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) affect the right of teachers to express their personal views about marriage in an appropriate way, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) mean that any teacher will be under any obligation to endorse a particular view of marriage.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Subsection (1) does not apply to a school designated as having a religious character by an order made by the Secretary of State under section 69(3) of the School Standards and Framework Act 1998.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[Amendments 47 and 48 are amendments to Amendment 46]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>47</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>47:</B> After Clause 7, line 3, leave out &#8220;For the avoidance of doubt&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>48</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>48:</B> After Clause 7, line 8, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) imply that an applicant&#8217;s view of marriage shall be taken into account by any interviewing panel&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>49</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>49:</B> After Clause 7, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Employment protection</quote>
         <quote>(1) After section 47F of the Employment Rights Act 1996 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;47G Beliefs about the definition of marriage</quote>
         <quote>(1) An employee has the right not to be subjected to any detriment by any act, or any deliberate failure to act, by his employer on the ground that the employee believes or expresses a belief that marriage should only take place between a man and a woman, provided that belief is expressed in a reasonable manner.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This section is without prejudice to any rights which an employer may have under Schedule 9 to the Equality Act 2010.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 48 of the Employment Rights Act 1996, at the end of subsection (1) insert &#8220;or 47G&#8221;.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>50</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>50:</B> After Clause 7, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Education Act 1996: right of withdrawal</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 405 of the Education Act 1996 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;405A General right of withdrawal: lessons about marriage</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies to any teaching about same sex marriage outside of sex education.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If the parent of any pupil in attendance at a maintained school requests that he may be wholly or partly excused from lessons to which this section applies, the pupil shall be so excused accordingly until the request is withdrawn.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51:</B> Clause 8, page 9, line 33, leave out &#8220;the marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>52</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>52:</B> Clause 8, page 9, line 36, leave out &#8220;the marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>53</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>53:</B> After Clause 8, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reasonable accommodation</quote>
         <quote>(1) An employer has a duty to take such steps as are reasonably practical to accommodate an employee who has a conscientious belief that marriage is the union of one man to one woman for life to the exclusion of all others.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The duty in subsection (1) applies where an employee would otherwise be required to act in a way which is contrary to their conscientious belief about marriage.</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of subsection (1), an employee is as defined in section 230 of the Employment Rights Act 1996 but does not include a registrar, a superintendent registrar, the Registrar General or any person holding or exercising judicial office.</quote>
         <quote>(4) This section is without prejudice to any rights which an employer has under Schedule 9 to the Equality Act 2010.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>54</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>54:</B> Clause 9, page 10, line 18, leave out &#8220;Registrar General&#8221; and insert &#8220;Secretary of State&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55:</B> Clause 9, page 10, line 28, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) Regulations under subsections (1) and (2) shall in particular provide that the conversion of a civil partnership to a marriage shall take place in a registered building with open doors in the presence of two or more witnesses and in the presence of either&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a registrar of the registration district in which the registered building is situated, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an authorised person whose name and address have been certified in accordance with the regulations by the trustees or governing body of that registered building or of some other registered building in the same registration district.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3B) Where the conversion of a civil partnership to a marriage takes place in a registered building each of the parties to the civil partnership shall, in some part of the ceremony and in the presence of the witnesses and the registrar or authorised person, make the following declaration&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(none) &#8220;I do solemnly declare that I know not of any lawful impediment why I, AB, may not be joined in matrimony to CD.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and each of them shall say to the other&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(none) &#8220;I call upon these persons here present to witness that I, AB, do take thee, CD, to be my lawful wedded wife (or husband)&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3C) As an alternative to the declaration set out in subsection (3B) the persons contracting the marriage may make the requisite declaration either&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) by saying &#8220;I declare that I know of no legal reason why I (name) may not be joined in marriage to (name)&#8221;; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) by replying &#8220;I am&#8221; to the question put to them successively &#8220;Are you (name) free lawfully to marry (name)?&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and as an alternative to the words of contract set out in that subsection the persons to be married may say to each other &#8220;I () take you ( thee) () to be my wedded wife (husband)&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56:</B> Clause 9, page 10, line 38, leave out from beginning to &#8220;provision&#8221; in line 42</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>57</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>57:</B> Clause 9, page 11, line 4, leave out &#8220;(e) or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58:</B> Clause 9, page 11, line 6, leave out &#8220;(e) or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>59</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>59:</B> Clause 9, page 11, line 12, leave out subsection (6)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>60</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>60:</B> Clause 10, page 11, line 45, leave out &#8220;the marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>61</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>61:</B> Clause 10, page 12, line 4, leave out &#8220;of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62:</B> Clause 10, page 12, line 6, leave out &#8220;marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>63</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>63:</B> Schedule 2, page 23, line 8, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64:</B> Schedule 2, page 23, line 19, leave out &#8220;marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>65</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>65:</B> Schedule 2, page 23, line 20, leave out &#8220;marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66:</B> Schedule 2, page 23, line 27, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67:</B> Schedule 2, page 24, line 22, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68:</B> Schedule 2, page 24, line 44, leave out &#8220;the marriage of the same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>69</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>69:</B> Clause 11, page 12, line 10, leave out from &#8220;marriage&#8221; to end of line 11 and insert &#8220;(same sex couples) has the same effect as marriage (opposite sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>70</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>70:</B> Clause 11, page 12, line 15, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) For provision about limitations on the effects of subsections (1) and (2) and Schedule 3, see Part 7 of Schedule 4.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>71&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>71&#042;:</B> Clause 11, page 12, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) an order under section (Legislative definitions) (1)(d)&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>72</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>72:</B> Schedule 3, page 25, line 30, leave out &#8220;marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriages (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73:</B> Schedule 3, page 26, line 39, leave out &#8220;marriage of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74:</B> Schedule 3, page 26, line 42, leave out &#8220;marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>75</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>75:</B> Schedule 4, page 28, line 6, leave out sub-paragraph (2) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) In subsection (2)(a) after &#8220;that the respondent has committed adultery&#8221; insert &#8220;or a sexual act with a person of the same sex similar to adultery&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76:</B> Schedule 4, page 28, line 14, leave out &#8220;the marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>77</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>77:</B> Schedule 4, page 28, line 23, leave out &#8220;of a man and a woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>78</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>78:</B> Schedule 4, page 28, line 25, leave out &#8220;of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>79</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>79:</B> Schedule 4, page 28, line 28, leave out from first &#8220;of&#8221; to end of line 29 and insert &#8220;a marriage (opposite sex couple) or a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>80</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>80:</B> Schedule 4, page 29, line 3, leave out &#8220;OF SAME SEX COUPLES&#8221; and insert &#8220;(SAME SEX COUPLES)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>81</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>81:</B> Schedule 4, page 29, line 7, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>82</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>82:</B> Schedule 4, page 31, line 43, leave out from first &#8220;marriage&#8221; to end and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple) or a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>83</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>83:</B> Schedule 4, page 34, line 18, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>84</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>84:</B> Schedule 4, page 36, line 20, leave out sub-paragraphs (2) and (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Omit sub-paragraph (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>85</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>85:</B> Before Clause 12, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Legislative definitions</quote>
         <quote>(1) For the purposes of legislation regulating or relating to marriage&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) there shall no difference or distinction be made between lawful marriage of same sex couples and lawful marriage between a man and a woman, save as provided for in this Act or as required to give effect to any difference or distinction which is made necessary by reason of physiological or biological differences of gender or consequences thereof;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where it is necessary to make legislative provision regulating or relating to marriages between same sex couples but not marriages between a man or a woman, or marriages between a man and a woman but not marriages between same sex couples, lawful marriage between same sex couples may be defined as same sex marriage, lawful marriages between same sex couples may be defined as same sex marriages, lawful marriage between a man and a woman may be defined as opposite sex marriage and lawful marriages between a man and a woman may be defined as opposite sex marriages;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) all legislation regulating or relating to marriage having effect before the passage of this Act continues in effect in relation to opposite sex marriages save as varied or modified by any provision of this Act;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the Secretary of State or the Lord Chancellor may by order vary, modify or repeal legislation regulating or relating to opposite sex marriage, if it appears that such variation, modification or repeal is required as a consequence of the passage of this Act.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>86</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>86:</B> Schedule 5, page 40, line 10, after &#8220;with&#8221; insert &#8220;this Part of&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87:</B> Schedule 5, page 40, line 21, leave out from &#8220;declaration&#8221; to end and insert &#8220;by the applicant&#8217;s spouse that the spouse consents to the marriage continuing after the issue of a full gender recognition certificate (&#8220;a statutory declaration of consent&#8221;)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>88</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>88:</B> Schedule 5, page 46, line 7, leave out from &#8220;consent&#8221;&#8221; to end of line 13 and insert &#8220;has the meaning given by section 3(6B)(a),&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>89</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>89:</B> Schedule 5, page 46, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 2</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Alternative grounds for granting applications for gender recognition certificates</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Introduction</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>15 The Gender Recognition Act 2004 is amended in accordance with this Part of this Schedule.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Alternative grounds for granting applications</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>16 Section 2 (determination of applications): after subsection (3) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) This section does not apply to an application under section 1(1)(a) which states that it is an application for a certificate to be granted in accordance with section 3A.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>17 After section 3 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;3A Alternative grounds for granting applications</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies to an application under section 1(1)(a) which states that it is an application for a certificate to be granted in accordance with this section.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Panel must grant the application if satisfied that the applicant complies with the requirements imposed by and under section 3B and meets the conditions in subsections (3) to (6).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The first condition is that the applicant was a party to a protected marriage or a protected civil partnership on or before the date the application was made.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The second condition is that the applicant&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) was living in the acquired gender six years before the commencement of section 12 of the Marriage (Same Sex Couples) Act 2013,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) continued to live in the acquired gender until the date the application was made, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) intends to continue to live in the acquired gender until death.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The third condition is that the applicant&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) has or has had gender dysphoria, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) has undergone surgical treatment for the purpose of modifying sexual characteristics.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The fourth condition is that the applicant is ordinarily resident in England, Wales or Scotland.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The Panel must reject the application if not required by subsection (2) to grant it.&#8221;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Evidence for granting applications on alternative grounds</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>18 Section 3 (evidence): after subsection (8) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(9) This section does not apply to an application under section 1(1)(a) which states that it is an application for a certificate to be granted in accordance with section 3A.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>19 After section 3A (inserted by paragraph 17) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;3B Evidence for granting applications on alternative grounds</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies to an application under section 1(1)(a) which states that it is an application for a certificate to be granted in accordance with section 3A.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The application must include either&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a report made by a registered medical practitioner, or </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a report made by a registered psychologist practising in the field of gender dysphoria.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) If the application is based on the applicant having or having had gender dysphoria&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the reference in subsection (2) to a registered medical practitioner is to one practising in the field of gender dysphoria, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) that subsection is not complied with unless the report includes details of the diagnosis of the applicant&#8217;s gender dysphoria.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Subsection (2) is not complied with in a case where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the applicant has undergone or is undergoing treatment for the purpose of modifying sexual characteristics, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) treatment for that purpose has been prescribed or planned for the applicant,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>unless the report required by that subsection includes details of it.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The application must also include a statutory declaration by the applicant that the applicant meets the conditions in section 3A(3) and (4).</quote>
         <quote>(6) The application must include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a statutory declaration as to whether or not the applicant is married or a civil partner,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any other information or evidence required by an order made by the Secretary of State, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any other information or evidence which the Panel which is to determine the application may require,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and may include any other information or evidence which the applicant wishes to include.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) If the applicant is married, the application must include a statutory declaration as to whether the marriage is a marriage under the law of England and Wales, of Scotland, of Northern Ireland, or of a country or territory outside the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(8) If the applicant is married, and the marriage is a protected marriage, the application must also include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a statutory declaration of consent by the applicant&#8217;s spouse (if the spouse has made such a declaration), or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a statutory declaration by the applicant that the applicant&#8217;s spouse has not made a statutory declaration of consent (if that is the case).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) If the application includes a statutory declaration of consent by the applicant&#8217;s spouse, the Panel must give the spouse notice that the application has been made.</quote>
         <quote>(10) If the Panel which is to determine the application requires information or evidence under subsection (6)(c) it must give reasons for doing so.&#8221;.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Membership of Panels determining applications on alternative grounds</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>20 Schedule 1 (Gender Recognition Panels), paragraph 4: after sub-paragraph (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) But a Panel need not include a medical member when determining an application under section 1(1)(a) for a certificate to be granted in accordance with section 3A.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>90</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>90:</B> After Clause 13, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Marriage according to the usages of belief organisations</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State must arrange for a review of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) whether an order under subsection (4) should be made permitting marriages according to the usages of belief organisations to be solemnized on the authority of certificates of a superintendent registrar, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if so, what provision should be included in the order.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The arrangements made by the Secretary of State under subsection (1) must provide for the review to include a full public consultation.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Secretary of State must arrange for a report on the outcome of the review to be produced and published before 1 January 2015.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State may by order make provision for and in connection with permitting marriages according to the usages of belief organisations to be solemnized on the authority of certificates of a superintendent registrar.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An order under subsection (4) may&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) amend any England and Wales legislation;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) make provision for the charging of fees.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) An order under subsection (4) must provide that no religious service may be used at a marriage which is solemnized in pursuance of the order.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In this section &#8220;belief organisation&#8221; means an organisation whose principal or sole purpose is the advancement of a system of non-religious beliefs which relate to morality or ethics.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>91</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>91:</B> Schedule 6, page 48, line 33, leave out sub-paragraph (2) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) An Order in Council may, in particular, make provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) prohibiting the solemnization of such marriages according to particular religious rites or usages; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) permitting the solemnization of such marriages according to particular religious rites or usages.</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) Sub-paragraph (2)(b) is subject to sub-paragraphs (2B) and (2C).</quote>
         <quote>(2B) An Order in Council may not make provision allowing the solemnization of forces marriages of same sex couples according to the rites of the Church of England or Church in Wales.</quote>
         <quote>(2C) If an Order in Council makes provision allowing the solemnization of forces marriages of same sex couples according to particular religious rites or usages (other than those of the Church of England or Church in Wales), the Order in Council must also make provision to secure that such a marriage may not be solemnized according to those rites or usages unless the relevant governing authority has given written consent to marriages of same sex couples.</quote>
         <quote>(2D) The person or persons who are the relevant governing body for that purpose are to be determined in accordance with provision made by an Order in Council under this Part of this Schedule.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92:</B> Schedule 6, page 48, line 41, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) If section 8 applies, the Lord Chancellor may, by order, make such relevant amending provision as the Lord Chancellor considers appropriate to allow for the solemnization of forces marriages of same sex couples according to the rites of the Church in Wales.</quote>
         <quote>(5) For that purpose &#8220;relevant amending provision&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) provision amending sub-paragraphs (2B) and (2C) by omitting the words &#8220;or Church in Wales&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provision amending any Order in Council made under this Part of this Schedule;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provision amending any other UK legislation (including legislation contained in this Part of this Schedule).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In making an order under sub-paragraph (4), the Lord Chancellor must have regard to the terms of the resolution of the Governing Body of the Church in Wales referred to in section 8(1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>93</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>93:</B> Schedule 6, page 50, line 8, leave out sub-paragraph (3)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>94</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>94:</B> Clause 14, page 13, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) The review under subsection (1) must deal with the case for amending the criteria in the Civil Partnership Act 2004 which define the eligibility of people to register as civil partners.</quote>
         <quote>(1B) The review must in particular consider&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the case for extending such eligibility to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) unpaid carers and those they care for, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) family members who share a house,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>provided that they have cohabitated for 5 years or more and are over the age of eighteen, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the case for creating a new legal status that would confer all the benefits of civil partnerships upon those mentioned in paragraph (a) without amending the criteria for eligibility for civil partnership.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendment of Education Act 1996</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 403 of the Education Act 1996 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After subsection (1B) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1BA) Nothing in subsection (1B) prevents teaching the tenets of the relevant religion or religious denomination concerning marriage and its importance for family life and the bringing up of children to registered pupils at schools which have a religious character.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) For the purposes of subsection (1BA)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a school has a religious character if it is designated as a school having such a character by an order made by the Secretary of State under section 69 of the School Standards and Framework Act 1998 (&#8220;the 1998 Act&#8221;); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;the relevant religion or religious denomination&#8221; means the religion or denomination specified in relation to the school under section 69(4) of the 1998 Act.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95A&#042;:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Education: duty of the Secretary of State to provide information</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must provide evidence-based information to teachers on the implications of the measures in this Act for the raising of children and the promotion of family life.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>96</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>96:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Referendum provisions</quote>
         <quote>(1) A referendum is to be held in England and Wales on the issue of same sex marriage.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The referendum is to be held on 24 October 2013.</quote>
         <quote>(3) If the Secretary of State is satisfied that it is impossible or impracticable for the referendum to be held on 24 October 2013, or that it cannot be conducted properly if held on that day, the Secretary of State may be order appoint a later day as the day on which the referendum is to be held.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Any day appointed by order under subsection (3) must be before 1 November 2014.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Where a day is appointed under subsection (4), the Secretary of State may by order make supplemental or consequential provision.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Secretary of State must by order make provisions for the conduct of the referendum.</quote>
         <quote>(7) An order under this section may not be made unless a draft of the order has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The question that is to appear on the ballot papers is&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>(9) Those entitled to vote in the referendum are the persons who, on the date of the referendum, would be entitled to vote as electors at a parliamentary election in any constituency.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>97</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>97:</B> Schedule 7, page 52, line 5, leave out &#8220;of same sex couples&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couples)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>98</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>98:</B> Schedule 7, page 52, line 27, leave out &#8220;&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8221;</quote>of a man and a woman(opposite sex couple)</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>99</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>99:</B> Schedule 7, page 52, line 30, leave out &#8220;of a man and woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>100</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>100:</B> Schedule 7, page 53, line 28, leave out from first &#8220;marriage&#8221; to end of line 29 and insert &#8220;(opposite sex couple)), or section 43B (in the case of the marriage (same sex couple))&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>101</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>101:</B> Schedule 7, page 53, line 38, leave out &#8220;the marriage of a man and a woman&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (opposite sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>102</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>102:</B> Schedule 7, page 53, line 40, leave out &#8220;the marriage of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;a marriage (same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>103</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>103:</B> Schedule 7, page 54, line 2, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104:</B> Schedule 7, page 54, line 5, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>105</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>105:</B> Schedule 7, page 54, line 34, leave out &#8220;of a same sex couple&#8221; and insert &#8220;(same sex couple)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>106</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>106:</B> Schedule 7, page 55, line 32, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(ab) after the definition of &#8220;ecclesiastical district&#8221; insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;England and Wales legislation&#8221; has the same meaning as in the Marriage (Same Sex Couples) Act 2013;&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>107</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>107:</B> Schedule 7, page 58, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>&#8220;<quote>43A After section 26 (harassment) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;26A Discussion or criticism of same sex marriage</quote>
         <IndentOne>For the purposes of this Act, and for the avoidance of doubt, discussion or criticism of same sex marriage shall not be taken of itself to be discrimination or harassment.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>108</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>108:</B> Clause 16, page 13, line 32, leave out &#8220;or Registrar General&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>109</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>109:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 1, after &#8220;made&#8221; insert &#8220;by the Secretary of State or Lord Chancellor&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>110</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>110:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(aa) the first regulations under section 9(1);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(ab) the first regulations under section 9(2);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>111</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>111:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) an order under section (Marriage according to the usages of belief organisations);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>112</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>112:</B> Clause 16, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>113</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>113:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 6, leave out from &#8220;2&#8221; to end of line 7</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>114</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>114:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) an order under paragraph 2 of Schedule 2;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) an order under paragraph 27 of Schedule 4.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>115</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>115:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(f) an order under paragraph 9(4) of Schedule 6.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>116</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>116:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 8, after &#8220;legislation&#8221; insert &#8220;made by the Secretary of State or Lord Chancellor&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>117</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>117:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(za) regulations under section 9(1) (except for the first such regulations);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(zb) regulations under section 9(2) (except for the first such regulations);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>118</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>118:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 12, leave out paragraphs (b) to (d)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>119</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>119:</B> Clause 16, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>120</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>120:</B> Clause 16, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>121</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>121:</B> Clause 16, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>122</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>122:</B> Clause 16, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>123</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>123:</B> Clause 16, page 14, line 19, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) The provision that may be made by the Secretary of State or Lord Chancellor in any order or regulations under this Act includes provision enabling the Registrar General to make regulations by statutory instrument (with or without the consent of a minister of the Crown).</quote>
         <quote>(4B) But the Secretary of State or Lord Chancellor may not make such provision unless that minister is satisfied that the provision is necessary in connection with administrative matters relating to functions of the Registrar General or functions of superintendent registrars or registrars.</quote>
         <quote>(4C) Regulations made by the Registrar General under any power conferred by an enabling instrument are subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(4D) But that is subject to any provision in the enabling instrument about the kind of Parliamentary scrutiny, if any, to which the regulations are to be subject.</quote>
         <quote>(4E) In subsections (4C) and (4D) &#8220;enabling instrument&#8221; means an order or regulations made under this Act by the Secretary of State or Lord Chancellor containing provision of the kind mentioned in subsection (4A).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>124</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>124:</B> Clause 16, [Withdrawn]</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>125</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>125:</B> Clause 17, page 15, line 27, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;superintendent registrar&#8221; means a superintendent registrar of births, deaths and marriages.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>126</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>126:</B> Clause 18, page 15, line 34, leave out &#8220;section&#8221; and insert &#8220;sections (Marriage according to the usages of belief organisations) and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>127</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>127:</B> Clause 18, page 15, line 38, leave out &#8220;section&#8221; and insert &#8220;sections (Marriage according to the usages of belief organisations) and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>128</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>128:</B> Clause 18, page 15, line 38, at end insert &#8220;and paragraphs 4, 5, 10 and 11 of Schedule 6&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>129</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>129:</B> Clause 18, page 15, line 40, leave out from &#8220;(3)&#8221; to end and insert &#8220;do not apply to an amendment or repeal or revocation made by this Act&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>130</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>130:</B> Clause 18, page 15, line 42, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5A) Subsection (5) is subject to subsections (6) to (8).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>131</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>131:</B> Clause 18, page 16, line 1, leave out &#8220;But&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>132</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>132:</B> Clause 18, page 16, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) The repeal of the Foreign Marriage Act 1892 made by section 13(2) does not extend to Northern Ireland.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133:</B> Clause 18, page 16, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(8) Any amendment made by Part 2 of Schedule 5 does not extend to Northern Ireland.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134:</B> Clause 19, leave out Clause 19 and insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Short title and commencement</quote>
         <quote>(1) This Act may be cited as the Marriage (Same Sex Couples) Act 2013.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This section, section 14 and section (Referendum provisions) come into force on the day on which this Act is passed.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Subject to subsections (2) and (4), this Act comes into force on such day as the Secretary of State may be order appoint; and different days may be appointed for different purposes.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State may not bring any part of this Act into force unless the referendum provided for at section (Referendum provisions) delivers an affirmative outcome.</quote>
         <quote>(5) For the purposes of subsection (4), an affirmative outcome shall be where a majority of votes cast in the referendum support the proposition contained in the referendum question.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>135</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>135:</B>In the Title, line 4, leave out first &#8220;and&#8221; and insert &#8220;for permitting marriages according to the usages of belief organisations to be solemnized on the authority of certificates of a superintendent registrar,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>136</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>136:</B> , line 4, after &#8220;partnership&#8221; insert &#8220;and arrangements for family members and relationships of care in cases of long-term house-sharing&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>