<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Marriage_(Same_Sex_Couples)_(Bill29_III)</billtitle>
      <headertext>THIRD MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext> The amendments have been marshalled in accordance with the Instruction of 12th June 2013, as follows&#8212;</headertext>
      <headertext>Schedule 4 Clause 12 Schedule 5 Clause 13 Schedule 6 Clauses 14 and 15 Schedule 7 Clauses 16 to 19 </headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 4</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ALLI</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HOWE OF IDLICOTE</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD BLACK OF BRENTWOOD</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>45</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>45:</B> Schedule 4, page 35, line 13, leave out sub-paragraphs (2) and (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Omit sub-paragraph (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 12</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ARMSTRONG OF ILMINSTER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46:</B> Before Clause 12, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Matrimonial marriages</quote>
         <quote>(1) Lawful marriage between a man and a woman is matrimony.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Lawful marriages between a man and a woman are matrimonial marriages.</quote>
         <quote>(3) All legislation regulating or relating to marriage having effect before the passage of this Act continues in effect in relation to matrimonial marriages save as varied or modified by any provision of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State or the Lord Chancellor may by order vary, modify or repeal legislation regulating or relating to matrimonial marriages if it appears that such variation, modification or repeal is required as a consequence of the passage of this Act.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 5</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS BARKER</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS GOULD OF POTTERNEWTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46ZA</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46ZA:</B> Schedule 5, page 40, line 6, after &#8220;full&#8221; insert &#8220;or interim&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46ZB</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46ZB:</B> Schedule 5, page 40, line 16, leave out &#8220;either of&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46ZC</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46ZC:</B> Schedule 5, page 40, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) Case C is where, on application by the person, the Panel is satisfied that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an interim gender recognition certificate has been issued to the person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the person was a party to a protected marriage at the time when the interim gender recognition certificate was issued;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the person is a party to a protected marriage; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) a period of either&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) six months beginning with the day on which that certificate was issued has elapsed and annulment proceedings have not been initiated in relation to the protected marriage, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) twelve months beginning with the day on which that certificate was issued has elapsed and no decree nisi has been issued in relation to the protected marriage.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(3B) Case D is where, on application by the person, the Panel is satisfied that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an interim gender recognition certificate has been issued to the person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a period of six months beginning with the day on which that certificate was issued has elapsed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a conversion application has been made;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the conversion application has resulted in the civil partnership being converted into a marriage; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) the person is a party to that marriage.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46ZD</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46ZD:</B> Schedule 5, page 40, line 40, leave out &#8220;or (3)&#8221; and insert &#8220;, (3), (3A) or (3B)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46ZE</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46ZE:</B> Schedule 5, page 41, line 1, after &#8220;(2)&#8221; insert &#8220;or (3A)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46ZF</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46ZF:</B> Schedule 5, page 41, line 4, after &#8220;(3)&#8221; insert &#8220;or (3B)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46ZG</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46ZG:</B> Schedule 5, page 41, line 9, after &#8220;(3)&#8221; insert &#8220;or (3B)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 14</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS DEECH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;CATHAIN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46A:</B> Clause 14, page 12, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) The review under subsection (1) must deal with the case for amending the criteria in the Civil Partnership Act 2004 which define the eligibility of people to register as civil partners.</quote>
         <quote>(1B) The review must in particular consider the case for extending such eligibility to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) unpaid carers and those they care for, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) family members who share a house, who have cohabited for 5 years or more and are over the age of eighteen.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 14</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE LORD BISHOP OF RIPON AND LEEDS</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS CUMBERLEGE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;LOAN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46B:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendment of Education Act 1996</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 403 of the Education Act 1996 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After subsection (1C) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1CA) Guidance under subsection (1A) must provide for education about the nature of marriage and its importance for family life and the bringing up of children to be given to registered pupils at schools which have a religious character in accordance with the tenets of the relevant religion or religious denomination.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) For the purposes of subsection (1CA)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a school has a religious character if it is designated as a school having such a character by an order made by the Secretary of State under section 69(3) of the School Standards and Framework Act 1998 (&#8220;the 1998 Act&#8221;); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;the relevant religion or religious denomination&#8221; means the religion or denomination specified in relation to the school under section 69(4) of the 1998 Act.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Subsection (5) applies where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) Academy arrangements have been entered into between the Secretary of State and another person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the terms of the Academy arrangements have the effect of requiring that other person to have regard to guidance issued under subsection (1A) above; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the Academy is designated as having a religious character by an order made by the Secretary of State under section 69, as applied by section 124B, of the 1998 Act or is treated as having been so designated by virtue of section 6(8) of the Academies Act 2010.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Where this subsection applies, subsection (1CA), and guidance issued under subsection (1A), are to be construed as if references to schools which have a religious character were references to the Academy.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>THE LORD BISHOP OF LEICESTER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46C:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Equality Act 2010</quote>
         <IndentOne>In the Equality Act 2010, after section 212, insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;212A Expression of opinion or belief as to marriage</quote>
         <IndentOne>For the purposes of this Act, the expression by a person of the opinion or belief that marriage is the union of one man with one woman does not of itself amount to discrimination against or harassment of another.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD PEARSON OF RANNOCH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>46D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>46D:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Financial benefit</quote>
         <IndentOne>A marriage between a same sex couple as provided by this Act does not confer any financial benefit or change in tax liability above that conferred upon blood relative partnerships.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 15</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEAR</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>47</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>47:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Review of impact of same sex marriage</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must arrange&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) for the operation and effects of this Act to be reviewed two years and five years after this Act is passed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for the report on the outcome of the first review to be produced and published within thirty months of this Act being passed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) for the report on the outcome of the second review to be produced and published within five years and six months of this Act being passed; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) for both reviews to be conducted by a Lord Justice of Appeal taking appropriate evidence with particular regard to the impact of this Act on civil liberties and the rates of&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) opposite sex marriage, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) same sex marriage.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD ANDERSON OF SWANSEA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD CORMACK</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD SINGH OF WIMBLEDON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>48</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>48:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Referendum provisions</quote>
         <quote>(1) A referendum is to be held in England and Wales on the issue of same sex marriage.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The referendum is to be held on 7 May 2015.</quote>
         <quote>(3) If the Secretary of State is satisfied that it is impossible or impracticable for the referendum to be held on 7 May 2015, or that it cannot be conducted properly if held on that day, the Secretary of State may by order appoint a later day as the day on which the referendum is to be held.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Any day appointed by order under subsection (3) must be before 1 June 2016.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Where a day is appointed under subsection (4), the Secretary of State may by order make supplemental or consequential provision.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Secretary of State must by order make provisions for the conduct of the referendum.</quote>
         <quote>(7) An order under this section may not be made unless a draft of the order has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The question that is to appear on the ballot papers is&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;At present, the law in England and Wales defines marriage as the union of a man and a woman. Should the law be changed to define marriage as the union of two people&#8212;whether a man and a woman, or woman and a woman, or a man and a man?&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(9) Those entitled to vote in the referendum are the persons who, on the date of the referendum, would be entitled to vote as electors at a parliamentary election in any constituency.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD STODDART OF SWINDON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>48A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>48A:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;The European Convention on Human Rights</quote>
         <IndentOne>In the event that the provisions of this Act are found by the European Court of Human Rights to be incompatible with the Convention for the Protection of Human Rights and Fundamental Freedoms, the Secretary of State shall act to withdraw the United Kingdom&#8217;s signature to the Convention.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 7</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS STOWELL OF BEESTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>49</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>49:</B> Schedule 7, page 50, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) Section 25 (void marriages) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) At the beginning insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) A marriage shall be void in any of the following cases.&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The existing wording of section 25 becomes subsection (2) of that section; and, at the beginning of that subsection, for &#8220;If any persons&#8221; substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) Case A is where any persons&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) For the words after paragraph (d) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) Case B is where any persons knowingly and wilfully consent to or acquiesce in the solemnization of a Church of England marriage between them by a person who is not in Holy Orders.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Case C is where any persons of the same sex consent to or acquiesce in the solemnization of a Church of England marriage between them.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In subsections (3) and (4) &#8220;Church of England marriage&#8221; means a marriage according to the rites of the Church of England.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>50</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>50:</B> Schedule 7, page 53, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>&#8220;<quote>After section 49 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;49A Void marriages: additional provision about same sex couples</quote>
         <quote>(1) If a same sex couple knowingly and wilfully intermarries under the provisions of this Part of this Act in the absence of the required consent, the marriage shall be void.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In this section, in relation to a marriage of a same sex couple, &#8220;required consent&#8221; means consent under&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 26A(3), in a case where section 26A applies to the marriage (but section 44A does not apply to it);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section 26A(3) and section 44A(6), in a case where section 26A and section 44A apply to the marriage;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) section 26B(2)(b), in a case where section 26B(1), (2) and (3) apply to the marriage;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) section 26B(4)(b), in a case where section 26B(1), (4) and (5) apply to the marriage;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) section 26B(6)(d), in a case where section 26B(1), (6) and (7) apply to the marriage.&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51:</B> Schedule 7, page 53, line 45, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) After subsection (5) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(6) If, for the purpose of any provision of this Act, a relevant governing authority has given written consent to marriages of same sex couples, the validity of that consent is not affected only because there is a change in the person or persons constituting that relevant governing authority.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>52</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>52:</B> Schedule 7, page 54, line 19, at end insert&#8212;</quote>&#8220;<quote>After section 13 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;13A Void marriages: additional provision about same sex couples</quote>
         <quote>(1) If a same sex couple knowingly and wilfully intermarries under the provisions of this Act in the absence of the required consent, the marriage shall be void.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In this section &#8220;required consent&#8221; means consent under section 1(3).&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>53</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>53:</B> Schedule 7, page 54, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Public Order Act 1986 (c. 64)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>(1) Section 29JA of the Public Order Act 1986 (protection of freedom of expression (sexual orientation)) is amended in accordance with this paragraph.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The existing provision of section 29JA becomes subsection (1) of that section.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After that provision insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) In this Part, for the avoidance of doubt, any discussion or criticism of marriage which concerns the sex of the parties to marriage shall not be taken of itself to be threatening or intended to stir up hatred.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>BARONESS BERRIDGE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;LOAN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>54</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>54:</B> Schedule 7, page 54, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Public Order Act 1986 (c. 64)</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>26A (1) The Public Order Act 1986 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For section 29JA substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;29JA Protection of freedom of expression (sexual orientation)</quote>
         <IndentOne>In this Part, for the avoidance of doubt, the discussion or criticism of sexual conduct or practices or the urging of persons to refrain from or modify such conduct or practices or the expression by a person of the opinion or belief that marriage is the union of one man with one woman shall not be taken of itself to be threatening or intended to stir up hatred.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD MACKAY OF CLASHFERN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55:</B> Schedule 7, page 55, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>&#8220;<quote>32A For paragraph 13(2) of Schedule 27 to the Civil Partnership Act 2004 substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In subsection (1), for the words from &#8220;solemnized&#8221; to &#8220;shall&#8221;, substitute &#8220;a man and any other of the persons mentioned in the first column of Part I of the First Schedule to this Act, or between a woman and any other of the persons mentioned in the second column of the said Part II,&#8221;.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD DEAR</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56:</B> Schedule 7, page 56, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>&#8220;<quote>39A After section 26 (harassment) insert&#8212; </quote>
         <quote>&#8220;26A Discussion or criticism of same sex marriage</quote>
         <IndentOne>For the purposes of this Act, and for the avoidance of doubt, discussion or criticism of same sex marriage shall not be taken of itself to be discrimination or harassment.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;LOAN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56A&#042;:</B> Schedule 7, page 56, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;39A Section 149 (public sector equality duty): after subsection (9), insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(10) Compliance with the duties in this section requires ensuring that a belief regarding the definition of marriage as being between a man and a woman is respected and that no person should suffer any detriment in respect of the holding or the reasonable expression of such a belief.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 16</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ARMSTRONG OF ILMINSTER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>57</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>57:</B> Clause 16, page 12, line 34, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) an order under section (Matrimonial marriages)(4);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>BARONESS STOWELL OF BEESTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58:</B> Clause 16, page 12, line 37, leave out paragraph (a)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 19</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ANDERSON OF SWANSEA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD CORMACK</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD SINGH OF WIMBLEDON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>59</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>59:</B> Clause 19, leave out Clause 19 and insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Short title and commencement</quote>
         <quote>(1) This Act may be cited as the Marriage (Same Sex Couples) Act 2013.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This section, section 14 and section (Referendum provisions) come into force on the day on which this Act is passed.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Subject to subsections (2) and (4), this Act comes into force on such day as the Secretary of State may by order appoint; and different days may be appointed for different purposes.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State may not bring any part of this Act into force unless the referendum provided for at section (Referendum provisions) delivers an affirmative outcome.</quote>
         <quote>(5) For the purposes of subsection (4), an affirmative outcome shall be where a majority of votes cast in the referendum support the proposition contained in the referendum question.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>