<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Pensions_(Bill55_VI)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <clausetext>[In substitution for Amendment 62C]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62D:</B> Clause 37, page 19, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) Regulations under this section shall not be made to exempt entire classes of business or businesses, such as small and medium-sized businesses, from automatic enrolment. </quote>
         <quote>(6) Regulations under this section shall be laid before and approved by resolution of both Houses of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62E</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62E:</B> After Clause 37, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Alternative quality requirements for UK defined benefits schemes</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Pensions Act 2008 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 23 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;23A Alternative quality requirements for UK defined benefits schemes</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by regulations provide that a defined benefits scheme that has its main administration in the United Kingdom satisfies the quality requirement in relation to a jobholder if any one or more of the following is satisfied&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the scheme is of a prescribed description and satisfies the quality requirement under section 20 in relation to that jobholder;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the cost of providing the benefits accruing for or in respect of the relevant members over a relevant period would require contributions to be made of a total amount equal to at least a prescribed percentage of the members&#8217; total relevant earnings over that period;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in the case of each of at least 90% of the relevant members, the cost of providing the benefits accruing for or in respect of the member over a relevant period would require contributions to be made of a total amount equal to at least a prescribed percentage of the member&#8217;s total relevant earnings over that period.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) For this purpose&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;contributions&#8221; means contributions to the scheme by, or on behalf or in respect of, a relevant member;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant earnings&#8221; means earnings of a prescribed description;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant members&#8221; means members of the scheme of a prescribed description;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant period&#8221; means a period specified in or determined in accordance with the regulations.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A percentage prescribed under subsection (1)(b) or (c) must be at least 8%.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Regulations under subsection (1)(b) or (c) may make provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) about how to calculate whether the requirement is satisfied, including provision requiring the calculation to be made in accordance with prescribed methods or assumptions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) requiring benefits of a prescribed description to be disregarded in determining whether the requirement is satisfied;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) that a scheme only satisfies the requirement if the scheme actuary certifies that it does; and for this purpose &#8220;scheme actuary&#8221; has the prescribed meaning.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Section 13(3) (meaning of &#8220;earnings&#8221;) applies for the purposes of this section as it applies for the purposes of that section.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Secretary of State must from time to time review any regulations in force under subsection (1).</quote>
         <quote>(7) A review must be carried out&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) during 2017, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after that, no more than three years after the completion of the previous review.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In section 24 (quality requirement: UK hybrid schemes), in subsection (1)(b), for &#8220;23&#8221; substitute &#8220;23A&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In section 28 (certification that quality requirement or alternative requirement is satisfied)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) after subsection (3A) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(3B) This section also applies to a defined benefits scheme that has its main administration in the United Kingdom and is of a description prescribed under section 23A(1)(a).&#8221;;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(b) in subsection (4), after paragraph (d) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(e) for a scheme within subsection (3B), means the quality requirement under section 23A(1)(a).&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In section 29 (transitional periods for money purchase and personal pension schemes), in subsections (1) and (3) omit &#8220;for money purchase and personal pension schemes&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Section 30 (transitional period for defined benefits and hybrid schemes) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In subsection (3), at the end of the substituted subsection (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;A reference in this subsection to a scheme does not include a scheme to which section 30(11)(a) or (b) applies.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) In subsection (5), in the substituted subsection (2)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), after &#8220;defined benefits scheme&#8221; insert &#8220;other than a scheme to which section 30(11)(a) applies&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (aa) (inserted by section 38 of this Act), after &#8220;a hybrid scheme&#8221; insert &#8220;other than a scheme to which section 30(11)(b) applies&#8221;; after paragraph (c) (inserted by section 38 of this Act), insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) becomes an active member, with effect from the automatic enrolment date, of an automatic enrolment scheme which is a defined benefits scheme to which section 30(11)(a) applies, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) becomes a defined benefits member , with effect from the automatic enrolment date, of an automatic enrolment scheme which is a hybrid scheme to which section 30(11)(b) applies.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) After subsection (10) (inserted by section 38 of this Act) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(11) In subsection (2) references to a scheme do not include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a defined benefits scheme that satisfies the quality requirement in relation to the jobholder by reason only of section 23A(1)(a), or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a hybrid scheme if&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the appropriate paragraph of section 24(1) for any provisions of the scheme is paragraph (b) (those provisions are referred to below as &#8220;the defined benefits section&#8221;),</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the defined benefits section satisfies section 23A(1)(a) as applied by section 24(1)(b), and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) the defined benefits section does not satisfy any of the other requirements mentioned in section 24(1)(b).&#8221;&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62F</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62F:</B> Clause 38, page 19, line 38,  leave out subsection (4) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) In subsection (5), in the substituted subsection (2)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), for &#8220;or a hybrid scheme, or&#8221; substitute&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(aa) becomes a defined benefits member, with effect from the closure date, of an automatic enrolment scheme which is a hybrid scheme,&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after paragraph (b) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) becomes a money purchase member, with effect from the automatic enrolment date, of an automatic enrolment scheme which is a hybrid scheme.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62G</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62G:</B> Clause 41, page 21, line 37, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;charges&#8221;; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;transaction costs&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>shall be defined in regulations by the Secretary of State.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Before making regulations under subsection (2), the Secretary of State must undertake a public consultation, which must include the views of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Financial Conduct Authority; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Pensions Regulator.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) With reference to subsection (2)(a), any public consultation must consider the different elements which comprise charges and not just the annual management charge.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Such charges, together with any transaction costs incurred by the funds in which qualifying schemes are invested, shall be declared on an annual basis to the Pensions Regulator, which shall maintain a public register thereof.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Secretary of State shall by regulations set the standards by which pension schemes must declare charges and transaction costs for the purposes of the register and for declaration to their members and their members&#8217; employers.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The standards set out in regulations under subsection (6) shall be reviewed every three years.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The Secretary of State shall have power to make regulations ordering other disclosure arrangements on administration charges.</quote>
         <quote>(9) Regulations under this section may not be made unless a draft has been laid before and approved by resolution of both Houses of Parliament.&#8221;.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62H</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62H:</B> Schedule 17, page 95, line 29, leave out &#8220;(whenever passed or made)&#8221; and insert &#8220;whether passed or made in this session or a previous session&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>63</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>63:</B> After Schedule 17, insert the following new Schedule&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Schedule</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Work-based schemes: requirements for disclosure of charges and other information</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>The Secretary of State shall by regulations make provision to require disclosure at least annually of the following management and transaction charges incurred by the administration and management of each investment portfolio managed by or on behalf of a work-based scheme&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) fees and performance fees paid to investment managers,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) commissions and bid-offer spreads paid to brokers,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) bid-offer spreads paid to foreign exchange counterparties,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) fees, revenue splits and bid-offer spreads paid to custodian banks,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) fees paid to in-house or third party scheme administrators,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) fees paid to professional advisors (e.g. actuaries, legal advisers, auditors, investment consultants etc.),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) initial charges, bid-offer spreads, exit charges, other fees and rebates charged on investments in pooled funds.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64:</B> Clause 45, page 23, line 37, leave out &#8220;sustainable growth&#8221; and insert &#8220;sustainability&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64A:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Pension Protection Fund: compensation cap to apply separately to certain benefits </quote>
         <quote>(1) Paragraph 26 of Schedule 7 to the Pensions Act 2004 (Pension Protection Fund: compensation cap) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In sub-paragraph (1)(b), for &#8220;sub-paragraph (2)(a) or (b)&#8221; substitute &#8220;sub-paragraph (2)(a), (b) or (c)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In sub-paragraph (2)(a)(ii), for &#8220;paragraph (b)(i) does not apply&#8221; substitute &#8220;neither of paragraphs (b) and (c) applies&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In sub-paragraph (2)(b)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) before paragraph (i) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(zi) benefit A is attributable to the person&#8217;s pensionable service,&#8221;;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (i), after &#8220;one or more other benefits&#8221; insert &#8220;that are attributable to his pensionable service&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In sub-paragraph (2), after paragraph (b) insert &#8220;, and</quote>
         <IndentOne>(c) this paragraph applies if&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) benefit A is attributable to a pension credit from a transferor,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) at the same time as the person becomes entitled to relevant compensation in respect of benefit A he also becomes entitled to relevant compensation in respect of one or more other benefits that are&#8212;</IndentTwo>iiaunder the scheme or a connected occupational pension scheme, andiibattributable to a pension credit from the same transferor,(&#8220;benefit or benefits B&#8221;), and<IndentTwo>(iii) the aggregate of the annual values of benefit A and benefit or benefits B exceeds the compensation cap.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(6) In sub-paragraph (5), after &#8220;sub-paragraph (2)(b)&#8221; insert &#8220;or (c)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The amendments made by this section are to be treated as always having had effect.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>65</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>65:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Public service pension schemes: transitional arrangements</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 18 of the Public Service Pensions Act 2013 (restriction of existing pension schemes) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After subsection (5) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5A) Scheme regulations may also provide for exceptions to subsection (1) in the case of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) persons who were members of a public body pension scheme specified in the regulations, or who were eligible to be members of such a scheme, immediately before 1 April 2012, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) such other persons as the regulations may specify, being persons who before that date had ceased to be members of a scheme referred to in paragraph (a) or to be eligible for membership of such a scheme.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In each of subsections (6) and (8), after &#8220;(5)&#8221; insert &#8220;or (5A)&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>65A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>65A:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Railways pension scheme</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Railways Act 1993 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In Schedule 11 (pensions), after paragraph 11 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;11A (1) This paragraph applies if an insolvency event occurs in relation to the employer or former employer of a protected person.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Where this paragraph applies, the Secretary of State shall become liable to discharge any liabilities in respect of relevant pension rights, to the extent that they are not discharged by the trustees of a new scheme in which the employer was a participating employer.</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of this paragraph&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;insolvency event&#8221; has the meaning set out in section 121 of the Pensions Act 2004;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;relevant pension rights&#8221; means the relevant pension rights referred to in paragraph 6(3) above.</IndentOne>
         <quote>11B The duty referred to in paragraph 11A also applies if an insolvency event has occurred in relation to the employer or former employer of a protected person on or after 1 October 1994.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendments to Universal Credit Regulations 2013</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Universal Credit Regulations 2013 are amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In paragraph 89 (claimants subject to no work-related requirements) after sub-paragraph (f) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(g) the claimant is claiming bereavement support payment and is eligible for child benefit for at least one child.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In paragraph 66(1)(b), omit paragraphs (v) and (vi).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Work-based schemes: requirements for disclosure of charges and other information</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must by regulations require work-based pension schemes to disclose periodically certain costs and information relating to the charges for management and administration described in Schedule (Work-based schemes: requirements for disclosure of charges and other information).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67ZA</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67ZA:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Decumulation</quote>
         <quote>(1) Any qualifying money purchase scheme must direct its savers to an independent annuity brokerage service or offer such a brokerage service itself.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Pension schemes shall ensure that any brokerage service selected or provided meets best practice in terms of providing members with&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an assisted path through the annuity process;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) ensuring access to most annuity providers;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) minimising costs; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) ensuring that information and support is available on alternative at-retirement products.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The standards meeting best practice on decumulation shall be defined by the Pensions Regulator after public consultation.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The standards set out in subsection (3) shall be reviewed every three years and, if required, updated.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67ZB</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67ZB:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Promotion of good value in scheme size</quote>
         <quote>(1) The fiduciary duty of pension scheme trustees shall include a duty to consider whether the scheme has sufficient scale to deliver good value for members.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Where trustees take the view that the scheme has insufficient scale, they must consider whether merger with another scheme would be in the members&#8217; interests.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Pensions Regulator shall have power to direct merger of pensions schemes where it would be in the interests of the members of each of the relevant schemes for merger to take place.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Pensions Regulator shall exercise this power in accordance with a methodology on which it has publicly consulted and which has been agreed with the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The methodology set out in subsection (4) shall be kept under regular review and revised when necessary, subject to further consultation and agreement from the Secretary of State.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67ZC</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67ZC:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Fiduciary duty of independent trustees</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by regulations&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) require any pension scheme, which is not already overseen by independent trustees, to appoint a board of independent trustees; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) set out the powers and duties of a board appointed under paragraph (a).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Regulations under this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall be made by statutory instrument; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may not be made unless a draft has been laid before and approved by resolution of each House of Parliament.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The board of independent trustees shall have a fiduciary duty towards members of the scheme overseen by them.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The fiduciary duty set out in subsection (3) shall take precedence over any duty to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the shareholders in, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) other owners of,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>the operators of the scheme.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In relation to any matters of member interest, decisions of the board of independent trustees shall be binding on the board of directors or other.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67ZD</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67ZD:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;National Employment Savings Trust transfers</quote>
         <quote>(1) In relation to NEST, the Government must by 30 August 2014 notify the European Commission that it wishes to lift the ban on transfers and the contribution cap.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State must make a statement to Parliament within 14 days of the Government notifying the European Commission in accordance with subsection (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67A:</B> Schedule 19, page 99, leave out lines 6 to 10</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67B:</B> Schedule 19, page 101, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 4</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Transitional provision: schemes undergoing assessment or winding up on the commencement date</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Schemes undergoing assessment on the commencement date</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>15 (1) This paragraph applies in relation to an eligible scheme that is undergoing assessment on the commencement date.</quote>Continue to use the old cap as the basis of assessment<quote>(2) For the purposes of sections 127(2)(a) and 128(2)(a) of the Pensions Act 2004, ignore any effect that this Schedule has on the compensation which would be payable if the Board assumed responsibility for the scheme in accordance with Chapter 3 of Part 2 of that Act.Going forwards, pay pensions on the basis of the new cap</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of section 138(2) of the Pensions Act 2004 take into account any effect that this Schedule has on the compensation which would be payable if the Board assumed responsibility for the scheme in accordance with Chapter 3 of Part 2 of that Act on the assessment date.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Schemes that begin winding up before the commencement date</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>16 (1) This paragraph applies in relation to an eligible scheme that is being wound up if the winding up began (or is treated as having begun) before the commencement date.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of section 73 and 73A of the Pensions Act 1995, ignore any effect that this Schedule  has on the compensation which would be payable if the Board assumed responsibility for the scheme in accordance with Chapter 3 of Part 2 of the Pensions Act 2004.Going forwards, pay pensions on the basis of the new cap during assessment</quote>
         <quote>(3) If for any period the scheme is being wound up and is also undergoing assessment (&#8220;the overlap period&#8221;), sub-paragraph (4) applies.</quote>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes of section 73A of the Pensions Act 1995 as it applies in relation to the overlap period, take into account any effect that this Schedule has on the compensation which would be payable if the Board assumed responsibility for the scheme in accordance with Chapter 3 of Part 2 of the Pensions Act 2004.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Meaning of &#8220;undergoing assessment&#8221;</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>17 For the purposes of this Part of this Schedule an eligible scheme is &#8220;undergoing assessment&#8221; if an assessment period has begun in relation to the scheme but has not yet ended.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Meaning of &#8220;eligible scheme&#8221;</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>18 Section 126(4) of the Pensions Act 2004 (list of provisions in relation to which regulations may provide that a scheme remains an &#8220;eligible scheme&#8221;) is to be treated as including a reference to this Part of this Schedule.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 5</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>General</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Interpretation</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>19 In this Schedule &#8220;the commencement date&#8221; means the date on which it comes fully into force.</quote>
         <quote>20 Other expressions used in this Schedule have the same meaning as in Part 2 of the Pensions Act 2004.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Further transitional provision may be made by order</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>21 The inclusion of Parts 3 and 4 of this Schedule does not prevent transitional provision being made by order under section 51(7).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68:</B> Clause 49, page 24, line 32, leave out paragraph (a) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) regulations under section 3, 17, 18(3) or (5), 19, 20, 29, 31 or 33,&#8221; </IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68ZA</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68ZA:</B> Clause 49, page 24, line 32, after &#8220;3,&#8221; insert &#8220;17(5),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68A:</B> Clause 49, page 24, line 32, after &#8220;18(5)&#8221; insert &#8220;, 24(8)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68B:</B> Clause 49, page 24, line 32, leave out &#8220;or 29&#8221; and insert &#8220;, 29 or 42&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>69</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>69:</B> Clause 49, page 24, line 33, leave out &#8220;or 20&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>70</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>70:</B> Clause 49, page 24, line 38, after &#8220;paragraph&#8221; insert &#8220;1 or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>71</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>71:</B> Clause 49, page 25, line 5, after &#8220;51(1)&#8221; insert &#8220;, (6A)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>72</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>72:</B> Clause 51, page 25, line 20, leave out subsection (2) </quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>72A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>72A:</B> Clause 51, page 25, line 22, leave out subsection (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) The following come into force on the day on which this Act is passed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 28;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section (Pension Protection Fund: compensation cap to apply separately to certain benefits);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) this Part.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73:</B> Clause 51, page 25, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(6A) Section (Public service pension schemes: transitional arrangements) comes into force on such day or days as the Treasury may by order appoint.</quote>
         <quote>(6B) An order under subsection (1) or (6A) may appoint different days for different purposes.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>