<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Transparency_of_Lobbying_Non-Party_Campaigning_and_Trade_Union_Administration_(Bill50_II(c))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 27, page 14, line 42, leave out subsection (1) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) In section 94 of the Political Parties, Elections and Referendums Act 2000, (limits on controlled expenditure by non-recognised third parties), for subsection (5) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) Subject to subsection (5ZA), the limits referred to in subsection (3) are as follows&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) £10,000 for England, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) £5,000 for each of Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5ZA) In any case where controlled expenditure is wholly or substantially confined to any one particular parliamentary constituency (as defined by paragraph 2A of Schedule 10) the limit is equal to the limit on controlled expenditure set by paragraph 2B of Schedule 10.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 28, page 16, line 22, leave out from &#8220;if&#8221; to end of line 23 and insert &#8220;the expenditure relates to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) sending election material falling within paragraph 1 of Schedule 3 which is&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) addressed to, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) by virtue of delivery instructions directed to,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>any person registered, or entitled to be registered, in the register of parliamentary electors for any particular constituency, or to households within a particular constituency;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) unsolicited telephone calls falling within paragraph 2 of Schedule 3, made to such persons or households.</IndentOne>
         <quote>( ) For the purposes of this paragraph, &#8220;election material&#8221; is defined as in section 143A of PPERA 2000 (as inserted by this Act).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 28, page 16, line 31, leave out from &#8220;is&#8221; to end of line 33 and insert &#8220;£10,000&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 28, page 16, leave out lines 37 and 38 and insert &#8220;£5,000&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 28, page 16, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2C) The Secretary of State may by order made by statutory instrument vary the amount of the limits in subsections (2A) and (2B).</quote>
         <quote>(2D) A statutory instrument containing an order made under subsection (2C) may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 28, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Constituency limits: exceptions</quote>
         <quote>(1) A recognised third party may exceed the constituency limits imposed by section 28 (&#8220;the constituency limits&#8221;) in the circumstances set out in subsection (2) and (3), subject to subsections (4) to (6).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The circumstances are that for the purposes of this section the recognised third party records all donations of any value as prescribed by Schedule 11 of PPERA 2000 notwithstanding paragraph 4 of that schedule (Payments etc to be disregarded), and;</quote>
         <quote>(3) The controlled expenditure is funded by donations of less than £250 each from permissible donors within the parliamentary constituency or constituencies within which the controlled expenditure has an effect under paragraph 2A of Schedule 10 to PPERA 2000 (as inserted by this Act).</quote>
         <quote>(4) A recognised third party may not by virtue of subsection (3) exceed the constituency limits by more than £250 in relation to any one permissible donor.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Nothing in this section shall permit a recognised third party to exceed by more than 50% the maximum campaign expenditure limit set out in paragraph 3 of Schedule 10 to PPERA 2000.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Nothing in this section shall permit a recognised third party to spend more than £15,000 in any one constituency during the regulated period, or more than £10,000 during the post-dissolution part of the regulated period.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 29, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Third parties acting in concert</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 94 of the Political Parties, Elections and Referendums Act 2000 (limits of controlled expenditure by non-recognised third parties) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (6)(b) after &#8220;arrangement&#8221; insert (&#8220;the plan&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (6), at end insert &#8220;in pursuance of the plan&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 3, page 56, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) Nothing in sub-paragraph (1) shall be taken as extending to communications with committed supporters, who have been actively involved in the activity of a recognised third party.</quote>
         <quote>(1B) For the purposes of sub-paragraph (1A) &#8220;actively involved&#8221; means those who have&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) made a donation (whether within purposes of Schedule 11 to PPERA 2000, or not) to the recognised third party; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) made a direct communication (whether solicited or otherwise) to the recognised third party in the past twelve months; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) consented to receiving communications from the recognised third party in the past twelve months.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 3, page 57, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Exclusions</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>1AA Nothing in sub-paragraphs (3) to (5) of paragraph 1 shall be taken as extending to any expenses incurred in respect of remuneration or allowances payable to any member of staff (whether permanent or otherwise) in the direct employ of the third party.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>