<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Transparency_of_Lobbying_Non-Party_Campaigning_and_Trade_Union_Administration_(Bill73_I)</billtitle>
      <headertext>MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON THIRD READING</headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 26</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1:</B> Clause 26, page 13, line 45, leave out from &#8220;that&#8221; to &#8220;on&#8221; in line 46 and insert &#8220;the offence would not have been committed&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 27</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2:</B> Clause 27, page 15, line 12, leave out &#8220;section 94A(5)&#8221; and insert &#8220;section &#8221;</quote>94B(3)</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3:</B> Clause 27, page 15, line 17, leave out &#8220;section 94A&#8221; and insert &#8220;section 94B(3) to (7)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>4:</B> Clause 27, page 15, line 20, leave out &#8220;section 94A&#8221; and insert &#8220;sections 94A and 94B&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>5:</B> Clause 27, page 15, line 21, leave out &#8220;section 94A&#8221; and insert &#8220;sections 94A and 94B&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>6:</B> Clause 27, page 15, line 23, leave out from beginning to end of line 18 on page 16 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;94A Arrangements between third parties notified to the Commission</quote>
         <quote>(1) A recognised third party may, at any time before the end of a regulated period, send a notice to the Commission&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) stating that it is party to an arrangement of the kind mentioned in section 94(6),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) undertaking to be a lead campaigner in relation to the arrangement, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) identifying one or more other third parties that are parties to the arrangement and have undertaken to be minor campaigners in relation to it.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) A recognised third party that has sent a notice under subsection (1) may, at any time before the end of the regulated period, send one or more supplementary notices to the Commission identifying additional third parties that are parties to the arrangement and have undertaken to be minor campaigners in relation to it.</quote>
         <quote>(3) As from the date of receipt by the Commission of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a notice under subsection (1), the recognised third party that sent the notice becomes &#8220;a lead campaigner&#8221; in relation to the arrangement;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a notice under subsection (1) or (2), a third party identified in the notice becomes &#8220;a minor campaigner&#8221; in relation to the arrangement.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A notice under subsection (1) or (2) may not&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) identify as a minor campaigner a third party that is a lead campaigner in relation to the same arrangement, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) be sent by a recognised Gibraltar third party.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The Commission must, as soon as reasonably practicable after receiving&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a notice under subsection (1), enter in the register maintained under section 89 (register of notifications) the fact that the recognised third party that sent the notice is a lead campaigner in relation to the arrangement;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a notice under subsection (1) or (2), enter in that register the name of each third party identified in the notice and the fact that it is a minor campaigner in relation to the arrangement.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) For provision about the effect of sending a notice under this section, see section 94B.</quote>
         <quote>94B Effect where arrangements are notified under section 94A</quote>
         <quote>(1) Subsection (2) applies where controlled expenditure is incurred during a regulated period in a part of the United Kingdom&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) by or on behalf of a minor campaigner in relation to an arrangement, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in pursuance of the arrangement.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The expenditure is treated for the purposes of sections 96 to 99A (returns as to controlled expenditure) as having also been incurred, during the period and in the part of the United Kingdom concerned, by or on behalf of any lead campaigner in relation to the arrangement who sent a notice under section 94A(1) or (2) identifying the minor campaigner.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In determining for the purposes of section 94(3)(a) whether a limit is exceeded by a third party during a regulated period, controlled expenditure incurred by or on behalf of the third party is to be disregarded if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) conditions A and B are met in relation to the expenditure, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) condition C is met.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Condition A is that the expenditure&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is incurred in pursuance of an arrangement that has been notified to the Commission under section 94A(1), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is, by virtue of section 94(6), treated for the purposes of section 94 and Schedule 10 as incurred by or on behalf of the third party.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Condition B is that the third party is, at the time the expenditure is incurred, a minor campaigner in relation to the arrangement.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Condition C is that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the total of the controlled expenditure incurred during the regulated period in any part of the United Kingdom by or on behalf of the third party, disregarding any expenditure in relation to which conditions A and B are met, does not exceed the limit for that part mentioned in section 94(5), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in the case of a regulated period in relation to which any limit is imposed by paragraph 3, 9 10 or 11 of Schedule 10 (periods involving parliamentary general elections), the total of the controlled expenditure incurred during the regulated period in any particular constituency by or on behalf of the third party, disregarding any expenditure in relation to which conditions A and B are met, does not exceed the limit mentioned in section 94(5ZA).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) References in subsection (6) to controlled expenditure incurred by or on behalf of the third party include controlled expenditure that is, by virtue of section 94(6), treated for the purposes of section 94 and Schedule 10 as so incurred.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>7&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>7&#042;:</B> Clause 27, page 16, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In section 99 (declaration by responsible person as to return under section 96), after subsection (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) Subsection (2)(b)(ii) does not apply to expenses that are treated as incurred by or on behalf of the recognised third party by virtue of section 94B(2) (arrangements between third parties notified to the Commission).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 28</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>8</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>8:</B> Clause 28, page 16, leave out lines 24 to 32 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;&#8220;(a) either&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) during a regulated period, any controlled expenditure is incurred in a part of the United Kingdom by or on behalf of a third party in excess of the limit for that part of the United Kingdom mentioned in subsection (5), or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) during a regulated period in relation to which any limit is imposed by paragraph 3, 9, 10 or 11 of Schedule 10 (periods involving parliamentary general elections), any controlled expenditure is incurred in a particular parliamentary constituency by or on behalf of a third party in excess of the limit mentioned in subsection (5ZA),&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TYLER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>9&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>9&#042;:</B> Clause 28, page 16, line 38, leave out &#8220;0.05% of the total&#8221; to end of line 40 and insert &#8220;£5,000&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 29</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>10</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>10:</B> Clause 29, page 17, line 36, leave out &#8220;that Schedule&#8221; and insert &#8220;Schedule 10&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD HARRIES OF PENTREGARTH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MALLALIEU</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD CORMACK</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>11&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>11&#042;:</B> Clause 29, page 18, leave out lines 5 to 18 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) For the purposes of this Schedule &#8220;third party constituency expenditure&#8221; means controlled expenditure incurred by or on behalf of a third party in relation to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) election material falling within paragraph 1 of Schedule 8A which is addressed to electors (whether addressed to them by name or intended for delivery to households or otherwise distributed within any particular constituency or constituencies), or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) unsolicited telephone calls falling within paragraph 2 of Schedule 8A, made to such electors or households which can reasonably be regarded as intended to ascertain or influence their voting intention,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>where the effects are wholly or substantially confined to any particular constituencies or constituency.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Third party constituency expenditure&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall be attributed to those constituencies in equal proportions, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) shall be attributed solely to that constituency,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>as the case may be.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of sub-paragraph (1), the effects of third party constituency expenditure are wholly or substantially confined to any particular constituencies or constituency if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) there is no significant effect in any other constituency or constituencies, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) it can reasonably be inferred that the third party selected the relevant electors or households (or both) or otherwise distributed the material wholly or substantially to contact electors in the particular constituency or constituencies and not a wider section of the public.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>12&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>12&#042;:</B> Clause 29, page 18, line 24, leave out &#8220;controlled&#8221; and insert &#8220;third party constituency&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 30</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>13</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>13:</B> Clause 30, page 21, line 1, leave out from &#8220;parties)&#8221; to &#8220;(as&#8221; in line 2 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) in subsection (6), after &#8220;the purposes of this section&#8221; insert &#8220;, sections 94D to 94H&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in subsections (8) and (10), after &#8220;sections 94A and 94B&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>14</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>14:</B> Clause 30, page 21, line 4, leave out &#8220;section 94A&#8221; and insert &#8220;section 94B&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>15</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>15:</B> Clause 30, page 21, line 39, leave out &#8220;3(2), 9(3) or (5), 10(3) or 11(3)&#8221; and insert &#8220;3, 9, 10 or 11&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>16</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>16:</B> Clause 30, page 22, leave out lines 7 and 8</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>17</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>17:</B> Clause 30, page 22, line 40, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) It is a defence for a third party charged with an offence under subsection (2) or (3) to show&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) that any code of practice for the time being issued under paragraph 4 of Schedule 8A was complied with in determining whether any expenditure is controlled expenditure for the purposes of this Part, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) that the offence would not have been committed on the basis of the controlled expenditure as determined in accordance with the code.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 34</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>18</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>18:</B> Clause 34, page 33, leave out lines 13 to 16 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;(1) Subsection (1A) applies where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) during a regulated period, any controlled expenditure is incurred by or on behalf of a recognised third party in a relevant part of the United Kingdom, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the incurring of that expenditure would, if the third party had not been recognised, have been an offence under section 94(4) (whether because it was incurred in excess of a limit mentioned in section 94(5) or 94(5ZA)).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 35</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>19</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>19:</B> Clause 35, page 33, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In sections 90(3) and 94(8), (10) and (11), for &#8220;99&#8221; substitute &#8220;99A&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>20</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>20:</B> Clause 35, page 34, leave out line 22</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 39</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD HARRIES OF PENTREGARTH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MALLALIEU</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TYLER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>21&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>21&#042;:</B> Clause 39, page 39, line 41, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The report under subsection (6) shall be laid before Parliament not more than 18 months after the date of the first relevant parliamentary general election.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 40</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEVENSON OF BALMACARA</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD MONKS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>22&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>22&#042;:</B> Clause 40, page 40, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) No union shall have to submit a membership audit certificate to the Certification Officer before August 2016.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 46</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>23</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>23:</B> Clause 46, page 52, leave out lines 24 to 31</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 46</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD WALLACE OF TANKERNESS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>24</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>24:</B> After Clause 46, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Power to make consequential provision</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Minister may by order made by statutory instrument make provision consequential on any provision of Part 2 or section .</quote>46<quote>(2) An order under this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) may include provision amending or modifying any provision of or made under PPERA 2000 (including any provision inserted by this Act),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may include incidental, supplementary, transitional, transitory or saving provision, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) may make different provision for different purposes or cases or for different areas.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) A statutory instrument containing an order under this section that amends or modifies any provision of PPERA 2000 may not be made unless a draft of the instrument containing it has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Any other statutory instrument containing an order under this section is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(5) No order may be made under this section after the date of the poll for the first relevant parliamentary general election.</quote>
         <quote>(6) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;the first relevant parliamentary general election&#8221; has the same meaning as in section ;</quote>39<quote>&#8220;the Minister&#8221; means the Secretary of State or the Lord President of the Council;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;PPERA 2000&#8221; means the Political Parties, Elections and Referendums Act 2000.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD MORRIS OF ABERAVON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>25</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>25:</B> Schedule 3, page 59, line 1, after first &#8220;of&#8221; insert &#8220;, or in consequence of,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>26</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>26:</B> Schedule 3, page 59, line 2, at end insert &#8220;including the costs of the production and preparation of such material for the public at large&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>