<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>International Development (Official Development Assistance Target) Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>9/1/2014</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 74" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Commons" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Cover>
<CoverTitle>EXPLANATORY NOTES</CoverTitle>
<CoverPara><Text><?start-line?>Explanatory notes to the Bill, prepared by Thomas Docherty, the Member in charge of <?new-line?>the Bill, are published separately as Bill 74—EN.</Text></CoverPara>
</Cover><Contents>
<Rubric TemplateVersion="4.2.002" xmlns="" /><Rubric xmlns="" /><ContentsTitle>Contents</ContentsTitle>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00008">
<ContentsNumber>1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Duty to meet United Nations 0.7% target from 2014</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00009">
<ContentsNumber>2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Duty to lay statement before Parliament if 0.7% target not met</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00010">
<ContentsNumber>3</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Accountability to Parliament</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00011">
<ContentsNumber>4</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Repeal of section 3 of the 2006 Act</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00012">
<ContentsNumber>5</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Independent International Development Office</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00013">
<ContentsNumber>6</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Short title</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsSchedules>
<ContentsSchedule ContentRef="p00014">
<ContentsNumber>Schedule</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>The Independent International Development Office</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsSchedule>
</ContentsSchedules>
</Contents>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Make provision about the meeting by the United Kingdom of the target for <?new-line?>official development assistance (ODA) to constitute 0.7 per cent of gross <?new-line?>national income; to make provision for independent verification that ODA is <?new-line?>spent efficiently and effectively; and for connected purposes.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<P1group id="p00008">
<Title><?start-line?>Duty to meet United Nations 0.7% target from 2014</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>It is the duty of the Secretary of State to ensure that the target for official <?new-line?>development assistance (referred to in this Act as “ODA”) to amount to 0.7% of <?new-line?>gross national income (in this Act referred to as “the 0.7% target”) is met by the <?new-line?>United Kingdom in the year 2014 and each subsequent calendar year.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Whether the 0.7% target has been met by the United Kingdom in any year is to <?new-line?>be determined for the purposes of this Act by reference to the amounts <?new-line?>specified for that year in an annual report (in particular, the percentage <?new-line?>specified in accordance with paragraph 1(h) of the Schedule to the 2006 Act).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In this Act—</Text>
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“the 2006 Act” means the International Development (Reporting and <?new-line?>Transparency) Act 2006;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“annual report” means an annual report under section 1 of the 2006 Act.</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00009">
<Title><?start-line?>Duty to lay statement before Parliament if 0.7% target not met</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>If an annual report laid before Parliament in the year 2015 or any subsequent <?new-line?>calendar year shows that the 0.7% target has not been met in the report year, <?new-line?>the Secretary of State must, as soon as reasonably practicable after laying the <?new-line?>report, lay before Parliament a statement complying with subsections (3) and <?new-line?>(4).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>If an annual report laid before Parliament in the year 2014 or any subsequent <?new-line?>calendar year shows that the 0.7% target has been met in the report year but—</Text>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the report is revised under section 1(4) of the 2006 Act by a subsequent <?new-line?>annual report, and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the effect of the revision is to show that the 0.7% target was not met in <?new-line?>the report year,</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<Text><?start-line?>the Secretary of State must, as soon as reasonably practicable after laying the</Text>
</P2para>
<P2para>
<Text><?new-line?>subsequent report, lay before Parliament a statement complying with</Text>
</P2para><P2para>
<Text><?new-line?>subsection (3).</Text>
</P2para></P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A statement under subsection (1) or (2) must explain why the 0.7% target has <?new-line?>not been met in the report year and, if relevant, refer to the effect of one or more <?new-line?>of the following—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>economic circumstances and, in particular, any substantial change in <?new-line?>gross national income;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>fiscal circumstances and, in particular, the likely impact of meeting the <?new-line?>target on taxation, public spending and public borrowing;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>circumstances arising outside the United Kingdom.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A statement under subsection (1) must also describe any steps that the <?new-line?>Secretary of State has taken to ensure that the 0.7% target will be met by the <?new-line?>United Kingdom in the calendar year following the report year.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In this section “the report year”, in relation to an annual report, means the <?new-line?>period of 12 months which is the most recent relevant period, as defined by <?new-line?>section 1(2) of the 2006 Act, to which the information included in accordance <?new-line?>with paragraph 1(h) of the Schedule to that Act relates.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00010">
<Title><?start-line?>Accountability to Parliament</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The only means of securing accountability in relation to the duty in section 1 is <?new-line?>that established by the provision in section 2 for the laying of a statement <?new-line?>before Parliament.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Accordingly, the fact that the duty in section 1 has not been, or will or may not <?new-line?>be, complied with does not affect the lawfulness of anything done, or omitted <?new-line?>to be done, by any person.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00011">
<Title><?start-line?>Repeal of section 3 of the 2006 Act</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>Section 3 of the 2006 Act (which requires each annual report to include an <?new-line?>assessment of the year in which the 0.7% target is expected to be met) is <?new-line?>repealed.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00012">
<Title><?start-line?>Independent International Development Office</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>There shall be established an independent body known as the Independent <?new-line?>International Development Office (referred to in this Act as “the IIDO”).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Schedule makes provision about the IIDO.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00013">
<Title><?start-line?>Short title</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the International Development (Official Development <?new-line?>Assistance Target) Act 2014.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Body>
<?new-page?>
<Schedules>
<Schedule id="p00014" NumberFormat="default">
<Number><?start-line?>Schedule</Number>
<TitleBlock>
<Title><?start-line?>The Independent International Development Office</Title>
</TitleBlock>
<Reference>Section 5</Reference>
<ScheduleBody>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Membership</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO is to consist of a member to chair it and six other members, <?new-line?>appointed by the Secretary of State for International Development following <?new-line?>a pre-appointment hearing by, and with the consent of, the International <?new-line?>Development Committee of the House of Commons.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Employees</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO may employ staff.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Staff are to be employed on such terms as to remuneration and other matters <?new-line?>as the IIDO may, with the approval of the Minister for the Civil Service, <?new-line?>determine.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Service as a member of staff of the IIDO is employment in the civil service of <?new-line?>the State.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>The IIDO must pay to the Minister for the Civil Service, at such times as the <?new-line?>Minister may direct, such sums as the Minister may determine in respect of the <?new-line?>increase in the sums payable out of money provided by Parliament that is <?new-line?>attributable to the provision of pensions, allowances or gratuities under section 1 of <?new-line?>the Superannuation Act 1972 payable to or in respect of persons who are or have <?new-line?>been members of staff of the IIDO.</Emphasis></Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Duties</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO will have the responsibility to carry out independent evaluation of <?new-line?>the relevance, impact, value-for-money and sustainability of ODA.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO will develop systems to verify the extent to which ODA is spent <?new-line?>efficiently and effectively.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Annual report</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO must prepare a report of the performance of its functions in each <?new-line?>financial year.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The report relating to a financial year must be prepared as soon as possible <?new-line?>after the end of the financial year.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The report must be sent to the Department for International Development.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Department for International Development must lay the report before <?new-line?>Parliament.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>“Financial year” means—</Text>
<?new-page?><P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the period which begins with the day on which this Schedule comes <?new-line?>into force and ends with the following 31 March;</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>each successive period of 12 months.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Accountability and Reporting</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>It will be the responsibility of the Secretary of State for International <?new-line?>Development to table responses to reports of the IIDO in Parliament.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The International Development Committee of the House of Commons will <?new-line?>provide parliamentary oversight of the work of the IIDO and report <?new-line?>annually on its current and future work programme.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Finance</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The budget of the IIDO will be agreed by the Secretary of State for <?new-line?>International Development.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?><Emphasis>The Department for International Development may make to the IIDO such <?new-line?>payments out of money provided by Parliament as the International Development <?new-line?>considers appropriate for the purpose of enabling the IIDO to meet its expenses.</Emphasis></Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Payments are to be made at such times, and subject to any such conditions, <?new-line?>as the Department for International Development considers appropriate.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Accounts and audit</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO must—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>keep proper accounts and proper records in relation to its accounts, <?new-line?>and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>prepare in respect of each financial year a statement of accounts.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Each statement of accounts must comply with any directions given by the <?new-line?>International Development Committee as to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the information to be contained in it and the manner in which it is to <?new-line?>be presented,</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the methods and principles according to which the statement is to be <?new-line?>prepared, and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the additional information (if any) which is to be provided for the <?new-line?>information of Parliament.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO must send a copy of each statement of accounts to—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the Secretary of State for International Development, and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>the Comptroller and Auditor General, before the end of the month of <?new-line?>June next following the financial year to which the statement relates.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Comptroller and Auditor General must—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>examine, certify and report on each statement of accounts, and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>send a copy of each report and certified statement to the <?new-line?>International Development.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Secretary of State for International Development must lay before <?new-line?>Parliament a copy of each such report and certified statement.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>“Financial year” has the same meaning as in paragraph 4(5).</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The IIDO must keep under review whether its internal financial controls <?new-line?>secure the proper conduct of its financial affairs.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>References to International Development Committee</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any reference in this Schedule to the International Development Committee <?new-line?>of the House of Commons—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>if the name of that Committee is changed, is to be treated as a <?new-line?>reference to that Committee by its new name, and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>if the functions of that Committee (or substantially corresponding <?new-line?>functions) become functions of a different Committee of the House <?new-line?>of Commons, is to be treated as a reference to the Committee by <?new-line?>which those functions are exercisable.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>Any question arising under sub-paragraph (1) is to be determined by the <?new-line?>Speaker of the House of Commons.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</ScheduleBody>
</Schedule>
</Schedules>
</Primary>
</Legislation>