<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><HansardDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print file:/C:/Users/edwardsc/Desktop/LordsHansard_Print2008.xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print"><House name="Lords"><System type="Cover"><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/Cover/24839ABC33DAE2963A8569960FB9A2D14DC1CEC4" __version__="1.6"><Cover-wrapper><Cover bcoveruri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/Cover/69960FB9A2D14DC1CEC424839ABC33DAE2963A85" cdate="14" cday="Friday" cmonth="February" cyear="2014" date="7" day="Friday" htmlBackCoverUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/Html_Index/24839ABC33D14DC1CEC4DAE2963A8569960FB9A2" htmlIndexUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/Html_Index/69960FB9A224839ABC33DAE2963A85D14DC1CEC4" indexuri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/Index/DAE2963A8569960FB9A2D14DC1CEC424839ABC33" issue="113" maxparts="1" month="February" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" type="back" volume="752" year="2014"><Contents><hs_FPNormal>Leasehold
Reform (Amendment) Bill</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>359</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Citizenship
(Armed Forces) Bill</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>369</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>International
Development (Gender Equality)
Bill</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>375</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Deep
Sea Mining Bill</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>391</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Written
Answers<I>WA
87</I></hs_FPNormal></Contents></Cover></Cover-wrapper></Fragment></System><System type="Debate" ColStart="359"><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/4B86F94AFB987A7F8E281D50515493265D9AD2C8" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AA-AA</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_Venue UID="14020749000333" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000333">House
of Lords</hs_Venue><hs_date UID="14020749000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000001">Friday, 7 February
2014.</hs_date><hs_time UID="14020749000248" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000248">10
am</hs_time><hs_Procedure UID="14020749000324" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000324">Prayers—read by
the Lord Bishop of
Wakefield.</hs_Procedure><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020749000320" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000320">Leasehold
Reform (Amendment) Bill</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="14020749000249" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000249">10.06
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="14020749000329" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000329">Moved by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Williams of Trafford" PimsId="7032" UID="14020749000279" xid="2215" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000279">Baroness
Williams of Trafford</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020749000275" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000275">That the Bill be read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="14020749000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000002"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Williams of Trafford" PimsId="7032" UID="14020749000280" xid="2215" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000280">Baroness
Williams of Trafford (Con):</Member></B>
My<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:06:02"></hs_TimeCode> Lords,
<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:06:12"></hs_TimeCode>this very
specific Leasehold Reform (Amendment) Bill will correct an anomaly that
currently exists in the Leasehold Reform, Housing and Urban Development
Act 1993 that requires leaseholders of flats who wish to participate in
enfranchisement or to extend their leases to have personally to sign
those notices. The Bill provides that where notices are served under
Sections 13 and 42 of the Act they are no longer required to
be signed personally by a leaseholder but may be signed on their
behalf<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:06:49"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000003">I
begin by congratulating Philip Hollobone MP and David Nuttall MP, who
steered the Bill through the other place. It has enjoyed cross-party
support and, appropriately for a Private Member’s Bill, is
clearly defined in its aim and does not seek wholesale reform, which I
hope will ensure its safe passage through your Lordships’ House.
I also thank the Association of Leasehold Enfranchisement
Practitioners, whose work in campaigning for improvements in leasehold
legislation over the years has yielded some very helpful advice, both
in the other place and in my preparation for
today<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:07:24"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000004">I
must declare an interest in this subject as detailed in the <I>Register
of Lords’ Interests</I>. Section 13 of the Leasehold Reform,
Housing and Urban Development Act 1993 provides the right for
leaseholders of flats to participate in collective enfranchisement and
Section 42 provides for leaseholders to extend their lease.
At present, notices under both these sections can only be
signed personally by the leaseholder and not by a person acting under
the power of attorney or under direction from the Court of
Protection<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:08:05"></hs_TimeCode>. The
wording of the legislation states that these notices must
be,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="14020749000240" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000240">“signed
by each of the tenants, or (as the case may be) by the tenant, by whom
it is
given”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="14020749000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000005">This
wording has since been interpreted by the courts to mean that the
notice must be signed personally by the leaseholder. The amendment
would thus allow a person such as a solicitor or a relative who has
appropriate authority to sign on the leaseholder’s
behalf<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:08:37"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="14020749000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000006">The
types of individual that this amendment might assist are in many cases
the most vulnerable in our society: for example, those who are
physically unable to sign because of a disability, those who are
seriously ill or those who are mentally incapacitated. It would 
<?notus-xml column=360?>also extend to those living or working abroad who
cannot, for practical reasons, be physically present to
sign<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:08:59"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000007">It
might be useful at this point to state what the Bill does not do. It
does not deal with any other part of the Leasehold Reform, Housing and
Urban Development Act 1993, or with the Leasehold Reform Act 1967. It
deals purely with Section 13 in relation to collective enfranchisement
claims and Section 42 concerning individual leasehold claims, both in
relation to blocks of
flats<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:09:29"></hs_TimeCode>. To extend
the reach of the Bill would probably ensure its demise, and I am sure
that noble Lords would not wish that to happen. I must also point out
that although the Act’s provisions extend to Wales, the Bill
does not alter the legal provision in relation to Wales. Housing is a
devolved matter, as I am sure noble Lords know, and if the Welsh
Government wanted to make the same changes for Wales, they would need
to bring forward their own legislation to do
that<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:10:01"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000008">I
hope the House will recognise the considerable benefits that the Bill
would bring to many vulnerable people, who often need others to act on
their behalf. If the Bill can enjoy the same support in your
Lordships’ House as it did in the other place, it would be a
small step in ironing out just one of the difficulties that
leaseholders face. I beg to
move<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:10:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="14020749000250" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000250">10.10
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:10:26"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000009"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Beecham" PimsId="5821" UID="14020749000281" xid="2085" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000281">Lord
Beecham (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords I congratulate the noble Baroness
on bringing forward the Bill. As one ex-council leader to another, I am
delighted that she has done so comprehensively and explained it so
well. I declare an interest as the holder of a leasehold interest in
the block of flats in which I
live<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:10:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000010">I
hope that the noble Baroness will forgive me if I depart slightly from
the provisions of the Bill, which she rightly says does not deal at all
with other issues of leasehold reform and more particularly the
commonhold issues. I suspect that the noble Baroness, Lady Gardner of
Parkes, may wish to raise those today and will certainly raise them in
a Question next week. I hope that the Minister will forgive me, too,
but I take this opportunity to address this almost by way of advance
warning. I wonder whether it is not time for the Government to review
how the commonhold process is working. How many cases have there been
where the right has been exercised and will any further changes need to
be made in the legislation that permits commonholds to be created? The
impression is that not very many have gone through, so it is perhaps
now time, several years after the latest piece of legislation, for a
review—although obviously not today. Perhaps the Government will
look at that and give an indication of whether they might be willing to
conduct a review or perhaps ask the Law Commission to do
so<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:12:10"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000011">Having said that, I
strongly support the Bill. It is a small measure, but it deals with a
matter that can affect a number of people. The House is indebted to the
noble Baroness for bringing it
forward.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/40501DF5E95AAF64517D90BC9AD87344AD8FA366" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AB-AC1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="14020749000251" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000251">10.12
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:30:00"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000012"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Gardner of Parkes" PimsId="3383" UID="14020749000282" xid="1170" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000282">Baroness
Gardner of Parkes (Con):</Member></B> I welcome this amending Bill
today and strongly support it, for a number different reasons. First,
there is clearly a need 
<?notus-xml column=361?>in these days when communications have moved on so far to regularise
this position. I was really surprised that even the Court of Protection
could not authorise someone else to do it on your behalf—that
amazed me. I thought that it had supreme powers to take over and look
after things that other people could not, yet it has been confirmed to
me that this is an instance when it is not able to do
it<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:13:01"></hs_TimeCode>. So that is
very important<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:13:02"></hs_TimeCode>.
I am also surprised that it has taken more than 20 years to get to the
point that we have got to today. If it really has been a problem, how
come no one has brought this issue up before? It gives us hope that
someone is now looking at the problems of leasehold, which is crying
out for reform<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:13:24"></hs_TimeCode>.
I am delighted to hear the points made by the noble Lord, Lord Beecham,
because I strongly agree—and I intend to mention the Law
Commission. This Bill is enabling us to discuss this subject a little
bit today, which is another reason why I welcome it. I should say that
my interest is registered in the register—I am a
leaseholder<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:13:49"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:13:46"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000013">I
have asked quite a number of Questions in this House over the years,
but the only Question on which no one from anywhere in the House came
in with a supplementary was on leasehold. Afterwards, a number of noble
Lords said to me that they would have liked to come in but they had no
idea what it was all about. There is a need to inform the public more
about the situation so that they know about such things as the point
that the noble Lord, Lord Beecham, made about commonhold, and the
subject of my Question next week. In that Question, I will ask about
the requirement that there is 100% agreement from people in a block of
flats to change from leasehold to commonhold. That is almost
unbelievable. I have a dossier of printouts from <I>Hansard</I>, with
Minister after Minister—including the noble Baroness, Lady
Hanham, who was not able to be here today, but said that I could quote
her—agreeing that it is impossible to get 100% consent, for all
sorts of reasons. It is sometimes because people are away or, in the
terms of the Bill today, because nobody was authorised to sign. For
whatever reason, 100% agreement is impossible. If you have a crooked or
sharp operator owning the head lease they could bribe one person to
oppose the move, and everyone else’s hope is
gone<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:15:25"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:15:32"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000014">I
was sorry to lose Mark Prisk as Housing
Minister<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:15:24"></hs_TimeCode>, as he
chaired an excellent roundtable meeting at the Department for
Communities and Local Government last year. It was because of that that
the redress scheme, which will come into force this year, has become
law, and it will be of great value to many leaseholders. At that
meeting was a huge range of people; it included organisations such as
the Association of Residential Managing Agents, or ARMA, and
ARLA—the letting one—LEASE, and Peverel, who were the
villains of the piece but keep sending me letters and have now become
angels. There were lots of politicians, including Members from both the
Lords and the Commons. It was such a comprehensive meeting. For the
first time, all these people, who were concerned but were looking at
different aspects of the issue, were together and hearing from one
another about the other side’s problems. But ALEP, the
Association of Leasehold Enfranchisement Practitioners, was not there,
and we were told that we would have another of
these 
<?notus-xml column=362?>meetings. I am really very hopeful that the new
Minister, Kris
Hopkins<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:16:48"></hs_TimeCode>, will
continue that practice, because we need to make
progress<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:17:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000015">I
support very clearly the comment made by the noble Lord, Lord Beecham,
about the Law Commission. I gave a keynote speech—I do not think
that I would ever do it again, because it was such hard work—to
the Federation of Private Residents’ Associations, in which I
said that it was time that the Law Commission looked at this whole
property issue and, in particular, at leasehold and commonhold,
although the whole thing needs
review<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:17:27"></hs_TimeCode>. It was
interesting because one of the people in the audience stood up and said
that they were from the Law Commission and that it did not do anything
off its own bat anymore. The Law Commission does a report only if it is
asked to do so by the Government, because then the Government pay. I
had not realised that—I have been here so long in this House
that I remember the days when the Law Commission brought forward
reports on a wide variety of subjects. Apparently, that has changed.
Therefore, it is very important for us to realise that the initiative
for such a report must come from Parliament and from the Government;
that is something that we should
consider<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:18:12"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:16:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000016">There<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:18:14"></hs_TimeCode>
needs to be a much wider understanding of leasehold and the
alternatives. In the London area, there are estimated to be about 3
million leaseholders and between 5 million and 7 million people living
in leasehold property, and most of them are very unhappy with the
situation in which they find themselves. Lots of them, when they took
the lease, were delighted to get their flat, having worked out all the
problems of purchase, but then found that all sorts of clauses were in
there that they had no idea about—they had not taken them in.
This is where the problem comes
up<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:18:54"></hs_TimeCode>. It is
definitely time to simplify the property law; I ask the Government to
look at that, and to look at the possibility of doing
something<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:19:05"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000017">Another
issue that is very relevant is the Water Bill. The noble Earl, Lord
Lytton, who is a highly experienced surveyor, has tabled amendments to
it that will be debated in the coming week. Leaseholders are totally
excluded from any hope of getting the type of flood insurance that
others get. Other people who will not get any will be occupants of
council property and retirement
sites<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:19:33"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:19:20"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:19:11"></hs_TimeCode>.
This situation will be damaging. The Water Bill should be looked at
because the financial implications of this situation for individuals
and even the nation are huge. The noble Earl spent some time explaining
it to me yesterday and will explain it himself when he moves his
amendments<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:19:49"></hs_TimeCode>. A
joint warning has been issued in relation to the Water Bill on the part
of the British Property Federation, the Leasehold Knowledge Partnership
and the Council of Mortgage Lenders which all point out how badly
leaseholders will be treated in this
regard<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:20:00"></hs_TimeCode>. Sir
Peter Bottomley in the Commons has made a great contribution to the
leasehold issue over the years. As there is not enough time to detail
it now, I refer noble Lords to the Commons <I>Hansard</I> of 24 January
2014, where he sets out very clearly his valuable
views<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:20:22"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000018">I
would like to put forward a brief list of matters that should be
thoroughly examined and that I hope will be brought forward in either
primary or secondary 
<?notus-xml column=363?>legislation in the near future. Above all, there is
a need for transparency in leasehold and for honesty and accuracy in
all dealings. Leaseholders have suffered from crooked landlords not
revealing that they are direct financial beneficiaries of contracts for
insurance, building, management and all sorts of things. It is
scandalous that the people who pay the bills have not been able to find
out whether a huge rake-off from those bills has gone to a corrupt head
lessee or
freeholder<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:21:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000019">The
lack of maintenance of buildings is a major complaint. Sometimes
buildings have been allowed to deteriorate for years and residents have
been completely frustrated in all efforts to get the work done. Peter
Bottomley has called for failures in some extremely serious cases to be
criminalised. I have not gone into the detail of which aspects he
thinks should be criminalised, whether it is the corrupt taking of the
money or the failure to maintain buildings, so, again, I refer noble
Lords to his comments. The OFT is carrying out an investigation of the
residential leasehold property management
market<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:21:36"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000020">As
leasehold is a property tenure used only in Hawaii and the
UK—this was stated very clearly during the passage of earlier
Bills in which I was involved—I think it is time that we looked
at it again and I commend the comments of the noble Lord, Lord Beecham,
in that regard. I still have a flat in Australia under a system known
as strata title. However, I understand that there are faults in the
Commonhold and Leasehold Reform Act 2002, and we should also look at
that. The major fault is the 100% agreement that is required in certain
circumstances<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:22:18"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000021">I
have set out these matters in order to place them on record in
<I>Hansard</I> as a starting point in explaining some of the problems
connected with leasehold property to people in general and to Members
of this House. I seek to give us an idea of how to move on. The
Minister—Kris Hopkins—sent a letter on 6 January 2014 to
the Association of Leasehold Enfranchisement Practitioners, which
states, “This Bill aims to make a minor but worthwhile
change”. That exactly sums up the position.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000022">I<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:09:59"></hs_TimeCode>
hope that the Bill will make progress. I was fascinated to hear my
noble friend, in introducing it, refer to one small step being taken. I
was born in Parkes, where the radio telescope transmitted man’s
first step on the moon worldwide, because they could not see it in the
US. Therefore, the words “one small step” are highly
significant to me and may be a good omen that we will get something out
of this process. I support the Bill and congratulate my noble friend on
bringing it before the
House<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:23:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/F4130F9B6150DF7621DD61D94841D589228FC47A" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AC2-AE1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="14020749000252" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000252">10.23
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:23:26"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000023"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Browning" PimsId="5795" UID="14020749000283" xid="2065" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000283">Baroness
Browning (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, I refer noble Lords to my entry
in the <I>Register of Lords’ Interests</I> as a leaseholder. I
congratulate my noble friend on bringing this much-needed legislation
forward. It is particularly needed for those people who are responsible
for assisting elderly relatives to dispose of property, often because
the relatives are going into residential care and the assets need to be
sold to pay for that. Once a lease drops much below 70 years, it
becomes increasingly difficult for people to whom the relevant property
is sold to remortgage or get a mortgage. The
necessity of 
<?notus-xml column=364?>extending the lease is particularly important for
those elderly people at that stage in their lives. Many elderly people
in that situation would benefit from the proposals in the
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:24:30"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000024">However,
I do have a reservation. Where the Court of Protection is involved,
people have power of attorney or solicitors have been instructed to act
on behalf of a client, it seems to me that there is a clear ability to
hand on the right to sign on behalf of the leaseholder. However, has my
noble friend given any thought to the question of who assesses capacity
in the case of mental incapacity? The House is currently giving
post-legislative scrutiny to the Mental Capacity Act 2005 and I am
pleased to be on the relevant committee. One of the weaknesses that
evidence brought before that committee has demonstrated is that, other
than among medical and social care professionals, there is very little
knowledge of the need to assess capacity: who can do it and how you
then act accordingly. I suggest that people such as bankers, solicitors
and others are not terribly clear about their responsibilities under
the Mental Capacity Act and ask my noble friend to take a look at
that<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:25:32"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="14020749000253" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000253">10.25
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:25:32"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000025"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord McKenzie of Luton" PimsId="1827" UID="14020749000284" xid="1824" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000284">Lord
McKenzie of Luton (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, I start by drawing
attention to my interests in the register and making clear, as did my
noble friend Lord Beecham, that we support the Bill and do not seek to
amend it. We congratulate the noble Baroness, Lady Williams of
Trafford, on taking up this measure and, we hope, seeing it through to
a successful conclusion. We also congratulate David Nuttall on piloting
the Bill through another
place<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:26:04"></hs_TimeCode>. It is, as
we have heard, a narrow measure, although the noble Baroness, Lady
Gardner of Parkes, and my noble friend Lord Beecham could not resist
the temptation to widen the debate. I hope noble Lords will forgive me
if I do not follow suit as I think that is a debate for another
day<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:26:23"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000026">The
Bill touches on two important rights of leaseholders: the right of
collective enfranchisement—that is, the right to compel the sale
of the freehold—and the right to require an extension to an
existing long lease. We support these rights and consider it important
that they can be effectively taken up. As we have heard, a key part of
progressing these rights is the giving of notice to a landlord. That is
the tenant’s notice in the case of a lease extension and the
initial notice in the case of collective enfranchisement. In both
cases, these kick-start the
process<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:27:01"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000027">We
accept that the courts have clearly stated that the provisions of
Section 99 of the 1993 Act require the tenant themselves—the
leaseholder themselves—to actually sign the Section 42 and
Section 13 notices. Mr Justice Lloyd was cited by Mr Nuttall
at Third Reading in the Commons, at col. 561 of Commons <I>Hansard</I>
of 24 January 2014, as distinguishing the method of signature of
notices required under these sections and other notices required under
the Act. As the debate in the other place highlighted, we would be
advantaged if we could better understand why Parliament chose to make
this distinction, but it seems—I have not revisited the
debates—that the limited scrutiny at the time does not throw any
light on the matter. I do not know whether the Minister can help us
further on that
today<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:27:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=365?><hs_para UID="14020749000028" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000028">As we have heard, the
purpose of the Bill is to redress for England the suggested
disadvantage that arises from the requirements of a personal signature.
I have given the Minister notice of my next question: what is the
position when there are joint leaseholders? Are they both required to
sign or is either one of them sufficient? It is suggested that this
affects broadly two groups: those who delegate some or all of
their leaseholder responsibilities either generally or specifically for
one of the processes under consideration to a lawyer, management
company or valuer, for example, and may themselves be abroad; and those
whose mental or physical impairment means that they appoint
someone to act on their behalf, under, say, a power of attorney
or, as we have heard, the Court of Protection. That is, the
first set of circumstances are entered into by choice, the second are
effectively
unavoidable<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:29:04"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000029">As
regards lease extensions, as the Leasehold Advisory Service booklet
makes clear, the process is not just a matter of signing a request;
there is preparatory work before notice on the landlord is given as
well as a prescribed route once the notice has been given. The
leaseholder is responsible for the landlord’s reasonable costs
from the date of receipt of the notice. Service of the notice will
trigger a timeframe within which the landlord can require evidence, and
the tenants must respond. The landlord can require a deposit and serve
a counter-notice, and there is a timeframe attached to a route to the
leasehold valuation tribunal.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000030" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000030">However<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:29:51"></hs_TimeCode>,
the leaseholder is very much in control, especially at the start of the
process, and it might be argued that there is no compelling reason to
change the law for those who choose to delegate the functions, because
it should be perfectly possible, even for those living abroad, to
factor in the personal signing of a notice. However, the provisions
concerning collective enfranchisement and the giving of a Section 13
initial notice potentially have wider implications if it is not just a
single tenant who is pursuing an individual benefit. If a potentially
qualifying tenant can be successfully challenged, this could presumably
undermine the action of the remaining tenants, due to the threshold
requirements. It is not so readily under the control of each individual
tenant, and reaching people abroad on a timely basis is potentially
more
important<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:30:45"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000031" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000031">We therefore believe
that that is a strong argument for the change in the law that the Bill
provides. An even stronger imperative in the case of both
notices is that when, because of incapacity, someone
has to rely on a third party to sign notices and execute
transactions, it is through necessity, not choice. I wonder whether the
status quo could anyway be challenged under human rights or equalities
legislation, because the personal signature requirement could
clearly be discriminatory to some disabled people in some
circumstances.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000032">However<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:39:44"></hs_TimeCode>,
the Bill rectifies the matter for England but leaves the position open
in Wales. The Minister may wish to comment on that. Indeed, what should
be the advice to someone in Wales who has entered into a power of
attorney? Should they nevertheless individually sign? Is the notice
capable of being challenged by the
landlord<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:31:46"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=366?><hs_para UID="14020749000033" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000033">The
rationale for the Bill has been admirably summed up by its promoter at
col. 562 of Commons <I>Hansard</I> of 24 January. We agree with that
summary, and the Bill has our support.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="14020749000254" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000254"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:31:57"></hs_TimeCode>10.32
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000034" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000034"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020749000285" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000285">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Communities and
Local Government (Baroness Stowell of Beeston) (Con):</Member></B> My
Lords, I share and echo the comments of noble Lords in congratulating
my noble friend Lady Williams of Trafford on, and thanking her for,
introducing this Bill. I hope that she will not mind me informing your
Lordships that this is the first time that she has spoken in the
Chamber, and I do not know how many other Members of your
Lordships’ House have spoken for the first time in the Chamber
while being responsible for a Private Member’s Bill. She gave
her maiden speech in Grand Committee in the Moses Room, so this is an
occasion all on its own, even though the Bill is important.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000035" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000035">I, too, must declare my
interest as an owner-occupier of a leasehold flat. Like other noble
Lords have done, I should mention the good work of my honourable
friends in the other place, David Nuttall and Philip Hollobone, in
introducing and leading the Bill. I congratulate them on the progress
it has made so far. I am pleased to say that the Government
fully support the Bill as it stands. Some brief and well targeted
amendments that were brought forward in the other place by the
honourable friends I mentioned, jointly with my honourable friend the
Housing Minister, have ensured that the Bill can effectively achieve
its worthwhile aim.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000036" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000036">Importantly<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:39:44"></hs_TimeCode>,
the Bill will, if it reaches the statute book, affect only the position
in England, not in Wales—housing being a devolved
matter<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:34:01"></hs_TimeCode>. This is
probably the right moment to respond to the point raised by the
noble Lord, Lord McKenzie, about Wales. I urge Members of the Welsh
Assembly to look at this legislation and consider it carefully. I do
not believe that prior to the Bill coming forward—and, I hope,
achieving Royal Assent—there is any discrepancy in terms of
equality law, but clearly there will be a difference between the
treatment of people in England and those in Wales who live in leasehold
properties. I hope that the Assembly will look at what we are doing
here and learn from
it<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:34:57"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000037">As my noble friend Lady
Williams explained, the Bill aims, by amending Section
99(5)—</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000038"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Richard" PimsId="361" UID="14020749000286" xid="1410" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000286">Lord
Richard (Lab):</Member></B> I do not quite follow the position
regarding Wales, because it has been explained that Wales is
deliberately excluded from the provisions of Bill. None the less,
subsection (3) of Clause 2 states:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="14020749000234" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000234">“The Act
extends to England and
Wales”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="14020749000222" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000222">Does
it<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:35:26"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="14020749000039" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000039"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020749000287" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000287">Baroness
Stowell of Beeston:</Member></B> The Act that is in place, which this
Bill is amending, extends to Wales, but because housing is a devolved
matter, the way in which we are amending the Act is specific, in that
the amendment applies only to England. One might describe it as a
convoluted way of going about it, as is sometimes necessary when
amending legislation. However, the effect will be that the Act that
this Bill is amending remains as it is and applies to England and
Wales, but 
<?notus-xml column=367?>the specific amendment to the Act via this Bill will
apply only to England, because we cannot apply it to Wales. It is a
devolved
matter<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:36:25"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000040"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Richard" PimsId="361" UID="14020749000288" xid="1410" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000288">Lord
Richard:</Member></B> The Bill states that the Act extends to
England and Wales. Does
it<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:36:29"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000041" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000041"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020749000289" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000289">Baroness
Stowell of Beeston:</Member></B> Okay, I see where the noble Lord is
coming from. The Act extends to England and Wales but we cannot amend
it in respect of Wales. Wales has to amend it for itself because it is
a devolved matter. I hope that that clarifies the situation for the
noble
Lord<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:36:57"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:36:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000042"><B><Member ContinuationText="Noble Lords" PimsId="0" UID="14020749000290" xid="2182" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000290">Noble
Lords:</Member></B>
Oh<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:36:58"></hs_TimeCode>!</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000043" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000043"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020749000291" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000291">Baroness
Stowell of Beeston:</Member></B> I understand it—and the
Government support the Bill.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000044" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000044">As my noble friend Lady
Williams explained, the Bill aims, by amending Section 99(5) of the
Leasehold Reform, Housing and Urban Development Act 1993, to remove
current restrictions on who can sign the legal notices required when
leaseholders exercise certain statutory rights. At present, the
leaseholder of a flat who wants to extend their lease or take part in
acquiring the freehold of their block must personally sign the legal
notices required. Currently, no one else is allowed to sign on behalf
of a leaseholder who is physically unable to do so, even if they are
acting under a power of attorney. This includes situations in which a
leaseholder has become the subject of mental incapacity and the Court
of Protection has issued a direction. This position has been confirmed
by case law<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:37:58"></hs_TimeCode>. I
should say to my noble friend Lady Browning, on the point that she
raised about testing, that it would not be necessary for anyone to test
or prove mental incapacity on the part of the leaseholder in order for
this Bill to assist
them<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:38:16"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000045">This Private
Member’s Bill would enable the legal notices to be signed in
future on the leaseholder’s behalf. In bringing forward this
change, it will help a range of people. In response to a point that my
noble friend Lady Gardner of Parkes raised about the extent of those
affected by the Bill, they are relatively small in number, but our
decisions to act should not always be based on the weight of the
mailbag we receive. If the case to act is clear—which this Bill
demonstrates—and the solution is simple and easy to administer,
and doing so brings no downside to others, I am glad that this
Government are able to offer their
support<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:39:08"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000046" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000046">In addition to the
elderly and vulnerable, the removal of current restrictions would also
be helpful to those who are charged with looking after the financial
affairs of a leaseholder—for example, relations who are acting
under a power of attorney. The Bill could also help some leaseholders
living abroad who need to sign these notices. For example, work may
take a flat’s leaseholder abroad for a period, and, without the
ability to have someone act with appropriate authority on their behalf
in respect of the property, it may be difficult for the leaseholder to
exercise their statutory rights.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000047" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000047">If individual
leaseholders who live or work abroad are hindered in this way, that
could have an unfortunate knock-on effect on other leaseholders in the
block. Where, for example, several leaseholders want to exercise 
<?notus-xml column=368?>their collective right to acquire the freehold of
their block, in order to satisfy the qualifying criteria they may need
one or more leaseholders who live or work abroad to take
part<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:40:12"></hs_TimeCode>. While the
Bill would not make any change to leaseholders’ rights, it might
helpfully remove a practical barrier to the efficient exercise of those
rights<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:40:17"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000048" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000048">We
have seen from the contributions made today that there is widespread
support for the Bill and I hope that it will receive a fair wind during
its onward progress. It offers help and hope to leaseholders who might
otherwise face an insurmountable barrier to exercising their rights. In
doing so, the Bill will assist the families and friends who care for
vulnerable leaseholders and thereby give them greater peace of mind,
too<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:40:55"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000049" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000049">My
noble friend Lady Gardner of Parkes has taken the opportunity to raise
a number of interesting issues that are not directly related to the
Bill. I am aware that a range of leasehold issues give my noble friend
and others cause for concern, and she outlined some of them
today.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000050" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000050"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:41:24"></hs_TimeCode>The
noble Lord, Lord Beecham, joined my noble friend Lady Gardner in
raising the issue of commonhold. As the noble Lord knows, commonhold
law is a matter for the Ministry of Justice rather than DCLG, but I
shall certainly make my colleagues in the MoJ aware of the points that
he raised, ahead of the Oral Question that my noble friend has tabled
on the Order Paper for
Monday<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:41:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000051" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000051">I
will reflect carefully on the points raised by my noble friend Lady
Gardner of Parkes and discuss them further with my honourable friend
Kris Hopkins, the Housing Minister. I hope my noble friend will feel
that he is just as good at his job of Housing Minister as his
predecessor. He is certainly interested in these issues and I hope that
we will continue to have a constructive dialogue about the legitimate
points she
raised<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:42:38"></hs_TimeCode>, which
deserve full
consideration<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:42:52"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000052" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000052">The
noble Lord, Lord McKenzie, asked about co-signatories to a lease. I can
confirm that where there are co-signatories, it may be necessary for
both to sign the notices in person. This Bill will assist in situations
where one or more of the leaseholders is unable to sign in person. I am
sure that my noble friend Lady Williams will confirm that when she
responds<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:43:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000053">I
am pleased to give the Government’s support for the Bill. I hope
that it will receive a Second Reading today, pass successfully on to
its next stages in this House and in due course receive Royal
Assent<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:43:33"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000054" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000054"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Skelmersdale" PimsId="719" UID="14020749000292" xid="1438" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000292">Lord
Skelmersdale (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, I wonder whether my noble
friend can clear up the issue of Wales. It is my understanding that
Clause 1 of the Bill specifically excludes Wales. Therefore, because
Wales is mentioned in Clause 1, this Bill has to apply to Wales as
well<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:43:59"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000055" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000055"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020749000293" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000293">Baroness
Stowell of Beeston:</Member></B> My noble friend is right. I thought I
had clarified this matter in response to the noble Lord, Lord Richard,
who asked the question previously. My noble friend is correct. The key
point, I stress, is that the change this Bill is making affects only
leaseholders in England. It does not affect leaseholders in
Wales<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:44:30"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=369?><hs_para UID="14020749000056" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000056"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Williams of Trafford" PimsId="7032" UID="14020749000294" xid="2215" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000294">Baroness
Williams of Trafford (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, I thank all noble
Lords who contributed to the debate—which, as I expected, ranged
further than the Bill. This is because there are so many concerns
surrounding leasehold issues. I also thank the Minister for answering
all of the non-Bill and Bill
questions<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:44:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000057" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000057">I will pick up on a few
points. My noble friend Lady Gardner of Parkes asked why it has taken
more than 20 years to get to the point today where this issue is such
an anomaly in the legislation. I agree. However, here we are, and I am
pleased that the Bill has had a favourable response. She also pointed
to the lack of knowledge generally about leasehold. I confess that I
was in that camp until about a week ago. It is a minefield and, as she
said, the Bill is but one small step in ironing out some of the
anomalies in the original
Act<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:45:46"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000058">The noble Lord, Lord
McKenzie, raised the issue of Wales, as did the noble Lord opposite
whose name—I hope he will forgive me—I do not know. I
have been desperately looking in the book. To reiterate the point,
while the Bill extends to Wales, the legislation does not. I hope that
following today’s debate or the Bill’s passage, the Welsh
Assembly may take forward this legislation under its devolved
powers<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:46:24"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000059" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000059">My
noble friend Lady Browning and the Minister answered the point about
who assesses incapacity. I am pleased to hear that it is not necessary
to prove that
incapacity<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:46:41"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000060" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000060">The
noble Lord, Lord Beecham, and my noble friend Lady Gardner of Parkes
asked about commonhold. This is an important but new area which will be
worthy of exploration going
forward<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:47:05"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000061" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000061">I
hope that I have covered all the points that the Minister has already
addressed. I thank all noble Lords who have contributed to the debate
and I ask the House to give the Bill a Second
Reading.</hs_para><hs_Procedure UID="14020749000325" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000325">Bill
read a second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/CEB5B4D9984D8F29407F692F751D0E587E9C312F" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AE2-AF1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020749000321" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000321">Citizenship
(Armed Forces) Bill</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="14020749000255" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000255">10.47
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="14020749000330" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000330">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Trefgarne" PimsId="4328" UID="14020749000295" xid="1470" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000295">Lord
Trefgarne</Member></B></hs_TabledBy><hs_Question UID="14020749000276" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000276">That
the Bill be read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate>
<hs_para UID="14020749000062" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000062"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Trefgarne" PimsId="4328" UID="14020749000296" xid="1470" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000296">Lord
Trefgarne (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, the Bill has, of course, now
passed through the other place in the expert hands of my honourable
friend Mr Jonathan Lord. It allows the Secretary of State—that
is to say, the Home Secretary—to waive the requirement in the
case of members of the Armed Forces to have been in the United Kingdom
on the date five years before an application for naturalisation. Your
Lordships will appreciate that members of the Armed Forces could be on
an overseas posting at the relevant date and thus placed at a
disadvantage<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:48:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000063" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000063">Accordingly,
the Bill seeks to amend Schedule 1 to the British Nationality Act 1981,
which sets out the requirements for naturalisation as a British citizen

<?notus-xml column=370?>under Section 6(1) of that Act. That section allows
for naturalisation on the grounds of residence in the United Kingdom.
The same Act requires the applicant to be physically present in the
United Kingdom at the start of the five-year qualifying period for
naturalisation. Although so-called Crown service provides an exemption
from this provision, that exemption can in practice be used only in
cases of exceptional Crown service. The effect of the Bill is to
broaden this exemption to accommodate service in Her Majesty’s
forces, including the circumstances where a member has been
subsequently discharged or has returned to the United Kingdom. The
definition of members of the Armed Forces is taken from Section 50 of
the British Nationality Act, to which I have just
referred<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:49:31"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:49:31"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000064" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000064">I am glad to say that
the costs associated with implementing this Bill will be negligible
since these applications are funded through application fees and no
significant change in the volume of applications is expected. Service
personnel will benefit from the Bill as soon as its provisions take
effect, which is set at two months from Royal Assent. I beg to
move.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="14020749000256" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000256"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:49:56"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.50
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:49:56"></hs_TimeCode></I><I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:50:08"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time>
<hs_para UID="14020749000065" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000065"><B><Member ContinuationText="The Lord Bishop of Wakefield" PimsId="4481" UID="14020749000297" xid="2005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000297">The
Lord Bishop of Wakefield:</Member></B> My Lords, I hope that not too
much of what is about to follow will be seen as motherhood and apple
pie. Being at the stage of trying to lose some weight, too much apple
pie is no good thing, and I have not yet tried motherhood. Those of us
who are survivors of the post-Second World War baby boomer generation
probably had parents who served in the forces during that war. My own
father was a Royal Marine. He rarely spoke of the war in detail, but
often commended the courage and generosity of others with whom he had
served. A frequent theme was the remarkable generosity of foreign and
Commonwealth nationals who came to serve with the British Armed Forces:
Australians, Canadians, New Zealanders and so on, as well as Polish
soldiers and airmen, and of course, then as now, the Gurkhas. This is a
remarkable story, and one that we will remember again next year when we
commemorate the 100th anniversary of Gallipoli in the First World
War.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000066" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000066">For that
reason I congratulate the honourable Member for Woking on bringing this
matter forward in another place. It is an inspired initiative and it is
very encouraging that Her Majesty’s Government have embraced it
so readily as an extension of all that has been so far achieved by
putting the Armed Forces covenant on to the statute book. Some three
years ago, I was pleased to offer a certain amount of time myself,
alongside Peers from all parties and, of course, the Cross Benches to
this very subject. During my time in this House it has been one of the
initiatives in which I have been proud to play a very modest
part.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000067">The
covenant has brought into statute law a tacit understanding of what our
nation owes to Her Majesty’s forces and what they might expect
from us in mutual support. It is an acknowledgment of the courage,
tenacity and sacrifice made by those serving in the forces on land, in
the air and at sea. But all those qualities are underpinned by a deeper
foundation rooted in the real generosity of those who have given their
time and sometimes their lives. This Bill recognises a still greater
sense of self-offering by those who serve in 
<?notus-xml column=371?>our forces but who hail from other nations and parts
of the world. The Bill is imaginative in drawing the implications of
the armed services covenant into conjunction with the British
Nationality Act 1981, as just noted by the noble Lord, Lord Trefgarne.
The amending of the requirements of that Act of Parliament ensures that
foreign and Commonwealth members and former members of Her
Majesty’s Armed Forces can apply for naturalisation on equal
terms, irrespective of whether they were posted in the United Kingdom
itself or
overseas.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000068" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000068">This
is, of course, entirely consistent with the underlying principles
enshrined in the Armed Forces covenant; namely, to combat disadvantage
and discrimination. It is a clear sign of an act of good faith and of
the trust which is implied by the very nature of the Armed Forces
covenant. A covenant is an expression of mutual trust with
implications, indeed imperatives, for those at either end of the
covenant who thus make it a reality. I hope that noble Lords will
forgive me for lapsing into theology, something which I know earlier
politicians have considered takes us away from the main point. It is no
accident, I would argue, that the word “covenant” is
firmly rooted in the Judaeo-Christian tradition. There are at least
four covenants enshrined in the Jewish scriptures, and an alternative
name for the New Testament is indeed the New Covenant, which is an
exact translation of the Greek. For the reason of the use of the word
“covenant” alone, but for so much more in the emphasis on
trust implied, the church is entirely supportive of these underlying
principles.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000069" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000069">The
Bill is not about providing preferential treatment or positive
discrimination for one particular section of society. Rather, it is
about building inclusive communities by combating marginalisation and
disadvantage. At heart it is about supporting the common good. For all
these reasons I want us to support the Bill with all our
hearts.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/2B29145689D25516B8E3EDEF344C353468D4C5E8" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AF2-AG</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="14020749000257" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000257"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:55:18"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.55
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:55:18"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time>
<hs_para UID="14020749000070" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000070"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="14020749000298" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000298">Lord
Cormack (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, it is very refreshing to be here
on a Friday in early 2014 with a Bill before us on which I think we can
all agree. It is a rather refreshing contrast to the experiences of
recent Friday sittings. I give my support to my noble friend Lord
Trefgarne unreservedly, and I do so for personal as well as general
reasons. Having been born in Lincolnshire, I was brought up in Scotland
during the war, as my father was stationed up there. One of his prized
possessions, which is still a treasured memento within the family, was
a little silver cigarette lighter inscribed by Polish officers whom he
had instructed in the arts of navigation in the war. I can remember one
or two of those Polish officers coming to our home and my father saying
what marvellous men they were. At the end of the war I went back to
Grimsby, the town I had been born in. A Polish regiment, the Carpathian
Lancers, was being disbanded. Many of those soldiers became esteemed
members of the local community. They also took up British citizenship,
not necessarily because they wanted to do so—they
wanted to go back to Poland—but because Poland had been absorbed
into the Soviet bloc and they could only hope to enjoy freedom by
staying in the United Kingdom. As I say, many of them became valued
members of the local
community<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:57:11"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=372?><hs_para UID="14020749000071" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000071">We
have moved on since then, and indeed in a year’s time we will be
marking the 70th anniversary of the end of the Second World War, but it
does well for us to remind ourselves, while we are discussing what I
hope is a totally uncontroversial Bill, of just what we in this country
owe to those who were not necessarily born as British subjects, but who
took up arms to fight for freedom and, in the process, to fight for our
country and for what they believed in. Today, the circumstances are
very different, but even now we still depend, with the much reduced
numbers in our Armed Forces, on a number of people who are not
native-born British subjects. We all know about the Gurkhas, but there
are many others from the Commonwealth and other countries who give
valiant service. A number have been decorated for their service in
Afghanistan, and some have lost their lives. So it is wholly right that
those who enlist in the British Armed Forces should not suffer any
impediment if they wish to become British subjects while they are still
serving in the forces, when they have retired, or if they have been
forced to leave through
injury<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:58:50"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000072" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000072">This is a modest
measure but it is a very important one symbolically. I hope that we
will never need to talk of it in a Scottish context. I give my noble
friend my total support. We all owe him a debt of gratitude for
bringing the Bill forward, and I trust that it will receive the
unanimous support of all Members of your Lordships’
House.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="14020749000258" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000258"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T10:59:14"></hs_TimeCode>10.59
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000073" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000073"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Smith of Basildon" PimsId="5786" UID="14020749000299" xid="2058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000299">Baroness
Smith of Basildon (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, I think that the noble
Lord, Lord Cormack, is right to say that the Bill will receive
unanimous support across your Lordships’ House. We certainly
welcome the Bill and join other noble Lords in congratulating Jonathan
Lord and the noble Lord, Lord Trefgarne, on bringing it forward to your
Lordships’ House. In addition to its content—which,
rightly, has widespread support—the Bill has the advantage of
being short and very clear and precise in what it seeks to do. Such
clarity of purpose is very welcome in a Private Member’s Bill. I
also join in the tributes to members of our Armed Forces. The right
reverend Prelate the Bishop of Wakefield and the noble Lord, Lord
Cormack, spoke with eloquent passion on that issue, and I concur with
the comments they
made.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000074" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000074">We all
read and see reports of the activities of those who serve in our Armed
Forces, both at home and abroad, but it is really only by talking to
them and their families that we can we fully appreciate the extent of
the work they do and the sacrifices that they and their families make.
We welcome the Bill. The principle enshrined in the Armed Forces
covenant—that no member of the Armed Forces should
face disadvantage as a result of their service—is a very
important one. We must also recognise that to fulfil that commitment to
our service men and women, they will at times receive special and
different treatment to ensure that they do not face discrimination or
disadvantage. That principle has our total support. It is also right
that it should apply to those who serve and apply for British
citizenship.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000075" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000075">I
know that in the other place they had lengthy debates, which I have
read, and they looked at all the potential problems with the Bill; but
there are none. 
<?notus-xml column=373?>Although I do not think that that kind of debate will be necessary here,
a couple of outstanding matters were raised in the other place which I
do not think were addressed by the Minister, Mr Harper. Perhaps the
noble Lord can help with those, either today or in
writing.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000076" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000076">First<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:01:21"></hs_TimeCode>,
can he clarify the numbers? Government immigration policy has been
largely based on numbers—for example in respect of net migration
and immigration —but the number of people who will be affected
by the Bill is not very clear. I think the noble Lord, Lord Trefgarne,
said there will be no impact on numbers, but the estimates that I have
seen from looking at the debates in the other place range between 100
and 300. It is slightly unclear. It may be that there is no reliable
estimate—I have no difficulty with that—and that the
strength of the case of those who are serving in our Armed forces and
wish to become British citizens is enough in itself. However, if there
is any reliable estimate of numbers, that would help your
Lordships’
House.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000077" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000077">The
second point was a specific example raised by both Diana Johnson and
Steve Reed, my honourable colleagues in the other place. I am aware of
the general point, and the Minister may be too, but I will put it to
him and hope that he can help me, even if it is in writing after
today’s debate. If the length of service is cut short by a
military injury, or due to an injury sustained while serving in HM
Armed Forces an individual cannot fulfil all the criteria required for
citizenship, although in both cases he or she would have done so
without such an injury, would they still be granted citizenship? It is
a matter that can be addressed in guidance, and I do not intend to hold
up the debate in any way, but I would be grateful for the noble
Lord’s assurances on that
point.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000078" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000078">We
agree that foreign and Commonwealth citizens who serve this country in
the Armed Forces should not face disadvantages for doing so when
applying for British citizenship. We are pleased to support the
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:03:01"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="14020749000259" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000259">11.03
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000079" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000079"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Taylor of Holbeach" PimsId="5065" UID="14020749000300" xid="1920" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000300">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Home Office (Lord Taylor of
Holbeach) (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, I am delighted to be here
myself today to support the Bill on behalf of the Government. I am
grateful to my noble friend Lord Trefgarne for taking up this Bill,
which was so ably steered through the Commons by my honourable friend
Jonathan Lord, and to colleagues in this House for lending their
support. I appreciate the support the Bill has had from Her
Majesty’s loyal Opposition, as expressed so positively by the
noble Baroness, Lady Smith of Basildon,
today<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:03:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000080" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000080">I<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:10:10"></hs_TimeCode>
can give the noble Baroness some indication on numbers, although it is
an imprecise science. The answer is that no separate figures are kept
but, anecdotally, caseworkers estimate that they deal with
approximately 200 to 300 cases per year. Only a small proportion of
those will directly benefit from the provision in the Bill. If I can
give any more precise figures I will do so in writing, but that is the
situation at
present<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:04:22"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000081" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000081">This
is one of those measures that does not affect a great many people, but
those whom it does affect, it affects greatly, so we are right to
support it in this 
<?notus-xml column=374?>House. I have discussed with the noble Baroness the
matter of service overseas being interrupted by injury or disability. I
have provided my noble friend Lord Trefgarne with a briefing note, as
it is his Bill and I felt it appropriate that he should be able to
answer that particular
aspect.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000082" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000082">The
Bill is likely to have a considerable impact on the people at whom it
is directed, as my noble friend—and fellow Lincolnshire
yellowbelly—Lord Cormack pointed out. He gave a graphic
description of how lives are affected by those who give service to this
country overseas and how the whole point of the Bill is to safeguard
their interest in questions of nationality.
Once<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:05:11"></hs_TimeCode>
implemented, it will enable us to overlook the requirement to be in the
UK on day 1 of the qualifying period for naturalisation, in the same
way as we already overlook the requirements to have spent a certain
number of days in the UK where the absence was a result of service in
our Armed Forces. It is an unintended and unjust consequence of
existing legislation that a member of our Armed Forces should have to
wait longer to gain British citizenship just because he or she happened
to have been posted overseas at the relevant time.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000083" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000083">I am sure that my noble
friend Lord Trefgarne will appreciate the support of the right reverend
Prelate the Bishop of Wakefield, who rightly connected this measure to
the Government’s commitment to the Armed Forces covenant. The
measure is recognised as a priority commitment under the covenant,
which the Home Office takes seriously. The service welfare
organisations have both supported and challenged the Home Office
throughout its delivery of this and other covenant commitments, and we
will continue to work with them for the benefit of the Armed Forces
community. The Government wish the Bill
well<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:07:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="14020749000260" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000260">11.07
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000084" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000084"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Trefgarne" PimsId="4328" UID="14020749000301" xid="1470" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000301">Lord
Trefgarne:</Member></B> My Lords, I am enormously grateful to all noble
Lords who have spoken in support of the Bill, including the noble
Baroness. The right reverend Prelate is of course quite right that the
Bill comes within the context of the military covenant and is very much
a downstream effect of that particular
measure<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:07:54"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000085" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000085">The
noble Baroness, Lady Smith, asked about delays caused by injuries that
might have been incurred
overseas<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:07:54"></hs_TimeCode>. For
settlement applications, the requirement for four years’ service
can be waived if an illness or injury is attributable to service and is
sustained in an operational theatre. If it is not, a number of factors
will be considered, including the severity of the injury, the length of
service, the prognosis for recovery and the applicant’s ability
to support himself or herself. Limited leave may be given where the
applicant does not qualify for settlement but needs a period of
recovery before they leave the United Kingdom. A member of the Armed
Forces who is granted settlement following medical discharge will be
able to apply for citizenship as and when the five-year residency
requirement is met. For example, if the individual is medically
discharged and granted indefinite leave to remain after two
years’ service, he must wait a further three years before
becoming eligible to naturalise. The Bill has the potential to help
such an individual where he or she was serving overseas on the date
five years before the application 
<?notus-xml column=375?>for naturalisation. The Secretary of State could, at
the moment, waive the requirement where the individual was still
serving and still overseas, but the Bill will extend this discretion to
those who have left Her Majesty’s forces or who have returned to
the UK. I hope that that is a satisfactory
explanation.</hs_para><hs_Procedure UID="14020749000326" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000326">Bill
read a second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/E16068FF91E3E10293F3C19D519D4FF9A1E75F96" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AH-AJ1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020749000322" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000322">International
Development (Gender Equality)
Bill</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="14020749000261" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000261">11.10
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="14020749000331" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000331">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord McColl of Dulwich" PimsId="1786" UID="14020749000302" xid="1330" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000302">Lord
McColl of Dulwich</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020749000277" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000277">That the Bill be
read a second
time<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:09:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="14020749000086" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000086"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord McColl of Dulwich" PimsId="1786" UID="14020749000303" xid="1330" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000303">Lord
McColl of Dulwich (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, Mr William
Cash MP deserves great credit for steering this Private Member’s
Bill through another place, from its introduction on 19 June 2013 to
its Third Reading on 17 January 2014. It is a modest Bill, intended to
ensure that when the Government provide development or humanitarian
assistance to countries outside the UK, they do so—wherever
possible—in a way that promotes gender
equality.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000087" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000087">Water, sanitation and
hygiene poverty disproportionately blights the lives of women and
girls. Lack of water, sanitation and hygiene—WASH—can,
first, prevent girls from attending primary school because they are too
busy collecting water or caring for sick family members, and, secondly,
expose them to sexual and physical violence while walking in isolated
areas or seeking private places in which to urinate. Secondary
education depends on water, sanitation and hygiene access because girls
cannot attend school when they are sick with diarrhoea or when they
have to collect water for the family. Those who are menstruating may
choose to skip a week of school or drop out altogether if there are no
private latrines or hygiene supplies at school.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000088" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000088">Lack of education has
an impact on the rest of girls’ lives, including their health,
their freedom to plan their families and, ultimately, the cycle of
poverty. Gender equality is not possible until everyone everywhere has
access to safe water, sanitation and hygiene. The International
Development (Gender Equality) Bill is essential if we are to stop
discriminatory legal frameworks, policies, practices and beliefs that
prevent some people accessing water, sanitation and hygiene
services.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="14020749000089" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000089">In
sub-Saharan Africa, women and girls spend 40 billion working
hours every year collecting water. With a safe supply of water and
toilets, women are able to spend time engaging in
income-generating activities or agriculture. Improving access to water,
sanitation and hygiene and providing expectant mothers with basic
services and accurate hygiene information are vital in order to reduce
maternal mortality rates and meet global goals for ending preventable
child
deaths.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000090" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000090">Caring
for disabled, sick and older family members usually falls to women and
girls, as it is considered to be domestic work. The tasks include
washing, supporting persons going to the toilet and collecting water.
Boys 
<?notus-xml column=376?>are often forced into the workforce rather than
being able to stay at school, to compensate for the loss of income.
During a visit to Nepal with WaterAid last year, I saw first-hand the
problems that women experience when living without adequate sanitation.
I saw how a simple latrine can really transform lives, impacting on
health, safety, dignity and
education.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000091">In
a small village called Thecho on the outskirts of Kathmandu, I met
women who were part of a women’s co-operative that was set up to
oversee the construction and maintenance of eco-friendly household
latrines, vastly improving the quality of life in the community. The
previous unsanitary environment had led to serious health concerns.
More than this, it was evident that sanitation had a clear and
significant impact on dignity, education and livelihoods. Before they
had latrines, they had no choice but to defecate in the open. The women
said that this put them at risk of harassment and even
attack.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000092" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000092">My
most memorable experience on that visit was marching in my first ever
street demonstration—it is never too late to learn. Kathmandu is
quite used to strikes and demonstrations, but a street march of 1,000
Nepalis, mainly women, calling for clean water and sanitation for all
by 2030 was one of the more unusual scenes it will have
seen—perhaps even more unusual for having a Member of the House
of Lords in attendance. Unusual or not, I hope that the dignity march
helped to bring home the
message.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000093" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000093">Investment
in WASH really is one of the most efficient and effective development
interventions that can help efforts to bring about gender equity.
Mr Cash’s hope is that this Bill will be a small
contribution towards ending the marginalisation and abuse of women
which is all too common in many developing countries. I believe the
aims of the Bill to be uncontroversial and, since amendments can
readily scupper a Private Member’s Bill such as this, I am sure
that no one will think of opposing these important measures. I beg to
move.</hs_para><hs_time UID="14020749000262" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000262">11.16
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:16:20"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000094" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000094"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hussein-Ece" PimsId="5766" UID="14020749000304" xid="2040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000304">Baroness
Hussein-Ece (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I thank the noble Lord, Lord
McColl, for introducing this Bill to your Lordships’ House. I
welcome and support this Bill. It is a subject I have spoken about on
numerous occasions, as have many other noble Lords.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000095" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000095">I am very pleased that
gender equality and the empowerment of women are seen as essential for
both the elimination of world poverty and the upholding of human
rights. Supporting all efforts to achieve gender equality must be at
the centre of the United Kingdom’s international development
programmes. I know how much is already being done, which is why I
particularly welcome the
Bill.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000096" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000096">We know
that violence against women and girls is endemic in conflict areas and
that its consequences are devastating and long-lasting, for not just
the individual but the entire community. Sexual violence is not
just a by-product of war, it is often a strategy of combat used
systematically to terrorise and humiliate. This is a key element that
needs urgent attention and vigilance.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000097" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000097">Women and girls must be
supported in all key areas in creating a positive and enabling
environment for them. This can happen in a range of areas, such as: 
<?notus-xml column=377?>giving them a voice and accountability in terms of
maternal mortality; gender violence, as I have mentioned; education,
which is so key; conflict and post-conflict reconstruction; HIV and
AIDS; and, of course,
migration.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000098" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000098">Giving
women a voice and supporting women’s participation in national
and local decision-making in promoting leadership are also essential.
Supporting women in this way ensures that not just the women and their
families but whole villages and whole areas are empowered. Women are
given a voice where they have not had one in the past and have been
silenced in the most horrific
way.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000099">I do not
plan to speak for too long but I will turn to the women of Afghanistan,
which is a subject that I have been particularly involved in and
exercised about. We in the United Kingdom have a significant
responsibility here. Afghanistan has been named the worst place in the
world to be a woman, and it does not seem to be getting any better.
Just a few days ago it was reported that a new Afghan law would allow
men to attack their wives, daughters and sisters without fear of
judicial punishment, undoing years of slow progress in tackling
violence in a country that has been blighted by so-called honour
killings, forced marriage and very vicious domestic abuse. The
so-called honour killings by fathers and brothers who disapprove of
women’s behaviour would be almost impossible to punish if this
proposed law was enacted. This is shocking and unacceptable. It will
make it impossible to prosecute cases of violence against women. The
most vulnerable people will not get
justice.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000100" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000100">After
all the years of conflict, war and the billions spent by the UK and
other countries on this war, which was intended initially—if we
cast our minds back—to free Afghan women from the violence meted
out to them by the Taliban, it seems inconceivable that we can watch
from the sidelines while this
happens.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000101" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000101">Countries
that spent billions trying to improve justice and human rights are now
focused largely on security and are retreating from Afghan politics. It
is precisely for this reason that we need to commit that all future aid
funds for these women are used to promote and protect women’s
rights and
education.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000102" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000102">Human
Rights Watch has said:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="14020749000235" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000235">“Opponents of
women's rights have been emboldened in the last year. They can see an
opportunity right now to begin reversing women’s
rights—no need to wait for 2015. The lack of response from
donors has energised them further. Everyone has known since May that
this law could be passed but we didn’t hear any donors speaking
out about it
publicly”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="14020749000103" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000103">This
must not prevail. It would be a betrayal of these
women.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="14020749000104" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000104">Last
year, I met a group of Afghan women MPs who were visiting our
Parliament. I and others were struck by how brave these women were,
facing threats daily just to be able to carry out their duties as
Members of Parliament—threats that we could not possibly imagine
here in the West. They were most concerned that once the troops
withdrew this year they would be left even more vulnerable than they
previously were. They were acutely aware of, and vocal on, how aid and
progress made on, for example, girls’ education could so easily
be dismantled. They all made a strong plea with us: that we ask the
Government 
<?notus-xml column=378?>to ensure that funds for Afghan women be protected
and be given specifically to the agencies which work with women, and
not be allowed to be channelled through the Afghan Government, who we
have seen are not reliable on these matters at the best of
times<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:21:33"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000105" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000105">I
note the Secretary of State’s annual report on how effective aid
has been in the pursuit of millennium development goal 3—to
promote gender equality and empower women. The evidence for the need
for this Bill is overwhelming. I again congratulate its initiator, Bill
Cash MP, and we on these Benches fully support
it<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:22:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/7C1EDA2FD23E3A8D0B6F1F1245BBF5A00CDF3E17" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AJ2-AJ2</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="14020749000263" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000263">11.22
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:22:06"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000106" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000106"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Quirk" PimsId="275" UID="14020749000305" xid="1402" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000305">Lord
Quirk (CB):</Member></B> My Lords, we must all be grateful to the noble
Lord, Lord McColl, for his lead on this important Bill. We should be
grateful to him but not surprised: he is known throughout Parliament
and far beyond for his devotion to philanthropy, extending his work as
a fine surgeon at Guy’s to deploying skills, gratis, on the
mercy ships along the west African
coast<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:22:45"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000107" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000107">I
enthusiastically support this present drive to tie overseas aid to the
reduction not only of poverty but of gender inequality; that is, as a
lever to improve the lives of girls and women. This is a huge area,
extending to personal healthcare, to FGM, to marital law, to property
rights and, not least, to the education that can enable
women to work in areas far above the
menial<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:23:42"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000108" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000108">I
do not have knowledge of west Africa remotely comparable to that of the
noble Lord, Lord McColl, but, 40 years ago, I was charged by the
British Council to assess some higher education projects that it was
considering, first in Ghana and then, a year or so later, in
Nigeria<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:24:07"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000109">Well,
you cannot report on universities without seeing something of the
elementary and secondary education that their students had had. In
Ghana, I noted that the schools were clearly progressive, with boys and
girls keen to learn despite poorly trained teachers and grim
classrooms. The same was true in some parts of Nigeria, especially in
Yoruba-speaking Lagos and Ibadan. But in the vast stretches of northern
Nigeria, in Hausa-speaking Kano, Zaria and Kaduna, it was a very
different story. Girls in classrooms were vanishingly rare, and I
raised this matter with the local authorities. I met with a range of
reactions, from embarrassment to incomprehension, from puzzlement to
outright hostility. One director of education told me that I should try
to see the Emir of Zaria. To my great surprise, this emir agreed to
speak to me and invited me to talks in his grand
palace<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:25:35"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000110" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000110">He
was both gracious and frank. Girls did not need education; their
fathers could barely afford schooling for their sons. What is more, the
future husbands of these girls certainly did not want their girls to be
educated. They did not want them to have been exposed—his
word—to schooling; their mothers would teach them all they
needed to know. By the way, when I reported this to the British
Council, I was told, “Well, of course, we must never interfere
with indigenous
cultures<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:26:32"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000111">Things
in west Africa are much better today, but recent horrific events in the
north-east of the country are a warning of how easily the clock can be
turned back, as it was when the Taliban took over again in 
<?notus-xml column=379?>Afghanistan—and as it may again turn back
there when western troops pull out this year, their mission not so much
completed as
abandoned<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:27:12"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000112" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000112">Pressure
through aid conditionality may well be the best tool we can devise, so
let us give this Bill, introduced by the noble Lord, Lord McColl, a
fair wind. One powerful ally will surely be Christine Lagarde, head of
the IMF<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:27:41"></hs_TimeCode>. Earlier
this very week, she delivered the Dimbleby Lecture right here in London
and, significantly, she dwelt at some length on the issue of female
oppression and neglect. Her concern was not merely for the sake of the
girls and women in a range of countries across the world, not excluding
our own of course, but for the sake of economic development itself. She
noted the ILO estimate that nearly 1 billion women in the world are
being held back,
facing,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="14020749000241" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000241">“discrimination
at birth, on the school bench, in the board room … yet, the
economic facts of life are crystal clear. By not letting women
contribute, we end up with lower standards for everyone … We
must let women succeed: for ourselves and for all the little
girls—and boys—of the future. It will be their
world—let us give it to
them<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:29:05"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_quotefo><hs_para UID="14020749000113" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000113">To
Madame Lagarde’s rousing words, we must surely say amen. This
Bill would just as surely make a powerful
contribution.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/28646559132B0892F1EDCD3D3687293FD9AF89DE" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AK-AK</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_parafo UID="14020749000223" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000223"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:29:20"></hs_TimeCode></hs_parafo><hs_time UID="14020749000264" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000264">11.29
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000114" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000114"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Jenkin of Kennington" PimsId="5927" UID="14020749000306" xid="2137" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000306">Baroness
Jenkin of Kennington (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, in the three years
that I have been in this House, we have had the opportunity and the
privilege to debate many of these issues on a number of occasions. It
is, therefore, very tempting for me merely to say, “I support
this Bill; it is the right thing to do”, and sit down, because
we have already had the chance to make these points. However, they are
such important points, and so many women across the world have such
terrible lives, that I fear I am not going to let your Lordships off so
lightly<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:29:45"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:29:45"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000115" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000115">I
start by echoing the praise of the noble Lord, Lord Quirk, for the
noble Lord, Lord McColl. I am lucky enough to share a room with the
noble Lord, Lord McColl; I can speak at first hand of his enormous
support for many good causes, of his personal support for me, which I
very much value, and of his extreme modesty in the wonderful causes
that he supports. I quite often have come back after the recess and
said, “Have you had a good time, Ian?” and he has said,
“Oh yes, I was operating on the Mercy Ships all the way
through”. His dedication to these causes is something to be
applauded and something that we should all honour as
well<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:30:30"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:30:33"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000116" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000116">Considering that the
International Development (Gender Equality) Bill was originally No. 18
on the Private Members’ Bills ballot, it is a significant
achievement that we are having this debate at all. Without
the support of my right honourable friend the Prime Minister
and the dedication of Bill Cash in getting it through, as well as the
support of the International Development Secretary, we would not have
got this far. I would like to pay tribute to her and to her
predecessor, Andrew Mitchell; they both focused particularly on policy
work at DfID to support women and
girls<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:31:07"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:31:07"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000117" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000117">Women
across the world, whether they live in Sweden or Sudan, are entitled to
live their lives with dignity, free from fear and empowered to control
their own futures. However, while we know that
women are 
<?notus-xml column=380?>integral to the development agenda, it remains the
case that in many parts of the world their contributions are neither
valued nor encouraged, as the noble Lord, Lord Quirk, told us so
eloquently. There have already been significant steps taken to
challenge the status quo, but the pursuit of gender equality cannot be
just an element of the international development agenda. It is true
that one of the eight millennium development goals is focused on women
and girls, but should this mean that they are excluded from the other
seven? Of course
not<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:31:53"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000118" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000118">Nevertheless,
for poor women in poor places, significant gender gaps remain in
education enrolment, fertility, access to healthcare and access to the
local economic market. Women produce 50% of the world’s food and
yet they earn only 10% of its income and own only 1% of its property.
Women do not participate in society on equal terms with men, meaning
that they are largely ignored in the decision-making process. It is not
a coincidence that women in wealthier sections of society have not only
received an education, but are more prominent within their communities.
Even where developing countries as a whole are getting richer,
differences between men and women remain, entrenched in ideology,
despite nearly a century of women’s
activism<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:32:37"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000119" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000119">The
participation of women in their communities and wider society is
invaluable. Government agendas which fail to address the representation
of women may lead to free and fair elections initially, but a
male-dominated parliament, as we know only too well, will never be able
fully to tap into and harness the entire population’s potential
and capacity. Furthermore, by considering the different needs of men
and women in emergency aid situations, we can better target our aid at
the vulnerable, helping those who need it most. Systemic shocks, such
as famine, economic downturn and conflict, adversely affect males and
females, and yet women often suffer disproportionately and have very
little say in rebuilding their communities after such events. Fewer
than 3% of signatories to peace agreements are
female<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:33:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000120" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000120">DfID’s
record on assisting women has been really good. Due to the
department’s focus on the women’s and girls’
agenda, more than 14 million women have gained access to financial
services; almost 3 million girls are in primary education; and more
than 4 million women are using modern methods of family planning. The
Government should be commended on these successes. The value of these
achievements should not be underestimated. By promoting equality
between the sexes, we can ensure that women receive a full education,
marry and have children later in life and fully participate in their
communities<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:34:02"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000121" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000121">Let
us take a moment to look at the evidence. An extra year of secondary
schooling for girls can increase their future wages by 10% to 20%.
Putting resources in women’s hands results in more household
spending that benefits children, and a recent study of 30 developing
countries showed that women with no schooling had three more children
on average than women who attended high school. The UN’s Food
and Agriculture Organization estimates that equalising access to
productive resources between men and women could raise output in
developing countries by as much as 4%. Estimates of
the loss of growth owing to gender inequality in 
<?notus-xml column=381?>education range from 0.3% in sub-Saharan Africa to
0.81% in south Asia. It cannot be said often enough that when half the
population is locked out of education and economic opportunity, there
is no realistic path to sustainability. Without gender equality,
economic prosperity will remain a
dream<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:35:07"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000122" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000122">As
has already been mentioned, education is the solution. By integrating
boys and girls in early childhood on an equal footing in an educational
environment, entrenched sexism can be eradicated. We must ensure that
this integration does not end at puberty. Equality for girls must
continue into their teenage and adult years. Access to micro-finance
initiatives and the ability to own their own land are as important for
women as early-years education. Ultimately, women will escape poverty
not, of course, through international aid but through business. They
must be able to reap the benefits of their own hard work for themselves
and their
families<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:35:47"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:35:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000123" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000123">While
I recognise fully that households where women have a greater say tend
to allocate a greater share of resources to education and health, these
aspects of family life should not be entirely relegated to mothers and
female family members. Programmes implemented in the developing world
ensuring that children receive regular health checks and vaccinations
are very often targeted at mothers, unintentionally reinforcing the
stereotype that childcare is very much their remit only. By simply
changing the word “mother” to “parent”, or
including pictures of fathers and children in literature and posters,
we can challenge the idea that a woman’s place is in the home.
By doing this, we can begin to combat the exclusion of women from wider
society<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:36:34"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000124" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000124">My
noble friend Lady Hussein-Ece focused her remarks on violence against
women, and I will not repeat her arguments. Suffice it to say that one
in three women worldwide will experience violence in their lifetime; by
2050, 50 million girls will have been forced into marriage before even
reaching their 15th birthday. One woman from Tanzania recently
reported:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="14020749000236" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000236">“I see some
women being beaten by their husband every day. When you talk to them,
they say they are married and they cannot separate. These women will
never climb the ladder: they will stay at the
bottom”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="14020749000224" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000224">There
you have
it<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:37:12"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="14020749000125" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000125">Another
challenge to gender equality is access to contraception and choice over
birth spacing. Traditional contraceptive methods are usually dependent
on the co-operation of men, resulting in more than 200 million women
who do not want to be pregnant but are not able to use contraceptives.
This means that they cannot determine when to have their children and
have a harder time feeding them, paying their medical bills and
providing them with education. They are trapped in this vicious cycle
of poverty, which could be broken simply by providing women with their
own contraceptive methods. Again, this can be implemented through
education<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:37:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000126" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000126">I
know that my honourable friend in the House of Commons has worked
closely on his Bill with the Gender Rights &amp; Equality Action Trust,
otherwise known as the GREAT initiative. This organisation also
deserves to be commended for its dedication to ensuring gender equality
across the developing world. It runs a number of
worthwhile projects, including the 
<?notus-xml column=382?>“Great Men Value Women” campaign,
which works with teenage boys to give them a safe space to discuss
their vision of masculinity and the tools they need to challenge the
stereotypes to which they are often required to conform. Projects such
as these are also vital to the gender equality
agenda<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:38:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000127" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000127">I
applaud the Secretary of State’s commitment to this Bill and am
grateful for the Opposition’s support as well. Who knows what
might follow in the future without this Bill, which will enshrine in
law Britain’s commitment to promoting gender equality around the
world? It will also introduce a reporting duty on the Department for
International Development, ensuring that all future Governments are
held to account on this issue. It is only through passing the Bill that
we can ensure the continuity of the equality agenda, not just for
today’s Government but for all
Governments<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:28:23"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/205B4EF214A8266C523950A6D5F7E87CE64E68BC" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AL-AL</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="14020749000265" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000265"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:39:15"></hs_TimeCode></I>11.39
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:39:25"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000128" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000128"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Loomba" PimsId="5906" UID="14020749000307" xid="2116" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000307">Lord
Loomba (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I congratulate the noble Lord, Lord
McColl, and the Government on this important Bill, which recognises the
importance of promoting gender equality in the assistance that our
Government give to countries outside the United Kingdom. The Bill could
not be more timely. On Wednesday, the Prime Minister spoke about
getting more women into public life. He
added,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="14020749000242" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000242">“we
will not represent or govern our country properly unless we have more
women at every level in our public life and in our
politics”.—[<I>Official Report</I>, Commons, 5/2/14; col.
264.]</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="14020749000225" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000225">That
is relevant not only in the UK but across the whole
world<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:40:09"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="14020749000129" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000129">I
have stated before that I am extremely proud that the UK Government
have committed to spending 0.7% of income on aid to help the
world’s poorest people. It is fantastic that the Bill is
intended to focus further on reducing poverty in a way which is likely
to contribute to reducing inequality. This builds on the excellent work
which DfID is already doing in tackling FGM and focusing on education
by improving learning, reaching more children than ever before and
keeping girls in school for as long as their
brothers.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000130" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000130">Children
are our future, and I hope that the Bill provides the world’s
poorest children with more opportunities to improve their
circumstances. As many noble Lords know, reducing the gender inequality
gap is key to solving so many problems in developing countries, as we
have heard from other speakers. I am also reassured that the Government
recognise the importance of annual reporting to Parliament, which will
help to provide an incentive for the department to deliver on the main
purpose of the
Bill.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000131" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000131">I wish
the Bill all success. I trust that the Government will recognise that
gender equality provision should include a clear public statement that
gender equality is at the heart of everything we do. Such a public
statement should be publicised immediately as part of DfID policy.
Gender equality has no meaning unless it is systematically monitored.
There should also be periodic assessments to ensure that any
shortcoming is
addressed.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000132" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000132">In
this way, we will ensure that the objectives of this excellent Bill are
met. I hope that the Bill is the first of many initiatives from the
Government to promote gender equality, and I look forward to the later
stages of the
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:42:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=383?><hs_time UID="14020749000266" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000266"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:42:38"></hs_TimeCode></I>11.42
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000133" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000133"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hodgson of Abinger" PimsId="7018" UID="14020749000308" xid="2201" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000308">Baroness
Hodgson of Abinger (Con):</Member></B> My Lords, I, too, thank my noble
friend Lord McColl for having introduced the Bill. I pay tribute to him
for all his work. Of course, we owe a debt of gratitude to Bill Cash,
the honourable Member for Stone, who piloted this important Bill so
ably through the House of
Commons.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000134" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000134">I
welcome the Bill enormously because, as the right honourable Alan
Duncan, the Minister of State for International Development, said, the
Bill can have a lasting impact on generations of girls and women around
the world. Still today, in the 21st century, there is not one country
where women have the same socio- economic and political
opportunities as men. Still today, too many countries have a
patriarchal culture and this, together with discriminatory practices,
leads to the disempowerment of women and gender
inequality<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:43:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000135" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000135">The
Bill addresses gender equality in the context of providing both
development assistance and humanitarian assistance, resulting from both
natural disasters and the terrible effects of conflict. Development
assistance addresses reducing poverty. According to GADN’s
recent report, it is estimated that women account for two-thirds of the
1.4 billion people currently living in extreme poverty. They also make
up 60% of the 572 million working poor in the world. In
reality, the situation for women is probably even worse, as there is
likely to be a significant number living in poverty within households
that are officially categorised as
non-poor<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:44:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000136" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000136">Women’s
poverty is, in part, caused by gender inequality. According to the UN
System Task Team on the Post-2015 UN Development Agenda, this
discrimination impairs progress in all other areas of development.
Unequal distribution of income, lack of control over resources, lack of
decision-making power, unequal distribution of household tasks, the
care-giving role assigned to women and gender-based violence all
contribute to compounding women’s
poverty.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000137" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000137">As we
have already heard from my noble friend Lady Hussein-Ece, violence
affects women in every part of the world. Seven in 10 women report that
they have experienced physical and/or sexual violence at some point in
their lifetime. Although 125 countries have laws that penalise domestic
violence, for 603 million women today domestic violence is
still not a crime in their
country<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:45:25"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000138">A
number of reviews of the MDGs over the past five years have noted that
women are less likely to benefit from progress than men in some
regions. For example, they may lack the resources, time and freedom of
movement to travel to access health, legal or social services due to
their enforced roles within the household, or they are restricted by
partners, family or society. In times of humanitarian crisis, when
natural disasters such as the earthquake in Haiti occur, state
institutions collapse, law and order breaks down, food and medical care
are scarce and violence prevails, thus making women particularly
vulnerable.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000139">Wars
today have shifted from battlefields to communities, impacting on
civilians, especially women and children, who make up 75% of all those
killed in modern warfare. It is not just by the enemy that women will
be attacked. We all know that where a 
<?notus-xml column=384?>conflict starts, levels of domestic violence escalate hugely, spiralling
out of control. In war, women frequently become targets of sexual
violence. Raping a woman in front of her family is one of the most
effective ways of disarming the men, and sometimes this is used as a
weapon of mass
destruction.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000140" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000140">Although
women in conflict bear a disproportionate burden of suffering, and
despite UN Resolution 1325 having been passed more than 10 years ago,
they are usually absent from negotiations at the peace table and from
decision-making in the aftermath of war. Over the past 25 years, only
one in 40 peace treaty signatories has been a woman, and only 12 out of
the 585 peace accords referred to women’s needs. Thus, women may
continue to suffer violence and abuse because no one is listening to
them or taking account of how really to protect them. I pay tribute to
the Foreign Secretary, who spoke up to insist that women in Syria were
at Geneva
II<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:47:41"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000141" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000141">In
terror, women often flee to take their families to a safer place. Of
the 42 million refugees and internally displaced people today, 80% are
women and children. No accurate data exist on the millions of widows
and “wives of the disappeared”, who often have no means
of support and may be targeted within their families and the wider
community. According to Widows for Peace through Democracy, there are
more than 2 million widows in Iraq; more than 50% of all
women in eastern Congo are widows; and there are 2.5 million widows in
Afghanistan, with 80,000 in Kabul alone, who often have to resort to
begging on the streets. I echo everything that my noble friend Lady
Hussein-Ece said about the situation for women in Afghanistan and how
we need to support
them.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000142" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000142">The
Commonwealth is the world’s greatest pressure group for gender
equality, and I welcome enormously the fact that Her Majesty’s
Government recognise the injustices to women today, and are trying to
address them and improve lives for women around the world in a number
of ways, as we have heard from my noble friend Lady
Jenkin<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:48:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000143" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000143"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Howell of Guildford" PimsId="1037" UID="14020749000309" xid="1752" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000309">Lord
Howell of Guildford (Con):</Member></B> Perhaps I may briefly reinforce
the remarks that my noble friend has just made about the Commonwealth.
It is indeed one of the world’s great pressure groups for gender
equality. That fact is embedded in the new Commonwealth
charter—the so-called maxima carta—which this House has
approved and which commits 54 nations to driving a long way forward to
beat gender inequality, although of course there is a long, long way to
go.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/6BA414098D18A41B1F406A6807484F7F8C654C2A" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AM1-AM1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_para UID="14020749000144" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000144"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:49:16"></hs_TimeCode><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hodgson of Abinger" PimsId="7018" UID="14020749000310" xid="2201" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000310">Baroness
Hodgson of Abinger:</Member></B> The Prime Minister has said that
Britain will “absolutely lead the charge” to promote
equality for women around the world during 2014 because, as Phumzile
Mlambo-Ngcuka, the new director of UN Women, said this week at the
eighth open working session on sustainable
development:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="14020749000237" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000237">“A
safe and sustainable world demands women’s rights,
women’s empowerment and gender equality”.</hs_quote>
<hs_parafo UID="14020749000226" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000226">The Bill contributes
greatly to this agenda and thus is important legislation. I very much
hope that noble Lords will resist tabling amendments to it, because if
they do I understand that, due to time constraints, it 
<?notus-xml column=385?>may mean that the Bill will fall. I have great
pleasure in supporting the Bill and very much hope that the
House will give it its Second Reading.</hs_parafo>
<hs_parafo UID="14020749000227" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000227"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:50:09"></hs_TimeCode></hs_parafo><hs_time UID="14020749000267" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000267">11.50
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000145" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000145"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Farrington of Ribbleton" PimsId="3193" UID="14020749000311" xid="1108" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000311">Baroness
Farrington of Ribbleton (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, with the leave of
the House and an apology for standing up too soon, I will speak briefly
in the gap. I echo the words of the noble Lord, Lord McColl, having
been present when some women from Haiti came to talk about the danger
to women and girls who have to go outside their living area because of
the lack of facilities for them, particularly at night. It is extremely
important that that is recognised.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000146" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000146">We have changed some
attitudes in Europe over my lifetime. I remember that it takes time. As
chair of education in Lancashire, I heard that a girl who was very good
at mathematics was told by the head of mathematics, “Once we get
to the fourth year, you will of course decline in your ability because
you are female”. That was said only 30 years ago.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000147" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000147">I speak as a mother of
three sons and a grandmother of three grandsons. Gender equality is not
only about ensuring that girls get access, very important though that
is in its own right. When I look at pictures—as a grandmother, I
am drawn to pictures of small boys who remind me of my
grandsons—and see the ones who are in poverty, distress or
illness, it occurs to me that they, too, are suffering because of the
lack of education for women and girls. That is because women and girls
are needed to complement the skills of humanity and they must have the
ability to develop not only their own skills but those of their
families—boys and girls. It is too late in some ways to change
male attitudes if the experience that boys have in growing up is one
where most people seem to accept that a girl’s education is
unimportant. The world needs all the skills that it can get. The lives
of many women are tied up in circumstances where world development can
only assist the whole of humanity in the future.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000148" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000148">Many people have paid
tribute to the noble Lord, Lord McColl, for his work and it is so
important that we recognise his words of warning. Tempted though your
Lordships may be to add amendments to strengthen or change the Bill, I
am sure that the noble Lord’s record calls on us all to avoid
that temptation to produce amendments. I wish the noble Lord’s
Bill
well<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:53:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="14020749000268" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000268">11.54
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000149" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000149"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Thornton" PimsId="4281" UID="14020749000312" xid="1466" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000312">Baroness
Thornton (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, I am grateful to the noble Lord,
Lord McColl, and add my voice to the tributes paid to him. He and I
have been involved many times in debates about health, women’s
health and Third World health over many years, and I was not surprised
to see that he was sponsoring this Bill today in your Lordships’
House. As usual, we have had an informed and passionate debate because
there is such expertise, experience and commitment in the House to
these issues. I also pay tribute to William Cash MP for introducing the
Bill in the Commons. It is a testament to his reputation that he
managed to bring this Private Member’s Bill so far up the list.
I also thank NGOs such as the GREAT Initiative, Plan and WaterAid for
their briefings.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=386?><hs_para UID="14020749000150" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000150">The aim of the Bill, as
noble Lords have said, is to embed gender considerations into every
aspect of the UK’s aid spending and to ensure consistent and
long-term monitoring of how UK aid impacts gender inequality. I cannot
resist a small and gentle aside to the Minister, in that I wish that
some of this was embedded into the monitoring of our domestic policies
and their gender impact. However, I leave that debate for another day.
The Bill places a duty on the Secretary of State for International
Development to consider gender in the disbursement of any development
and humanitarian assistance and introduces an additional duty to report
annually on the activities undertaken to tackle gender inequality. From
the briefing that I have read, I understand that the Bill may be one of
the first of its kind anywhere to enshrine a commitment to reducing
gender inequality in development. I commend the Government on their
support for that.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000151" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000151">Importantly, the debate
has shown that gender inequality holds back development. It is not
enough to address democratic reform if the political representation of
women is not also addressed—or, for example, to fund family
planning initiatives that fail also to address men’s roles and
responsibilities. That was mentioned by noble Baronesses earlier in the
debate. As has also been mentioned, women around the world continue to
face serious levels of violence, limited control over assets and
property and unequal participation in private and public
decision-making. All those issues are important and they all provide us
with the backdrop and the reason why the Bill is
important<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:50:35"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000152" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000152">The
previous Government and this Government have put improving the lives of
women and girls as a policy priority for the work of the UK Department
for International Development. They have seen it
as,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="14020749000243" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000243">“stopping
poverty before it starts”.</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="14020749000228" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000228">I was very struck by
the remarks made by my honourable friend Meg Hillier in Committee in
the Commons. She said that she had visited Nigeria several times, and
one of her points was that,</hs_parafo>
<hs_quotefo UID="14020749000244" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000244">“we went to
look at human
rights”,</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="14020749000229" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000229">but,</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="14020749000245" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000245">“we
quickly concluded that women’s rights, if tackled, would solve
many of the wider problems, particularly with children’s rights.
That underlines the importance of the first part of new clause
1”—</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="14020749000230" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000230">as
it then
was—</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="14020749000246" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000246">“which
deals with development assistance. If people are aware of their rights,
that can make a big difference”.—[<I>Official Report</I>,
Commons, Gender Equality (International Development) Bill Committee,
11/12/13; col.
9.]</hs_quotefo><hs_para UID="14020749000153" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000153">My
honourable friend Gavin Shuker, who has responsibility for this issue
on the Front Bench in the Commons, said:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="14020749000238" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000238">“One of the
challenges of gender equality is that all too often it is treated as a
women’s issue, but in an international development context,
holding back women in a society does not just hold back women; it holds
back societies”.—[Official Report, Commons, Gender
Equality (International Development) Bill Committee, 11/12/13; col.
6.]</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="14020749000231" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000231">That is
absolutely right, so from these Benches we are very happy to give
wholehearted support to the Bill. We will certainly do everything we
can to make sure that it reaches the statute
book.</hs_parafo></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/7E6890A5F3D4A5A8279179FF7D0BDBD338B8CCA4" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AM2-AO1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">

<?notus-xml column=387?><hs_time UID="14020749000269" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000269"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:49:16"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:58:20"></hs_TimeCode>11.58
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000154" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000154"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Northover" PimsId="2142" UID="14020749000313" xid="1368" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000313">Baroness
Northover (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I am pleased to speak in support
of the Private Member’s Bill sponsored by my noble friend Lord
McColl and introduced so effectively by him. My noble friend has such a
formidable commitment to development through his Mercy Ships and so
many other efforts, as my noble friend Lady Jenkin said, and I, too,
pay tribute to him. I love the image of our noble friend Lord McColl
marching in his first demonstration in Nepal. It shows his level of
commitment that that was in a march for dignity for gender equality.
Like my noble friend Lady Jenkin and others, I, too, pay tribute to my
honourable friend Bill Cash for having the vision, grasp and commitment
to introduce and pilot this vital Bill through the other place. I pay
tribute to the other noble Lords who have contributed today for their
long and considerable contribution to addressing gender inequality
worldwide.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000155" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000155">There is no doubt that
over the past few decades the world has made significant progress on
improving the lives and prospects for girls and women. More girls are
now going to school. Women are living longer and having fewer children,
and more are in productive employment. As the noble Baroness, Lady
Farrington, has made clear, there has been much change but, as she and
others have noted, we are nowhere near where we need to be. As the
noble Lord, Lord Quirk, also made clear, there have been major
improvements in the position of women and girls, especially in
education, but there is still much more to do.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000156" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000156">By 2020, unless
attitudes change and without steps to address child marriage, 50
million girls will have been forced into marriage before they reach
their 15th birthday. As we have heard, violence against women and girls
is a global pandemic: one in three women has experienced violence in
her lifetime, a terrible statistic. My noble friend Lord McColl
mentioned the dangers even in carrying out simple tasks such as
collecting water.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000157" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000157">My noble friend Lady
Hodgson spelt out the level of violence against women and its
devastating effects. It was a milestone when rape was rightly
recognised as a weapon of war. Now we must ensure, as she and other
noble Lords have said, that women are at the table in peace
negotiations. I, too, pay tribute to my right honourable friend William
Hague for what he is doing to recognise and combat violence against
women in conflict. His involvement is extremely
welcome.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000158" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000158">Ours
is a changing world, and the challenges that girls and women face will
become more pressing. More girls and women will live in urban areas and
in areas of conflict. The impact of natural resource scarcity and
climate change will be disproportionately hard on girls and women
because they are so often at the margins. They are in real danger of
being locked out of the economic progress that we see in some of the
developing countries at the moment.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000159" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000159">My noble friend Lady
Hussein-Ece flags up the situation of women in Afghanistan. She knows
that we are very actively engaged there. We are seeking to uphold
women’s rights as an important element of DfID’s strategy
in Afghanistan, so we provide grants for Afghan women’s
organisations that emphasise the 
<?notus-xml column=388?>strengthening of civil society. They emphasise various areas, including
strengthening women’s rights and access to justice, and we are
providing £7.1 million to the Ministry of the Interior to help
to improve the Afghan police’s role to protect and uphold
women’s rights. My noble friend will also know how we are
supporting girls’ education in Afghanistan. However, we are also
keenly aware that things can go backwards as well as forwards. We
assure her that we remain active and vigilant in this regard. We are
looking into the recent reports that she flagged up, and I will provide
noble Lords with more information on that as soon as we have it. I
shall put it in a letter to my noble friend, copy it to other noble
Lords who have participated in the debate and put a copy in the
Library. We know the importance of ensuring that things go forwards,
not
backwards.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000160" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000160">That
is why action to improve the lives of girls and women is rightly front
and centre in UK development. We need to turn the challenges of a
changing world into opportunities. As we all know, gender equality is a
critical building block for progress towards building prosperity. Time
and again we see that investing in girls and women leads to incredible
returns, not only for them but for their families and communities and
for their economies and countries. When a woman generates her own
income, she reinvests 90% of it in her family and community. Getting
more girls into secondary education is shown to boost a
country’s economic growth, a point that the noble Lord, Lord
Quirk, picked up.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000161" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000161">The UK is already
helping to change the lives of millions of girls and women for the
better. As noble Lords will know, DfID has put gender equality front
and centre for the very reasons that noble Lords have laid out. Our
strategic vision for girls and women, launched in March 2011, aims to
unlock the potential of girls and women in order to stop poverty before
it starts. Maintaining our important cross-party consensus, I, too, pay
tribute to the previous Government’s recognition of this and to
the remarkable vision of my right honourable friend Andrew Mitchell
when he came into the department.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000162" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000162">Supporting girls and
women enables them to have a voice in decision-making in their
household, community and country, and in politics and business. My
noble friends Lady Hussein-Ece and Lady Jenkin and others have made the
case for this very clearly. It gives women and girls the freedom to
exercise choice in their lives: to be able to choose to complete
education and to benefit from paid work and to choose whether, when and
whom to marry. It recognises they should have control over their own
bodies and be safe from violence; control over their own income and
other resources such as food, water and energy; and equal legal rights
and access to justice.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000163" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000163">My noble friend Lady
Jenkin has given figures for DfID’s work, some of which bear
repeating here because they are very important. The UK aid
programme has already helped 270,000 girls to go to secondary
school. By 2015 we shall have saved the lives of at least 50,000 women
during pregnancy and childbirth, enabled 10 million more women to use
modern methods of family planning, improved access to financial
services 
<?notus-xml column=389?>for more than 18 million women, secured access to
land for 4.5 million women and helped 10 million women to access
justice through the courts, police and legal assistance.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000164">We are supporting the
efforts to end female genital mutilation worldwide through a £35
million programme, the first time that a programme like that has been
put in place. Noble Lords will know that yesterday was the
international day to end FGM, the first such day, and I was struck and
impressed by the level of social media involvement in that by
institutions from all over the world, organisations from Africa,
Australia, the United States and the EU and many organisations
within the UK, as well as the accounts in the <I>Times</I> and
the campaign by the <I>Guardian</I>. I pay tribute to those who have
brought it to this point and I hope that we will indeed end this within
a generation or, hopefully, before.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000165" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000165">We are determined to do
more to end violence against women and girls. Last November the
Secretary of State for International Development, who has been a strong
supporter of the Bill, launched an international call to action on
violence against women and girls in humanitarian emergencies. The
result was Governments and aid agencies from around the world signing
up to a groundbreaking commitment to make the safety of girls and women
a life-saving priority in our response to emergencies.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000166" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000166">I attended that
conference and was very struck by the commitments that were made and
that we must hold countries and institutions to. Like my noble friend
Lord Howell, I welcome the new Commonwealth charter with its
commitments in this area. Drafting things is the first stage, signing
up is the second and implementing is the third. We need
everyone’s efforts to ensure that that third stage is in fact
reached. In June this year the UK will host an international summit
where we will challenge the culture of impunity that exists for sexual
violence in conflict, and work to ensure that more perpetrators are
held to account through improved international
collaboration.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000167" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000167">So
the Bill comes at a critical point in development. Although we have
come so far in improving the lives of girls and women, there is much
further to go. There are still too many girls and women whose potential
is wasted. As my noble friend Lady Hodgson said, holding back women
impairs all development. It will not be easy to reach these women as we
are talking about some of the poorest and most vulnerable people in the
world, so we must keep up the pressure, the resources and the
visibility and lead by example.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000168" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000168">I am the first to
recognise, as did my noble friends Lady Jenkin and Lord Loomba and
others, that in this country we have a way to go in terms of gender
equality in Parliament, in business and in
society.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000169" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000169">If
the Bill is passed, it will mean that the Secretary of State for
International Development must have regard to reducing gender
inequality before making decisions to provide development assistance
under the International Development Act 2002. It will give our
commitment to addressing gender inequality in countries where we
provide development assistance a statutory footing, enshrined in law.
It will raise the bar on the way that gender equality is considered,
crystallising it in the early stages of the programme
development.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=390?><hs_para UID="14020749000170" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000170">Gender
is not something that can be tacked on to our development and
humanitarian assistance programmes for the very reasons that noble
Lords have laid out. The Bill will introduce an annual reporting duty
in respect of gender through an amendment to the International
Development (Reporting and Transparency) Act. My noble friend Lord
Loomba cogently argued that it is by this kind of monitoring and
transparency that we ensure the action and commitment that we
need.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000171" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000171">I note
that the Bill will not introduce any significant costs in
implementation—not that any noble Lord flagged that up—or
impose additional bureaucracy in decision-making or slow processes
down—not that any noble Lord flagged that up. It is about
ensuring that Ministers and officials fully take into account the
interests of girls and women as well as those of others in determining
the UK’s bilateral aid
programme.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000172" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000172">I
welcome the debate today and especially the cross-party support we have
heard for gender equality. It is heartening to hear so many positive
views on the important role that girls and women should have in the
world and on their right to a better life. This Bill will help keep
girls and women at the forefront in the delivery of development
assistance and in the planning that goes into it. The path to
sustainable development cannot be achieved where half the population is
locked out. Improving the lives of women and girls is already a top
priority in our international development work, but this Bill is
another important step forward enshrining our commitment to gender
equality in law, and the Government are proud to support
it<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:11:18"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="14020749000270" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000270">12.11
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000173" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000173"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord McColl of Dulwich" PimsId="1786" UID="14020749000314" xid="1330" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000314">Lord
McColl of Dulwich:</Member></B> My Lords, I thank all noble Lords for
their splendid contribution to this very important debate. I thank the
noble Baroness, Lady Hussein-Ece, for drawing attention to the proposed
new law in Afghanistan which could increase the violence against women,
and to their bravery. The noble Lord, Lord Quirk, was a distinguished
vice-chancellor of London University 30 years ago. I expect we all hope
that when we reach his age we will still be able to speak so lucidly
and with such courage on so many different topics. He reminds me of the
time when I had to give a speech to several hundred people. I went in,
and in the front row, there was a man who had just celebrated his 100th
birthday, so I took the microphone down and I said to him,
“Congratulations on your 100th birthday. I expect they’d
much rather listen to you than to me”, and he took the
microphone and made a speech. How right he was! He said that he was
interviewed in the village in Kent where he lived, and the BBC
interviewer asked, “Have you lived the whole of your life in
this village?”. “Not yet”, he said. I hope we will
be that bright when we are that
age.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000174" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000174">I thank
my noble friend Lady Jenkin for her contribution and especially for
mentioning what a great contribution Andrew Mitchell made in DfID. The
noble Lord, Lord Loomba, drew attention again to the fact that the
Government are maintaining their 0.7% help to developing countries and
how important that is. I was amazed when my noble friend Lady Hodgson
arrived and gave such a splendid speech because only three hours ago,
she had an operation. 
<?notus-xml column=391?>These ladies are tough. The noble Baroness, Lady
Farrington, emphasised that the attitude of males must be changed, not
before time. The noble Baroness, Lady Thornton, mentioned the help she
had from WaterAid. I should point out that it was WaterAid that had me
marching around the streets of
Kathmandu.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000175" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000175">I
thank the Minister for the promise of government support, and finally I
thank all noble Lords for their contributions.</hs_para>
<hs_Procedure UID="14020749000327" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000327">Bill read a second
time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/3A21F48B3CE0B2B12A6D086E5D4188F74A1E3C5F" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AO2-AP1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill">
<hs_DebateHeading UID="14020749000323" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000323">Deep Sea
Mining Bill</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="14020749000271" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000271">12.14
pm</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="14020749000332" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000332">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Wilcox" PimsId="4608" UID="14020749000315" xid="1496" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000315">Baroness
Wilcox</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020749000278" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000278">That the Bill be
read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="14020749000176" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000176"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Wilcox" PimsId="4608" UID="14020749000316" xid="1496" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000316">Baroness
Wilcox (Con):</Member></B>
My<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:49:11"></hs_TimeCode> Lords, some
noble Lords will be aware of my keen interest in the sea as a native of
Plymouth, with its rich maritime history. So my curiosity was drawn to
this Deep Sea Mining Bill, despite its less than auspicious title. Now,
knowing more about it, I am persuaded of the importance of this Bill
and of UK involvement in deep sea mining, including, paradoxically, for
the marine
environment.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000177" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000177">First,
let me explain the essence of what this Bill is about because deep sea
mining is still an industry in its infancy, working in an environment
about which little is known, and I suspect the subject is perhaps new
to a few of my noble
colleagues.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000178" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000178">Back
in the 1970s, when the deep sea mining provisions of the United Nations
Convention on the Law of the Sea—UNCLOS—were being
negotiated, polymetallic nodules were the only mineral resource
envisaged as commercially exploitable in the deep sea. No doubt this
was due to the relative ease of access to them. Polymetallic nodules
lie on the seabed or partially submerged in the sediment on the seabed.
So while they are found only at great depths, at least 3,000
metres deep and up to 6,000 metres deep, no drilling would be required
to harvest
them.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000179" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000179">Why
would these lumps of rock be exploitable? The clue is in the name:
polymetallic nodules. It is for the metal content. Polymetallic nodules
are potato-like rocks in shape and size, by which I mean smallish, but
variable. They are created by the accretion of minerals from the seabed
under great pressure over some millions of years and in places they lie
in great abundance on the sea floor. They contain a variety of metals,
mainly manganese, but also iron, aluminium, copper, nickel, cobalt and
some rare earth elements. Moreover, some of these metals are found in
greater concentration in polymetallic nodules than they are in mineral
sources on
land.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000180" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000180">Around
that time, the Deep Sea Mining (Temporary Provisions) Act 1981 was
passed. This allowed the Government to license companies for the
exploration and exploitation of polymetallic nodules in the deep sea in
areas beyond any state’s national jurisdiction.
Let me be clear that for the purposes of the Bill,
we are talking of areas at least beyond 200 nautical miles 
<?notus-xml column=392?>from the coast of any state. Potentially, we are referring to areas in
the southern Indian Ocean, a swathe down the middle of the Atlantic
Ocean and extensive areas of the Pacific
Ocean.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000181" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000181">The
reason for the “Temporary Provisions” in the title was in
recognition that international rules on deep sea mining were still
being negotiated as part of UNCLOS. The convention was eventually
finalised in 1982. It defined the deep seabed and its resources as the
common heritage of mankind. This novel concept meant that they did not
belong to any one state: it was not going to be the case of a
free-for-all. Under UNCLOS, the benefits from the minerals are to be
shared among states, particularly developing nations. UNCLOS provided
for the establishment of the International Seabed Authority, based in
Jamaica, to oversee the exploration and exploitation of minerals in the
deep sea, and ultimately to oversee the sharing of the
benefits.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000182" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000182">Some
30 years on, despite the early expectation that deep sea mining was
imminent, the International Seabed Authority issued its first contract
for the exploration of polymetallic nodules to a commercial operator
only in 2011. A year later, the ISA approved an application for
exploration of these nodules by a UK company, and subsequently signed a
contract with them in 2013. The UK Government have sponsored a second
application by the same company, and this is expected to be approved by
the ISA at its meeting in
2014.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000183" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000183">Why,
when the Government are already able to issue licences to UK companies,
and then sponsor their application to the ISA, do we then need a new
Bill to amend the Deep Sea Mining (Temporary Provisions) Act 1981? The
answer is twofold. First, the 1981 Act predated UNCLOS and, on a few
small and technical issues, it is not compatible with the convention.
In this new and developing industry, and as one of the early sponsors
of a commercial operator exploring in the deep sea, it is important
that the United Kingdom sets a good example to others by demonstrating
that it upholds international law in every respect, and that it
is able to act accordingly as and when
required<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:20:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000184" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000184">Secondly, in recent
years the ISA has agreed regulations for the exploration of two other
mineral types: polymetallic sulphides and cobalt-rich crusts. The 1981
Act allows the Government to issue licences only for exploration and
exploitation of polymetallic nodules. If the Government cannot license
for exploration of other minerals, it cannot demonstrate that it has
legislative oversight of the operations of the company concerned and
thus it cannot sponsor an application to the ISA. It would be a great
shame if, as would be likely, a United Kingdom company then applied for
sponsorship to another state. The United Kingdom would, in effect, be
turning business
away<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:21:16"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000185" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000185">The second amendment
therefore widens the definition of what is licensable from polymetallic
nodules to all mineral resources. This means that the Government can
license applications for the exploration and exploitation of
polymetallic sulphides and cobalt-rich crusts. It also means that if
the ISA introduces regulations for the exploration of different mineral
types in the future, such as oil and gas, no further amendments to
United Kingdom legislation will be
needed<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:21:50"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=393?><hs_para UID="14020749000186" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000186">Now that I have
explained what the Bill does with two apparently small amendments to
the 1981 Act, that begs the question of why the Bill is so important.
There are two main reasons. I will not be shy in saying that the first
is for the economic value to the United Kingdom. Noble Lords will be
only too aware that the price of metals has rocketed over the past
decade or so. Alas, the consequences have been felt by some of us with
rail services having been disrupted when power cables, and occasionally
the rails themselves, have disappeared. Metal prices are no doubt why
commercial companies are now looking hard at the possibility of deep
sea mining. New sources of supply would be hugely
beneficial<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:22:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000187" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000187">For some metals,
particularly rare earths required for a lot of modern technology
applications, there is a near monopolistic source of supply. In these
cases, there are additional, important, strategic benefits in the
diversification of supply. Another area of potential benefits is in job
creation. Deep sea mining should play to some of the UK’s
industrial and technological strengths that have developed over the
decades of oil and gas mining in the North Sea, some of which has
occurred at great depths. The United Kingdom has, for example,
developed some of the most advanced autonomous underwater
vehicles—mini-submarines to you and me—which can go down
to great depth for exploring and studying the deep seabed. We can also
expect our science and academic community, which already has some
expertise in the deep ocean floor, to benefit from the study of the
environment. It gives me great pleasure to mention the University of
Plymouth, which is to benefit from a link-up with the commercial
company that the UK Government have licensed. I went to that university
when it was a polytechnic, and was honoured to become one of its first
governors and am now able to hold an honorary science doctorate from
there, so I am
prejudiced<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:24:08"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000188" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000188">The more direct taxable
benefits are difficult to quantify because the industry is still at the
exploration stage. International regulations for exploitation have yet
to be developed. A good understanding of the environment on the deep
seabed has yet to be fully realised. Full environmental impact studies
based on the technologies for mining, which are themselves still to be
developed, are still some way off. The negotiations for how the revenue
from any mining operation is to be shared between the operator, the
sponsoring state and the ISA on behalf of the common heritage of
mankind have yet to take place. Despite the uncertainty of the
regulatory framework for exploitation, and despite this being still a
few years off, I am certain that it will happen. There seems little
doubt about this, as I noted with interest that both the Government and
the Opposition accepted this point in their deliberations in the other
place<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:25:16"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:25:12"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000189" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000189">That brings me to my
second reason why the Bill is important. If we accept that deep sea
mining will happen, we want it to do so adhering to the highest
possible environmental standards. The United Kingdom will be best
placed to help that happen if it is at the forefront of the industry.
The Government can do this domestically by, first, carrying out due
diligence on the companies applying for a UK licence to ensure 
<?notus-xml column=394?>that they are able to carry out their proposed work; secondly, ensuring
that the applications they consider for a licence employ the best
possible standards; and, thirdly, maintaining oversight of the
activities and reports of the company during the lifetime of its
licence. I know that I am reassured by the idea of a company being
given a licence by the UK Government, rather than by many other
Governments which I might not name, and which might not be as thorough
as ours.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="14020749000190" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000190">At
an international level, backed up by the example set by United Kingdom
companies, the Government have assured me that they will argue for the
best possible standards in the negotiations over what should go into
the mining regulations. As Kerry McCarthy said at Third Reading in the
other place,</hs_para>
<hs_quotefo UID="14020749000247" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000247">“we want to
be at the forefront not just because of the business opportunities
afforded to the UK, but in order to be able to determine standards for
ourselves rather than leaving it to others who may not consider
environmental protection as important as we
do”.—[<I>Official Report</I>, Commons, 24/1/14; col.
584.]</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="14020749000232" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000232">I
feel bound to add that Kerry McCarthy also proposed an amendment on
Report. This was with the expressed intention of strengthening the
environmental requirements under which the Government may offer a
licence for exploration or exploitation of minerals on the deep seabed.
I am assured that this is unnecessary because there are already
sufficient powers for the Government to impose high environmental
standards. Moreover, as knowledge of the deep sea environment increases
and technology improves, the Bill provides the flexibility for the
Government to adapt and increase the standards they consider
applicable.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="14020749000191" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000191">On
this basis, with support from the Government and thus far from the
Opposition too, I am pleased to support this Private Member’s
Bill. I beg to
move.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/16E9067EA76F2E94D7CFF18BC7C3A9F33C195A36" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AP2-AR1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="14020749000272" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000272"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:25:14"></hs_TimeCode>12.28
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000192" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000192"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Triesman" PimsId="4335" UID="14020749000317" xid="1688" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000317">Lord
Triesman (Lab):</Member></B> My Lords, I congratulate the noble
Baroness, Lady Wilcox, on introducing an important and timely Bill. I
was also pleased to hear her remind us that she is from Plymouth. I
hope that she is able to travel home and back to us without any
unwanted contact with the deep sea as she makes her
progress<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:28:29"></hs_TimeCode>. I also
place on the record our appreciation of the steps taken to introduce
the proposals in another place by the noble Baroness’s
honourable friend Sheryll Murray. It is clear from debates at all
stages that there is broad support for the Bill—and so it will
be from these Benches in your Lordships’
House<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:28:45"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000193" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000193">I personally welcome
the Bill. I dealt for nearly three years with the interpretation of the
international law of the sea, and also with territories, including the
hyper-fragile Antarctica territories for which the United Kingdom is
responsible<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:29:05"></hs_TimeCode>.
What we do on land has significance for the habitats in the oceans, and
how we treat the oceans will have vital ramifications for
life on land. The earth is, in a couple of words, wholly
interdependent<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:29:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000194" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000194">I also express
appreciation for the work of the FCO officials, not least for the
provision of a really helpful set of Explanatory Notes. As the notes
observe, part 11 of the United Nations Convention on the Law
of the Sea, which was modified in 1994, provides for regulation 
<?notus-xml column=395?>of deep seabed mining. Individual states that are signatories to the
convention are required to make certain that mining contractors act
within domestic law in each of the assenting states so as to be
sponsored by those states for the conduct of the work. Moreover, all
those contractors must enter a contract with the International Seabed
Authority before any activity can commence, whether exploration or
mining mineral
resources<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:30:09"></hs_TimeCode>. Some
may regard such a system of safety interlocks as being inhibiting. I do
not, and it is clear in moving that the noble Baroness did not think
them inhibiting either. I am sure that she is right; this is a prudent
set of
arrangements<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:30:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000195" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000195">It
is also true that few commercial businesses were interested initially.
Companies I spoke with gave three interlinked reasons for that. First,
it was technically difficult and expensive to undertake such work, as
the commercial risks were high. Secondly, there was little clarity
about what might be found, and in what quantities. Again, that
compounded the commercial risk. Thirdly, even if there were significant
polymetallic nodules or resources lying in the sediment at slightly
deeper levels, it was not clear that there was a significant enough
market, given that there are known polymetallic resources on dry land
and that the size of existing markets for mined products might not at
one stage have been sufficiently large. That gave little reassurance to
businesses assessing commercial risk. The consequence, at least in my
view, was that it was close to impossible to price the risk. Companies
could not price it in allocating their own working capital, and neither
could they or market analysts price it for either quoted markets or for
private equity or debt. It was pretty much beyond reasonable
computation. No wonder that things moved at the pace of a deep-ocean
snail<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:31:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000196" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000196">What
changed all that—and I was very grateful to the noble Baroness,
Lady Wilcox, for touching on these facts—is that there has been
a considerable move in a positive commercial direction. There has been
progress in the development of technologies capable of operating in
deep water, both submarines and robotics, and the rapid growth in
demand for polymetallic nodules and polymetallic sulphides, as well as
cobalt and rare earths—which are of some significance in
this—created by the huge economic surges in China, India, Russia
and Brazil, and now in Turkey, Mexico, Indonesia and Nigeria, has all
but overwhelmed the supplies that might be available on land. The same
has happened with other commodities as varied as oil, concrete, iron,
wheat and beef, which are all part of the same economic
trajectory<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:32:47"></hs_TimeCode>.
Finally, the science has become clearer about what could be found at
different depths, making the targeting of specific minerals a practical
task. In short, it became easier to price risk, raise and deploy
capital with a degree of certainty about the returns, and then commence
the
work<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:33:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000197" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000197">Two
problems immediately surface. The original convention and consequential
legislation did not cover all the new circumstances that we have seen
and which have been among the areas of change described by the noble
Baroness and by me today. The updating this new Bill aims to achieve
would be welcome enough on those grounds alone. However, it helps us
add the second missing ingredient: the environmental issues and our
responsibility to protect the environment. We 
<?notus-xml column=396?>cannot regard this obligation as merely helpful. It is obligatory and
summed up in the initial iteration of Clause 5 of our own 1981 Act. I
will quote it briefly because the groundwork was set at that time. It
states:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="14020749000239" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000239">“In
determining whether to grant an exploration or exploitation licence the
Secretary of State shall have regard to the need to protect (so far as
reasonably practicable) marine creatures, plants and other organisms
and their habitat from any harmful effects which might result from any
activities to be authorised by the licence; and the Secretary of State
shall consider any representations made to him concerning such
effects”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="14020749000198" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000198">That
is not a bad
start<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:34:34"></hs_TimeCode>. However,
more than 30 years on, and guided by the Rio Declaration,
particularly at principle 15, we know more but still not enough about
the environment. A precautionary approach seems very sensible. That
precautionary approach, urged on us by the World Wide Fund for Nature
and many others, should be part of our focus today. We have urged the
same approach on other nations in fragile environments, for example in
our legislation on the Antarctic and in our criticisms of some of the
mining proposals others have had in respect of the Arctic as
well<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:35:23"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="14020749000199" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000199">I
hope that the House will not misunderstand the argument I am
trying to put. I do not say for a moment, “Do nothing until we
know every possible consequence”. That is not what I mean by
“precautionary”, and would be a legal and practical veto
on doing anything. I accept that it is impossible to say that nothing
is permitted until we know everything; there would be no progress at
all if such an overwhelming test of efficacy was to be imposed. I
argue, rather, that we should proceed in a circumspect and incremental
manner, using what science can tell us wherever possible.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000200" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000200">The<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:50:35"></hs_TimeCode>
first-order question is easy: should we protect the environment and
husband its living resources? The answer is obviously yes, but what
follows? Perhaps the noble Baroness, Lady Wilcox, and others involved
in advancing the Bill may take a view, even if not in the course of
today’s debate. I just wish to record some things which we need
to resolve, but I do it in a wholly friendly spirit, because these
issues concern us
all.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000201" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000201">Will the
entire procedure<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:36:59"></hs_TimeCode>
for granting exploitation contracts be sufficiently robust and well
integrated, given the multiple issues—authority at the mining
location, knowledge of the ecosystem at the location, and control over
mining practices? Not all the information or decisions will lie in the
hands of any one party. They will need to be integrated to get a
holistic picture and avoid the scope for real
error<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:37:08"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000202" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000202">Is
the ISA able to monitor and police at scale? I have no doubt that it
can do it in a limited way, but I am not as convinced that it
can do it at scale; that is something that we should explore. Do we
have evidence of risk of extinction for affected species? For example,
do we know if sedimentary plumes below known densities of specific
depths are dangerous or benign? Can scientists advise us on risk
mitigation capable of being written into any set of regulations? What
density of mining activity in any one location will be allowed on
environmental grounds? Indeed, what will be the criteria for awarding
permissions<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:37:56"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000203" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000203">There
is an opportunity to mine between 1,400 metres and 5,000
metres below the surface. I think that I am right in saying that it is
usually near active or extinct 
<?notus-xml column=397?>hydrothermal vents in the earth’s
crust—and I am grateful to the noble Baroness for identifying
these parts of the globe. But we know that those are precisely the
locations of a vast array of aquatic life; they happen to be
particularly dense in species of animal life. Preferred methods will
spread the sedimentary plumes far more widely than the water column
where the mining is actually undertaken. Will the Government perhaps be
able to commit themselves to funding longitudinal research to ensure
that we know as much as possible about each incremental step so that we
can make the best informed decisions without preventing the development
of this commercial and necessary
opportunity<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:38:55"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000204" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000204">I<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T11:50:35"></hs_TimeCode>
hope that no one will say, in answering, that we should rely on the
United Nations agencies for the research, as they take too
long—and much of the research, to be candid, is not that great.
We, along with the United States and some our European partners, have
universities capable of really credible research in these areas, and I
would wish to see that done because I am much more confident of the
quality of the research that could be done that
way<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:39:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000205" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000205">Important
as these questions are, progress today on the Bill is important, as it
will be in later stages. For those
reasons<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:39:29"></hs_TimeCode>, I
finish by saying that we support the Bill and wish it rapid progress,
and I thank the noble Baroness for introducing
it.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/0300EEA8F2E3583F44EA14398BBE3B09199A7BA5" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AR2-AS1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="14020749000273" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000273"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:39:38"></hs_TimeCode></I>12.39
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:39:38"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000206" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000206"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="14020749000318" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000318">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member></B> My Lords, I start by saying that
the Government give this Bill their whole-hearted support. I thank my
noble friend Lady Wilcox for introducing the Bill for your
Lordships’ consideration, along with her honourable friend in
the House of Commons, Sheryll Murray, who brought forward this valuable
Bill. Both of them have good links with the sea in south-west
England—happier links than in the current conditions. I have had
many conversations with the noble Baroness, Lady Wilcox, on
the fisheries
issue<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:40:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000207" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000207">To
some extent, this is a journey down Memory Lane for me. In the 1970s,
as a young academic working on British foreign policy, I did some work
on the British-Icelandic fisheries dispute and got from there into the
question of international fisheries regulation. I then found myself
invited to some of the
conference<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:40:33"></hs_TimeCode>s
preparing the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea, and I remember
hearing about manganese nodules and how they were very much one of the
materials of the future. The future is clearly rather longer term than
people in the late 1970s and early 1980s were thinking, but it is clear
that, as some companies begin investigating whether one can mine
asteroids, the deep sea will be rather easier than that, as we search
for other
resources<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:41:12"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000208" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000208">In
answer to the noble Lord, Lord Triesman, efforts at global fisheries
regulation, in treating global fisheries as the common heritage of
mankind, have not yet succeeded in providing the level of enforcement
of regulation that we all hoped for then. That raises a number of
issues for how well global and regional institutions will be able to
co-operate to make sure that, in these very deep oceans, regulations
are observed. It is yet another area in which the
idea that Britain on 
<?notus-xml column=398?>its own as a sovereign country, not co-operating
with others, can do things—the myth of UKIP and others—is
clearly idiotic. We have to work intensively with others to conduct the
sort of research that the noble Lord, Lord Triesman, is talking about,
and that is much better done in a European, OECD or UN
context<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:42:05"></hs_TimeCode>. That is
the way in which any intelligent foreign policy has to go
forward—a message that all of us who believe in international
co-operation are going to have to make loud and clear over the next few
months. We are better together in the European Union, in the UN
and within the
UK<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:42:30"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000209" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000209">We
have heard that deep sea mining has tremendous potential, but it is
still potential. We expect that at some point in the next generation it
will begin to play a very significant role in the world economy. We
welcome this Bill partly as reinforcing the ability of the United
Kingdom Government to be an active participant at the leading edge of
such developments. The Government have already sponsored two
applications to the International Seabed Authority by a British company
to explore for polymetallic nodules in the north Pacific. We want to
make sure that British business is well placed to take advantage of all
future developments in deep sea
mining<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:43:15"></hs_TimeCode>. Britain
already has substantial expertise in relevant technologies learnt
through exploiting gas industries in the North Sea, in deeper and
deeper
waters<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:43:30"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:42:40"></hs_TimeCode>.
Much of this technology and the associated expertise could also be
utilised in the deeper sea mining that is
envisaged.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000210" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000210">Last<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:43:38"></hs_TimeCode>
year, my colleagues in the Department for Business, Innovation and
Skills organised a very successful industry day to alert British
companies to the opportunities which deep sea mining might in time
provide for them. I am pleased to say that about 80 British companies
participated. The economic opportunities which deep sea mining might
open up are potentially very substantial. The Government have already
taken action to bring them to the attention of British
companies<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:44:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000211" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000211">At
present, we are only at the stage where exploration for minerals on the
deep seabed is taking place. In due course, we can expect that the
International Seabed Authority will move to consider
exploitation—in other words, actual mining—of minerals on
the deep seabed. The Government are, of course, committed to ensuring
that the highest environmental standards are applied at the exploration
phase, and even more so at the exploitation phase. The UK delegation
made it clear during a first discussion of exploitation regulations at
last year’s session of the council of the ISA that we would
expect to see the exploitation regulations include the highest possible
environmental standards, and we are determined to press this position.
We also emphasised the importance of there being full consultations
with all relevant shareholders, including, therefore, non-governmental
organisations with an interest in the marine environment. I say to the
noble Lord, Lord Triesman, that we will engage with the question of how
we manage to enforce what is agreed as well as getting through the
process of what is agreed. We certainly need to learn from the
difficulties that we have experienced with regard to international
fisheries.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000212" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000212">During<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:45:26"></hs_TimeCode>
the debates in the other place, we were urged to look again at Section
5 of the 1981 Act. This section requires the Government, when issuing
licences, 
<?notus-xml column=399?>to have regard to the need to protect the marine
environment so far as is reasonably practicable. It is clear that deep
sea mining cannot have no effect on the marine environment, but we can
mitigate the effects, and that is what Section 5 of the 1981 Act
already requires us to do. Therefore, the Bill does make amendments to
Section 5 of the 1981 Act, but these are all purely consequential upon
the fact that Scottish Ministers will now have the ability to issue
licences under the
Act<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:49:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/27BA956A1E652378540C8B12337A1C10981E617F" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>AS2-AT</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_para UID="14020749000213" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000213">However,
in the light of the comments made in the other place, we have looked
again at whether more substantive changes should be made to Section 5.
We remain of the view that Section 5 is still adequate for our
purposes. In particular, in carrying out their duties under Section 5,
Ministers would necessarily have to take into account the terms of the
advisory opinion from the International Tribunal for the Law of the Sea
given in 2011. This made it clear that, in sponsoring applications to
the International Seabed Authority, states must have regard to their
environmental obligations. That includes specifically the precautionary
approach set out in the Rio declaration. Therefore, we are satisfied
that Section 5 is adequate as it stands and, indeed, that it is worded
in such a way that account can be taken of further developments in the
international law relating to the protection of the
environment.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000214" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000214">It<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:47:04"></hs_TimeCode>
was suggested in the other place that, since the ISA will shortly be
considering the question of exploitation regulations, the Bill might be
premature. I can assure the House that this is not so. On the contrary,
it is important that the law of the United Kingdom should enable us to
ensure compliance with the mining regulations once they are adopted,
and that is what this Bill will do. The new Section 2(3A) will enable
Ministers to include in licences a requirement on contractors to comply
with any rules, regulations or procedures adopted by the International
Seabed Authority. Therefore, the Bill is not at all premature. It is,
in fact, very timely because it will enable us to give effect to the
mining regulations as soon as they are adopted by the ISA. I am happy
to reiterate that the Government are committed to applying the highest
environmental standards in any applications which they sponsor, and
will do all they can to ensure that the ISA also incorporates such
standards in its
regulations.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000215" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000215">The
Bill itself applies only to exploration and exploitation on the deep
seabed; that is to say, the area of the seas beyond the jurisdiction of
any state, including that of the United Kingdom. The Bill makes
extensive amendments to the existing legislation— the 1981 Act,
which has proved anything but temporary, being now of course more than
30 years old—and, in recognition of this, the Short Title will
be amended to remove the reference to its temporary
character.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000216" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000216">There<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:48:49"></hs_TimeCode>
are two principal reasons why it was felt necessary to bring forward
amendments to the 1981 Act. As has already been remarked, the first was
that it was passed before the UK’s ratification of the United
Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea.
<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:49:10"></hs_TimeCode>It is therefore
not surprising that in some respects the 1981 Act does not fully
reflect the requirements of the convention. However, the most
significant reason for needing this Bill is that the 1981 Act covered
only polymetallic nodules, or manganese nodules as they 
<?notus-xml column=400?>were known in those days. I have already explained
what these are, and it was thought at the time that the 1981 Act was
passed that they were the only mineral resources on the deep seabed
likely to be exploitable. Now we are discovering polymetallic sulphides
and cobalt-rich crusts; I am sure that all of us would instantly
recognise these when we saw them. They happen to be a mere 3,000 metres
down, under the ocean.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000217" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000217">In the past few years,
the ISA has adopted regulations about cobalt-rich crusts and
polymetallic sulphides. I am told that cobalt-rich crusts occur on sea
mounts in the western Pacific Ocean and there is already interest in
exploring for them from China, Japan and Russia. I am pleased also that
Brazil, one of the key emerging markets in the world, has just
submitted an application to explore for crusts in the south Atlantic.
As to polymetallic sulphides, these normally occur at the source of
extinct volcanic activity on the deep seabed, as the noble Lord, Lord
Triesman, said. There are now six applications to explore for these
minerals, covering areas of the Indian Ocean and the Atlantic
Ocean.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020749000218" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000218">Obviously,
I am sure all noble Lords will agree, the Government would like to have
an open door to any contractor who wishes to explore for any of the
mineral resources of the deep seabed. However, under the 1981 Act as it
stands, we could not give a licence to a commercial company that wished
to explore for cobalt-rich crusts or polymetallic sulphides. If a
company came along with a request for the United Kingdom to sponsor an
application to explore for either of these mineral resources, we would
be obliged to say no. The company would no doubt simply then go to one
of the other 160 states that are members of the ISA and seek
sponsorship from it. To put it crudely, the United Kingdom would simply
lose out.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000219" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000219">It<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:51:30"></hs_TimeCode>
is for this reason among others that the Government fully support this
Bill—indeed, they are enthusiastic about it. It demonstrates
that the UK is open for business internationally and that we are keen
to participate in what will, I am sure, in time—perhaps not in
my time—be a ground-breaking and innovative industry. I
congratulate again my noble friend Lady Wilcox on introducing this Bill
and I hope that it will receive the unanimous support of the
House.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="14020749000274" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000274"><hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:51:55"></hs_TimeCode>12.52
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="14020749000220" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000220"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Wilcox" PimsId="4608" UID="14020749000319" xid="1496" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000319">Baroness
Wilcox:</Member></B> My Lords, I have been fortunate indeed to have as
my Minister someone with whom I have worked over time. My noble friend
Lord Wallace of Saltaire knows the area that we are talking about and
certainly knows the sea very well; it is certainly worth having him on
board. I am always interested to hear about the career of the noble
Lord, Lord Triesman, because he has always done something with which I
have been involved somewhere along the line. He is a man of many
parts—there is no doubt about that—and I am very grateful
to
him<hs_TimeCode time="2014-02-07T12:52:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020749000221" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000221">I should have started
my earlier remarks by of course thanking Sheryll Murray, who introduced
the Bill in another place. I also thank the FCO officials who have done
a wonderful job of giving me a superb briefing and making me sound as
if I really know what I am talking about on this very complex subject.
However, it is an exciting subject. For me, anything to 
<?notus-xml column=401?>do with the sea is an exciting subject. So little is known yet about the
potential impact of deep sea exploitation but because we are coming at
it in the way we are, and with the support of all sides of the House, I
am extremely grateful and hope that we will move forward at
speed.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=402?><hs_parafo UID="14020749000233" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000233"><I>Bill read a second
time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</I></hs_parafo><hs_Procedure UID="14020749000328" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207-0001.htm#14020749000328">House
adjourned at 12.54
pm.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Writtens" ColStart="87"><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/7E58125DE5B9046272E73033F1D50FD45B646FC0" __version__="1.2"><Header><House>0</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date="7 February 2014">Friday
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>Header-10-755</Section><TransformationVersion>0.5</TransformationVersion></Header><Body><hs_HoL UID="14020747000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000002">Written
Answers</hs_HoL><hs_date UID="14020747000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000001"><I>Friday 7 February
2014</I></hs_date></Body></Fragment><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/0C5294995B37184EFA8D0CB5A88E99A316A210A5" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>1</System><Sitting short-date=" 7 February 2014">Friday,
7 February
2014</Sitting><Section>Section</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020747000052" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000052">Coastal
Communities
Fund</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000059" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000059">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Winston" PimsId="4649" UID="14020747000030" xid="1499" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000030">Lord
Winston</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000019">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government, given the Coastal Communities Fund was set
up in 2011, (1) how soon the promised grants from the
updated total of £29m advertised in August 2013 will be
allocated, (2) how many coastal communities are scheduled to benefit,
and (3) which Minister will be responsible for allocating the
funds.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL5063]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000003"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020747000031" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000031">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Communities and
Local Government (Baroness Stowell of Beeston) (Con):</Member>
The £29 million funding announced for the
UK-wide Coastal Communities Fund last August is for the 2014-15
financial year. The Department for Communities and Local Government,
together with the devolved administrations for Wales, Scotland and
Northern Ireland will be inviting applications for this funding round
shortly with the aim of allocating the money available to projects by
the end of
2014.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020747000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000004">The
Coastal Communities Fund is a competitive bid-led fund so it is not
possible at this stage to say how many coastal communities will
benefit. However, 104 grants were awarded across the UK in the first
year of the Fund benefitting over 130 coastal
communities.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020747000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000005">Decisions
on grant awards in England are taken by the Secretary of State for
Communities and Local Government, informed by recommendations from the
Big Lottery Fund which helps to deliver the Fund on behalf of the UK
Government. In Wales and Northern Ireland decisions are taken by an
independent panel but with sign off by Welsh Assembly and Northern
Ireland Assembly Ministers. In Scotland, decisions are taken by an
independent panel with no involvement of Scottish Government
Ministers.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020747000053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000053">Electoral
Registration</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Questions</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000060" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000060">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Kennedy of Southwark" PimsId="5762" UID="14020747000032" xid="2042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000032">Lord
Kennedy of Southwark</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000020">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what discussions they have had with the
Society of Local Authority Chief Executives and Senior Managers about
registering United Kingdom citizens who are eligible to vote but are
not on the electoral
register.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL4941]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000006"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="14020747000033" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000033">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member> The Government has regular
engagement with the Society of Local Authority Chief Executives
(SOLACE) and Local Authority Senior Officers on the support it is
giving local authorities and Valuation Joint Boards in Scotland during
the transition to Individual Electoral Registration; this includes
support to maximise the levels of electoral registration.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=88?><hs_para UID="14020747000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000007">Dave Smith, Head of the
SOLACE Electoral Matters Panel, is a member of the Cabinet Office
Programme Board overseeing the change to IER and officials regularly
meet with him.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="14020747000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000008">The Minister of State
for Cities and Constitution attended the annual SOLACE elections
conference on 16th January. Officials have also met with a wide range
of local authority Chief Executives and senior officers over the past
three years in preparing for the transition to IER.</hs_para>
<hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000061" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000061">Asked by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Kennedy of Southwark" PimsId="5762" UID="14020747000034" xid="2042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000034">Lord
Kennedy of Southwark</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000021">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what discussions they have had with the
Local Government Association about registering United Kingdom citizens
who are eligible to vote but not on the electoral
register. <hs_QuestionUIN>[HL4942]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000009"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="14020747000035" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000035">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member> The Cabinet Office has engaged with the
Local Government Association with Ministerial attendance at the Local
Government Association’s Annual Conference in
2013.</hs_para><hs_para UID="14020747000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000010">Funding
is being provided to local authorities to maximise registration amongst
currently under-registered groups as part of the introduction of
individual electoral registration, in addition to the duty that EROs
have to ensure completeness and accuracy of the electoral
register.</hs_para><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000062" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000062">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Kennedy of Southwark" PimsId="5762" UID="14020747000036" xid="2042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000036">Lord
Kennedy of Southwark</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000022">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what discussions they have had with London
councils about registering United Kingdom citizens who are eligible to
vote but not on the electoral
register.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL4943]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000011"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="14020747000037" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000037">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member> The Government is providing funding to
all Electoral Registration Officers, including in London Councils,
through the £4.2 million maximising registration fund to
encourage them to take steps to maximise registration during the
transition to Individual Electoral
Registration.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020747000054" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000054">Government:
Ministerial
Responsibilities</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000063" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000063">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Myners" PimsId="5359" UID="14020747000038" xid="1997" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000038">Lord
Myners</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000023">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government which Ministers currently hold unpaid
posts.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL4979]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000012"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="14020747000039" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000039">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member> I refer the Noble Lord to the GOV.uk
web page:
https://www.gov.uk/government/ministers</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020747000055" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000055">Lord-Lieutenants</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000064" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000064">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Palmer" PimsId="91" UID="14020747000040" xid="1378" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000040">Lord
Palmer</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000024">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government when they will announce who will be the
next Lord-Lieutenant of
Berwickshire.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL5022]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question>

<?notus-xml column=89?><hs_para UID="14020747000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000013"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="14020747000041" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000041">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member> The appointment of the next
Lord-Lieutenant of Berwickshire will be announced
shortly.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020747000056" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000056">Planning</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Questions</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000065" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000065">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Marlesford" PimsId="1697" UID="14020747000042" xid="1138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000042">Lord
Marlesford</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000025">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what are their plans with respect to the
priorities they expect local planning authorities to give when
considering applications for the conversion of agricultural buildings
to (1) holiday homes, and (2) houses to meet housing
needs.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL4951]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000014"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020747000043" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000043">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Communities and
Local Government (Baroness Stowell of Beeston) (Con):</Member>
Local planning authorities are required to determine
any planning application in accordance with its local plan and the
National Planning Policy Framework unless material considerations
indicate
otherwise.</hs_para><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000066" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000066">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Marlesford" PimsId="1697" UID="14020747000044" xid="1138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000044">Lord
Marlesford</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000026">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government when they expect to publish their summary
of, and conclusions from, the <I>Greater flexibilities for change of
use</I> consultation on the conversion of agricultural
buildings.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL4952]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000015"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020747000045" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000045">Baroness
Stowell of Beeston:</Member> The consultation document <I>Greater
flexibilities for change of use</I> noted that we would aim to
introduce any new legislation by 6 April 2014. We are currently
considering the responses to the consultation and will make any
announcement in the
Spring.</hs_para><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000067">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Willoughby de Broke" PimsId="4627" UID="14020747000046" xid="1498" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000046">Lord
Willoughby de Broke</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000027">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government when they expect to complete the
consultation process on the proposals contained in the consultation
paper “Greater flexibilities for change of use”, issued
in August 2013.
<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL5131]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000016"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020747000047" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000047">Baroness
Stowell of Beeston:</Member> The consultation on extending permitted
development rights for change of use closed on 15 October 2013.
We are currently 
<?notus-xml column=90?>considering the responses to the consultation and, as indicated in the
consultation document <I>Greater flexibilities for change of use</I>,
we will publish our response in due
course.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020747000057" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000057">Quangos
and Non-governmental
Organisations</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000068" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000068">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Stoddart of Swindon" PimsId="4150" UID="14020747000048" xid="1452" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000048">Lord
Stoddart of Swindon</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000028" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000028">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what proportion of chairpersons of quangos
and non-governmental organisations have party political affiliations or
sympathies to (1) the Conservative Party, (2) the Labour Party, (3) the
Liberal Democrats, and (4) other
parties.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL5233]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000017"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="14020747000049" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000049">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire (LD):</Member> The Commissioner for Public
Appointments’ Annual Survey of Ministerial Appointments and
Reappointments to the Board of Public Bodies sets out the declared
political activity for appointments and reappointments by party since
2000-01.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="14020747000058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000058">Waste
Management: Rubbish
Bins</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="14020747000069" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000069">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Kennedy of Cradley" PimsId="7021" UID="14020747000050" xid="2213" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000050">Baroness
Kennedy of Cradley</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="14020747000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000029">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what assessment has been made of the case
for regulation of the provision of storage facilities for rubbish bins
in residential blocks of
flats.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL4961]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="14020747000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000018"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stowell of Beeston" PimsId="5900" UID="14020747000051" xid="2111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/140207w0001.htm#14020747000051">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Communities and
Local Government (Baroness Stowell of Beeston) (Con):</Member>
Requirement H6 of Schedule 1 to the Building
Regulations seeks to ensure that adequate provision is made for waste
storage. Statutory guidance as to how this requirement can be met is
provided in Approved Document H. Last year's Housing Standards Review
consultation sought views on whether, and if so how, these provisions
needed to be updated to better tackle bin blight. We are currently
considering responses to the
consultation.</hs_para></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Index"><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/Index/DAE2963A8569960FB9A2D14DC1CEC424839ABC33" __version__="1.2"><Index cdate="14" cday="Friday" cmonth="February" cyear="2014" date="7" day="Friday" issue="113" maxparts="1" month="February" part="1" price="" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="752" year="2014"><tocdate col="WA87">Friday 7 February 2014</tocdate><title>ALPHABETICAL
INDEX TO WRITTEN ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA87">Coastal Communities
Fund</level1><level1 col="WA87">Electoral
Registration</level1><level1 col="WA88">Government:
Ministerial
Responsibilities</level1><level1 col="WA88">Lord-Lieutenants</level1><level1 col="WA89">Planning</level1><level1 col="WA90">Quangos
and Non-governmental
Organisations</level1><level1 col="WA90">Waste
Management: Rubbish Bins</level1><title>NUMERICAL
INDEX TO WRITTEN
ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA87">[HL4941]</level1><level1 col="WA88">[HL4942]</level1><level1 col="WA88">[HL4943]</level1><level1 col="WA89">[HL4951]</level1><level1 col="WA89">[HL4952]</level1><level1 col="WA90">[HL4961]</level1><level1 col="WA88">[HL4979]</level1><level1 col="WA88">[HL5022]</level1><level1 col="WA87">[HL5063]</level1><level1 col="WA89">[HL5131]</level1><level1 col="WA90">[HL5233]</level1></Index></Fragment></System><System type="Back_Cover"><?date 2014-02-07?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2014_02_07_PT_1/Cover/69960FB9A2D14DC1CEC424839ABC33DAE2963A85" __version__="1.2"><Contents cdate="14" cday="Friday" cmonth="February" cyear="2014" date="7" day="Friday" issue="113" maxparts="1" month="February" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="752" year="2014"><citicont1 col="359">Leasehold
Reform (Amendment) Bill <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="369">Citizenship
(Armed Forces) Bill <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="375">International
Development (Gender Equality) Bill <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="391">Deep
Sea Mining Bill <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="WA 87">Written
Answers</citicont1></Contents></Fragment></System></House></HansardDoc>