<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill52_IV(b))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 110, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 110 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 135, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Long-term police authorisation requiring independent approval</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 32A (authorisations requiring judicial approval) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;32AA Long-term police authorisations requiring independent approval</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where a relevant person has granted a long-term authorisation under section 29.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The authorisation is not to take effect until such time (if any) as the relevant independent body has made an order approving the grant of the authorisation.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The relevant independent body may give approval under this section to the granting of an authorisation under section 29 if, and only if, the relevant independent body is satisfied that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the time of the grant&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) there were reasonable grounds for believing that the requirements of section 29(2), and any requirements imposed by virtue of section 29(7)(b) are satisfied in relation to that authorisation, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the relevant conditions were satisfied in relation to that authorisation, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) at the time when the relevant independent body is considering the matter, there remain reasonable grounds for believing that the requirements of section 29(2), and any requirements imposed by virtue of section 29(7)(b) are satisfied in relation to that authorisation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes of subsection (3) the relevant conditions in relation to a grant by an individual holding an office, rank or position in a relevant law enforcement agency, that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the individual was a designated person for the purposes of section 29,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the grant of an authorisation was not in breach of any prohibition imposed by virtue of section 29(7)(a) or any restriction imposed by virtue of section 30(3), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any other conditions that may be provided for by the Secretary of State were satisfied.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant law enforcement authority&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a police force in the United Kingdom, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the National Crime Agency;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant judicial authority&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in relation to England and Wales, the High Court of Justice in England, and Wales,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to Scotland, the Court of Session, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in relation to Northern Ireland, the High Court of Justice in Northern Ireland;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant person&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an individual holding an office, rank or position in a police force in the United Kingdom, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an individual holding an office, rank or position in the National Crime Agency.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant independent body&#8221; must be set out by the Home Secretary in a motion passed by both Houses of Parliament before this Clause is enacted;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;long-term&#8221; must be set out by the Home Secretary in a motion passed by both Houses of Parliament before this Clause is enacted.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 141, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 141 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 160, page 128, line 31, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(11) Within three months of the passage of this Act, the Secretary of State shall seek written advice from the Intelligence and Security Committee as to whether there are any considerations of national security and intelligence which would need to be examined in relation to the appointment of a non-UK national to the following posts&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Commissioner of Police for the Metropolis,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Deputy Commissioner of Police for the Metropolis,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the Assistant Commissioner of the Metropolitan Police appointed by the Commissioner to have operational responsibility for UK counter-terrorist policing,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the Director General of the National Crime Agency, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) any successors who hold posts with equivalent responsibilities in the future.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(12) Section 126 shall not come into force until the Intelligence and Security Committee has reported its findings under subsection (11) to the Secretary of State and a copy of those findings has been laid before both Houses of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>