<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill78(a))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON THIRD READING</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 10, leave out subsection (3)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Meaning of &#8220;anti-social behaviour&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(1) In this Part &#8220;anti-social behaviour&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) conduct that has caused, or is likely to cause, harassment, alarm or distress to any person,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) conduct capable of causing nuisance or annoyance to a person in relation to that person&#8217;s occupation of residential premises, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) conduct capable of causing housing-related nuisance or annoyance to any person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Subsection (1)(b) applies only where the injunction under section 1 is applied for by&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a housing provider,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a local authority, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a chief officer of police.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (1)(c) &#8220;housing-related&#8221; means directly or indirectly relating to the housing management functions of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a housing provider, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a local authority.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes of subsection (3) the housing management functions of a housing provider or a local authority include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) functions conferred by or under an enactment;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the powers and duties of the housing provider or local authority as the holder of an estate or interest in housing accommodation.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 19</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 19, page 9, line 38, leave out &#8220;1(2)&#8221; and insert &#8220;(Meaning of &#8220;anti-social behaviour&#8221;)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 20</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 20, page 11, line 16, leave out &#8220;section 13(5)&#8221; and insert &#8220;subsection (5A)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 20, page 11, line 19, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5A) The provisions referred to in subsection (5)(b) are&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 1(7);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) sections 3(2) and 8 (if a power of arrest is attached);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) sections 5 to 7;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) section 9;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) section 10 and Schedule 1;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) section 11 and Schedule 2;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) section 17(1).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 100</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 100, page 68, line 16, leave out from &#8220;behaviour&#8221;&#8221; to end of line 17 and insert &#8220;has the meaning given by section (Meaning of &#8220;anti-social behaviour&#8221;) (ignoring subsection (2) of that section);&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 101</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 101, page 69, line 19, leave out from &#8220;behaviour&#8221;&#8221; to end of line 20 and insert &#8220;has the meaning given by section (Meaning of &#8220;anti-social behaviour&#8221;) (ignoring subsection (2) of that section);&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 113</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 113, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Use of premises for child sex offences</quote>
         <quote>(1) Schedule (Amendments of Part 2A of the Sexual Offences Act 2003) (amendments of Part 2A of the Sexual Offences Act 2003) has effect.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of sections 136BA and 136D(7A) of the Sexual Offences Act (inserted by that Schedule), it does not matter whether the offence or offences in question were committed before, or on or after, the date on which this section comes into force.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 119</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 119, page 85, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In relation to a victim who lacks capacity to consent to marriage, the offence under subsection (1) is capable of being committed by any conduct carried out for the purpose of causing the victim to enter into a marriage (whether or not the conduct amounts to violence, threats or any other form coercion).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 119, page 85, line 44, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) &#8220;Lacks capacity&#8221; means lacks capacity within the meaning of the Mental Capacity Act 2005.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 119, page 86, line 5, leave out &#8220;coercion&#8221; and insert &#8220;conduct&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 120</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 120, page 86, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In relation to a victim who is incapable of consenting to marriage by reason of mental disorder, the offence under subsection (1) is capable of being committed by any conduct carried out for the purpose of causing the victim to enter into a marriage (whether or not the conduct amounts to violence, threats or any other form coercion).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 120, page 86, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) &#8220;Mental disorder&#8221; has the meaning given by section 328 of the Mental Health (Care and Treatment) (Scotland) Act 2003.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 120, page 86, line 43, leave out &#8220;coercion&#8221; and insert &#8220;conduct&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 151</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 151, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Littering from vehicles</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Environmental Protection Act 1990 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 88 (fixed penalty notices for leaving litter) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;88A Littering from vehicles: civil penalty regime</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may make regulations under which the keeper of a vehicle may be required to pay a fixed penalty to a litter authority where there is reason to believe that a littering offence in England has been committed in respect of the vehicle.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A littering offence is committed in respect of a vehicle if an offence under section 87(1) occurs as a result of litter being thrown, dropped or otherwise deposited from the vehicle (whether or not by the vehicle&#8217;s keeper).</quote>
         <quote>(3) Regulations under this section must make provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) setting the amount of fixed penalties or specifying how the amount is to be determined;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) about the period within which fixed penalties must be paid;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) for payment within that period of a fixed penalty imposed for a littering offence committed in respect of a vehicle to discharge any liability for conviction for the offence (whether on the part of the keeper or anybody else);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) for a fixed penalty to be payable by the keeper of a vehicle only if a written notice is given to the keeper (&#8220;a penalty notice&#8221;);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) about the persons authorised to give penalty notices;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) about the procedure to be followed in giving penalty notices;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) about the form and content of penalty notices;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) conferring rights to make representations about, and to bring appeals against, penalty notices.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Provision under subsection (3)(e) may authorise a person to give a penalty notice for a littering offence committed in respect of a vehicle only if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the person is under a duty under section 89(1) in respect of the land where the offence is committed (and that person is a &#8220;litter authority&#8221; in relation to a fixed penalty payable under the regulations), or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the person is an authorised officer of a litter authority,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and regulations under this section may include provision about the meaning of &#8220;authorised officer&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Regulations under this section may include provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) for the enforcement of penalty notices (and such provision may in particular authorise an unpaid fixed penalty to be recovered summarily as a civil debt or as if payable under an order of a court if the court so orders);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) about the application of sums paid under penalty notices (and such provision may in particular authorise sums paid to a litter authority to be applied for the purposes of such functions of the authority as the regulations may specify);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) about the application of the regulations to keepers of vehicles in the public service of the Crown.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) Regulations under this section may, in consequence of any provision contained in the regulations, amend&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) this Part, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) Part 2 of the London Local Authorities Act 2007.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) Regulations under this section may&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) make provision corresponding or similar to any provision made by or under section 88;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) make provision subject to exceptions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) include saving, transitional, transitory, supplementary or consequential provision.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) Provision of the kind mentioned in subsection (7)(a) may include provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) conferring a discretion on a litter authority, subject to such constraints or limitations as the regulations may specify (whether or not of a corresponding or similar kind to those mentioned in section 97A(2));</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) creating an offence of the kind mentioned in section 88(8B) and (8C),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>but may not include provision conferring power on a person to make orders or regulations.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;keeper&#8221;, in relation to a vehicle, means the person by whom the vehicle is kept at the time when the littering offence in question occurs, which in the case of a registered vehicle is to be presumed, unless the contrary is proved, to be the registered keeper;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;litter authority&#8221; has the meaning given in subsection (4)(a);</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;registered keeper&#8221;, in relation to a registered vehicle, means the person in whose name the vehicle is registered;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;registered vehicle&#8221; means a vehicle which is for the time being registered under the Vehicle Excise and Registration Act 1994;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;vehicle&#8221; means a mechanically-propelled vehicle or a vehicle designed or adapted for towing by a mechanically-propelled vehicle.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 161 (regulations, orders and directions), after subsection (2ZA) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2ZB) Subsection (2) does not apply to a statutory instrument containing regulations under section 88A if the regulations&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) are the first set of regulations to be made under that section, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) include provision falling within subsection (3)(a) or (6) of that section.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2ZC) A statutory instrument to which subsection (2) does not apply by virtue of subsection (2ZB) may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 181</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 181, page 141, line 4, leave out &#8220;section 151&#8221; and insert &#8220;sections 151 and (Littering from vehicles)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 181, page 141, line 15, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Use of premises for child sex offences) and Schedule (Amendments of Part 2A of the Sexual Offences Act 2003);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Schedule 5</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Schedule 5, insert the following new Schedule&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Schedule</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Amendments of Part 2A of the Sexual Offences Act 2003</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>1 Part 2A of the Sexual Offences Act 2003 (closure orders) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>2 (1) Section 136A (meaning of specified prostitution offence etc) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (2)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a) the words &#8220;section 47 of this Act or&#8221; are omitted;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (b) the words &#8220;section 48 of this Act, or&#8221; are omitted;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in paragraph (c) the words &#8220;section 49 of this Act, or&#8221; are omitted;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) in paragraph (d) the words &#8220;section 50 of this Act, or&#8221; are omitted.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (3)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a) the words &#8220;section 48 of this Act, or&#8221; are omitted;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (b) the words &#8220;section 49 of this Act, or&#8221; are omitted;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in paragraph (c) the words &#8220;section 50 of this Act, or&#8221; are omitted.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) After that subsection there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) The specified child sex offences are&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an offence under any of the following sections of this Act&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>sections 5 to 13;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>sections 16 to 19;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>sections 25 and 26;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>sections 47 to 50;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an offence under section 1 of the Protection of Children Act 1978 (indecent photographs of children);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) an offence under any of the following sections of this Act committed against a person under 18&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>sections 1 to 4;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>sections 30 to 41;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>section 59A;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>section 61;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>sections 66 and 67.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In subsection (4)(a)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the words &#8220;section 47 of this Act or&#8221; are omitted;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the words &#8220;subsection (1)(a) of that section or, as the case may be,&#8221; are omitted.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) After subsection (5) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5A) Premises are being used for activities related to a specified child sex offence at any time when the premises are used&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to commit the offence, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for activities intended to arrange or facilitate the commission of the offence.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>3 In section 136B (power to authorise issue of closure notice), in the heading, for &#8220;notice&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;notice: prostitution or pornography offences&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>4 After that section there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;136BA  Power to authorise issue of closure notice: child sex offences in England and Wales</quote>
         <quote>(1) A member of a police force not below the rank of superintendent (&#8220;the authorising officer&#8221;) may authorise the issue of a closure notice in respect of any premises in England and Wales if three conditions are met.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The first condition is that the officer has reasonable grounds for believing that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) during the relevant period, the premises were used for activities related to one or more specified child sex offences, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the premises are likely to be used (unless a closure order is made) for activities related to one or more specified child sex offences.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (2)(a), &#8220;the relevant period&#8221; means the period of 3 months ending with the day on which the officer is considering whether to authorise the issue of the notice.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The second condition is that the officer has reasonable grounds for believing that the making of a closure order under section 136D is necessary to prevent the premises being used for activities related to one or more specified child sex offences.</quote>
         <quote>(5) For the purposes of the second condition, it does not matter whether the officer believes that the offence or offences in question have been committed or that they will be committed (or will be committed unless a closure order is made).</quote>
         <quote>(6) The third condition is that the officer is satisfied that reasonable efforts have been made&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to consult the local authority for the area in which the premises are situated, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to establish the identity of any person who resides on the premises or who has control of or responsibility for or an interest in the premises.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) If the local authority has not been consulted when the notice is issued, it must be consulted as soon as possible afterwards.</quote>
         <quote>(8) An authorisation under subsection (1) may be given orally or in writing, but if it is given orally the authorising officer must confirm it in writing as soon as it is practicable.</quote>
         <quote>(9) The issue of a closure notice may be authorised whether or not a person has been convicted of any specified child sex offence that the authorising officer believes has been committed.</quote>
         <quote>(10) The Secretary of State may by regulations specify premises or descriptions of premises to which this section does not apply.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>5 (1) Section 136C (contents and service of closure notice) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (1)(c), after &#8220;section 136B&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or 136BA&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (3)(d), after &#8220;section 136B(7)(b)&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or 136BA(6)(b)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>6 (1) Section 136D (power to make a closure order) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (5), for &#8220;either subsection (6) or subsection (7) (or both)&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;at least one of subsections (6), (7) and (7A)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (7) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7A) This subsection applies if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) during the relevant period, the premises were used for activities related to one or more specified child sex offences, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the premises are likely to be used (unless a closure order is made) for activities related to one or more specified child sex offences.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (8), for &#8220;subsections (6) and (7)&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;subsections (6), (7) and (7A)(a)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In subsection (9), for &#8220;prostitution or pornography offences&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;prostitution, pornography or child sex offences&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(6) In subsection (10)(a), after &#8220;section 136B(7)(b)&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or 136BA(6)(b)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In subsection (12), for &#8220;prostitution or pornography offences&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;prostitution, pornography or child sex offences&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>7 In section 136H (applications for extension of closure order), in subsection (4), for &#8220;prostitution or pornography offences&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;prostitution, pornography or child sex offences&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>8 In section 136I (orders extending closure orders), in subsection (2), for &#8220;prostitution or pornography offences&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;prostitution, pornography or child sex offences&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>9 In section 136J (discharge of closure order), in subsection (3), for &#8220;prostitution or pornography offences&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;prostitution, pornography or child sex offences&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>10 In section 136O (compensation), in subsection (5)(a), after &#8220;section 136B&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or 136BA&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>11 (1) Section 136R (interpretation) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (2), after &#8220;section 136B&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or 136BA&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (14) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(15) In the application of this Part to England and Wales, references to specified pornography offences are to be ignored.</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(16) &#8220;Specified child sex offence&#8221; means an offence listed in section 136A(3A).</quote>
         <quote>(17) In the application of this Part to Northern Ireland, references to specified child sex offences and to section 136BA are to be ignored.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 10, page 205, line 23, leave out paragraph 31 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;31 (1) Section 50 of the Police Reform Act 2002 (power of constable to require person acting in an anti-social manner to give name and address) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (1) the words &#8220;(within the meaning of section 1 of the Crime and Disorder Act 1998 (c. 37) (anti-social behaviour orders)&#8221; are omitted.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After that subsection there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) In subsection (1) &#8220;anti-social behaviour&#8221; has the meaning given by section (Meaning of &#8220;anti-social behaviour&#8221;) of the Anti-social Behaviour, Crime and Policing Act 2014 (ignoring subsection (2) of that section).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>In the Title</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B>In the Title, line 3, after &#8220;1991,&#8221; insert &#8220;the Police Act 1997,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B>In the Title, line 4, leave out &#8220;and the Extradition Act 2003&#8221; and insert &#8220;, the Extradition Act 2003 and Part 3 of the Police Reform and Social Responsibility Act 2011&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B>In the Title, line 7, after &#8220;Office;&#8221; insert &#8220;to make provision about invalid travel documents;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>