<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill66(e))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 2, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) For the purpose of determining whether the condition mentioned in subsection (2) is fulfilled, the court shall disregard any act of the respondent which he or she shows was reasonable in the circumstances.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 2, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) It shall be a defence to an application for an injunction under this section that the respondent acted reasonably in the circumstances.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 21</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 21, page 12, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) For the purpose of determining whether the condition mentioned in subsection (3) is fulfilled, the court shall disregard any act of the defendant which he or she shows was reasonable in the circumstances.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 21, page 12, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) It shall be a defence to an application for an order under this section that the defendant acted reasonably in the circumstances.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 66</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <clausetext>[As an amendment to the new clause &#8220;Convention rights, consultation,publicity and notification&#8221; after]</clausetext>
   <clausetext>[Clause 66 printed on sheet HL Bill 66(c)]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 66, line 3, after &#8220;authority&#8221; insert &#8220;or person or body designated under section (Bodies other than local authorities with statutory functions in relation to land)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 69</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 69, page 41, line 37, leave out &#8220;habitually&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 74</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 74, page 45, line 26, after &#8220;in&#8221; insert &#8220;or who lives in&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 75</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 75, page 46, line 11, after &#8220;in&#8221; insert &#8220;or who lives in&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 76</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 76, page 46, line 32, after &#8220;in&#8221; insert &#8220;or who lives in&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 77</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 77, page 47, line 21, after &#8220;order&#8221; insert &#8220;or as to the extent of the building or structure to which the order has been applied&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 77, page 47, line 24, after &#8220;in&#8221; insert &#8220;or who lives in&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 142</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HENIG</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 142, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendments to the licensing regime for private security businesses</quote>
         <quote>(1) Sections 42 and 43 of, and Schedule 1 to, the Crime and Security Act 2010 are repealed.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Private Security Industry Act 2001 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After section 4 there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;4A Requirement to license businesses undertaking work for or on behalf of public authorities</quote>
         <quote>(1) It shall be an offence for a business to engage in any licensable conduct except under and in accordance with a license.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A business engages in licensable conduct if it&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is contracted with a public authority, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) seeks contracts with a public authority,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>to undertake any of the activities contained in Schedule 2, or acts as a sub-contractor to another business which meets the criteria in paragraph (b) or (c).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;a business&#8221; is defined as any body corporate, Scottish partnership or unincorporated association;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;public authority&#8221; is any person certain whose functions are functions of a public nature.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Authority may publish, under section 7(1), different criteria for businesses as to those it applies to individuals.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Authority shall&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) publish a code of conduct for licensed businesses to which licensed businesses shall be expected to adhere;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) publish a list of sanctions for non-adherence by a licensed business to the code produced under subsection (5)(a) which may include, but is not limited to, fines, suspension of licence, withdrawal of licence and criminal prosecution;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) impose sanctions from the list prepared under subsection (5)(b) to any business it deems to have breached or failed to comply with the code produced under subsection (5)(a).&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In section 11 (appeals in licensing matters), in subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the end of paragraph (b), delete &#8220;or&#8221;, and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) at the end of paragraph (c), insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) sanctions are imposed on a licensed business under section 4C(5)(c).&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) After section 22 there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;22A Information relating to license holders</quote>
         <quote>(1) Information held by any person for the purposes of, or for any purpose connected with, the exercise of functions under this Act&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) may be supplied to any other person for use for any such purpose, and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may be supplied to any person having functions in relation to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the enforcement of any other enactment applying to the operations of a licensed person or licensed business,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) offences committed by any person in connection with or by reason of their doing work to which this Act applies,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>for use for the purposes of, or for any purpose connected with, those functions.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(2) Information relating to the operations or licensing of a licensed person or licensed business which is held by any person for the purposes of, or for any purpose connected with, such functions as are mentioned in subsection (1)(b) may be supplied to any person having functions under this Act for the purposes of, or for any purpose connected with, the exercise of those functions.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Information supplied under subsection (2) by or on behalf of the Commissioners of Inland Revenue or the Commissioners of Customs and Excise must not be supplied by the recipient to any other person without the consent of the Commissioners concerned.</quote>
         <quote>(4) This section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) has effect notwithstanding any restriction on the disclosure of information imposed by any enactment or rule of law, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) does not limit the circumstances in which information may be used or supplied apart from this section.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section &#8220;enactment&#8221; means and Act of Parliament, an Act of the Scottish Parliament or any Northern Ireland legislation or any instrument made under or having effect by virtue of an Act of Parliament, an Act of the Scottish Parliament or any Northern Ireland legislation.</quote>
         <quote>(6) References in this section to a person having functions of any description include references to any person providing, or employed in the provision of, services for that person in connection with those functions.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>