<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill66_II(b))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Second Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 111</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS SMITH OF BASILDON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 111, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Long-term police authorisation requiring independent approval</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 32A (authorisations requiring judicial approval) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;32AA Long-term police authorisations requiring independent approval</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where a relevant person has granted a long-term authorisation under section 29.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The authorisation is not to take effect until such time (if any) as the relevant independent body has made an order approving the grant of the authorisation.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The relevant independent body may give approval under this section to the granting of an authorisation under section 29 if, and only if, the relevant independent body is satisfied that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the time of the grant&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) there were reasonable grounds for believing that the requirements of section 29(2), and any requirements imposed by virtue of section 29(7)(b) are satisfied in relation to that authorisation, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the relevant conditions were satisfied in relation to that authorisation, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) at the time when the relevant independent body is considering the matter, there remain reasonable grounds for believing that the requirements of section 29(2), and any requirements imposed by virtue of section 29(7)(b) are satisfied in relation to that authorisation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes of subsection (3) the relevant conditions in relation to a grant by an individual holding an office, rank or position in a relevant law enforcement agency are that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the individual was a designated person for the purposes of section 29,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the grant of an authorisation was not in breach of any prohibition imposed by virtue of section 29(7)(a) or any restriction imposed by virtue of section 30(3), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any other conditions that may be provided for by the Secretary of State were satisfied.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant law enforcement authority&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a police force in the United Kingdom, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the National Crime Agency.</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant judicial authority&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in relation to England and Wales, the High Court of Justice in England and Wales,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to Scotland, the Court of Session, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in relation to Northern Ireland, the High Court of Justice in Northern Ireland.</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant person&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an individual holding an office, rank or position in a police force in the United Kingdom, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an individual holding an office, rank or position in the National Crime Agency.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant independent body&#8221; must be defined by the Home Secretary in a motion passed by both Houses of Parliament before this section is enacted.</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;long-term&#8221; must be defined by the Home Secretary in a motion passed by both Houses of Parliament before this section is enacted.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 128</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD BLAIR OF BOUGHTON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD CONDON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 128, page 99, line 27, at end insert &#8220;subject to the successful completion of developed (or equivalent) security vetting&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 132</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 132, transpose Clause 132 to after Clause 106</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 133</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 133, transpose Clause 133 to after Clause 106</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 134</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 134, transpose Clause 134 to after Clause 106</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 139</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 139, page 107, line 22, leave out &#8220;which amends&#8221; and insert &#8220;amendments of or relating to&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 8</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 179, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In paragraph 1(5) (definition of examining officer) for &#8220;paragraph&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;Schedule&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>( ) In paragraph 2(2)(d), the words &#8220;(within the meaning of that Schedule)&#8221; are omitted.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 179, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) After paragraph 7 there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;7A (1) This paragraph applies where a person detained under Schedule 7 requests to consult a solicitor.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The examining officer may not question the detained person under paragraph 2 or 3 of Schedule 7 until the person has consulted a solicitor (or no longer wishes to do so).</quote>
         <quote>(3) Sub-paragraph (2) does not apply if the examining officer reasonably believes that postponing the questioning until then would be likely to prejudice determination of the relevant matters.</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) The powers given by paragraph 8 of Schedule 7 (search powers where a person is questioned under paragraph 2 of Schedule 7) may be used when questioning is postponed because of sub-paragraph (2).</quote>
         <quote>(5) The detained person is entitled to consult a solicitor in person.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Sub-paragraph (5) does not apply if the examining officer reasonably believes that the time it would take to consult a solicitor in person would be likely to prejudice determination of the relevant matters.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In that case the examining officer may require any consultation to take place in another way.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In this paragraph &#8220;the relevant matters&#8221; means the matters the examining officer seeks to determine under paragraph 2 or 3 of Schedule 7.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 180, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) After paragraph 16 there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;16A (1) This paragraph applies where a person detained under Schedule 7 requests to consult a solicitor.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The examining officer may not question the detained person under paragraph 2 or 3 of Schedule 7 until the person has consulted a solicitor (or no longer wishes to do so).</quote>
         <quote>(3) Sub-paragraph (2) does not apply if the examining officer reasonably believes that postponing the questioning until then would be likely to prejudice determination of the relevant matters.</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) The powers given by paragraph 8 of Schedule 7 (search powers where a person is questioned under paragraph 2 of Schedule 7) may be used when questioning is postponed because of sub-paragraph (2).</quote>
         <quote>(5) The detained person is entitled to consult a solicitor in person.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Sub-paragraph (5) does not apply if the examining officer reasonably believes that the time it would take to consult a solicitor in person would be likely to prejudice determination of the relevant matters.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In that case the examining officer may require any consultation to take place in another way.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In this paragraph &#8220;the relevant matters&#8221; means the matters the examining officer seeks to determine under paragraph 2 or 3 of Schedule 7.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 180, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in sub-paragraph (1), for &#8220;and&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;to&#8221;;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 180, leave out lines 34 to 39 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;General requirements</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>20K (1) A person&#8217;s detention under Schedule 7 must be periodically reviewed by a review officer.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The first review must be carried out before the end of the period of one hour beginning with the person&#8217;s detention under that Schedule.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Subsequent reviews must be carried out at intervals of not more than two hours.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 181, line 8, leave out &#8220;paragraph&#8221; and insert &#8220;Part of this Schedule&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 181, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State must under paragraph 6 of Schedule 14 issue a code of practice about reviews under this Part of this Schedule.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 181, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Representations</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>20L (1) Before determining whether to authorise a person&#8217;s continued detention, a review officer must give either of the following persons an opportunity to make representations about the detention&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the detained person, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a solicitor representing the detained person who is available at the time of the review.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Representations may be oral or written.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A review officer may refuse to hear oral representations from the detained person if the officer considers that the detained person is unfit to make representations because of the detained person&#8217;s condition or behaviour.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Rights</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>20M (1) Where a review officer authorises continued detention the officer must inform the detained person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) of any of the detained person&#8217;s rights under paragraphs 6 and 7 which have not yet been exercised, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the exercise of any of those rights is being delayed in accordance with the provisions of paragraph 8, of the fact that it is being delayed.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Where a review of a person&#8217;s detention is being carried out at a time when the person&#8217;s exercise of a right under paragraph 6 or 7 is being delayed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the review officer must consider whether the reason or reasons for which the delay was authorised continue to subsist, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if in the review officer&#8217;s opinion the reason or reasons have ceased to subsist, the review officer must inform the officer who authorised the delay of that opinion (unless the review officer was that officer).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In the application of this paragraph to Scotland, for the references to paragraphs 6, 7 and 8 substitute references to paragraph 16.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Record</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>20N (1) A review officer carrying out a review must make a written record of the outcome of the review and of any of the following which apply&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the fact that the officer is satisfied that continued detention is necessary for the purposes of exercising a power under paragraph 2 or 3 of Schedule 7,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the fact that the detained person has been informed as required under paragraph 20M(1),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the officer&#8217;s conclusion on the matter considered under paragraph 20M(2)(a), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the fact that the officer has taken action under paragraph 20M(2)(b).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The review officer must inform the detained person whether the officer is authorising continued detention, and if so that the officer is satisfied that continued detention is necessary for the purposes of exercising a power under paragraph 2 or 3 of Schedule 7.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Sub-paragraph (2) does not apply where the detained person is&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) incapable of understanding what is said,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) violent or likely to become violent, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in urgent need of medical attention.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 8, page 181, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Codes of practice</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>(1) Schedule 14 to the Terrorism Act 2000 (exercise of powers&#8212;codes of practice etc) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In paragraph 1, after &#8220;&#8220;officer&#8221; means&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;(subject to paragraph 6A&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After paragraph 6 there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;6A In paragraphs 5 and 6, &#8220;officer&#8221; includes a constable, immigration officer or customs officer who&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) has functions under Schedule 7, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) has functions under Schedule 8 in relation to a person detained under Schedule 7,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>otherwise than as an examining officer.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>otherwise than as an examining officer.&#8221;&#8221;</text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 140</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 140, page 107, line 26, leave out from &#8220;Service),&#8221; to end of line 31 and insert &#8220;after subsection (3) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) This section applies to the Serious Fraud Office as it applies to the Crown Prosecution Service.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 140</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 140, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Jurisdiction of Investigatory Powers Tribunal over Surveillance Commissioners</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 91 of the Police Act 1997 (Surveillance Commissioners) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (10), for &#8220;sections 104 and 106&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;section 104&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (10) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(11) Subsection (10) is not to be read as affecting the jurisdiction of the Tribunal conferred by section 65 of the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000 or section 23 of the Regulation of Investigatory Powers (Scotland) Act 2000.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 142</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEBEN</proposer>
   <proposer>THE LORD BISHOP OF NEWCASTLE</proposer>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;CATHAIN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 142, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Use of amplified noise equipment in vicinity of the Palace of Westminster</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Police Reform and Social Responsibility Act 2011 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 142 there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;142A Other controlled areas in vicinity of the Palace of Westminster</quote>
         <quote>(1) For the purposes of this Part, the &#8220;Palace of Westminster controlled area&#8221; means the area of land in the City of Westminster that is comprised in&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the highways in the postal district SW1 known as&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) Bridge Street,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) St Margaret&#8217;s Street, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) Abingdon Street,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) so much of the highway in the postal district SW1 known as Great College Street as immediately adjoins Abingdon Street Garden,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) Old Palace Yard,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) Abingdon Street Garden (and its pathways), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) Victoria Tower Gardens.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Abingdon Street Garden&#8221; means the garden constructed on the sites of properties formerly known as 18 to 28 (both inclusive) Abingdon Street, London, SW1, together with the garden surrounding the adjoining Jewel Tower and the lawn surrounding the King George V Memorial;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;highway&#8221; has the same meaning as in the Highways Act 1980 (see section 328 of that Act);</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Old Palace Yard&#8221; includes the King George V Memorial.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 143 (prohibited activities in controlled area of Parliament Square)&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the title, at the end there is inserted &#8220;or in Palace of Westminster controlled area&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in subsection (2)(a) after &#8220;Parliament Square&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or in the Palace of Westminster controlled area&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In section 144 (directions under section 143: further provision), in subsection (5) after &#8220;Parliament Square&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;, or the Palace of Westminster controlled area,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In section 145 (power to seize property)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in subsection (1) at the end there is inserted &#8220;in that area&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after that subsection there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) A constable or authorised officer may seize and retain a prohibited item that is on any land in the Palace of Westminster controlled area if it appears to that constable or officer that the item is being, or has been, used in connection with the commission of an offence under section 143 in that area.&#8221;,</quote>
         <IndentOne>(c) in subsection (2) at the end there is inserted &#8220;in that area&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) after that subsection there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) A constable may seize and retain a prohibited item that is on any land outside of the Palace of Westminster controlled area if it appears to the constable that the item has been used in connection with the commission of an offence under section 143 in that area.&#8221;, and</quote>
         <IndentOne>(e) in subsection (8), for &#8220;subsections (1) and (2)&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;this section&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In section 146 (power of court on conviction)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in subsection (1)(b) for &#8220;the controlled area of Parliament Square&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;a relevant area&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in subsection (2) for &#8220;the controlled area of Parliament Square&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;a relevant area&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) after that subsection there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) In this section &#8220;relevant area&#8221; means an area consisting of either or both of the following areas&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the controlled area of Parliament Square, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Palace of Westminster controlled area.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) In section 147 (authorisation for operation of amplified noise equipment), in subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) after &#8220;Parliament Square&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or the Palace of Westminster controlled area&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after &#8220;that land&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;(or any part of it)&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) In section 148 (meaning of &#8220;authorised officer&#8221; and &#8220;responsible authority&#8221;)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in subsection (2) after &#8220;Parliament Square&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;, or in relation to any land in the Palace of Westminster controlled area other than Royal Park land,&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after subsection (3) there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) &#8220;Responsible authority&#8221;, in relation to any land in the Palace of Westminster controlled area, means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Secretary of State, for any land comprised in Royal Park land;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) Westminster City Council, for any other land.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section &#8220;Royal Park land&#8221; means any land of a description specified in Schedule 1 to the Royal Parks and Other Open Spaces Regulations 1997 (S.I. 1997/1639), as that Schedule has effect on the day on which the Anti-social Behaviour, Crime and Policing Act 2014 is passed.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(9) In section 149 (effect of Part on byelaws), in subsection (3), after &#8220;Parliament Square&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;or the Palace of Westminster controlled area&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(10) In the italic cross-heading before section 142, for &#8220;Garden and adjoining pavements&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;etc&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(11) In the title of Part 3, for &#8220;Garden and surrounding area&#8221; there is substituted &#8220;etc&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 152</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 152, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Extradition to the United Kingdom to be sentenced or to serve a sentence</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 142 of the Extradition Act 2003 (issue of Part 3 warrant), for subsection (2A) there is substituted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) The condition is that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the person has been convicted of an extradition offence by a court in the United Kingdom,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) his extradition is sought for the purpose of his being sentenced for the offence or of his serving a sentence of imprisonment or another form of detention imposed in respect of the offence, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) either a domestic warrant has been issued in respect of the person or the person may be arrested without a warrant.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 152, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Detention of extradited person for trial in England and Wales for other offences</quote>
         <quote>(1) In sections 150 and 151A of the Extradition Act 2003 (dealing with extradited person for other offences), at the end of subsection (2) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;This is subject to section 151B.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 151A of that Act there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;151B  Detention of person for trial in England and Wales for other offences</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 150 or 151A does not prevent a person in whose case that section applies from being detained with a view to trial in England and Wales for an offence if the conditions in subsection (2) are satisfied.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The conditions are that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the United Kingdom and the territory from which the person was extradited have each made a declaration under Article 14(3) of the Extradition Convention, and the declarations are still in force;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Secretary of State makes a request for the consent referred to in section 150(3)(c) or 151A(3)(c) in respect of the offence (&#8220;the consent request&#8221;);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the Secretary of State gives notification, which is explicitly acknowledged on behalf of the territory, of the date on which the detention is to begin (&#8220;the notified date&#8221;).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The Extradition Convention is the European Convention on Extradition done at Paris on 13 December 1957.</quote>
         <quote>(4) This section applies only to detention during the period beginning with the notified date and ending with whichever of the following occurs first&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if a notification of opposition to the detention is given on behalf of the territory, the date on which Secretary of State receives it;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the date on which the Secretary of State receives notification given on behalf of the territory as to whether the consent request is granted or refused;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the expiry of the period of 90 days beginning with the date on which the consent request is received.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 162</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD PANNICK</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 162, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Abolition of defence of marital coercion</quote>
         <quote>(1) The defence of marital coercion is abolished.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Accordingly, section 47 of the Criminal Justice Act 1925 (coercion of married woman by husband) is repealed.</quote>
         <quote>(3) This section does not have effect in respect of an offence alleged to have been committed before the date on which it comes into force.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 10, page 206, leave out lines 36 and 37</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 10, page 210, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220; In section 226 of that Act (extent), in subsection (2), after &#8220;Sections&#8221; there is inserted &#8220;151B,&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 167</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 167, page 132, line 34, leave out &#8220;or&#8221; and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) regulations under section 132(5)(b), or&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 169</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DEBEN</proposer>
   <proposer>THE LORD BISHOP OF NEWCASTLE</proposer>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;CATHAIN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 169, page 133, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Use of amplified noise equipment in vicinity of the Palace of Westminster);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 169, page 133, line 31, after &#8220;sections&#8221; insert &#8220;(Detention of person for trial in England and Wales for other offences),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD PANNICK</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 169, page 133, line 32, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Abolition of defence of marital coercion);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 169, page 134, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Jurisdiction of Investigatory Powers Tribunal over Surveillance Commissioners);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 169, page 134, line 10, after &#8220;sections&#8221; insert &#8220;(Detention of person for trial in England and Wales for other offences) and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 170</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 170, page 134, line 31, after &#8220;sections&#8221; insert &#8220;(Jurisdiction of Investigatory Powers Tribunal over Surveillance Commissioners),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TAYLOR OF HOLBEACH</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD PANNICK</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 170, page 134, line 33, leave out &#8220;section 141, which comes&#8221; and insert &#8220;sections 141 and (Abolition of defence of marital coercion), which come&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>