<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Anti-social_Behaviour_Crime_and_Policing_(Bill52_I(b)(Rev))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 7, leave out &#8220;on the balance of probabilities&#8221; and insert &#8220;beyond reasonable doubt&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 8, leave out from &#8220;conduct&#8221; to &#8220;(&#8220;anti-social&#8221; in line 9 and insert &#8220;that had caused, or was likely to cause, harassment, alarm or distress&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 10, leave out &#8220;just and convenient&#8221; and insert &#8220;necessary and proportionate&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 2, page 3, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) This section will not come into effect until the Secretary of State has published and laid before both Houses of Parliament guidance on where the funding for a &#8220;person&#8221;, as defined in subsection (1), responsible for supervising a respondent&#8217;s compliance with an injunction, will be coming from to carry out duties as specified in subsection (4).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 9, page 6, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Before this section comes into force, the Secretary of State shall provide guidance on the length of time that relevant courts will take to reach decisions on whether or not to issue warrants under this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 13, page 7, line 16, at end insert &#8220;or with any other person&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 13, page 7, line 17, leave out from beginning to &#8220;on&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 14, page 8, line 8, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Within a year of this section coming into force, the Secretary of State shall review the length of time taken by consultations under this section with local youth offending teams.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 20, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Corporate anti-social behaviour order</quote>
         <quote>(1) It is an offence for a corporate body to act in a manner that caused or was likely to cause harassment, alarm or distress to one or more persons.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In this section &#8220;corporate body&#8221; has the same meaning as in Part 12 of the Corporation Tax Act 2009 (see section 1005 of that Act).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Secretary of State shall, by regulations, set out the circumstances under which an offence has been committed under subsection (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 23, page 14, line 1, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State shall produce guidance on the scope of requirements that can be used under this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 32, page 18, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;and once the relevant local authority has been consulted.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 32, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 32 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 141, page 108, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in subsection (4), for &#8220;7&#8221; substitute &#8220;14&#8221;;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 142, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Discretion to refuse extradition where requested person wanted under European arrest warrant is a British national or resident</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 20 of the Extradition Act 2003 there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;20A Service of sentence in United Kingdom</quote>
         <quote>(1) If the judge is required to proceed under this section, he must decide whether the person is a United Kingdom national or a resident of the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If the judge decides the question in subsection (1) in the negative, he must proceed under section 21.</quote>
         <quote>(3) If the judge decides that question in the affirmative, he must decide whether it is possible for the person to serve the sentence in the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(4) If the judge decides the question in subsection (3) in the negative, he must proceed under section 21.</quote>
         <quote>(5) If the judge decides that question in the affirmative, he must decide whether the person consents to serve the sentence for which his extradition is sought in the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(6) If the judge decides the question in subsection (5) in the negative, he must proceed under section 21.</quote>
         <quote>(7) If the judge decides that question in the affirmative, he may refuse extradition provided that he orders the person to serve the sentence (or to complete the service of the sentence) in the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Where the judge makes an order under subsection (7), he shall issue a warrant authorising the person&#8217;s detention in the United Kingdom and containing any provisions which the judge considers appropriate for giving effect to the sentence which gave rise to the proceedings (or the portion of the sentence remaining unserved).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 142, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Request of further information where suspicion of mistaken identity</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 7 of the Extradition Act 2003 (identity of person arrested), after subsection (4) there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) If the judge decides that question in the affirmative, he must decide whether the person in respect of whom the warrant was issued is the person who is alleged to have committed, or to have been convicted for, the offence on which the warrant is based.</quote>
         <quote>(4B) The judge must decide the question in subsection (4A) on the balance of probabilities, but if he considers there is reasonable doubt as to that question, he may not decide it in the affirmative unless he has first requested the issuing authority to provide further information within the time specified in the request (which must not be less than a reasonable time in all the circumstances) and the issuing authority has provided him with the information requested within that time.</quote>
         <quote>(4C) If the judge decides the question in subsection (4A) in the negative, he must order the person&#8217;s discharge.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 142, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Effective refusal grounds for breach of human rights</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 21B of the Extradition Act 2003 there is inserted&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;21C Human rights: legal and evidential standards</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies if the judge is required, under section 21 or 21A, to determine whether extradition would be compatible with the Convention rights.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The person&#8217;s extradition would not be compatible with the Convention rights if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) there is a real risk that the person, if surrendered, would be subject to treatment in the category 1 territory that, if taking place in the United Kingdom, would be an act or omission made unlawful by section 6 of the 1998 Act;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in relation to the matters giving rise to the Part 1 warrant, the person has previously been subject to treatment that, if taking place in the United Kingdom, would be an act or omission made unlawful by section 6 of the 1998 Act; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the person&#8217;s removal from the United Kingdom would be incompatible with the Convention rights.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The judge shall not treat a matter set out in subsection (2)(a) or (b) as established unless there is material before him on which a court might reasonably so conclude; but if there is such material before him, he shall treat that matter as established unless satisfied to the contrary.</quote>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes of subsection (3), the judge shall have regard to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) judgments issued by the European Court of Human Rights against the category 1 territory under Article 46 of the Convention (pilot judgment);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the existence of proceedings under Article 226 of the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union against the category 1 territory in respect of measures adopted under Article 82(2) of that Treaty, and any judgment given by the Court of Justice of the European Union in such proceedings.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 9, page 180, line 9, leave out paragraphs 24 to 27</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>