<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Care_(HLBill45_III)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>83</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>83:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Human Rights Act 1998: provision of &#8220;care and support services&#8221; to be public function</quote>
         <quote>(1) A person (&#8220;P&#8221;) who provides regulated &#8220;social care&#8221; is to be taken for the purposes of subsection (3)(b) of section 6 of the Human Rights Act 1998 (acts of public authorities) to be exercising a function of a public nature in doing so.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This section applies to persons providing services regulated by the Care Quality Commission.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In this section &#8220;social care&#8221; has the same meaning as in the Health and Social Care Act 2008.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>83A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>83A:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 5, at beginning insert &#8220;When a child receiving services reaches the age of 14 or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>84</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>84:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 5, leave out from &#8220;Where&#8221; to &#8220;after&#8221; in line 7 and insert &#8220;it appears to a local authority that a child is likely to have needs for care and support&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>84A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>84A:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 7, after &#8220;18&#8221; insert &#8220;(whichever is sooner)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>85</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>85:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 8, leave out &#8220;may&#8221; and insert &#8220;must&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>86</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>86:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 16, leave out subsection (3)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>87</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>87:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 19, leave out from beginning to &#8220;the&#8221; in line 20</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>88</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>88:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Where a child refuses a child&#8217;s needs assessment and the consent condition is accordingly not met, the local authority must nonetheless carry out the assessment if the child is experiencing, or is at risk of, abuse or neglect.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>89</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>89:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 26, leave out from beginning to &#8220;must&#8221; and insert &#8220;Where a local authority, having received a request to carry out a child&#8217;s assessment from the child concerned or a parent or carer of the child, decides not to comply with the request, it&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>89A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>89A:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 40, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The child&#8217;s needs assessment must be completed before the child reaches the age of 16, or within two years of the commencement of services being provided to the child, whichever is later.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>89B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>89B:</B> After Clause 58, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Transition plans</quote>
         <quote>(1) When a local authority has completed an assessment under this section and is satisfied that the child has needs for care and support, is likely to have needs for care and support after becoming 18, and has determined what those needs are likely to be, the local authority must, before the child reaches 16 or within two years of the child beginning to receive services (whichever is later)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) secure that a transition plan is prepared for the child or young person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) once a transition plan has been prepared, it must maintain the plan.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of this Part, a transition plan is a plan specifying, for the proceeding five years of the child or young person&#8217;s life&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any health care and social care provision reasonably required by him;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the outcomes sought for him, including intentions to enter further or higher education, enter the workplace or move to independent or assisted living;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the housing provision required by him.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) &#8220;Health care provision&#8221; means the provision of health care services as part of the comprehensive health service in England continued under section 1(1) of the National Health Service Act 2006.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Regulations may make provision about the preparation and content of transition plans.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Where a local authority is required to secure that a transition plan is prepared for a child or young person, it must consult the child&#8217;s parent or the young person about the content of the plan during the preparation of a draft of the plan.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The local authority must then send the draft plan to the child or parent or carer.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The local authority must send a copy of the finalised transition plan to the child or parent or carer.</quote>
         <quote>(8) A transition plan shall be maintained until the young person reaches the age of 25.</quote>
         <quote>(9) A local authority in England and its partner commissioning bodies must make arrangements about the health, care and housing provision to be secured for children and young people for whom a transition plan is prepared and maintained.</quote>
         <quote>(10) Where an Education, Health and Care (EHC) plan is being prepared for a child or young person by a local authority under Part 3 of the Children and Families Act 2013 and a transition plan is already maintained for the child or young person, the transition plan must become part of the EHC plan.</quote>
         <quote>(11) Where an EHC plan is already maintained for a child or young person by a local authority and a child&#8217;s needs assessment is undertaken under section 58(1), the local authority must ensure that the child or young person&#8217;s EHC plan includes the transition plan as set out under subsection (2).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>90</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>90:</B> Clause 59, page 48, line 6, leave out paragraph (d)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>91</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>91:</B> Clause 59, page 48, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) When carrying out a child&#8217;s needs assessment, a local authority must also consider whether, and if so to what extent, matters other than the provision of care and support could contribute to the achievement of the outcomes that the child wishes to achieve in day-to-day life.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92:</B> Clause 59, page 48, leave out line 16 and insert &#8220;child&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>93</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>93:</B> Clause 59, page 48, line 24, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) But in a case where the child is not competent or lacks capacity to understand the things which the local authority is required to give under subsection (3), that subsection is to have effect as if for &#8220;must give the child&#8221; there were substituted &#8220;must give the child&#8217;s parents&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>93A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>93A:</B> Clause 60, page 48, line 38, at beginning insert &#8220;When a child receiving services reaches the age of 14 or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>94</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>94:</B> Clause 60, page 48, line 38, leave out from &#8220;Where&#8221; to &#8220;after&#8221; in line 40 and insert &#8220;it appears to a local authority that a carer of a child is likely to have needs for support&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>94A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>94A:</B> Clause 60, page 48, line 40, after &#8220;18&#8221; insert &#8220;(whichever is sooner)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>94B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>94B:</B> Clause 60, page 48, line 46, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment must be completed before the child reaches the age of 16, or within two years of the commencement of services being provided to the child, whichever is later.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>95</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>95:</B> Clause 60, page 49, line 1, leave out subsection (2)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>96</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>96:</B> Clause 60, page 49, line 10, leave out &#8220;or (2)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>97</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>97:</B> Clause 60, page 49, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) Where a child&#8217;s carer refuses a child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment, the local authority is not required to carry out the assessment (and subsection (1) does not apply in the carer&#8217;s case).</quote>
         <quote>(3B) Where, having refused a child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment, a child&#8217;s carer requests the assessment, subsection (1) applies in the carer&#8217;s case (and subsection (3A) does not).</quote>
         <quote>(3C) Where a child&#8217;s carer has refused a child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment and the local authority concerned thinks that the carer&#8217;s needs or circumstances have changed, subsection (1) applies in the carer&#8217;s case (but subject to further refusal as mentioned in subsection (3A).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>98</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>98:</B> Clause 60, page 49, leave out lines 12 and 13 and insert &#8220;Where a local authority, having received a request to carry out a child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment from the carer concerned, decides not to comply with the request, it must give the carer&#8212;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>99</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>99:</B> Clause 60, page 49, line 17, leave out subsection (5)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>100</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>100:</B> Clause 61, page 50, line 10, leave out paragraph (f)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>101</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>101:</B> Clause 61, page 50, line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) When carrying out a child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment, a local authority must also consider whether, and if so to what extent, matters other than the provision of support could contribute to the achievement of the outcomes that the carer wishes to achieve in day-to-day life.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>102</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>102:</B> Clause 61, page 50, leave out line 23 and insert &#8220;carer&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>103</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>103:</B> Clause 63, page 50, line 44, leave out from &#8220;Where&#8221; to &#8220;after&#8221; in line 1 on page 51 and insert &#8220;it appears to a local authority that a young carer is likely to have needs for support&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104:</B> Clause 63, page 51, line 2, leave out &#8220;may&#8221; and insert &#8220;must&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>105</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>105:</B> Clause 63, page 51, line 10, leave out subsection (3)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>106</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>106:</B> Clause 63, page 51, leave out line 13</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>107</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>107:</B> Clause 63, page 51, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Where a young carer refuses a young carer&#8217;s assessment and the consent condition is accordingly not met, the local authority must nonetheless carry out the assessment if the young carer is experiencing, or is at risk of, abuse or neglect.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>108</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>108:</B> Clause 63, page 51, line 21, leave out from beginning to &#8220;must&#8221; and insert &#8220;Where a local authority, having received a request to carry out a young carer&#8217;s assessment from the young carer concerned or a parent of the young carer, decides not to comply with the request, it&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>109</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>109:</B> Clause 64, page 52, line 7, leave out paragraph (f)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>110</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>110:</B> Clause 64, page 52, line 14, leave out &#8220;whether&#8221; and insert &#8220;the extent to which&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>111</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>111:</B> Clause 64, page 52, line 16, leave out &#8220;whether&#8221; and insert &#8220;the extent to which&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>112</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>112:</B> Clause 64, page 52, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) When carrying out a young carer&#8217;s assessment, a local authority must also consider whether, and if so to what extent, matters other than the provision of support could contribute to the achievement of the outcomes that the young carer wishes to achieve in day-to-day life.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>113</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>113:</B> Clause 64, page 52, leave out line 25 and insert &#8220;young carer&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>114</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>114:</B> Clause 64, page 52, line 33, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) But in a case where the young carer is not competent or lacks capacity to understand the things which the local authority is required to give under subsection (3), that subsection is to have effect as if for &#8220;must give the young carer&#8221; there were substituted &#8220;must give the young carer&#8217;s parents&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>115</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>115:</B> Clause 65, page 53, line 6, leave out subsections (2) and (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) A local authority may combine a child&#8217;s needs assessment or young carer&#8217;s assessment with an assessment it is carrying out (whether or not under this Part) in relation to another person only if the consent condition is met in relation to the child to whom the child&#8217;s needs or young carer&#8217;s assessment relates and&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) where the combination would include an assessment relating to another child, the consent condition is met in relation to that other child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the combination would include an assessment relating to an adult, the adult agrees.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) A local authority may combine a child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment with an assessment it is carrying out (whether or not under this Part) in relation to another person only if the adult to whom the child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment relates agrees and&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) where the combination would include an assessment relating to another adult, that other adult agrees, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the combination would include an assessment relating to a child, the consent condition is met in relation to that child.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3A) The consent condition is met in relation to a child if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the child has capacity or is competent to agree to the assessments being combined and does so agree, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the child lacks capacity or is not competent so to agree but the local authority is satisfied that combining the assessments would be in the child&#8217;s best interests.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>116</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>116:</B> Clause 65, page 53, line 24, leave out from &#8220;in&#8221; to &#8220;, the&#8221; in line 25 and insert &#8220;relation to the person to whom the assessment relates or in relation to a relevant person&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>117</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>117:</B> Clause 65, page 53, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A person is a &#8220;relevant person&#8221;, in relation to a child&#8217;s needs, child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s or young carer&#8217;s assessment, if it would be reasonable to combine an assessment relating to that person with the child&#8217;s needs, child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s or young carer&#8217;s assessment (as mentioned in subsections (2) and (3)).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>118</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>118:</B> After Clause 66, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Independent advocacy support: involvement in assessments, plans etc.</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where a local authority is required by a relevant provision to involve an individual in its exercise of a function.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The authority must, if the condition in subsection (4) is met, arrange for a person who is independent of the authority (an &#8220;independent advocate&#8221;) to be available to represent and support the individual for the purpose of facilitating the individual&#8217;s involvement; but see subsection (5).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The relevant provisions are&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 9(5)(a) and (b) (carrying out needs assessment);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section 10(7)(a) (carrying out carer&#8217;s assessment);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) section 25(3)(a) and (b) (preparing care and support plan);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) section 25(4)(a) and (b) (preparing support plan);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) section 27(2)(b)(i) and (ii) (revising care and support plan);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) section 27(3)(b)(i) and (ii) (revising support plan);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) section 59(2)(a) and (b) (carrying out child&#8217;s needs assessment);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) section 61(3)(a) (carrying out child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(i) section 64(3)(a) and (b) (carrying out young carer&#8217;s assessment).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The condition is that the local authority considers that, were an independent advocate not to be available, the individual would experience substantial difficulty in doing one or more of the following&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) understanding relevant information;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) retaining that information;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) using or weighing that information as part of the process of being involved;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) communicating the individual&#8217;s views, wishes or feelings (whether by talking, using sign language or any other means).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The duty under subsection (2) does not apply if the local authority is satisfied that there is a person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) who would be an appropriate person to represent and support the individual for the purpose of facilitating the individual&#8217;s involvement, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) who is not engaged in providing care or treatment for the individual in a professional capacity or for remuneration.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) For the purposes of subsection (5), a person is not to be regarded as an appropriate person unless&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) where the individual has capacity or is competent to consent to being represented and supported by that person, the individual does so consent, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the individual lacks capacity or is not competent so to consent, the local authority is satisfied that being represented and supported by that person would be in the individual&#8217;s best interests.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) Regulations may make provision in connection with the making of arrangements under subsection (2); the regulations may in particular&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) specify requirements that must be met for a person to be independent for the purposes of subsection (2);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) specify matters to which a local authority must have regard in deciding whether an individual would experience substantial difficulty of the kind mentioned in subsection (4);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) specify circumstances in which the exception in subsection (5) does not apply;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) make provision as to the manner in which independent advocates are to perform their functions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) specify circumstances in which, if an assessment under this Part is combined with an assessment under this Part that relates to another person, each person may or must be represented and supported by the same independent advocate or by different independent advocates;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) provide that an independent advocate may, in such circumstances or subject to such conditions as may be specified, examine and take copies of relevant records relating to the individual.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) This section does not restrict the provision that may be made under any other provision of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(9) &#8220;Relevant record&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a health record (within the meaning given in section 68 of the Data Protection Act 1998 (as read with section 69 of that Act)),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a record of, or held by, a local authority and compiled in connection with a function under this Part or a social services function (within the meaning given in section 1A of the Local Authority Social Services Act 1970),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a record held by a person registered under Part 2 of the Care Standards Act 2000 or Chapter 2 of Part 1 of the Health and Social Care Act 2008, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) a record of such other description as may be specified in the regulations.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>119</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>119:</B> After Clause 66, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Independent advocacy support: safeguarding enquiries and reviews</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where there is to be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an enquiry under section 42(2),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a review under section 44(1) of a case in which condition 2 in section 44(3) is met or a review under section 44(4).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The relevant local authority must, if the condition in subsection (3) is met, arrange for a person who is independent of the authority (an &#8220;independent advocate&#8221;) to be available to represent and support the adult to whose case the enquiry or review relates for the purpose of facilitating his or her involvement in the enquiry or review; but see subsections (4) and (6).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The condition is that the local authority considers that, were an independent advocate not to be available, the individual would experience substantial difficulty in doing one or more of the following&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) understanding relevant information;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) retaining that information;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) using or weighing that information as part of the process of being involved;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) communicating the individual&#8217;s views, wishes or feelings (whether by talking, using sign language or any other means).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The duty under subsection (2) does not apply if the local authority is satisfied that there is a person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) who would be an appropriate person to represent and support the adult for the purpose of facilitating the adult&#8217;s involvement, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) who is not engaged in providing care or treatment for the adult in a professional capacity or for remuneration.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) For the purposes of subsection (4), a person is not to be regarded as an appropriate person unless&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) where the adult has capacity to consent to being represented and supported by that person, the adult does so consent, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the adult lacks capacity so to consent, the local authority is satisfied that being represented and supported by that person would be in the adult&#8217;s best interests.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) If the enquiry or review needs to begin as a matter of urgency, it may do so even if the authority has not yet been able to comply with the duty under subsection (2) (and the authority continues to be subject to the duty).</quote>
         <quote>(7) &#8220;Relevant local authority&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in a case within subsection (1)(a), the authority making the enquiry or causing it to be made;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in a case within subsection (1)(b), the authority which established the SAB arranging the review.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>120</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>120:</B> Clause 67, page 57, line 17, leave out from &#8220;person&#8221; to &#8220;in&#8221; in line 18 and insert &#8220;fraudulently or negligently misrepresents or fails to disclose any material fact that they might have reasonably been aware would have a bearing on expenditure incurred by the local authority&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>121</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>121:</B> Before Clause 69, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Initial funding assessment</quote>
         <IndentOne>Before enactment of Part 1, the Secretary of State must ask the Office for Budget Responsibility to complete by the end of 2014 a review of the funding of adult social care that assesses&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) the adequacy of current public funding of these services;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the proposals for funding the provisions in this Act;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the implications of the Act and its funding for the NHS over the next five years; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) in particular the short and long term costs of setting the eligibility criteria at the level set out in regulations.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>122</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>122:</B> Clause 69, page 59, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In advance of the first five-yearly review, the Secretary of State must prepare and publish a review of the working of Part I and its funding before the date in subsection (4) and after consultation with interested parties.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>123</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>123:</B> After Clause 69, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Appeals on care and support decisions</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall make regulations setting out a system for appeal or review of decisions made about their care and support, on a question of fact or law, including where a local authority&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) makes a decision under section 13(1) that some or all of an adults needs meet the eligibility criteria, or none of their needs meet the eligibility criteria,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) exercises its power to charge for meeting needs under section 14,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) completes a financial assessment under section 17,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) makes a determination under section 18 or 19 that it must or may provide services to meet the adults care and support needs,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) makes a determination under section 20 that it must or may provide services to meet a carer&#8217;s needs for support,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) makes any other decisions about an individual&#8217;s care and support as shall be prescribed.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>124</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>124:</B> After Clause 69, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Appeals on decisions for NHS continuing care</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall make regulations setting out a system for appeal or review of decisions made about NHS continuing care, independent of the NHS, on a question of fact or law.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>125</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>125:</B> Schedule 3, page 110, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) specify matters which the local authority and relevant partners must have regard to in carrying out an assessment of a person who may have care needs following discharge from a hospital or other acute care setting, including the content of the admission process to that acute setting.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>126</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>126:</B> Clause 71, page 59, line 24, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(aa) if, immediately before being detained, the person concerned was ordinarily resident in Wales, for the area in Wales in which he was ordinarily resident; or&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>127</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>127:</B> Clause 71, page 59, leave out lines 25 to 27</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>128</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>128:</B> Clause 71, page 59, leave out lines 30 to 33 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) Where there is a dispute about where a person was ordinarily resident for the purposes of subsection (3) above&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the dispute is between local social services authorities in England, section 40 of the Care Act 2013 applies to the dispute as it applies to a dispute about where a person was ordinarily resident for the purposes of Part 1 of that Act;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the dispute is between local social services authorities in Wales, section 164 of the Social Services and Well-being (Wales) Act 2013 applies to the dispute as it applies to a dispute about where a person was ordinarily resident for the purposes of that Act;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) if the dispute is between a local social services authority in England and a local social services authority in Wales, it is to be determined by the Secretary of State or the Welsh Ministers.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4A) The Secretary of State and the Welsh Ministers shall make and publish arrangements for determining which of them is to determine a dispute under subsection (4)(c); and the arrangements may, in particular, provide for the dispute to be determined by whichever of them agree is to do so.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>128A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>128A&#042;:</B> Clause 71, page 59, leave out lines 35 to 42 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) In this section, &#8220;after-care services&#8221; means services that reduce the risk of a deterioration of the person&#8217;s mental condition (and, accordingly, to reduce the risk of the person requiring admission to a hospital again for treatment for mental disorder).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>129</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>129:</B> Clause 71, page 59, line 35, after &#8220;services&#8221;&#8221; insert &#8220;, in relation to a person,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>130</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>130:</B> Clause 71, page 59, line 37, leave out &#8220;mental disorder of the person concerned&#8221; and insert &#8220;person&#8217;s mental disorder&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>131</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>131:</B> Clause 71, page 59, line 41, leave out &#8220;the&#8221; and insert &#8220;mental&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>132</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>132:</B> Clause 71, page 60, line 28, after &#8220;purpose&#8221; insert &#8220;Part 1 of&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133:</B> Clause 71, page 60, line 29, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7A) In section 37 of the Social Services and Well-being (Wales) Act 2013 (direct payments: further provision), at the end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(11) The ways in which a local authority may discharge its duty under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 include by making direct payments; and for that purpose Schedule A1 (which includes modifications of sections 34 and 35 and this section) has effect.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(7B) Before Schedule 1 to that Act insert the Schedule A1 contained in Part 2 of Schedule 4 to this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(7C) In section 163 of that Act (ordinary residence), after subsection (4) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) A person who is being provided with accommodation under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 (after-care) is to be treated for the purposes of this Act as ordinarily resident in the area of the local authority, or the local authority in England, on which the duty to provide that person with services under that section is imposed.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(7D) In consequence of subsections (7) to (7B), in subsection (2C) of section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), for &#8220;regulations under section 57 of the Health and Social Care Act 2001 or&#8221; substitute &#8220;&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) sections 31 to 33 of the Care Act 2013 (as applied by Schedule 4 to that Act),</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) sections 34, 35 and 37 of the Social Services and Well-being (Wales) Act 2013 (as applied by Schedule A1 to that Act), or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) regulations under&#8221;,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (b), after &#8220;apart from&#8221; insert &#8220;those sections (as so applied) or&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134:</B> Clause 71, page 60, line 33, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In section 145 of the Mental Health Act 1983 (interpretation), for the definition of &#8220;local social services authority&#8221; substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;local social services authority&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>(a) an authority in England which is a local authority for the purposes of Part 1 of the Care Act 2013, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(b) an authority in Wales which is a local authority for the purposes of the Social Services and Well-being (Wales) Act 2013.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>135</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>135:</B> Schedule 4, page 111, line 13, leave out paragraph 2</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>136</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>136:</B> Schedule 4, page 111, line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 2</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Provision to be inserted in Social Services and Well-Being (Wales) Act 2013</HeadingTwo>
         <text>
            <quote>
               <B>136:</B> Schedule 4, </quote>
            <HeadingTwo>ScheduleA1</HeadingTwo>
            <HeadingTwo>Direct payments: after-care under the Mental Health Act 1983</HeadingTwo>
            <HeadingTwo>General</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>1 Sections 34 (direct payments to meet an adult&#8217;s needs), 35 (direct payments to meet a child&#8217;s needs) and 37 (direct payments: further provision) apply in relation to section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 but as if the following modifications were made to those sections.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Modifications to section 34</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>2 For subsection (1) of section 34 substitute&#8212;</quote>
            <quote>&#8220;((1)) Regulations may require or allow a local authority to make payments to an adult to whom section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 (after-care) applies that are equivalent to the cost of providing or arranging for the provision of after-care services for the adult under that section.&#8221;</quote>
            <quote>3 In subsection (3) of that section&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), for &#8220;who has needs for care and support (&#8220;A&#8221;)&#8221; substitute &#8220;in respect of the provision to the adult (&#8220;A&#8221;) of after-care services under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (c)(i), for &#8220;of meeting A&#8217;s needs&#8221; substitute &#8220;of discharging its duty towards A under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8221;.</IndentOne>
            <quote>4 In subsection (4) of that section&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), for &#8220;who has needs for care and support (&#8220;A&#8221;)&#8221; substitute &#8220;to whom section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 applies (&#8220;A&#8221;)&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (d)(i), for &#8220;meeting A&#8217;s needs&#8221; substitute &#8220;discharging its duty towards A under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8221;.</IndentOne>
            <quote>5 In subsection (5) of that section&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), for &#8220;A&#8217;s needs for care and support&#8221; substitute &#8220;the provision to A of after-care services under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (b), for &#8220;towards the cost of meeting A&#8217;s needs for care and support&#8221; substitute &#8220;equivalent to the cost of providing or arranging the provision to A of after-care services under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8221;.</IndentOne>
            <quote>6 In subsection (6)(b) of that section, for &#8220;A&#8217;s needs for care and support&#8221; substitute &#8220;the provision to A of after-care services under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8221;.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Modifications to section 35</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>7 For subsection (1) of section 35 substitute&#8212;</quote>
            <quote>&#8220;((1)) Regulations may require or allow a local authority to make payments to a person in respect of a child to whom section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 (after-care) applies that are equivalent to the cost of providing or arranging the provision of after-care services for the child under that section.&#8221;</quote>
            <quote>8 In subsection (3)(a), (b) and (c) of that section, for &#8220;who has needs for care and support&#8221; (in each place it occurs) substitute &#8220;to whom section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 applies&#8221;.</quote>
            <quote>9 In subsection (5)(a) of that section, for &#8220;meeting the child&#8217;s needs&#8221; substitute &#8220;discharging its duty towards the child under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983&#8221;.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Modifications to section 37</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>10 In subsection (1) of section 37&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) in the opening words, for &#8220;34, 35 and 36&#8221; substitute &#8220;34 and 35&#8221;,</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) omit paragraphs (a), (b) and (c),</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(c) in paragraph (i), for &#8220;a local authority&#8217;s duty or power to meet a person&#8217;s needs for care and support or a carer&#8217;s needs for support is displaced&#8221; substitute &#8220;a local authority&#8217;s duty under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 (after-care) is discharged&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(d) in paragraph (k), for &#8220;34 to 36&#8221; substitute &#8220;34 and 35&#8221;.</IndentOne>
            <quote>11 Omit subsections (2) to (8) of that section.</quote>
            <quote>12 After subsection (8) of that section insert&#8212;</quote>
            <quote>&#8220;((8A)) Regulations under sections 34 and 35 must specify that direct payments to meet the cost of providing or arranging for the provision of after-care services under section 117 of the Mental Health Act 1983 (after-care) must be made at a rate that the local authority estimates to be equivalent to the reasonable cost of securing the provision of those services to meet those needs.&#8221;</quote>
            <quote>13 In subsection (9) of that section&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) for &#8220;, 35 or 36&#8221; substitute &#8220;or 35&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) for &#8220;care and support&#8221; substitute &#8220;after-care services&#8221;.</IndentOne>
            <quote>14 In subsection (10) of that section, for &#8220;care and support to meet needs&#8221; substitute &#8220;after-care services&#8221;.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
         </text>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>136A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>136A&#042;:</B> Clause 72, page 61, line 18, leave out from beginning to &#8220;not&#8221; in line 19 and insert &#8220;Section 42 and 47 does&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>136B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>136B&#042;:</B> Clause 72, page 61, line 22, leave out subsection (8)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>137</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>137:</B> After Clause 73, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;End of life care</quote>
         <IndentOne>After consultation, the Secretary of State may make regulations for terminally ill persons to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) have their preference for place of death recorded by local health and social care services and for that preference to be implemented wherever practicable;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) have their care and support needs and those of their carer treated as urgent by the local authority responsible for assessing those needs; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) be exempt from any local authority charges for adult social care.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138:</B> Clause 74, page 62, line 41, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State must have regard to the general duty of local authorities under section 1(1) (promotion of individual well-being)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in issuing guidance for the purposes of subsection (1);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in making regulations under this Part.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138A:</B> Clause 75, page 63, line 26, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In exercising any function to which an authorisation under this section relates, the person authorised is subject to the same legal obligations as the local authority.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138B:</B> Clause 75, page 63, line 30, after &#8220;as&#8221; insert &#8220;also&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>139</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>139:</B> After Clause 76, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) In the Health and Social Care Act 2008, after section 128 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 2A</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>128A Establishment of an office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) There shall be an office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Schedule (The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner) shall have effect with respect to the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.</quote>
         <quote>128B Functions of the office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner has the function under this Part of promoting the wellbeing, dignity and respect of older people and safeguarding and promoting their rights and welfare.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In fulfilling their duties under subsection (1), the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner may review, and monitor the operation of, arrangements falling within subsection (2), (3) or (4) for the purpose of ascertaining whether, and to what extent, the arrangements are effective in promoting the wellbeing, dignity and respect, and safeguarding and promoting the rights and welfare of older people.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The arrangements falling within this subsection are the arrangements made by the providers of regulated services in England, or by the Secretary of State, for dealing with complaints or representations in respect of such services made by or on behalf of older people.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The arrangements falling within this subsection are arrangements made by the providers of regulated services in England, or by the Secretary of State, for ensuring that proper action is taken in response to any disclosure of information which may tend to show that, in the course of, or in connection with, the provision of regulated services to older people&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) that a criminal offence has been committed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) that a person has failed to comply with any legal obligation to which he is subject;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) that the health and safety of any person has been endangered; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) that information tending to show that any matter falling within one of the preceding paragraphs has been deliberately concealed.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The arrangements falling within this subsection are arrangements made (whether by providers of regulated services in England, by the Secretary of State or by any other person) for making persons available&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to represent the views and wishes of older people to whom this Part applies; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to ensure the adequate provision to older people of advice and support of any prescribed kind.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The Secretary of State may, by regulations confer power on the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to require prescribed persons to provide any information which the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner considers it necessary or expedient to have for the purposes of his functions under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(7) A statutory instrument containing regulations under subsection (5) is not to be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>128C Examination of cases by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may, by regulations, make provision for the examination by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner of the cases of particular older people.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The regulations may include provision about&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the types of case which may be examined;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the circumstances in which an examination may be made;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the procedure for conducting an examination, including provision about the representation of parties;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the publication of reports following an examination.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The regulations may, for the purposes of enabling the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to examine or determine whether any recommendation made in a report following an examination has been complied with, make provision for&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) requiring persons to provide the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner with information; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) requiring persons who hold or are accountable for information to provide the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner with explanations or other assistance,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>for the purpose of an examination or for the purposes of determining whether any recommendation made in a report following an examination has been complied with.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes mentioned in subsection (3), the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner shall have the same powers as the High Court in respect of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the attendance and examination of witnesses (including the administration of oaths and affirmations and the examination of witnesses abroad); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the provision of information.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) No person shall be compelled for the purposes mentioned in subsection (3) to give any evidence or provide information which he could not be compelled to give or provide in civil proceedings before the High Court.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The regulations may make provision for the payment by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner of sums in respect of expenses or allowances to persons who attend or provide information for the purposes mentioned in subsection (3).</quote>
         <quote>(7) A statutory instrument containing the first regulations made under subsection (1), (2) or (3) is not to be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(8) A statutory instrument that contains regulations made under subsection (6) is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>128D Obstruction</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner may certify an offence to the High Court where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a person, without lawful excuse, obstructs him or any member of his staff in the exercise of any of his functions under regulations made under section 128B(5) or 128C; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a person is guilty of any act or omission in relation to an examination under regulations made by under section 128C which, if that examination were proceedings in the High Court, would constitute contempt of court.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Where an offence is so certified the High Court may inquire into the matter; and after hearing&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any witnesses who may be produced against or on behalf of the person charged with the offence; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any statement that may be offered in defence,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>the High Court may deal with the person charged with the offence in any manner in which it could deal with him if he had committed the same offence in relation to the High Court.</IndentOne>
         <quote>128E Further functions</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner may, in connection with his functions under this Part give advice and information to any person.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Regulations may confer power on the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to assist an older person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in making a complaint or representation to or in respect of a provider of regulated services in England; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in any prescribed proceedings.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of subsection (2), assistance includes&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) financial assistance; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) arranging for representation, or the giving of advice or assistance, by any person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Regulations under subsection (2) may also provide for assistance to be given on conditions, including (in the case of financial assistance) conditions requiring repayment in specified circumstances.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Regulations may, in connection with the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner&#8217;s functions under this Part, confer further functions on the Commissioner.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Regulations may, in particular, include provision about the making of reports on any matter connected with any of his functions.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Apart from identifying any person investigated, a report by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner shall not&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) mention the name of any person, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) include any particulars which, in the opinion of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner, are likely to identify any person and can be omitted without impairing the effectiveness of the report,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>unless, after taking account of the public interest (as well as the interests of any person who made a complaint and other persons), the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner considers it necessary for the report to mention his name or include such particulars.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) For the purposes of the law of defamation, the publication of any matter by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner in a report is absolutely privileged.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In subsection (1) of this section &#8220;proceedings&#8221; includes a procedure of any kind and any prospective proceedings.</quote>
         <quote>(10) A statutory instrument containing the regulations under this section is not to be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>128F Restrictions</quote>
         <quote>(1) This Part does not authorise the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to enquire into or report on any matter so far as it is the subject of legal proceedings before, or has been determined by, a court or tribunal.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This Part does not authorise the Commissioner to exercise any function which by virtue of an enactment is also exercisable by the prescribed person.</quote>
         <quote>128G Interpretation</quote>
         <quote>(1) For the purposes of this Part &#8220;regulated services&#8221; has the same definition as &#8220;regulated activity&#8221; in section 8 of this Act as they relate to older people.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This Part applies to any older person normally domiciled in England.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) After Schedule 5, insert the following new Schedule&#8212;</quote>
         <text>
            <quote>
               <B>139:</B> After Clause 76, </quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Schedule 5A</HeadingTwo>
            <HeadingTwo>The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</HeadingTwo>
            <HeadingTwo>Status</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>1 (1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner is to be a corporation sole.</quote>
            <quote>(2) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner is not to be regarded as the servant or agent of the Crown or as enjoying any status, immunity or privilege of the Crown; and the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner&#8217;s property is not to be regarded as property of, or property held on behalf of, the Crown.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Appointment and tenure of office</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>2 Regulations may make provision&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) as to the appointment of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner (including any conditions to be fulfilled for appointment);</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) as to the filling of vacancies in the office of Commissioner;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(c) as to the tenure of office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner (including the circumstances in which he ceases to hold office or may be removed or suspended from office).</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Remuneration</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>3 The Secretary of State shall&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) pay the Commissioner such remuneration and allowances; and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) pay, or make provision for the payment of, such pension or gratuities to or in respect of him, as may be provided for under the terms of his appointment.</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Staff</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>4 (1) The Commissioner may appoint any staff he considers necessary for assisting him in the exercise of his functions, one of whom shall be appointed as deputy Commissioner.</quote>
            <quote>(2) During any vacancy in the office of Commissioner or at any time when the Commissioner is for any reason unable to act, the deputy Commissioner shall exercise his functions (and any property or rights vested in the Commissioner may accordingly be dealt with by the deputy as if vested in him).</quote>
            <quote>(3) Without prejudice to sub-paragraph (2), any member of the Commissioner&#8217;s staff may, so far as authorised by him, exercise any of his functions.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>General powers</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>5 (1) Subject to any directions given by the Secretary of State, the Commissioner may do anything which appears to him to be necessary or expedient for the purpose of, or in connection with, the exercise of his functions.</quote>
            <quote>(2) That includes, in particular&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) co-operating with other public authorities in the United Kingdom;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) acquiring and disposing of land and other property; and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(c) entering into contracts.</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Reports</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>6 Regulations may provide for the Commissioner to make periodic or other reports to the Secretary of State relating to the exercise of his functions and may require the reports to be published in the manner required by the regulations.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Accounts</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>7 (1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner must keep accounts in such form as the Secretary of State may determine.</quote>
            <quote>(2) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner must prepare annual accounts in respect of each financial year in such form as the Secretary of State may determine.</quote>
            <quote>(3) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner must send copies of the annual accounts to the Secretary of State and the Comptroller and Auditor General within such period after the end of the financial year to which the accounts relate as the Secretary of State may determine.</quote>
            <quote>(4) The Comptroller and Auditor General must examine, certify and report on the annual accounts and must lay copies of the accounts and of his report before Parliament.</quote>
            <quote>(5) In this paragraph &#8220;financial year&#8221;, in relation to the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner, means&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) the period beginning with the date on which the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner is established and ending with the next 31st March following that date; and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) each successive period of twelve months ending with 31st March.</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Payments</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>8 The Secretary of State may make payments to the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner of such amounts, at such times and on such conditions (if any) as he considers appropriate.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>General</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>9 In the House of Commons Disqualification Act 1975, in Part III of Schedule 1 (certain disqualifying offices), the following entries are inserted at the appropriate places&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>&#8220;Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.&#8221;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>&#8220;Member of the staff of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.&#8221;</IndentOne>
            <quote>10 In the Northern Ireland Assembly Disqualification Act 1975, the same entries as are set out in paragraph 9 are inserted at the appropriate places in Part III of Schedule 1.</quote>
            <quote>11 (1) Regulations may provide that the office of Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner shall be added to the list of &#8220;Offices&#8221; in Schedule 1 to the Superannuation Act 1972 (offices etc. to which section 1 of that Act applies).</quote>
            <quote>(2) The Secretary of State shall pay to the Minister for the Civil Service, at such times as he may direct, such sums as he may determine in respect of any increase attributable to provision made under sub-paragraph (1) in the sums payable out of money provided by Parliament under the Superannuation Act 1972.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
         </text>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>140</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>140:</B> Before Clause 77, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty of candour</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 20 of the Health and Social Care Act 2008 (regulation of regulated activities), after subsection (5) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(5A) Regulations under this section must make provision as to the provision of information in a case where an incident of a specified description affecting a person&#8217;s safety occurs in the course of the person being provided with a service.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>141</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>141:</B> Clause 77, page 66, line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in so deciding in the case of an NHS trust, the Commission must review the effectiveness of previous interventions with that trust by the Trust Development Authority (or its predecessor bodies) and consider whether to require the Authority to advise the Secretary of State to appoint a trust special administrator.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>142</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>142:</B> After Clause 82, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Chief Inspectors</quote>
         <IndentOne>After paragraph 3 of Schedule 1 to the Health and Social Care Act 2008 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Chief Inspectors</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>3A (1) The non-executive members must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) appoint an executive member to be the Chief Inspector of Hospitals,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) appoint an executive member to be the Chief Inspector of Adult Social Care, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) appoint an executive member to be the Chief Inspector of General Practice.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Each of those executive members is to exercise such functions of the Commission on its behalf as it determines.</quote>
         <quote>(3) When exercising functions under sub-paragraph (2), an executive member must have regard to the importance of safeguarding and promoting the Commission&#8217;s independence from the Secretary of State.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>143</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>143:</B> After Clause 82, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Independence of the Care Quality Commission</quote>
         <quote>(1) Part 1 of the Health and Social Care Act 2008 (the Care Quality Commission) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 48 (special reviews or investigations), omit subsection (7) (Secretary of State&#8217;s power to make regulations as to procedure for representations before publication of report).</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 54 (studies as to economy, efficiency etc), in subsections (1) and (3), omit &#8220;, with the approval of the Secretary of State,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) After subsection (2) of that section, insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) The Commission may not exercise the power under subsection (1)(a), so far as it relates to the activity mentioned in subsection (2)(d), without the approval of the Secretary of State.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(5) In section 55 (publication of results of studies under section 54), omit subsection (2) (Secretary of State&#8217;s power to make regulations as to procedure for representations before publication of report).</quote>
         <quote>(6) In section 57 (reviews of data, studies and research), in subsection (1), omit &#8220;, with the approval of the Secretary of State,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In section 61 (inspections carried out for registration purposes), omit&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) subsection (1) (Secretary of State&#8217;s power to make regulations specifying frequency etc. of inspections), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) subsection (4) (Secretary of State&#8217;s power to make regulations as to procedure for representations before publication of report).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) In section 83 (annual reports), omit subsection (3) (Secretary of State&#8217;s power to direct preparation of separate reports).</quote>
         <quote>(9) In paragraph 5 of Schedule 4 (inspection programmes etc.), omit&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in sub-paragraph (1) (preparation of programme etc.), &#8220;, or at such times as the Secretary of State may specify by order,&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) sub-paragraph (3) (Secretary of State&#8217;s power to specify form of programme etc.).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) In consequence of subsections (3) and (6), omit section 293(3) and (4) of the Health and Social Care Act 2012.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[As an amendment to Amendment 143]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>143A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>143A&#042;:</B> After Clause 82, line 10, leave out subsection (4)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>144</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>144:</B> After Clause 82, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Staffing numbers and skills mix</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Care Quality Commission shall, in carrying out its functions, have regard to any official guidance on staffing numbers and skills mix.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>145</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>145:</B> Clause 83, page 72, leave out lines 16 to 27</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>146</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>146:</B> Clause 83, page 72, line 28, leave out &#8220;or local authority&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>147</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>147:</B> Clause 83, page 72, line 45, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Indicators the Commission devises for the purposes of subsection (5) should include indicators of the quality of services provided for the identification and treatment of those conditions that most frequently occur in a particular care setting.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>147A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>147A&#042;:</B> Clause 83, page 72, line 45, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Indicators the Commission devises for the purposes of subsection (5) may include indicators relating to the uptake of medicines recommended for use by the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>148</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>148:</B> Clause 83, page 73, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(13) Consultation undertaken before the commencement of this section is as effective for the purposes of subsection (9) as consultation undertaken after that commencement.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>149</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>149:</B> Clause 83, page 73, line 16, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In section 48 (special reviews and investigations), in subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) omit &#8220;, with the approval of the Secretary of State,&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) at the end insert &#8220;; but the Commission may not conduct a review or investigation under subsection (2)(ba) or (bb) without the approval of the Secretary of State.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>( ) Omit subsection (1A) of that section.</quote>
         <quote>( ) In subsection (2) of that section, for &#8220;a periodic review&#8221; substitute &#8220;a review under section 46&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>( ) In that subsection, after paragraph (ba) (but before the following &#8220;or&#8221;) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(bb) the exercise of the functions of English local authorities in arranging for the provision of adult social services,&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>( ) After subsection (3) of that section insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) A review or investigation under subsection (2)(b), in so far as it involves a review or investigation into the arrangements made for the provision of the adult social services in question, is to be treated as a review under subsection (2)(bb) (and the requirement for approval under subsection (1) is accordingly to apply).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>150</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>150:</B> Clause 83, page 73, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in section 293 of the Health and Social Care Act 2012, omit subsections (1) and (2);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>151</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>151:</B> After Clause 83, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Periodic reviews and assessments of standards of employment and impact of quality of care</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Commission shall have a duty to carry out periodic reviews and assessments of standards of employment in health and social care provision with particular emphasis on workforce conditions which support continuity and quality of care, and are consistent with the wellbeing principle as set out in section 1.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152:</B> Before Clause 84, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty of candour</quote>
         <quote>(1) Every organisation registered with the Care Quality Commission to provide health or social care services must be honest, open and truthful in all their dealing with patients and the public.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Organisational interests of those so registered must never be allowed to outweigh the duty to be honest, open and truthful.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Where death or serious harm has been or may have been caused to a patient by an act or omission of the organisation or its staff, the patient or any lawfully entitled personal representative or other authorised person should be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) informed of the incident;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) given full disclosure of the surrounding circumstances; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) be offered an appropriate level of support,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>whether or not the patient or representative has asked for this information.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152A:</B> Clause 84, page 73, line 42, leave out &#8220;exercises functions in connection with the provision of&#8221; and insert &#8220;provides&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152B:</B> Clause 84, page 74, line 1, leave out &#8220;body (other than a public body) which&#8221; and insert &#8220;person who&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152C:</B> Clause 84, page 74, line 4, at end insert &#8220;, or</quote>
         <IndentOne>(c) a person who provides health services or adult social care in England all or part of the cost of which is paid for by means of a direct payment under section 12A of the National Health Service Act 2006 or under Part 1 of this Act.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152D:</B> Clause 85, page 74, line 35, leave out &#8220;care provider&#8221; and insert &#8220;person&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152E</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152E:</B> Clause 85, page 74, line 35, leave out from &#8220;liable&#8221; to end of line 36 and insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) on summary conviction, to a fine;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) on conviction on indictment, to imprisonment for not more than two years or a fine (or both).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152F</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152F:</B> After Clause 85, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Offences by bodies</quote>
         <quote>(1) Subsection (2) applies where an offence under section 84(1) is committed by a body corporate and it is proved that the offence is committed by, or with the consent or connivance of, or is attributable to neglect on the part of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a director, manager or secretary of the body, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a person purporting to act in such a capacity.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The director, manager, secretary or person purporting to act as such (as well as the body) is guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly (but section 85(2) does not apply).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The reference in subsection (2) to a director, manager or secretary of a body corporate includes a reference&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to any other similar officer of the body, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the body is a local authority, to a member of the authority.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Proceedings for an offence under section 84(1) alleged to have been committed by an unincorporated association are to be brought in the name of the association (and not in that of any of the members); and rules of court relating to the service of documents have effect as if the unincorporated association were a body corporate.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In proceedings for an offence under section 84(1) brought against an unincorporated association, section 33 of the Criminal Justice Act 1925 and Schedule 3 to the Magistrates&#8217; Courts Act 1980 apply as they apply in relation to a body corporate.</quote>
         <quote>(6) A fine imposed on an unincorporated association on its conviction for an offence under section 84(1) is to be paid out of the funds of the association.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Subsection (8) applies if an offence under section 84(1) is proved&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to have been committed by, or with the consent or connivance of, an officer of the association or a member of its governing body, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to be attributable to neglect on the part of such an officer or member.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) The officer or member (as well as the association) is guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against accordingly (but section 85(2) does not apply).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>153</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>153:</B> After Clause 85, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Training for persons working in regulated activity</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 20 of the Health and Social Care Act 2008 (regulation of regulated activities), after subsection (4) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) Regulations made under this section by virtue of subsection (3)(d) may in particular include provision for a specified person to set the standards which persons undergoing the training in question must attain.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>154</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>154:</B> Schedule 5, page 112, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(0 ) The non-executive members of HEE must include a person who will represent the interests of patients.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>155</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>155:</B> Schedule 5, page 114, line 33, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) HEE may arrange for any of its committees, sub-committees or members or any other person to exercise any of its functions on its behalf (but see sub-paragraph (4)).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>156</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>156:</B> Schedule 5, page 114, line 36, after &#8220;sub-paragraph&#8221; insert &#8220;(1A) or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>157</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>157:</B> Schedule 5, page 115, line 1, after &#8220;LETB&#8221; insert &#8220;, or for a sub-committee, member or any other person,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>158</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>158:</B> After Clause 89, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Mandatory training and certification for health and care support workers and nursing assistants</quote>
         <quote>(1) HEE must develop a mandatory training curriculum and certification standards, with two levels, for health and care support workers who are delivering direct care to service users and for nursing assistants.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of subsection (1), a health or care support worker shall be an individual who works in support of health or care professionals and delivers direct care to service users.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The training curriculum, under subsection (1), will have&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a basic level; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an advanced level,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>of certification in health and care standards.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Providers of health or care services must be reponsible for ensuring that all health and care support workers hold a certificate in health and care standards.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Any individual working directly with patients or clients must have completed training and hold, at least, a basic level certificate in health and care standards.</quote>
         <quote>(6) A nursing assistant must have completed training and hold an advanced level certificate in health and care standards.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The training curriculum and certification standards set out in subsection (1) will be set by the Nursing and Midwifery Council and approved by HEE.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Employers must retain a register of individuals who hold any certificate in health and care standards.</quote>
         <quote>(9) It is an offfence for any employer to employ&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an individual to work directly with patients or clients who is not registered as holding at least a basic level certificate in health and care standards; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a nursing assistant who is not registered as holding an advanced level certificate in health and care standards.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>159</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>159:</B> After Clause 89, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Safeguarding patients</quote>
         <quote>(1) The first duty that a health or care service provider must consider for any decision is patient safety.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Health or care service providers must publish a report containing staffing levels based on evidence of safe staffing levels supported by acuity and dependency levels for each patient.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The report must relate safe staffing levels to patient outcomes and mortality rates.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The report must be presented to the hospital management board or any other relevant board of management.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The frequency of the report will be determined by the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Care Quality Commission or Monitor will be able to request to see the report, under subsection (2), at any time.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>160</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>160:</B> After Clause 89, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Regulation of health and care support workers</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State shall, by regulations and in consultation with the Care Quality Commission, HEE and such other persons as it considers appropriate, ensure the establishment of a system of regulation of health and care support workers.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purpose of subsection (1), a health or care support worker shall be an individual who works in support of health or care professionals and delivers direct care to service users.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>160A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>160A&#042;:</B> Clause 91, page 78, line 43, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the needs of patients to have their conditions diagnosed promptly,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>161</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>161:</B> Clause 93, page 80, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Subsections (1), (2) and (4) of section 89 (quality improvement in education and training etc.) apply to an LETB in the exercise of its functions as they apply to HEE in the exercise of its functions.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>162</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>162:</B> Clause 94, page 80, line 23, at end insert &#8220;, and</quote>
         <IndentOne>( ) a person who will represent the interests of patients.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>163</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>163:</B> Clause 94, page 80, line 24, leave out &#8220;The regulations&#8221; and insert &#8220;Regulations under paragraph (b) of subsection (3)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>164</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>164:</B> Clause 94, page 80, line 24, leave out &#8220;that expertise&#8221; and insert &#8220;the expertise mentioned in that paragraph&#8221; </quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>165</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>165:</B> Schedule 7, page 126, line 36, after &#8220;any&#8221; insert &#8220;of its committees, sub-committees or members or any other&#8221; </quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>166</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>166:</B> Clause 100, page 85, line 12, leave out &#8220;such research&#8221; and insert &#8220;research that is safe and ethical (including by promoting transparency in research)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>167</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>167:</B> Clause 100, page 85, line 25, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Promoting transparency in research includes promoting&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the registration of research;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the publication and dissemination of research findings and conclusions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the provision of access to data on which research findings or conclusions are based;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the provision of information at the end of research to participants in the research;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) the provision of access to tissue used in research, for use in future research.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>168</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>168:</B> Schedule 8, page 132, line 45, leave out from second &#8220;a&#8221; to end of line 3 on page 133 and insert &#8220;research ethics committee recognised or established by or on behalf of the Health Research Authority under the Care Act 2013.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>169</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>169:</B> Clause 112, page 92, line 25, leave out &#8220;or duty&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>170</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>170:</B> Clause 114, page 94, line 23, after &#8220;cases)&#8221; insert &#8220;or 71 (after-care under the Mental Health Act 1983)&#8221;.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>