<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Care_(HLBill1_VI(b))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 66, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Access to appeals for care decisions</quote>
         <quote>(1) In this section &#8220;the Tribunal&#8221; means the first tier Tribunal.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Where a local authority&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) makes a decision under section 13(1) that some or all of an adults needs meet the eligibility criteria, or none of their needs meet the eligibility criteria,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) exercises its power to charge for meeting needs under section 14,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) completes a financial assessment under section 17,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) makes a determination under section 18 or section 19 that it must or may provide services to meet the adults care and support needs,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) makes a determination under section 20 that it must or may provide services to meet a carers needs for support,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) has prepared or reviewed a care and support plan, or a care plan under section 25 or section 27,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) has prepared a personal budget under section 26 or section 28, or a care account under section 29,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) the outcome of an inquiry under section 41,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>an application may be made to the tribunal within the relevant period.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The relevant period shall be prescribed by the Secretary of State in regulations.</quote>
         <quote>(4) An application may be made by the relevant service user or carer who is the subject of the relevant decision listed in subsection (2) above.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An application may be made by any other person with leave of the tribunal.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The powers of the Tribunal are to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) dismiss the appeal,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) allow the appeal and quash the decision appealed against, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) remit the case to the local authority to dispose of in accordance with the directions of the tribunal.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) The tribunal shall have powers to order costs as it see fit.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The Secretary of State must make regulations concerning the process and procedures of the Tribunal.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In making regulations under subsection (8) the Secretary of State must seek to ensure adequate service user and carer representation on the tribunal.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>