<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Care_(HLBill1(e))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 5, page 104, line 28, leave out sub-paragraph (1)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 5, page 104, line 28, leave out from &#8220;expertise&#8221; to end of line 29 and insert &#8220;including a registered nurse&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 5, page 104, line 29, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The members of HEE must include someone with experience in staff groups that are not professionally registered.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 5, page 106, line 16, at end insert &#8220;and the consent of the Health Select Committee of the House of Commons&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 5, page 106, line 20, leave out sub-paragraph (1)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 5, page 107, line 17, leave out sub-paragraph (2)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 5, page 107, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) HEE must exercise its functions consistent with the promotion of a comprehensive health service, giving equal consideration to the importance of physical and mental health.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 84, page 71, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In performing any of its functions or duties as laid out or applied to it under this Act or any other legislation, HEE must ensure equal consideration of importance is given to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) physical health and mental health; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the training and education of health workers who work in physical health, mental health or with people with learning difficulties.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 84, page 72, line 11, leave out &#8220;, with the consent of the Secretary of State,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 84, page 72, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) work with persons who provide health services to ensure an adequate provision of continuing professional development for health care workers.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 85, page 72, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In carrying out its functions under this section, HEE should have regard to any official guidance on staffing numbers and skills mix.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 86, page 73, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the importance of practical based training in the education of clinicians&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 86, page 73, line 13, leave out subsection (5)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 86, page 73, line 15, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) HEE has a responsibility to ensure that its duties under this section are also extended to the Local Education and Training Boards.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 86, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Mandatory training for health and care support workers</quote>
         <quote>(1) HEE must develop a mandatory training curriculum for health and care support workers who are delivering direct care to service users.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of (1) a health or care support worker shall be an individual who works in support of health or care professionals and delivers direct care to service users.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In setting the training curriculum set out in (1), HEE must seek to ensure that standards and competencies are developed in conjunction with the Nursing and Midwifery Council and other relevant organisations.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Providers of health or care services must be responsible for ensuring that all health care support workers have completed the mandatory training curriculum in subsection (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 87, page 73, line 23, after the first &#8220;the&#8221; insert &#8220;short and long-term&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 87, page 73, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In performing its duties under subsection (4) and (5), HEE must ensure that the document produced should&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) include one plan looking 5 years ahead,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) include one plan looking 10 years ahead,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) be updated annually.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 88, page 74, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the need for equality of funding for education and training across England, and consistency of education and training opportunities,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 88, page 74, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the need for speciality training places to be planned nationally,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 88, page 74, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the need for HEE to co-ordinate its activities with the NHS in Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 89, page 75, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) CQC and Monitor&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 91, page 75, line 42, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) persons who deliver education and training to health care workers,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 91, page 76, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) a registered nurse&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 91, page 76, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) persons with experience in staff groups that are not professionally registered&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 91, page 76, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) health care workers who receive education and training from within the LETB&#8217;s area&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 91, page 76, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) patients and carers or their representatives&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 91, page 76, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) a representative of the local Health and Wellbeing Board&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 92, page 77, line 23, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) HEE shall provide guidance on how this section is to be implemented.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 93, page 77, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(e) support the continuing professional development of medical professionals in its area.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 93, page 78, line 8, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) a representative of the relevant local authority or authorities,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 93, page 78, line 8, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) patient and carer groups or their representatives,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 93, page 78, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) HEE must direct a LETB to amend the local education and training plan if not doing so would lead to a failure to ensure national workforce priorities are implemented.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 95, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 95 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 104, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Human Tissue and Embryo Authority</quote>
         <quote>(1) There shall be a body corporate called the Human Tissue and Embryo Authority.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Authority shall consist of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a chairman and deputy chairman, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) such number of other members as the Secretary of State appoints.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The Authority shall keep proper accounts and proper records in relation to the accounts and shall prepare for each accounting year a statement of accounts.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The annual statement of accounts shall comply with any direction given by the Secretary of State, with the approval of the Treasury, as to the information to be contained in the statement, the way in which the information is to be presented or the methods and principles according to which the statement is to be prepared.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Not later than five months after the end of an accounting year, the Authority shall send a copy of the statement of accounts for that year to the Secretary of State and to the Comptroller and Auditor General.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Comptroller and Auditor General shall examine, certify and report on every statement of accounts received by him under subsection (5) above and shall lay a copy of the statement and of his report before each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The Secretary of State and the Comptroller and Auditor General may inspect any records relating to the accounts.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In this section &#8220;accounting year&#8221; means the period beginning with the day when the Authority is established and ending with the following 31st March, or any later period of twelve months ending with the 31st March. Schedule 1 to this Act (which deals with the membership of the Authority, etc) shall have effect.</quote>
         <quote>(9) The Authority shall prepare&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a report for the period beginning with the 1st August preceding the day when the Authority is established (or if that date is a 1st August, beginning with that date) and ending with the next 31st March, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a report for each succeeding period of 12 months ending with 31st March.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) The Authority shall send each report to the Secretary of State as soon as practicable after the end of the period for which it is prepared.</quote>
         <quote>(11) A report prepared under subsection (9) for any period shall deal with the activities of the Authority in the period and the activities the Authority proposes to undertake in the succeeding period of twelve months.</quote>
         <quote>(12) The Secretary of State shall lay before each House of Parliament a copy of every report received by him under subsection (10).</quote>
         <quote>(13) The following provisions of the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 are repealed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) Sections 5 to 10, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) Sections 11(1)(a) and 11(1)(aa).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(14) Save for the provision in subsection (13), references in the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 to &#8220;the Authority&#8221; shall be taken to be references to the Human Tissue and Embryo Authority.</quote>
         <quote>(15) The Care Quality Commission may grant the following licences&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) licences under paragraph 1 of Schedule 2 to the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 authorising activities in the course of providing treatment services,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) licences under paragraph 1A of that Schedule authorising activities in the course of providing non-medical fertility services.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(16) Sections 12, 13 and 13A, and paragraph 4 of Schedule 2 to the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990 have effect in the case of all licences granted under subsection (15) as they would do for licences granted under that Act.</quote>
         <quote>(17) Section 13 of the Human Tissue Act 2004 is repealed.</quote>
         <quote>(18) Save for the provision in subsection (17), references in the Human Tissue Act 2004 to &#8220;the Authority&#8221; shall be taken to be references to the Human Tissue and Embryo Authority.</quote>
         <quote>(19) In Schedule 5 (power to modify or transfer functions) of the Public Bodies Act 2011 omit&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the entry for the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Authority, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the entry for the Human Tissue Authority.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>