<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Care_(HLBill45_I(b))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 37</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS CAMPBELL OF SURBITON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;LOAN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 37, page 31, line 39, at end insert &#8220;with a view to securing, so far as reasonably practicable, the outcomes referred to in section 9(4)(b) or 10(5)(d)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 38</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS CAMPBELL OF SURBITON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS O&#8217;LOAN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 38, leave out Clause 38 and insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Arrangements to ensure continuity of provision</quote>
         <quote>(1) Until the second authority has complied with the conditions set out in subsection (2), the first authority must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) continue to meet the adult&#8217;s needs for care and support, and the needs for support of any carer who is continuing as the adult&#8217;s carer, which it has been meeting, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where it has been keeping a care account in the adult&#8217;s case, continue to keep that account on the same basis as it has been keeping it.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The conditions are that the second authority has&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) carried out the assessment or assessments under section 37(6), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) taken the other steps required under this Part in the adult&#8217;s case.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The first authority may recover from the second authority the costs it incurs in complying with the duty under subsection (1).</quote>
         <quote>(4) Regulations may specify matters to which the first authority must have regard in performing the duty under subsection (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 58</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD PATEL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 5, at beginning insert &#8220;When a child receiving services reaches the age of 14 or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 7, after &#8220;18&#8221; insert &#8220;(whichever is sooner)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 58, page 47, line 40, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The child&#8217;s needs assessment must be completed before the child reaches the age of 16, or within two years of the commencement of services being provided to the child, whichever is later.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 58</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD PATEL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 58, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Transition plans</quote>
         <quote>(1) When a local authority has completed an assessment under this section and is satisfied that the child has needs for care and support, is likely to have needs for care and support after becoming 18, and has determined what those needs are likely to be, the local authority must, before the child reaches 16 or within two years of the child beginning to receive services (whichever is later)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) secure that a transition plan is prepared for the child or young person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) once a transition plan has been prepared, it must maintain the plan.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of this Part, a transition plan is a plan specifying, for the proceeding five years of the child or young person&#8217;s life&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any health care and social care provision reasonably required by him;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the outcomes sought for him, including intentions to enter further or higher education, enter the workplace or move to independent or assisted living;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the housing provision required by him.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) &#8220;Health care provision&#8221; means the provision of health care services as part of the comprehensive health service in England continued under section 1(1) of the National Health Service Act 2006.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Regulations may make provision about the preparation and content of transition plans.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Where a local authority is required to secure that a transition plan is prepared for a child or young person, it must consult the child&#8217;s parent or the young person about the content of the plan during the preparation of a draft of the plan.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The local authority must then send the draft plan to the child or parent or carer.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The local authority must send a copy of the finalised transition plan to the child or parent or carer.</quote>
         <quote>(8) A transition plan shall be maintained until the young person reaches the age of 25.</quote>
         <quote>(9) A local authority in England and its partner commissioning bodies must make arrangements about the health, care and housing provision to be secured for children and young people for whom a transition plan is prepared and maintained.</quote>
         <quote>(10) Where an Education, Health and Care (EHC) Plan is being prepared for a child or young person by a local authority under Part 3 of the Children and Families Act 2013 and a transition plan is already maintained for the child or young person, the transition plan must become part of the EHC plan.</quote>
         <quote>(11) Where an EHC Plan is already maintained for a child or young person by a local authority and a child&#8217;s needs assessment is undertaken under Clause 58(1), the local authority must ensure that the child or young person&#8217;s EHC Plan includes the transition plan as set out under subsection (2).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 60</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD PATEL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 60, page 48, line 38, at beginning insert &#8220;When a child receiving services reaches the age of 14 or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 60, page 48, line 40, after &#8220;18&#8221; insert &#8220;(whichever is sooner)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 60, page 48, line 43, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The child&#8217;s carer&#8217;s assessment must be completed before the child reaches the age of 16, or within two years of the commencement of services being provided to the child, whichever is later.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 84</clausenumber>
   <proposer>EARL HOWE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 84, page 73, line 42, leave out &#8220;exercises functions in connection with the provision of&#8221; and insert &#8220;provides&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 84, page 74, line 1, leave out &#8220;body (other than a public body) which&#8221; and insert &#8220;person who&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 84, page 74, line 4, at end insert &#8220;, or</quote>
         <IndentOne>(c) a person who provides health services or adult social care in England all or part of the cost of which is paid for by means of a direct payment under section 12A of the National Health Service Act 2006 or under Part 1 of this Act.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 85</clausenumber>
   <proposer>EARL HOWE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 85, page 74, line 35, leave out &#8220;care provider&#8221; and insert &#8220;person&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 85, page 74, line 35, leave out from &#8220;liable&#8221; to end of line 36 and insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) on summary conviction, to a fine;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) on conviction on indictment, to imprisonment for not more than two years or a fine (or both).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 85</clausenumber>
   <proposer>EARL HOWE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 85, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Offences by bodies</quote>
         <quote>(1) Subsection (2) applies where an offence under section 84(1) is committed by a body corporate and it is proved that the offence is committed by, or with the consent or connivance of, or is attributable to neglect on the part of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a director, manager or secretary of the body, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a person purporting to act in such a capacity.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The director, manager, secretary or person purporting to act as such (as well as the body) is guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly (but section 85(2) does not apply).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The reference in subsection (2) to a director, manager or secretary of a body corporate includes a reference&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to any other similar officer of the body, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the body is a local authority, to a member of the authority.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Proceedings for an offence under section 84(1) alleged to have been committed by an unincorporated association are to be brought in the name of the association (and not in that of any of the members); and rules of court relating to the service of documents have effect as if the unincorporated association were a body corporate.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In proceedings for an offence under section 84(1) brought against an unincorporated association, section 33 of the Criminal Justice Act 1925 and Schedule 3 to the Magistrates&#8217; Courts Act 1980 apply as they apply in relation to a body corporate.</quote>
         <quote>(6) A fine imposed on an unincorporated association on its conviction for an offence under section 84(1) is to be paid out of the funds of the association.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Subsection (8) applies if an offence under section 84(1) is proved&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to have been committed by, or with the consent or connivance of, an officer of the association or a member of its governing body, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to be attributable to neglect on the part of such an officer or member.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) The officer or member (as well as the association) is guilty of the offence and liable to be proceeded against accordingly (but section 85(2) does not apply).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>