<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Care_(HLBill45(h))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 76, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;76A Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) In the Health and Social Care Act 2008, after section 128 insert the following new Part:</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 2A</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>128A Establishment of an office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) There shall be an office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Schedule (The Older Persons&#8217; CommissionerThe Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner) shall have effect with respect to the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.</quote>
         <quote>128B Functions of the office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner has the function under this Part of promoting the wellbeing, dignity and respect of older people and safeguarding and promoting their rights and welfare.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In fulfilling their duties under subsection (1), the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner may review, and monitor the operation of, arrangements falling within subsection (2), (3) or (4) for the purpose of ascertaining whether, and to what extent, the arrangements are effective in promoting the wellbeing, dignity and respect, and safeguarding and promoting the rights and welfare of older people.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The arrangements falling within this subsection are the arrangements made by the providers of regulated services in England, or by the Secretary of State, for dealing with complaints or representations in respect of such services made by or on behalf of older people.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The arrangements falling within this subsection are arrangements made by the providers of regulated services in England, or by the Secretary of State, for ensuring that proper action is taken in response to any disclosure of information which may tend to show that, in the course of, or in connection with, the provision of regulated services to older people&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) that a criminal offence has been committed;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) that a person has failed to comply with any legal obligation to which he is subject;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) that the health and safety of any person has been endangered; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) that information tending to show that any matter falling within one of the preceding paragraphs has been deliberately concealed.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The arrangements falling within this subsection are arrangements made (whether by providers of regulated services in England, by the Secretary of State or by any other person) for making persons available&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to represent the views and wishes of older people to whom this Part applies; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to ensure the adequate provision to older people of advice and support of any prescribed kind.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The Secretary of State may, by regulations confer power on the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to require prescribed persons to provide any information which the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner considers it necessary or expedient to have for the purposes of his functions under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(7) A statutory instrument containing regulations under subsection (5) is not to be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>128C Examination of cases by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may, by regulations, make provision for the examination by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner of the cases of particular older people.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The regulations may include provision about&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the types of case which may be examined;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the circumstances in which an examination may be made;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the procedure for conducting an examination, including provision about the representation of parties;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the publication of reports following an examination.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The regulations may, for the purposes of enabling the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to examine or determine whether any recommendation made in a report following an examination has been complied with, make provision for&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) requiring persons to provide the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner with information; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) requiring persons who hold or are accountable for information to provide the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner with explanations or other assistance,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>for the purpose of an examination or for the purposes of for the purpose of an examination or for the purposes of determining whether any recommendation made in a report determining whether any recommendation made in a report following an examination has been complied with.following an examination has been complied with.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes mentioned in subsection (3), the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner shall have the same powers as the High Court in respect of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the attendance and examination of witnesses (including the administration of oaths and affirmations and the examination of witnesses abroad); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the provision of information.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) No person shall be compelled for the purposes mentioned in subsection (3) to give any evidence or provide information which he could not be compelled to give or provide in civil proceedings before the High Court.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The regulations may make provision for the payment by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner of sums in respect of expenses or allowances to persons who attend or provide information for the purposes mentioned in subsection (3).</quote>
         <quote>(7) A statutory instrument containing the first regulations made under subsections (1), (2) or (3) is not to be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(8) A statutory instrument that contains regulations made under subsection (6) is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>128D Obstruction</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner may certify an offence to the High Court where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a person, without lawful excuse, obstructs him or any member of his staff in the exercise of any of his functions under regulations made under section 128B(5) or 128C; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a person is guilty of any act or omission in relation to an examination under regulations made by under section 128C which, if that examination were proceedings in the High Court, would constitute contempt of court.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Where an offence is so certified the High Court may inquire into the matter; and after hearing&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any witnesses who may be produced against or on behalf of the person charged with the offence; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any statement that may be offered in defence,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>the High Court may deal with the person charged with the offence the High Court may deal with the person charged with the offence in any manner in which it could deal with him if he had committed in any manner in which it could deal with him if he had committed the same offence in relation to the High Court.the same offence in relation to the High Court.</IndentOne>
         <quote>128E Further functions</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner may, in connection with his functions under this Part give advice and information to any person.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Regulations may confer power on the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to assist an older person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in making a complaint or representation to or in respect of a provider of regulated services in England; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in any prescribed proceedings.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of subsection (2), assistance includes&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) financial assistance; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) arranging for representation, or the giving of advice or assistance, by any person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Regulations under section (2) may also provide for assistance to be given on conditions, including (in the case of financial assistance) conditions requiring repayment in specified circumstances.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Regulations may, in connection with the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner&#8217;s functions under this Part, confer further functions on the Commissioner.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Regulations may, in particular, include provision about the making of reports on any matter connected with any of his functions.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Apart from identifying any person investigated, a report by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner shall not&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) mention the name of any person, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) include any particulars which, in the opinion of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner, are likely to identify any person and can be omitted without impairing the effectiveness of the report,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>unless, after taking account of the public interest (as well as the unless, after taking account of the public interest (as well as the interests of any person who made a complaint and other persons), interests of any person who made a complaint and other persons), the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner considers it necessary for the the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner considers it necessary for the report to mention his name or include such particulars.report to mention his name or include such particulars.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) For the purposes of the law of defamation, the publication of any matter by the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner in a report is absolutely privileged.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In subsection (1) of this section &#8220;proceedings&#8221; includes a procedure of any kind and any prospective proceedings.</quote>
         <quote>(10) A statutory instrument containing the regulations under this section is not to be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>128F Restrictions</quote>
         <quote>(1) This Part does not authorise the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner to enquire into or report on any matter so far as it is the subject of legal proceedings before, or has been determined by, a court or tribunal.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This Part does not authorise the Commissioner to exercise any function which by virtue of an enactment is also exercisable by the prescribed person.</quote>
         <quote>128G Interpretation</quote>
         <quote>(1) For the purposes of this Part &#8220;regulated services&#8221; has the same definition as &#8220;regulated activity&#8221; in section 8 of this Act as they relate to older people.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This Part applies to any older person normally domiciled in England.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) After Schedule 5, insert the following new Schedule&#8212;</quote>
         <text>
            <quote>
               <B>000:</B> After Clause 76, </quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Schedule 5A</HeadingTwo>
            <HeadingTwo>The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner</HeadingTwo>
            <HeadingTwo>Status</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>1 (1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner is to be a corporation sole.</quote>
            <quote>(2) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner is not to be regarded as the servant or agent of the Crown or as enjoying any status, immunity or privilege of the Crown; and the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner&#8217;s property is not to be regarded as property of, or property held on behalf of, the Crown.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Appointment and tenure of office</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>2 Regulations may make provision&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) as to the appointment of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner (including any conditions to be fulfilled for appointment);</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) as to the filling of vacancies in the office of Commissioner;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(c) as to the tenure of office of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner (including the circumstances in which he ceases to hold office or may be removed or suspended from office).</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Remuneration</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>3 The Secretary of State shall&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) pay the Commissioner such remuneration and allowances; and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) pay, or make provision for the payment of, such pension or gratuities to or in respect of him, as may be provided for under the terms of his appointment.</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Staff</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>4 (1) The Commissioner may appoint any staff he considers necessary for assisting him in the exercise of his functions, one of whom shall be appointed as deputy Commissioner.</quote>
            <quote>(2) During any vacancy in the office of Commissioner or at any time when the Commissioner is for any reason unable to act, the deputy Commissioner shall exercise his functions (and any property or rights vested in the Commissioner may accordingly be dealt with by the deputy as if vested in him).</quote>
            <quote>(3) Without prejudice to sub-paragraph (2), any member of the Commissioner&#8217;s staff may, so far as authorised by him, exercise any of his functions.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>General powers</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>5 (1) Subject to any directions given by the Secretary of State, the Commissioner may do anything which appears to him to be necessary or expedient for the purpose of, or in connection with, the exercise of his functions.</quote>
            <quote>(2) That includes, in particular&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) co-operating with other public authorities in the United Kingdom;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) acquiring and disposing of land and other property; and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(c) entering into contracts.</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Reports</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>6 Regulations may provide for the Commissioner to make periodic or other reports to the Secretary of State relating to the exercise of his functions and may require the reports to be published in the manner required by the regulations.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Accounts</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>7 (1) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner must keep accounts in such form as the Secretary of State may determine.</quote>
            <quote>(2) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner must prepare annual accounts in respect of each financial year in such form as the Secretary of State may determine.</quote>
            <quote>(3) The Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner must send copies of the annual accounts to the Secretary of State and the Comptroller and Auditor General within such period after the end of the financial year to which the accounts relate as the Secretary of State may determine.</quote>
            <quote>(4) The Comptroller and Auditor General must examine, certify and report on the annual accounts and must lay copies of the accounts and of his report before Parliament.</quote>
            <quote>(5) In this paragraph &#8220;financial year&#8221;, in relation to the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner, means&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) the period beginning with the date on which the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner is established and ending with the next 31st March following that date; and</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) each successive period of twelve months ending with 31st March.</IndentOne>
            <HeadingTwo>Payments</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>8 The Secretary of State may make payments to the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner of such amounts, at such times and on such conditions (if any) as he considers appropriate.</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>General</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>9 In the House of Commons Disqualification Act 1975, in Part III of Schedule 1 (certain disqualifying offices), the following entries are inserted at the appropriate places&#8212;</quote>
            <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.&#8221;</HeadingTwo>
            <quote/>&#8220;Member of the staff of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.&#8221;&#8220;Member of the staff of the Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner.&#8221;<quote>10 In the Northern Ireland Assembly Disqualification Act 1975, the same entries as are set out in paragraph 9 are inserted at the appropriate places in Part III of Schedule 1.</quote>
            <quote>11 (1) Regulations may provide that the office of Older Persons&#8217; Commissioner shall be added to the list of &#8220;Offices&#8221; in Schedule 1 to the Superannuation Act 1972 (offices etc. to which section 1 of that Act applies).</quote>
            <quote>(2) The Secretary of State shall pay to the Minister for the Civil Service, at such times as he may direct, such sums as he may determine in respect of any increase attributable to provision made under sub-paragraph (1) in the sums payable out of money provided by Parliament under the Superannuation Act 1972.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
         </text>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>