<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill32(m))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 24, line 31, leave out &#8220;it expects to be&#8221; and insert &#8220;which is&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 24, line 34, leave out &#8220;it expects to be&#8221; and insert &#8220;which is&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 25, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7A) The Secretary of State shall lay a draft of regulations setting out the minimum level of specific special educational provision, health care provision and social care provision that local authorities must provide as part of their local offer, and the regulations are not to be made unless they have been approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(7B) Once regulations under subsection (7A) have been made, the Secretary of State must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) issue guidance to local authorities on how to meet these regulations, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) publish information on these regulations accessible to the families of children and young people with special educational needs on the Department&#8217;s website, and in any other way he sees fit.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 67, page 48, line 4, at end insert &#8220;in a plain English style and make it available on the internet&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 68, page 48, line 14, leave out from &#8220;consult&#8221; to &#8220;about&#8221; in line 15 and insert &#8220;publicly, for a period of not less than 90 days&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 68, page 48, line 15, leave out &#8220;by them&#8221; and insert &#8220;as part of that consultation&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 68, page 48, line 16, leave out subsections (3) to (8) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) A code, or revision of a code, does not come into operation until the Secretary of State by order so provides.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The power conferred by subsection (3) shall be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An order bringing a code, or revision of a code, into operation may not be made unless a draft order has been laid before and approved by resolution of each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(6) When an order or draft of an order is laid, the code or revision of a code to which it relates must also be laid.</quote>
         <quote>(7) No order or draft of an order may be laid until the consultation required by subsection (2) has taken place.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>