<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill32_IV(a))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 78</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD NASH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>241A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>241A&#042;:</B> After Clause 78, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty to support pupils with medical conditions</quote>
         <quote>(1) The appropriate authority for a school to which this section applies must make arrangements for supporting pupils at the school with medical conditions.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In meeting the duty in subsection (1) the appropriate authority must have regard to guidance issued by the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The duty in subsection (1) does not apply in relation to a pupil who is a young child for the purposes of Part 3 of the Childcare Act 2006 (regulation of provision of childcare in England).</quote>
         <quote>(4) This section applies to the following schools in England&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a maintained school;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an Academy school;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) an alternative provision Academy;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) a pupil referral unit.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;the appropriate authority for a school&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the case of a maintained school, the governing body,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in the case of an Academy, the proprietor, and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in the case of a pupil referral unit, the managing committee;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;maintained school&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a community, foundation or voluntary school, within the meaning of the School Standards and Framework Act 1998, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a community or foundation special school, within the meaning of that Act.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The Education Act 1996 and this section are to be read as if this section were included in that Act.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 112</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD NASH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>274&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>274&#042;:</B> Clause 112, page 116, line 14, leave out &#8220;is&#8221; and insert &#8220;and section (Duty to support pupils with medical conditions) (duty to support pupils with medical conditions) are&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>