<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill32_II(a))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Second Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 88</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>266A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>266A&#042;:</B> After Clause 88, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Children&#8217;s rights duty</quote>
         <IndentOne>Any person whose functions are of a public nature must in the exercise of his or her functions have due regard to the need to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) respect, protect and fulfil children&#8217;s rights; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) actively seek and give due weight to the views of children in matters affecting them.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 93</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS DRAKE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>267A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>267A&#042;:</B> After Clause 93, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Kinship carers&#8217; adjustment leave</quote>
         <quote>(1) A qualifying employee who satisfies prescribed conditions may be absent from work at any time during an adjustment leave period.</quote>
         <quote>(2) An adjustment leave period is a period calculated in accordance with regulations made by the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The regulations under subsection (2) above shall include provision for determining the extent of an employee&#8217;s entitlement to leave under this section but shall secure that where an employee is entitled to leave under this section he is entitled to at least four weeks&#8217; leave, or for a longer period to be prescribed.</quote>
         <quote>(4) An employee who exercises his rights under subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is entitled, for such purposes and to such extent as may be prescribed, to the benefit of the terms and conditions of employment which would have applied if he had not been absent,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is bound, for such purposes and to such extent as may be prescribed, by any obligations arising under those terms and conditions (except in so far as they are inconsistent with subsection (1)), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is entitled to return from leave to a job of a prescribed kind.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) For the purposes of this section, an employee is a qualifying employee if he is a family and friends (kinship) carer looking after a child full-time because the parent(s) is unable to look after the child, in the first 12 months after the child moves in.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>267B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>267B&#042;:</B> After Clause 93, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Carers&#8217; leave</quote>
         <quote>(1) A qualifying employee who satisfies prescribed conditions may be absent from work for a specified period to provide care for a child or vulnerable adult.</quote>
         <quote>(2) An adjustment leave period is a period calculated in accordance with regulations made by the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The regulations under subsection (2) above shall include provision for determining the extent of an employee&#8217;s entitlement to leave under this section but shall secure that where an employee is entitled to leave under this section he is entitled to two week&#8217;s leave in any given year.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The leave may be taken in a two week block or part-time, with the agreement of the employer.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An employee who exercises his rights under subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is entitled, for such purposes and to such extent as may be prescribed, to the benefit of the terms and conditions of employment which would have applied if he had not been absent,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is bound, for such purposes and to such extent as may be prescribed, by any obligations arising under those terms and conditions (except in so far as they are inconsistent with subsection (1)), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is entitled to return from leave to a job of a prescribed kind.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) For the purposes of this section, an employee is a qualifying employee if he has caring responsibilities for a child or vulnerable adult.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 97</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS DRAKE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>267C&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>267C&#042;:</B> After Clause 97, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Extension of emergency leave entitlement to grandparents</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 57A(3) of the Employment Rights Act 1996 (time off for dependants), after paragraph (d) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(e) a grandchild&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>