<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Defence_Reform_(Bill60_II)</billtitle>
      <headertext>SECOND MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext> The amendments have been marshalled in accordance with the Instruction of 21st January 2014, as follows&#8212;</headertext>
      <headertext>Clauses 5 to 7 Schedule 2 Clauses 8 to 10 Schedule 3 Clauses 11 and 12 Clauses 44 and 45 Schedule 6 Clause 46 Schedule 7 Clause 47 Clause 13 Schedule 4 Clauses 14 to 38 Schedule 5 Clauses 39 to 43 Clauses 48 to 50 </headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 5</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD HODGSON OF ASTLEY ABBOTTS</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS STERN</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MILLER OF CHILTHORNE DOMER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD DUBS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>10</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>10:</B> Clause 5, page 5, line 3, at end insert &#8220;, unmanned aerial systems, distributed common ground systems, ground control and other stations used to support the operation of unmanned aerial systems&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>11</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>11:</B> Clause 5, page 5, line 6, after &#8220;contractor&#8221; insert &#8220;or any person who provides defence procurement services to a contractor or to the Secretary of State for the purposes of DE&amp;S pursuant to the arrangements set out in section 1&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 5, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 5 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 6</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 6, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 6 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 6</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CRAIG OF RADLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>12</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>12:</B> After Clause 6, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Immunity for contractor</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by Order made under section 2 of the Crown Proceedings (Armed Forces) Act 1987 revive section 10 of the Crown Proceedings Act 1947 for the purposes of providing immunity for a contractor.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Before making an order in accordance with the provisions of this section, the Secretary of State shall publish and lay before Parliament a report on the impact of making such an order on&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the procurement of defence equipment and modifications and training facilities including material for urgent operational requirements; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the possibility of risk to the contractor of challenge, whether under the Human Rights Act 1998 or under any other statutory provision, arising from such procurement, whether at the time of the procurement or at any future date.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 7</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 7, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 7 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 2</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>13</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>13:</B> Schedule 2, page 35, line 5, leave out paragraphs 1 to 5 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Information to which Schedule applies</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>1 (1) This Schedule applies to information if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) it was obtained by the Secretary of State or the contractor under or by virtue of this Part or otherwise in connection with the carrying out of functions under or by virtue of this Part, or is derived to any extent from information that was so obtained, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) it relates to the affairs of an individual or to a particular business.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Information ceases to be information to which this Schedule applies&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the case of information relating to the affairs of an individual, when the individual dies, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in the case of information relating to a particular business, on the earlier of&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the day on which the business ceases to be carried on, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the end of the period of 30 years beginning with the date on which the information was obtained by the Secretary of State or the contractor.</IndentTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Offence of disclosing information</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>2 (1) A person commits an offence if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the person discloses information, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) information is disclosed or lost as a result of the person&#8217;s failure to prevent the disclosure or loss through measures taken under sub-paragraph (2), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) it is information to which this Schedule applies.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) A person holding information to which this Schedule applies must take adequate technical and organisational measures against unauthorised or unlawful disclosure of, and against accidental loss of, the information.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Sub-paragraph (1) is subject to paragraphs 4 to 6.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A person who is guilty of an offence under sub-paragraph (1) is liable&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) on summary conviction, to imprisonment for not more than 12 months or to a fine not exceeding the statutory maximum (or both), or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) on conviction on indictment, to imprisonment for not more than two years or to a fine (or both).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The reference in sub-paragraph (4)(a) to 12 months is to be read as a reference to 6 months&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in its application to England and Wales in relation to an offence committed before the date on which section 154(1) of the Criminal Justice Act 2003 comes into force, and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in its application to Northern Ireland.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) If section 85(1) of the Legal Aid, Sentencing and Punishment of Offenders Act 2012 comes into force on or before the day on which this Act is passed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) Section 85 of that Act (removal of limit on certain fines on conviction by magistrates&#8217; court) applies in relation to an offence under sub-paragraph (1) on and after that day as if it were a relevant offence (as defined in section 85(3) of that Act), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) regulations described in section 85(11) of that Act may amend, repeal or otherwise modify sub-paragraph (43)(a).</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>Disclosure with consent</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>3 (1) Paragraph 2(1) does not apply to a disclosure made with the consent of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the individual, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the person for the time being carrying on the business (or, where there are two or more such persons, all those persons).</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>Disclosure of information already available to public</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>4 Paragraph 2(1) does not apply to information that has been made available to the public by being lawfully disclosed in circumstances in which, or for a purpose for which, disclosure is not precluded by this Schedule.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Other permitted disclosures</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>5 (1) Paragraph 2(1) does not apply where information is disclosed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) for the purpose of facilitating the carrying out of functions of a Minister of the Crown (within the meaning of the Ministers of the Crown Act 1975),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for the purpose of facilitating the carrying out by the SSRO of any of its functions,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) for the purpose of enabling or assisting an authorised person to carry out any of its functions,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) for the purpose of enabling or assisting a contractor to provide defence procurement services to the Secretary of State by virtue of arrangements mentioned in section 1,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) to the person from whom the information was obtained or, where that person is associated with one or more other persons, to any such associated person,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) by a person to whom the information is disclosed by virtue of paragraph (e),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) under the Freedom of Information Act 2000 where there is a requirement to disclose notwithstanding available defences,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) in connection with the investigation of a criminal offence or for the purposes of criminal proceedings,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(i) for the purposes of civil proceedings,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(j) in pursuance of an EU obligation, </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(k) for the purpose of facilitating the carrying out by the Comptroller and Auditor General of functions, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(l)  in anonymised form.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In sub-paragraph (1)(d), &#8220;contractor&#8221; and &#8220;defence procurement services&#8221; have the same meanings as in Part 1.</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of sub-paragraph (1)(l), information is disclosed in anonymised form if no individual or other person to whom the information relates can be identified from it.</quote>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes of sub-paragraph (1), disclosures under paragraph 5(1)(a) to (d) and paragraph 5(1)(h) to (k) must be strictly necessary for the purpose, made in confidence and paragraph 2(1) applies to the recipient of that disclosure.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Prior to making a disclosure under paragraph 5(1)(a) to (d) or paragraph 5(1)(h) to (k), the individual or business to which the information relates must be notified of the intended disclosure and must have the opportunity to challenge that disclosure.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Power to prohibit disclosure</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>6 (1) The Secretary of State may by order&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) prohibit the disclosure of information to which this Schedule applies;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provide that a prohibition imposed by virtue of paragraph (a) is subject to exceptions corresponding to those set out in paragraphs 3 to 5 (other than paragraph 5(1)(g));</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provide that a person who discloses information in contravention of such a prohibition commits an offence punishable&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) on summary conviction, with imprisonment for not more than 12 months or with a fine not exceeding the statutory maximum (or both), or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) on conviction on indictment, with imprisonment for not more than two years or with a fine (or both).</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(2) The reference in sub-paragraph (1)(c)(i) to 12 months is to be read as a reference to six months&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in its application to England and Wales in relation to an offence committed before the date on which section 154(1) of the Criminal Justice Act 2003 comes into force, and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in its application to Northern Ireland.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) An order under sub-paragraph (1) may repeal paragraphs 2 to 5.</quote>
         <quote>(4) If section 85(1) of the Legal Aid, Sentencing and Punishment of Offenders Act 2012 comes into force on or before the day on which this Act is passed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 85 of that Act (removal of limit on certain fines on conviction by magistrates&#8217; court) applies in relation to the power under sub-paragraph (1)(c)(i) on or after that day as if it were a relevant power (as defined in section 85(3) of that Act), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) regulations described in section 85(11) of that Act may amend, repeal or otherwise modify sub-paragraph (1)(c)(i).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) An order under sub-paragraph (1) is to be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(6) A statutory instrument containing an order under sub-paragraph (1) may not be made unless a draft of it has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Authority to inspect measures to protect information</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>7 (1) A person holding information to which this Schedule applies must permit an industry body, acting on behalf of the owner of that information, within six months of the relevant date and subsequently every three years, on reasonable prior written notice and on reasonable confidentiality and other undertakings, to audit and inspect the person&#8217;s technical and organisational measures for protecting that information in compliance with this Schedule.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A person holding information to which this Schedule applies must comply with all reasonable requests or directions by the industry body to enable the industry body to verify that the person is in compliance with their obligations under this Schedule.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The industry body must provide a report of its findings on each inspection to the Secretary of State within three months of that inspection. The industry body may publish each report within six months of that inspection and must include with each report any response made by the Secretary of State to that report.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 8</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 8, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 8 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 8</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD HODGSON OF ASTLEY ABBOTTS</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS STERN</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MILLER OF CHILTHORNE DOMER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD DUBS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>14</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>14:</B> After Clause 8, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Reporting obligations</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Reporting obligation on contractors</quote>
         <IndentOne>In providing any defence procurement services, the contractor shall&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) report annually to the Secretary of State or at any more frequent intervals as the Secretary of State may specify on&#8212;procured under the arrangements set out in section 1; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the technical characteristics;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) capabilities; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) use of equipment and services,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>procured under the arrangements set out in section 1; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) ensure that any person who provides provision of goods or services to a contractor or to the Secretary of State for the purposes of DE&amp;S pursuant to the arrangements set out in section 1 provides the contractor with all information necessary to carry out the contractor&#8217;s reporting obligation under paragraph (a).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>15</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>15:</B> After Clause 8, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reporting obligations relating to defence procurement services: consequential amendments</quote>
         <quote>(1) In the Visiting Forces Act 1952, after section 8, insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;8A Reporting obligations</quote>
         <quote>(1) It shall be the duty of the RAF commander responsible for liaison with visiting forces to provide a scrutiny group to report annually in July to the Secretary of State or at any more frequent intervals as the Secretary of State may specify on the state of all premises and property used by visiting forces for defence purposes, making particular reference to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) defence procurement services used or available for use by visiting forces;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the degree of control exercised by the RAF commander;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any factors which may have a bearing on the Secretary of State determining impact of use of premises and property by visiting forces on any arrangements made or proposed pursuant to section 1 of the Defence Reform Act 2014;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) any other factors which may have a bearing on whether to make any provision under section 8 of the Visiting Forces Act or any other enactment or arrangement to regulate use of premises and property by visiting forces.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The membership of the scrutiny group shall include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the RAF officer responsible for liaison with visiting forces at each premises used for defence purposes;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a member holding high judicial office;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) an independent member with expertise in the particular technology used and services carried out by the visiting forces.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The Defence Committee shall provide compensation for members of the scrutiny group as appropriate for the purposes of reasonable expense encountered in the course of work undertaken in this capacity.</quote>
         <quote>(4) For the purpose of undertaking work in this capacity the members of the scrutiny group may on reasonable notice&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) access any premises or property used by visiting forces for defence purposes;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) request a report from any unit of a visiting force relevant to use of premises and property;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) request documentary or other material relevant to work undertaken by the member;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) request an interview with any visiting officer or agent who may provide information relevant to work undertaken by the member.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000, after section 58, insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;58A Visiting forces</quote>
         <IndentOne>It shall be the duty of the Interception of Communications Commissioner to report annually in July to the Secretary of State or at any more frequent intervals as the Secretary of State may specify on the use of all premises and property by visiting forces or agents for any activity which may be subject to the provisions of the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>16</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>16:</B> After Clause 8, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reporting obligation on use of premises and property</quote>
         <quote>(1) On receipt of any report provided by a scrutiny group established under section 8A of the Visiting Forces Act 1952, the Secretary of State shall&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) lay a copy of the report before Parliament;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) lay a copy of the report before the Intelligence and Security Committee; and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) lay a copy of the government&#8217;s response to the report before Parliament, making particular reference to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the impact of use of premises and property by visiting forces on any arrangements made or proposed under section 1; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) whether any provision should be made under section 8 of the Visiting Forces Act 1952 or any other enactment or arrangement to regulate use of premises and property by visiting forces.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(2) On receipt of any report provided by the Interception Commissioner under section 58A of the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000, the Secretary of State shall&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) lay a copy of the report before Parliament;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) lay a copy of the report before the Intelligence and Security Committee; and </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) lay a copy of the government&#8217;s response to the report before Parliament, making particular reference to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the impact of use of premises and property by visiting forces on any arrangements made or proposed under section 1; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) whether any provision should be made under section 8 of the Visiting Forces Act 1952 or any other enactment or arrangement to regulate use of premises and property by visiting forces.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 9, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 9 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 10, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 10 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Schedule 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>17</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>17:</B> After Schedule 3, insert the following new Schedule&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Schedule 3A</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Super-affirmative procedure for orders under Part 1</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Prior consultation</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>1 (1) If the Secretary of State is proposing to make an order to commence Part 1 of this Act, the Secretary of State must undertake a consultation with&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) relevant persons whom the Secretary of State deems appropriate;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any persons or bodies recommended to the Secretary of State by the House of Commons Defence Select Committee; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) such persons or organisations as appear to him to be representative of interests substantially affected by the proposals.</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>Draft order</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>2 (1) If, after such a consultation, the Secretary of State considers it appropriate to proceed with the making of the order, the Secretary of State must lay before Parliament&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a draft order, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a document which explains the order.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State may not act under this paragraph before the end of the period of twelve weeks beginning with the day on which the consultation began.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Draft order approved</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>3 (1) The Secretary of State may make an order in the terms of the draft order laid under section 2 if, after the expiry of the 40-day period, the draft order is approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(2) But the procedure in section 4 is to apply to the draft order instead of the procedure in this paragraph if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) either House of Parliament so resolves within the 30-day period, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a committee of either House charged with reporting on the draft order so recommends within the 30-day period and the House to which the recommendation is made does not by resolution reject the recommendation within that period.</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>Scrutiny extended</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>4 (1) The Secretary of State must have regard to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any representations,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any resolution of either House of Parliament, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the recommendations of the Defence Select Committee, and any other recommendations of a committee of either House of Parliament charged with reporting on the draft order, made during the 60-day period with regard to the draft order.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) If after the expiry of the 60-day period the draft order is approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament, the Secretary of State may make an order in the terms of the draft order.</quote>
         <quote>(3) If after the expiry of the 60-day period the Secretary of State wishes to proceed with the draft order but with material changes, the Secretary of State may lay before Parliament&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a revised draft order, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a statement giving a summary of the changes proposed; and any representations made to the Secretary of State under section 4.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) If the revised draft order is approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament, the Secretary of State may make an order in the terms of the revised draft order.</quote>
         <quote>5 However, a committee of either House charged with reporting on the revised draft order may, at any time after the revised draft order is laid under section 4(3) and before it is approved by that House under section 4(4), recommend under this section that no further proceedings be taken in relation to the revised draft order.</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Interpretation</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>6 (1) For the purposes of this paragraph an order is made in the terms of a draft order or revised draft order if it contains no material changes to its provisions.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In this Schedule, references to the &#8220;30-day&#8221;, &#8220;40-day&#8221; and &#8220;60-day&#8221; periods in relation to any draft order are to the periods of 30, 40 and 60 days beginning with the day on which the draft order was laid before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Account is to be taken of any time during which Parliament is dissolved or prorogued or during which either House is adjourned.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 11</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 11, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 11 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 12</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 12, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 12 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 47</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ASTOR OF HEVER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>18</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>18:</B> Before Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on volunteer reserve forces</quote>
         <IndentOne>In Part 11 of the Reserve Forces Act 1996 (reserve associations), after section 113 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;113A Duty to prepare report on volunteer reserve forces</quote>
         <quote>(1) An association must prepare an annual report on the state of the volunteer reserve forces so far as concerns the area for which the association is established.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A report on the state of the volunteer reserve forces is a report that sets out the association&#8217;s assessment of the capabilities of the volunteer reserve forces, having regard to the duties that may be imposed on members of those forces by or under this Act or any other enactment.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The assessment referred to in subsection (2) must, in particular, include the association&#8217;s views on the effect of each of the following matters on the capabilities of the volunteer reserve forces&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the recruiting of members for the volunteer reserve forces;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the retention of members of those forces;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the provision of training for those forces;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the upkeep of land and buildings for whose management and maintenance the association is responsible.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A report under subsection (1) must also set out the association&#8217;s assessment of the provision that is made as regards the mental welfare of members and former members of the volunteer reserve forces.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An association must send a report under subsection (1) to the Secretary of State&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the case of the first report, before the first anniversary of the day on which the last Future Reserves 2020 report prepared before the coming into force of this section was presented to the Secretary of State, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in the case of subsequent reports, before the anniversary of the day on which the first report was laid before Parliament under subsection (6).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) On receiving a report under subsection (1), the Secretary of State must lay a copy of it before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The duties under this section may, instead of being performed by an association, be performed by a joint committee appointed under section 116 by two or more associations in relation to their combined areas.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Where by virtue of subsection (7) a joint committee has the duty to prepare a report&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) references in subsections (1) to (5) to an association are to be read as if they were to the joint committee, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section 117(1)(a) (power to regulate manner in which functions are exercised) has effect as if the reference to associations were to the joint committee.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) In subsection (5)(a), &#8220;Future Reserves 2020 report&#8221; means a report prepared by the External Scrutiny Group on the Future Reserves 2020 programme.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 33</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ASTOR OF HEVER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>19</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>19:</B> Clause 33, page 24, leave out line 21 and insert &#8220;single source contract regulations&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>20</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>20:</B> Clause 33, page 24, line 34, leave out subsection (6) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The provision that may be made under subsection (1) by virtue of section 42(2) includes power to specify penalties of different amounts according to the value of the contract to which the contravention relates.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>21</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>21:</B> Clause 33, page 24, line 37, leave out subsection (7)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 39</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ASTOR OF HEVER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>22</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>22:</B> Clause 39, page 26, line 38, leave out &#8220;regulations under this Part&#8221; and insert &#8220;single source contract regulations&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 42</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ASTOR OF HEVER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>23</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>23:</B> Clause 42, page 27, line 33, leave out subsection (4) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) A statutory instrument containing&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the first single source contract regulations,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provision made by virtue of section 14(2), (6) or (8) (contracts to which single source contract regulations apply), whether alone or with other provision, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provision made by virtue of section 33 (amount of penalty), whether alone or with other provision,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Any other statutory instrument containing single source contract regulations is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 49</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ASTOR OF HEVER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD PALMER OF CHILDS HILL</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD ROPER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>24</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>24:</B> Clause 49, page 31, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) No statutory instrument containing an order under subsection (1) in respect of Part 1 (with or without provision under subsection (4)) is to be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD ROSSER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>25</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>25:</B> Clause 49, page 31, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) No statutory instrument containing an order under subsection (1) in respect of Part 1 (with or without provision under subsection (4)) is to be made unless the Secretary of State has first satisfied the conditions set out in subsection (2B) below and, subsequent to this, a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by Parliament, in strict accordance with the super-affirmative procedure as set out in Schedule (Super-affirmative procedure for orders under Part 1).</quote>
         <quote>(2B) The conditions that the Secretary of State must fulfil are as follows&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to publish and lay before Parliament an evidence-based impact assessment which must assess the risks and merits of at least the following options&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) DE&amp;S as modified by the Secretary of State in 2014,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the arrangements for provision of defence procurement services as laid out in Part 1 of the Defence Reform Act 2014 (&#8220;GoCo&#8221;), and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) other options as may be recommended following consultation with the House of Commons Defence Select Committee (Defence Select Committee);</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) to lay before Parliament an independent report setting out the comparative advantages of the defence procurement arrangements referred to in paragraph (a)(i) to (iii) above;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) to require the Defence Select Committee to review and scrutinise the independent report referred to in paragraph (b) and report on its findings to Parliament; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) to lay before Parliament such other documents as the Secretary of State may deem necessary to properly inform Parliament&#8217;s decision.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>