<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Defence_Reform_(Bill60(d))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 33, page 24, leave out line 21 and insert &#8220;single source contract regulations&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 33, page 24, line 34, leave out subsection (6) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The provision that may be made under subsection (1) by virtue of section 42(2) includes power to specify penalties of different amounts according to the value of the contract to which the contravention relates.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 33, page 24, line 37, leave out subsection (7)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 39, page 26, line 38, leave out &#8220;regulations under this Part&#8221; and insert &#8220;single source contract regulations&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 42, page 27, line 33, leave out subsection (4) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) A statutory instrument containing&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the first single source contract regulations,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provision made by virtue of section 14(2), (6) or (8) (contracts to which single source contract regulations apply), whether alone or with other provision, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provision made by virtue of section 33 (amount of penalty), whether alone or with other provision,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Any other statutory instrument containing single source contract regulations is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on volunteer reserve forces</quote>
         <IndentOne>In Part 11 of the Reserve Forces Act 1996 (reserve associations), after section 113 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;113A Duty to prepare report on volunteer reserve forces</quote>
         <quote>(1) An association must prepare an annual report on the state of the volunteer reserve forces so far as concerns the area for which the association is established.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A report on the state of the volunteer reserve forces is a report that sets out the association&#8217;s assessment of the capabilities of the volunteer reserve forces, having regard to the duties that may be imposed on members of those forces by or under this Act or any other enactment.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The assessment referred to in subsection (2) must, in particular, include the association&#8217;s views on the effect of each of the following matters on the capabilities of the volunteer reserve forces&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the recruiting of members for the volunteer reserve forces;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the retention of members of those forces;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the provision of training for those forces;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the upkeep of land and buildings for whose management and maintenance the association is responsible.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A report under subsection (1) must also set out the association&#8217;s assessment of the provision that is made as regards the mental welfare of members and former members of the volunteer reserve forces.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An association must send a report under subsection (1) to the Secretary of State&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in the case of the first report, before the first anniversary of the day on which the last Future Reserves 2020 report prepared before the coming into force of this section was presented to the Secretary of State, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in the case of subsequent reports, before the anniversary of the day on which the first report was laid before Parliament under subsection (6).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) On receiving a report under subsection (1), the Secretary of State must lay a copy of it before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The duties under this section may, instead of being performed by an association, be performed by a joint committee appointed under section 116 by two or more associations in relation to their combined areas.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Where by virtue of subsection (7) a joint committee has the duty to prepare a report&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) references in subsections (1) to (5) to an association are to be read as if they were to the joint committee, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) section 117(1)(a) (power to regulate manner in which functions are exercised) has effect as if the reference to associations were to the joint committee.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) In subsection (5)(a), &#8220;Future Reserves 2020 report&#8221; means a report prepared by the External Scrutiny Group on the Future Reserves 2020 programme.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>