<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Energy_(Bill30_VIII)</billtitle>
      <headertext>EIGHTH MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext> The amendments have been marshalled in accordance with the Instruction of 4th June 2013, as follows&#8212;</headertext>
      <headertext>Clauses 14 to 20 Clauses 43 to 46 Clause 38 Schedule 2 Clauses 39 to 41 Schedule 3 Clause 42 Clauses 52 to 55 Clauses 137 to 142 </headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 14</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROPER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD JENKIN OF RODING</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS LIDDELL OF COATDYKE</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD CAMERON OF DILLINGTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AB</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AB:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Regulations: backstop power purchase agreements</quote>
         <quote>(1) Regulations made under section 6 must include provision under which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) every eligible generator who is a party to a CFD may, in specified circumstances, by notice in writing require the Authority (or such other person on whom the regulations confer functions) to secure, within no later than one month after the notice is given, that an electricity supplier (or a person of such other description as may be specified) enter into a power purchase agreement on terms set out in, or determined in accordance with, the regulations (a &#8220;backstop PPA&#8221;); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for the duration of the backstop PPA, the strike price under that CFD (or under any other CFD entered into in connection with the backstop PPA) is set at a level specified in, or determined in accordance with, the regulations.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In determining the provision to be made under this section, the Secretary of State must have regard, in particular, to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the desirability of ensuring that every eligible generator who is a party to a CFD is able to borrow money commercially for its business purposes at reasonable cost and over a reasonable period (including borrowing which involves the lender taking an equity stake in the generator);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) accordingly, the need to ensure that the terms of every backstop PPA, and the level of the associated strike price, are such that every backstop PPA is demonstrably viable for the eligible generator.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Where, at the time a CFD is made, regulations make provision for any matter referred to in subsection (1), subsequent regulations may not alter that provision in relation to that CFD during its term.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State may exercise the powers conferred by Chapter 6 of this Part (modification of licence conditions) for the purpose of giving effect to provision made under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Secretary of State must keep under review the effectiveness of provision proposed or made under this section for achieving the objects set out in paragraphs (a) and (b) of subsection (2).</quote>
         <quote>(6) In this section, &#8220;specified&#8221; means specified in the regulations.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AC</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AC:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Alternative route to market</quote>
         <quote>(1) If at any time after the section (Regulations: backstop power purchase agreements) comes into force, the Secretary of State is not satisfied that provision made under that section will be effective, or (as the case may be) has been effective, to achieve the objects set out in paragraphs (a) and (b) of subsection (2) of that section, the Secretary of State must as soon as practicable exercise the powers conferred by Chapter 6 of this Part so as to establish an auction market (the &#8220;green power auction market&#8221;) in which eligible generators are entitled to offer, and other persons (including, in particular, electricity suppliers) are entitled to bid for, electricity generated from renewable sources.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State must exercise those powers, and take such other steps (including the exercise of any other power conferred by or under a provision of this Part) as the Secretary of State considers necessary, for the purpose of ensuring that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the green power auction market begins to operate as soon as reasonably practicable and does not cease to operate until expiry of the last CFD that has been made; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the reference price under a CFD entered into by a generator who is a party to an agreement made through the green power auction market is based on the price payable to the generator under that agreement.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 15</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD JENKIN OF RODING</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55ACA</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55ACA:</B> Clause 15, page 11, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) conferring on the Secretary of State further powers to require operators of generating stations which use woody biomass fuel to provide a fuel supply strategy for approval by Ministers.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 17</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WORTHINGTON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD GRANTCHESTER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD WHITTY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55ACB </Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55ACB	:</B> Clause 17, page 12, line 7, leave out subsection (4)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TEVERSON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS PARMINTER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AD</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AD:</B> Clause 17, page 12, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The powers of the Secretary of State under this section must be exercised with a view to ensuring that, within six months of commencement of this section, an order is in force making provision pursuant to subsections (1)(c) and (4)(a) and (c) for targets relating to the contribution to be made by generating stations located outside the United Kingdom to electricity supply in the United Kingdom.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 43</clausenumber>
   <proposer>VISCOUNT HANWORTH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AE</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AE:</B> Clause 43, page 26, line 40, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State must by regulations make provisions for ensuring that there is a route to market for independent electricity generators employing renewable power technologies.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 44</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS VERMA</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AF</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AF:</B> Clause 44, page 27, line 40,  leave out from &#8220;by&#8221; to end of line 2 on page 28 and insert &#8220;means of a power purchase agreement scheme.</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of this section and section (Power purchase agreement scheme: regulations)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a power purchase agreement scheme is a scheme established by supply licence conditions and regulations under section (Power purchase agreement scheme: regulations) for promoting the availability to electricity generators of power purchase agreements, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;power purchase agreement&#8221; means an arrangement under which a licensed supplier agrees to purchase electricity generated by an electricity generator.</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>For this purpose, &#8220;supply licence condition&#8221; means any condition, document or agreement of a kind mentioned in subsection (1).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Provision that may be made under subsection (1) in relation to a power purchase agreement scheme includes provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) as to the eligibility of an electricity generator to enter into a power purchase agreement under the scheme;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) as to the terms of any power purchase agreement to be entered into under the scheme, including provision&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) for determining the price at which electricity is to be purchased under the agreement;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) as to the duration of any such agreement;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(c) as to the circumstances in which a licensed supplier is or may be required or permitted to enter, or offer to enter, into a power purchase agreement under the scheme;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) for the provision of information in connection with the scheme.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Provision within subsection (4)(c) includes provision for determining which licensed supplier or suppliers is or are to be required or permitted to enter, or offer to enter, into a power purchase agreement with an electricity generator in any particular case.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Such provision may in particular include provision for the licensed supplier or suppliers in question to be determined&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) by a process involving a determination or determinations by one or more of the following&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the Secretary of State;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the Authority;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) the electricity generator;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) by auction or other competitive process;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and provision that may be made by virtue of paragraph  includes provision as to the circumstances in which a licensed supplier is or may be required or permitted to participate in an auction or other process.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) For the purposes of this section and section (Power purchase agreement scheme: regulations), &#8220;licensed supplier&#8221; means the holder of a licence under section 6(1)(d) of EA 1989.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>VISCOUNT HANWORTH</proposer>
   <clausetext>[Amendments 55AFA and 55AFB are amendments to Amendment 55AF]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AFA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AFA&#042;:</B> Clause 44, leave out lines 16 and 17 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) as to the eligibility of an electricity generator to enter the power purchase agreement scheme that establishes its entitlement to a power purchase agreement under the scheme for the duration of its CfD contract;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AFB&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AFB&#042;:</B> Clause 44, line 38, at beginning insert &#8220;by reference to current market prices or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 44</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS VERMA</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AG</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AG:</B> After Clause 44, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Power purchase agreement scheme: regulations</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by regulations make provision, in connection with any modifications made under section 44, for or in connection with a power purchase agreement scheme.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Any such regulations may in particular&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) make provision for apportioning amongst licensed suppliers, or any of them, all or any part of the value of any or all of the costs or benefits of any licensed supplier in connection with the scheme;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) confer functions on the Secretary of State or the Authority (which may include provision for directions to be given to the Authority by the Secretary of State);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) make provision for the delegation of functions conferred on the Secretary of State or the Authority by the regulations or by virtue of section 44;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) include provision for obligations imposed by the regulations on licensed suppliers to be enforceable by the Authority as if they were relevant requirements on a regulated person for the purposes of section 25 of EA 1989;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) make provision about the provision of information in connection with the scheme.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Provision that may be included in regulations under this section by virtue of subsection (2)(a) includes, in particular, provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) for requiring licensed suppliers to pay a levy to the Authority at specified times;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) specifying how such a levy is to be calculated;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) conferring an entitlement on a licensed supplier to receive a payment from the Authority.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Provision which may be included in regulations by virtue of subsection (3)includes provision for the Secretary of State or the Authority to determine what is to be taken into account as a cost or benefit of any licensed supplier in connection with the scheme and its value.</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) Regulations under this section may&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) include incidental, supplementary and consequential provision;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) make transitory or transitional provision or savings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) make different provision for different cases or circumstances or for different purposes;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) make provision subject to exceptions.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) Before making any regulations under this section, the Secretary of State must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) licensed suppliers,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Authority, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) such other persons as the Secretary of State considers it appropriate to consult.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) Subsection (6) may be satisified by consultation before, as well as by consultation after, the passing of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Regulations under this section must be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(9) An instrument containing regulations under this section is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AH</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AH:</B> After Clause 44, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Power purchase agreement scheme: disclosure of information</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 105 of the Utilities Act 2000 (general restrictions on disclosure of information)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) in subsection (1)(a), after &#8220;2010&#8221; insert &#8220;or section 44 or (Power purchase agreement scheme: regulations) of the Energy Act 2013&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in subsection (3)(a), after &#8220;2010&#8221; insert &#8220;, sections 44 to (Power purchase agreement scheme: regulations) of the Energy Act 2013&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AJ</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AJ:</B> After Clause 44, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Principal objective and general duties: power purchase agreement scheme</quote>
         <IndentOne>Sections 3A to 3D of EA 1989 (principal objective and general duties) apply in relation to functions of the Secretary of State or the Authority conferred by or by virtue of section  or (Power purchase agreement scheme: regulations), or section  so far as it relates to a power purchase agreement scheme, as they apply in relation to functions under Part 1 of that Act.&#8221;</IndentOne>4445</text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 46</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD STEPHEN</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WORTHINGTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AK</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AK:</B> Clause 46, page 28, line 23, at end insert &#8220;for the purposes of replacing the arrangements in effect under a renewables obligation order, and shall exercise their powers in a manner that is best calculated to replicate the effect of such arrangements on the accreditation status and renewable obligation certificate banding provision of, and value derived from renewable obligation certificates by, accredited generating stations&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>BARONESS WORTHINGTON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD GRANTCHESTER</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD WHITTY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AKA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AKA&#042;:</B> Clause 46, page 30, line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(p) provision made under subsection (2)(j) must be in place for 36 months following commencement of section 2 of this Act&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD WHITTY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AKB&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AKB&#042;:</B> Clause 46, page 33, line 43, leave out &#8220;&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8221;</quote>athe</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AKC&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AKC&#042;:</B> Clause 46, page 33, line 45, leave out &#8220;a&#8221; and insert &#8220;the&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD STEPHEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AL</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AL:</B> Clause 46, page 40, leave out lines 29 to 36</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 53</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS VERMA</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AM</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AM:</B> Clause 53, page 53, line 22, leave out &#8220;or (4)&#8221; and insert &#8220;, (4) or (6A)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 53</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CAMERON OF DILLINGTON</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD ROPER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55B:</B> After Clause 53, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Domestic microhydro power</quote>
         <quote>(1) Domestically based microhydro power shall be exempt from non-domestic rates.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of the section &#8220;domestically based microhydro power&#8221; is a single plant located within the curtelege of an owner or owner&#8217;s residential property with a plant capacity of up to and including 1250 kW.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 55</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TEVERSON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55C:</B> After Clause 55, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reduction of landfilling of organic waste</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must, as soon as reasonably practicable, set out a plan and timeframe for the reduction and eventual elimination of landfilling of organic waste in order to make it available for 100% renewable energy generation, and other appropriate uses consistent with the waste hierarchy as defined in the Waste (England and Wales) Regulations 2011.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD STEPHEN</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TEVERSON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55D:</B> After Clause 55, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Energy storage systems</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) set out a plan to support the development of storage systems for electricity that is generated from renewable sources,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) put in place pilot schemes to store renewable energy and reduce the problem associated with intermittency of supply,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) set targets in relation to the provision of renewable energy storage capacity, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) set out progress made on these issues in the form of a report, which must be laid before Parliament.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 140</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS VERMA</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56:</B> Clause 140, page 108, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) Part 1 (decarbonisation);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56A:</B> Clause 140, page 108, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Section (Fuel poverty) extends to England and Wales only.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 141</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS VERMA</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>57</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>57:</B> Clause 141, page 109, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Feed-in tariffs: increase in maximum capacity of plant) (feed-in tariffs: increase in maximum capacity of plant);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58:</B> Clause 141, page 109, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Fuel poverty) (fuel poverty);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>