<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Energy_(Bill30_V)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51B:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Long-term energy policy</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Energy Investment Advisory Board</quote>
         <quote>(1) There shall be body corporate known as the Energy Investment Advisory Board.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The role of the Board shall be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to take a panoramic and long-term view of the country&#8217;s energy needs and opportunities;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to provide Parliament and Ministers in the department responsible for energy with advice in implementing Government policy objectives for energy, that advice based on the continuity and experience of its members.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The remit of the Board would include all energy matters including generation, distribution, energy storage, inter-connectors, and new energy sources and include implementation of the reformed energy market and early recognition of unforeseen problems.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Board should report annually to Parliament and the minutes of its meeting should be published.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Board should comprise four or five expert members appointed for their experience in or knowledge of the energy industries with the relevant Permanent Secretary in attendance; they should serve for staggered terms of five or seven years; and the Secretary of State and Minister of State for Energy may attend meetings of the Board at their discretion.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51C:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Gas capacity</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Power to make gas capacity regulations</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by regulations make provision for the purpose of providing capacity to meet the demands of consumers for the supply of gas in Great Britain.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Regulations under this section are referred to in this Chapter as &#8220;gas capacity regulations&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (1) &#8220;providing capacity&#8221; means facilitating and promoting the provision and use of gas storage infrastructure to secure the availability of gas at prices which are lower and more stable insofar as is reasonably practicable and mitigating the consequences of gas supply interruption.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The provision that may be made in gas capacity regulations includes, but is not limited to, the provision described in this Chapter.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51D</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51D:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Enforcement and dispute resolution</quote>
         <quote>(1) Gas capacity regulations may make provision about the enforcement of any obligation or requirement imposed by the regulations.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Provision in gas capacity regulations about enforcement or the resolution of disputes may include provision conferring functions on any public body or any other person.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Provision made by virtue of this section may include provision&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) about powers to impose financial penalties;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for requirements under the gas capacity regulations to be enforceable by the Authority as if they were relevant requirements on a regulated person for the purposes of section 28 of the Gas Act 1986;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) about reference to arbitration;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) about appeals.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51E</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51E:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Licence modifications for the purposes connected with capacity regulations</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may, for any purpose related to provision that is made by this Chapter, or any purpose for which provision may be made under this Chapter, modify&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a condition of a particular licence under section 7 or 7A of the Gas Act 1986 (licenses for gas transporters, gas shippers and suppliers);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the standard conditions incorporated in licences under those provisions by virtue of section 8 of that Act;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a document maintained in accordance with the conditions of licences under those provisions, or an agreement that gives effect to a document so maintained.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) A modification under this section may in particular include a modification&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to provide for a new document to be prepared and maintained in accordance with the conditions of a licence; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to provide for an agreement to give effect to a document so maintained.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Provision included in a licence, or in a document or agreement relating to licences, by virtue of the modification power may in particular include provision of any kind that may be included in gas capacity regulations.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Before making a modification under this section, the Secretary of State must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the holder of any licence being modified,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Authority, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) such other persons as the Secretary of State considers it appropriate to consult.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Subsection (4) may be satisfied by consultation before, as well as by consultation after, the passing of this Act.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51F</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51F:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendment of enactments</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State may by regulations, for the purpose of or in connection with any provision made by or by virtue of this Chapter&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) amend section 172 of the Energy Act 2004 (annual report on security of energy supplies);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) amend section 28 of and Schedule 4B to the Gas Act 1986 (enforcement of obligations of regulated persons);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) make such provision amending, repealing or revoking any other enactment as the Secretary of State considers appropriate in consequence of provision made by or by virtue of this Chapter.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51G</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51G:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Principal objective and general duties</quote>
         <IndentOne>Sections 4AA to 4B of the Gas Act 1986 (principal objective and general duties) apply in relation to functions of the Authority conferred by or by virtue of this Chapter as they apply in relation to functions under Part 1 of that Act.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51H</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51H:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Regulations under Chapter 2</quote>
         <quote>(1) Regulations under this Chapter may&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) include incidental, supplementary and consequential provision;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) make transitory or transitional provision or savings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) make different provision for different cases or circumstances or for different purposes;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) make provision subject to exceptions.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Before making any regulations under this Chapter, the Secretary of State must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Authority,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any person who is a holder of a licence under section 7A of the Gas Act 1986 (licensing of gas suppliers and shippers),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) such other persons as the Secretary of State considers it appropriate to consult.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Subsection (2) may be satisfied by consultation before, as well as consultation after, the passing of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Regulations under this Chapter must be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(5) An instrument containing (whether alone or with other provision)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the first set of gas capacity regulations;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) regulations which make provision amending or repealing a provision of an enactment contained in primary legislation, may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before and approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) A statutory instrument to which subsection (5) does not apply and containing regulations under this Chapter is subject to annulment in pursuance of a resolution of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51J</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51J:</B> After Clause 136, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 6A</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Geothermal energy</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Licensing system</quote>
         <quote>(1) Within eighteen months of this Act coming into force, the Secretary of State shall, after a period of consultation with industry, geological experts, the devolved administrations, local authorities, energy producers and other interested parties, put into place for the United Kingdom a licensing system and supporting regulations for the exploitation of heat from deep geothermal sources for both direct use and for the generation of electricity.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The licences shall relate to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) individual, geographically delineated areas of land; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the heat held by rocks greater than 500 metres below the local surface level.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The licences shall confer exclusive exploration and production rights for the purpose of energy production to the licensee for that area, for a specific period of time for both direct heat and electricity generation.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State shall put in place regulations governing the allocation of licences and the conduct of holders of licences.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Secretary of State shall undertake the first round of allocations within six months of the licensing system being put in place.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Any organisation already in possession of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a water abstraction licence for the purpose of developing deep geothermal energy resources;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) planning permission for the development of deep geothermal energy resources,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>at the time the licensing regime comes into force, shall be entitled to preferential bidding rights to that licence area and any licence fee or other consideration for that licence area as a part of the licensing regime will then be determined by arbitration under rules determined by the Secretary of State reflecting the fees or other consideration paid for licences deemed to have similar potential.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) The holding of a licence for the exploration or exploitation (or both) of deep geothermal heat shall not convey any automatic rights to planning permission for surface development or surface access.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51JA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51JA&#042;:</B> Clause 47, page 46, line 27, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Section 47(1) does not apply to CCS plant until completion of the commissioning and proving period that shall last no longer than 3 years.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51JB&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51JB&#042;:</B> Clause 47, page 46, line 28, leave out &#8220;2044&#8221; and insert &#8220;2029&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51K</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51K:</B> Clause 47, page 47, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) for determining how the duty imposed by subsection (1) should apply to carbon dioxide emissions associated with the lifecycle of production and use of biomass fuels in all generating stations&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51L</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51L:</B> Schedule 4, page 125, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) conversion to biomass burning at the generating station is undertaken&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51M&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51M&#042;:</B> Schedule 4, page 125, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(iii) substantial pollution abatement equipment dealing with oxides of sulphur, oxides of nitrogen, heavy metal emissions or particles is fitted to the generating station&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51N</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51N:</B> Clause 5, page 5, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(f) to give priority to demand side management and demand reduction measures in preference to increased generating capacity whenever and wherever this is economically appropriate;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) to progressively increase the energy efficiency of the United Kingdom as measured in terms of quantity of energy used per unit of GDP&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>52</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>52:</B> Clause 5, page 5, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(f) the desirability of promoting effective competition between persons engaged in, or in commercial activities connected with, the generation, transmission, distribution or supply of electricity or the provision or use of electricity interconnectors, wherever appropriate.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>53</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>53:</B> After Clause 5, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Divestment of retail business</quote>
         <quote>(1) Any electricity generator which also supplies electricity to either domestic, commercial or industrial users shall, within two years of this Act coming into force, divest itself of its supplier business so that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an electricity generator shall have no financial interest in, or exercise any right over, a supplier of electricity or gas;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a supplier of electricity or gas shall have no financial interest in, or exercise any right over, an electricity generator;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) no person may hold a directorship of an electricity generator and a supplier of electricity or gas concurrently,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and any contracts entered into between any of the divesting parties shall cease to have effect when this section comes into effect.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Generators which have a direct contract to supply the majority of their output to a defined site through a private transmission scheme are exempt from this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>54</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>54:</B> Clause 33, page 20, line 3, after &#8220;to&#8221; insert &#8220;the respective&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55:</B> Clause 33, page 20, line 3, after &#8220;Authority&#8221; insert &#8220;and the Secretary of State&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55ZA</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55ZA:</B> Clause 37, leave out Clause 37 and insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Pilot schemes for electricity demand reduction</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) make arrangements&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) for the purpose of reducing demand for electricity; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) wholly or partly for the purpose of determining provision to be included in electricity capacity regulations; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) make arrangements for the purpose of piloting a measure (or measures) to secure a reduction in the demand for electricity.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Arrangements under this section may be paid for either by money provided by Parliament or by the means established for the provision of capacity agreements in sections 22 and 24.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55A:</B> Clause 9, page 7, line 29, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) Regulations must set the duration of support provided by CFDs to renewable technologies at a minimum of 25 years.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AA</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AA:</B> Clause 10, page 8, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Eligibility rules will not exclude electricity supplied from generating capacity located outside the United Kingdom.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AB</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AB:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Regulations: backstop power purchase agreements</quote>
         <quote>(1) Regulations made under section 6 must include provision under which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) every eligible generator who is a party to a CFD may, in specified circumstances, by notice in writing require the Authority (or such other person on whom the regulations confer functions) to secure, within no later than one month after the notice is given, that an electricity supplier (or a person of such other description as may be specified) enter into a power purchase agreement on terms set out in, or determined in accordance with, the regulations (a &#8220;backstop PPA&#8221;); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for the duration of the backstop PPA, the strike price under that CFD (or under any other CFD entered into in connection with the backstop PPA) is set at a level specified in, or determined in accordance with, the regulations.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In determining the provision to be made under this section, the Secretary of State must have regard, in particular, to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the desirability of ensuring that every eligible generator who is a party to a CFD is able to borrow money commercially for its business purposes at reasonable cost and over a reasonable period (including borrowing which involves the lender taking an equity stake in the generator);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) accordingly, the need to ensure that the terms of every backstop PPA, and the level of the associated strike price, are such that every backstop PPA is demonstrably viable for the eligible generator.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Where, at the time a CFD is made, regulations make provision for any matter referred to in subsection (1), subsequent regulations may not alter that provision in relation to that CFD during its term.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State may exercise the powers conferred by Chapter 6 of this Part (modification of licence conditions) for the purpose of giving effect to provision made under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Secretary of State must keep under review the effectiveness of provision proposed or made under this section for achieving the objects set out in paragraphs (a) and (b) of subsection (2).</quote>
         <quote>(6) In this section, &#8220;specified&#8221; means specified in the regulations.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AC</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AC:</B> After Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Alternative route to market</quote>
         <quote>(1) If at any time after the section (Regulations: backstop power purchase agreements) comes into force, the Secretary of State is not satisfied that provision made under that section will be effective, or (as the case may be) has been effective, to achieve the objects set out in paragraphs (a) and (b) of subsection (2) of that section, the Secretary of State must as soon as practicable exercise the powers conferred by Chapter 6 of this Part so as to establish an auction market (the &#8220;green power auction market&#8221;) in which eligible generators are entitled to offer, and other persons (including, in particular, electricity suppliers) are entitled to bid for, electricity generated from renewable sources.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State must exercise those powers, and take such other steps (including the exercise of any other power conferred by or under a provision of this Part) as the Secretary of State considers necessary, for the purpose of ensuring that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the green power auction market begins to operate as soon as reasonably practicable and does not cease to operate until expiry of the last CFD that has been made; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the reference price under a CFD entered into by a generator who is a party to an agreement made through the green power auction market is based on the price payable to the generator under that agreement.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55AD</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55AD:</B> Clause 17, page 12, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The powers of the Secretary of State under this section must be exercised with a view to ensuring that, within six months of commencement of this section, an order is in force making provision pursuant to subsections (1)(c) and (4)(a) and (c) for targets relating to the contribution to be made by generating stations located outside the United Kingdom to electricity supply in the United Kingdom.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55B</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55B:</B> After Clause 53, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Domestic microhydro power</quote>
         <quote>(1) Domestically based microhydro power shall be exempt from non-domestic rates.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of the section &#8220;domestically based microhydro power&#8221; is a single plant located within the curtelege of an owner or owner&#8217;s residential property with a plant capacity of up to and including 1250 kW.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55C</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55C:</B> After Clause 55, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reduction of landfilling of organic waste</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State must, as soon as reasonably practicable, set out a plan and timeframe for the reduction and eventual elimination of landfilling of organic waste in order to make it available for 100% renewable energy generation, and other appropriate uses consistent with the waste hierarchy as defined in the Waste (England and Wales) Regulations 2011.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56:</B> Clause 140, page 108, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) Part 1 (decarbonisation);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56A</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56A:</B> Clause 140, page 108, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Section (Fuel poverty) extends to England and Wales only.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>57</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>57:</B> Clause 141, page 109, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Feed-in tariffs: increase in maximum capacity of plant) (feed-in tariffs: increase in maximum capacity of plant);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58:</B> Clause 141, page 109, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) section (Fuel poverty) (fuel poverty);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>