<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Financial_Services_Banking_Reform_(Bill54_II)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>122</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>122:</B> Clause 30, page 42, line 9, leave out &#8220;38&#8221; and insert &#8220;(Publication)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>123</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>123:</B> Clause 30, page 42, line 18, after &#8220;to&#8221; insert &#8220;(Disclosure of information by Bank to Regulator) contain information and investigation powers and provision about the disclosure of information. </quote>
         <quote>( ) Sections 81 and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>124</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>124:</B> Schedule 4, page 134, line 1, after &#8220;imposing&#8221; insert &#8220;generally-imposed&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>125</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>125:</B> Schedule 4, page 134, line 1, leave out from &#8220;45&#8221; to end of line 2</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>126</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>126:</B> Schedule 4, page 135, line 32, at beginning insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(A1) For the purposes mentioned in sub-paragraph (A2) the FCA may make rules requiring participants in regulated payment systems to pay to the FCA specified amounts or amounts calculated in a specified way.</quote>
         <quote>(A2) The purposes are&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) meeting the relevant costs (see sub-paragraph (1)), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) enabling the Regulator to maintain adequate reserves.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>127</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>127:</B> Schedule 4, page 136, line 1, leave out sub-paragraph (2)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>128</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>128:</B> Schedule 4, page 136, line 4, leave out &#8220;(2)&#8221; and insert &#8220;(A1)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>129</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>129:</B> Schedule 4, page 136, line 16, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) But the requirements to carry out a cost benefit analysis under section 138I of FSMA 2000 do not apply in relation to rules made under this paragraph.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>130</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>130:</B> Schedule 4, page 136, line 19, leave out from &#8220;Treasury&#8221; to end of line 20 and insert &#8220;its penalty receipts after deducting its enforcement costs.</quote>
         <quote>(1A) The Regulator&#8217;s &#8220;penalty receipts&#8221; in respect of a financial year are any amounts received by it during the year by way of penalties imposed under section 63.</quote>
         <quote>(1B) The Regulator&#8217;s &#8220;enforcement costs&#8221; in respect of a financial year are the expenses incurred by it during the year in connection with&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the exercise, or consideration of the possible exercise, of any of its enforcement powers in particular cases, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the recovery of penalties imposed under section 63.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(1C) For the purposes of sub-paragraph (1B) the Regulator&#8217;s enforcement powers are&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) its powers under sections 62 to 65;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) its powers under any other enactment specified by the Treasury by order;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) its powers in relation to the investigation of relevant offences;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) its powers in England and Wales or Northern Ireland in relation to the prosecution of relevant offences.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(1D) In sub-paragraph (1C) &#8220;relevant offences&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) offences under this Part;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any other offences specified by the Treasury by order.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>131</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>131:</B> Schedule 4, page 136, line 24, leave out paragraphs (a) and (b) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) specify descriptions of expenditure that are, or are not, to be regarded as incurred in connection with either of the matters mentioned in sub-paragraph (1B),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) relate to the calculation and timing of the deduction in respect of the Regulator&#8217;s enforcement costs, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) specify the time when any payment is required to be made to the Treasury.</IndentOne>
         <quote>( ) The directions may also require the Regulator to provide the Treasury at specified times with specified information relating to&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) penalties that the Regulator has imposed under section 63, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Regulator&#8217;s enforcement costs.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>132</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>132:</B> Schedule 4, page 136, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;10A (1) The Regulator must prepare and operate a scheme (&#8220;the financial penalty scheme&#8221;) for ensuring that the amounts that, as a result of the deduction for which paragraph 10(1) provides, are retained by the Regulator in respect of amounts paid to it by way of penalties imposed under section 63 are applied for the benefit of participants in regulated payment systems.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The financial penalty scheme may, in particular, make different provision with respect to different classes of participant.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The financial penalty scheme must ensure that those who have become liable to pay a penalty to the Regulator in any financial year do not receive any benefit under the scheme in the following financial year.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Up-to-date details of the financial penalty scheme must be set out in a document (the &#8220;scheme details&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>10B (1) The scheme details must be published by the Regulator in the way appearing to it to be best calculated to bring them to the attention of the public.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Before making the financial penalty scheme, the Regulator must publish a draft of the proposed scheme in the way appearing to the Regulator to be best calculated to bring it to the attention of the public.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The draft must be accompanied by notice that representations about the proposals may be made to the Regulator within a specified time.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Before making the scheme, the Regulator must have regard to any representations made to it in accordance with sub-paragraph (3).</quote>
         <quote>(5) If the Regulator makes the proposed scheme, it must publish an account, in general terms, of&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the representations made to it in accordance with sub-paragraph (3), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) its response to them.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) If the scheme differs from the draft published under sub-paragraph (2) in a way which is, in the opinion of the Regulator, significant, the Regulator must (in addition to complying with sub-paragraph (5)) publish details of the difference.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The Regulator must, without delay, give the Treasury a copy of any scheme details published by it.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The Regulator may charge a reasonable fee for providing a person with a copy of&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a draft published under sub-paragraph (2);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) scheme details.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) Sub-paragraphs (2) to (6) and (8)(a) also apply to a proposal to alter or replace the financial penalty scheme.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133:</B> Schedule 4, page 137, line 17, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Freedom of information</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>13 In Part 6 of Schedule 1 to the Freedom of Information Act 2000 (public authorities to which Act applies), at the appropriate place insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;The Payment Systems Regulator established under section 31 of the Financial Services (Banking Reform) Act 2013.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <HeadingTwo>Equality</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>14 In Part 1 of Schedule 19 to the Equality Act 2010 (public authorities: general), under the heading &#8220;Industry, business, finance etc.&#8221;, at the appropriate place insert&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;The Payment Systems Regulator established under section 31 of the Financial Services (Banking Reform) Act 2013.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133A&#042;:</B> Clause 35, page 44, leave out lines 27 to 29</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133B&#042;:</B> Clause 35, page 44, line 27, leave out from &#8220;satisfied&#8221; to &#8220;have&#8221; in line 28 and insert &#8220;after due and proper examination and on the basis of compelling evidence that the design of the system is materially deficient such that it is likely to result in a significant disruption of the system that would&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133C&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133C&#042;:</B> Clause 35, page 44, line 29, leave out &#8220;or are likely to use,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133D&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133D&#042;:</B> Clause 35, page 44, line 30, leave out &#8220;In considering whether to&#8221; and insert &#8220;The Treasury may only&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133E&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133E&#042;:</B> Clause 35, page 44, line 31, leave out &#8220;the Treasury must have regard to&#8221; and insert &#8220;where it is satisfied on the basis of compelling evidence, after due and proper examination, that such action is necessary and proportionate after giving due and proper consideration to each of the following&#8212;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133F&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133F&#042;:</B> Clause 35, page 44, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(e) the good operation of the payment system within the preceding 12 months,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) whether any other less-intrusive regulatory alternative would be sufficient to address any perceived deficiency or potential deficiency in the design of the payment system,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) any adverse consequences likely to result from a designation order being made in respect of the payment system for users, the payment system provider, operator or any other affected party,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) the consistency of treatment of the payment system and other payment systems.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133G&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133G&#042;:</B> Clause 36, page 45, line 1, leave out &#8220;notify&#8221; and insert &#8220;consult&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133H&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133H&#042;:</B> Clause 36, page 45, line 7, leave out &#8220;or&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>133J&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>133J&#042;:</B> Clause 36, page 45, line 8, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(e) the operator of the system, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) any other representations made&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134:</B> After Clause 38, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Publication</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Treasury must publish any designation order.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If the Treasury amends a designation order, the Treasury must publish the amended order.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Treasury must publish any revocation of a designation order.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134A&#042;:</B> Clause 40, page 46, line 28, leave out &#8220;may&#8221; and insert &#8220;must&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134B&#042;:</B> Clause 40, page 47, line 9, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(o) the consistency of treatment of payment system operators; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(p) the impact of any past or proposed regulatory intervention&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134C&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134C&#042;:</B> Clause 41, page 47, line 18, at end insert &#8220;and the creation and sustaining of a regulatory environment that is conducive to innovation&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134D&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134D&#042;:</B> Clause 43, page 47, line 42, at end insert &#8220;while ensuring consistency and fairness in the treatment of all&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>134E&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>134E&#042;:</B> Clause 43, page 48, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(i) the need to target activities only at cases where action is needed and only on the basis of compelling evidence;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(j) the need to ensure accountability of the Payment Systems Regulator to owners, providers and users of payments systems;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(k) the need to uphold the principles of regulatory best practices;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(l) the promotion of principles of responsible self-regulation where appropriate;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(m) the desirability of facilitating innovation in payment systems,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>135</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>135:</B> Clause 44, page 48, line 15, leave out paragraph (b) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(b) in relation to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) all operators, or every operator of a regulated payment system of a specified description,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) all infrastructure providers, or every person who is an infrastructure provider in relation to a regulated payment system of a specified description, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) all payment service providers, or every person who is a payment service provider in relation to a regulated payment system of a specified description,&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>136</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>136:</B> Clause 44, page 48, line 20, after &#8220;(3)(a)&#8221; insert &#8220;or (b)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>137</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>137:</B> Clause 45, page 48, line 32, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) A requirement under this section that is imposed on&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) all operators of regulated payment systems, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) every operator of a regulated payment system of a specified description,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>is referred to in this Part as a &#8220;generally-imposed requirement&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138:</B> Clause 46, page 49, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) Before an order is made under subsection (3), the Payment Systems Regulator must consider any representations made by the payment service provider about the risks to which the payment service provider may be exposed as a result of the order.</quote>
         <quote>(3B) The Payment Systems Regulator may revoke an order made under subsection (3) if it is satisfied that compliance with the order would expose the payment service provider to risks which it is not reasonable for the payment service provider to bear.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138A&#042;:</B> Clause 48, page 49, line 36, after &#8220;by&#8221; insert &#8220;sections 47 and 48(1)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138B&#042;:</B> Clause 48, page 49, line 36, leave out &#8220;subsection (1)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138C&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138C&#042;:</B> Clause 48, page 49, line 36, after &#8220;only&#8221; insert &#8220;after a person&#8217;s interest in the operator of a regulated payment system has been referred by the Payments Systems Regulator to the Competition and Markets Authority and has resulted in a decision by the Competition and Markets Authority that such interest has resulted, or is likely to result, in a substantial lessening of competition&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>138D&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>138D&#042;:</B> Clause 48, page 49, line 36, leave out from &#8220;only&#8221; to &#8220;in&#8221; in line 38</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>139</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>139:</B> Clause 49, page 50, line 14, leave out &#8220;(&#8220;the concurrent functions&#8221;)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>140</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>140:</B> Clause 50, page 51, line 11, leave out &#8220;has the same meaning as in section 49&#8221; and insert &#8220;means the functions which by virtue of section 49 are concurrent functions of the Payment Systems Regulator and the CMA.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>141</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>141:</B> Clause 50, page 51, line 19, leave out &#8220;has the same meaning as in section 49&#8221; and insert &#8220;means the functions which by virtue of section 49 are concurrent functions of the Payment Systems Regulator and the CMA&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>142</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>142:</B> Clause 52, page 52, line 16, leave out &#8220;requirment on all operators of regulated payment systems)&#8221; and insert &#8220;generally-imposed requirement);&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>143</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>143:</B> Clause 66, page 57, leave out line 22 and insert &#8220;generally-imposed requirement),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>144</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>144:</B> Schedule 5, page 145, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;&#8220;appellant&#8221; has the meaning given by paragraph 3(4);&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>145</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>145:</B> Clause 71, page 60, line 38, leave out subsections (4) to (9)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>146</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>146:</B> Clause 72, page 61, line 23, leave out &#8220;(&#8220;the relevant participant&#8221;)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>147</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>147:</B> Clause 72, page 61, line 24, after &#8220;to&#8221; insert &#8220;the person&#8217;s participation in&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>148</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>148:</B> Clause 72, page 61, line 27, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;The person whose participation in the payment system is to be the subject of the report is referred to in this section as &#8220;the relevant participant&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>149</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>149:</B> After Clause 80, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Restrictions on disclosure of confidential information</quote>
         <quote>(1) Confidential information must not be disclosed by a primary recipient, or by any person obtaining the information directly or indirectly from a primary recipient, without the consent of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the person from whom the primary recipient obtained the information, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if different, the person to whom it relates.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In this section &#8220;confidential information&#8221; means information which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) relates to the business or other affairs of any person,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) was received by the primary recipient for the purposes of, or in the discharge of, any functions of the Payment Systems Regulator under this Part, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is not prevented from being confidential information by subsection (4).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) It is immaterial for the purposes of subsection (2) whether or not the information was received&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) as a result of a requirement to provide it imposed by or under any enactment;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for other purposes as well as purposes mentioned in that subsection.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Information is not confidential information if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) it has been made available to the public by virtue of being disclosed in any circumstances in which, or for any purposes for which, disclosure is not precluded by this section, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) it is in the form of a summary or a collection of information that is framed in such a way that it is not possible to ascertain from it information relating to any particular person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Each of the following is a primary recipient for the purposes of this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Payment Systems Regulator;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the FCA;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a person who is or has been employed by the Payment Systems Regulator or the FCA;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) a person who is or has been engaged to provide services to the Payment Systems Regulator or the FCA;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) any auditor or expert instructed by the Payment Systems Regulator or the FCA;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) a person appointed to make a report under section 72;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) a person appointed under section 73.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) Nothing in this section applies to information received by a primary recipient for the purposes of, or in the discharge of, any functions of the Payment Systems Regulator under the Competition Act 1998 or the Enterprise Act 2002 by virtue of section 49 or 51. </quote>
         <IndentOne>(For provision about the disclosure of such information, see Part 9 of the Enterprise Act 2002.)&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>150</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>150:</B> After Clause 80, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Exemptions from section (Restrictions on disclosure of confidential information)</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section (Restrictions on disclosure of confidential information) does not prevent a disclosure of confidential information which&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is made for the purpose of facilitating the carrying out of a public function, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is permitted by regulations made by the Treasury under this section.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of this section &#8220;public functions&#8221; includes&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) functions conferred by or in accordance with any provision contained in any enactment;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) functions conferred by or in accordance with any provision contained in the EU Treaties or any EU instrument;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) similar functions conferred on persons by or under provisions having effect as part of the law of a country or territory outside the United Kingdom;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) functions exercisable in relation to specified disciplinary proceedings.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Regulations under this section may, in particular, make provision permitting the disclosure of confidential information or of confidential information of a specified kind&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) by specified recipients, or recipients of a specified description, to any person for the purpose of enabling or assisting the recipient to discharge specified public functions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) by specified recipients, or recipients of a specified description, to specified persons, or persons of specified descriptions, for the purpose of enabling or assisting those persons to discharge specified public functions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) by the Payment Systems Regulator to the Treasury for any purpose;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) by any recipient if the disclosure is with a view to or in connection with specified proceedings.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Regulations under this section may also include provision&#8212; In relation to confidential information, each of the following is a &#8220;recipient&#8221;&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) making any permission to disclose confidential information subject to conditions (which may relate to the obtaining of consents or any other matter);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) restricting the uses to which confidential information disclosed under the regulations may be put.</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) a primary recipient;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a person obtaining the information directly or indirectly from a primary recipient.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;confidential information&#8221; and &#8220;primary recipient&#8221; have the same meaning as in section (Restrictions on disclosure of confidential information);</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;specified&#8221; means specified in regulations.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>151</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>151:</B> After Clause 80, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Offences relating to disclosure of confidential information</quote>
         <quote>(1) A person who discloses information in contravention of section (Restrictions on disclosure of confidential information) is guilty of an offence.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A person guilty of an offence under subsection (1) is liable&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) on summary conviction&#8212; </IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) in England and Wales, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 3 months or a fine, or both;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) in Scotland, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 12 months or a fine not exceeding the statutory maximum, or both;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) in Northern Ireland, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 3 months or a fine not exceeding the statutory maximum, or both;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) on conviction on indictment, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 2 years or a fine, or both.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) A person is guilty of an offence if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) information has been disclosed to the person in accordance with regulations made under section (Exemptions from section (Restrictions on disclosure of confidential information)), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the person uses the information in contravention of any provision of those regulations.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A person guilty of an offence under subsection (3) is liable on summary conviction&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in England and Wales, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 51 weeks (or 3 months, if the offence was committed before the commencement of section 280(2) of the Criminal Justice Act 2003) or a fine, or both;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in Scotland, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 3 months or a fine not exceeding level 5 on the standard scale, or both;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in Northern Ireland, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 3 months or a fine not exceeding level 5 on the standard scale, or both.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In proceedings against a person (&#8220;P&#8221;) for an offence under this section it is a defence for P to prove&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) that P did not know and had no reason to suspect that the information was confidential information;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) that P took all reasonable precautions and exercised all due diligence to avoid committing the offence.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In this section &#8220;confidential information&#8221; has the same meaning as in section (Restrictions on disclosure of confidential information).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>152</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>152:</B> After Clause 80, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Information received from Bank of England</quote>
         <quote>(1) The following are regulators for the purposes of this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Payment Systems Regulator;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the FCA.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) A regulator must not disclose to any person specially protected information.</quote>
         <quote>(3) &#8220;Specially protected information&#8221; is information in relation to which the first and second conditions are met.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The first condition is that the regulator received the information from&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Bank of England (&#8220;the Bank&#8221;), or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the other regulator where that regulator had received the information from the Bank.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The second condition is that the Bank notified the regulator to which it disclosed the information that the Bank held the information for the purpose of its functions with respect to any of the following&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) monetary policy;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) financial operations intended to support financial institutions for the purposes of maintaining stability;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the provision of private banking services and related services.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The notification referred to in subsection (5) must be&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in writing, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) given before, or at the same time as, the Bank discloses the information.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) The prohibition in subsection (2) does not apply&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to disclosure by one regulator to the other regulator where the regulator making the disclosure informs the other regulator that the information is specially protected information by virtue of this section;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the Bank has consented to disclosure of the information;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) to information which has been made available to the public by virtue of being disclosed in any circumstances in which, or for any purposes for which, disclosure is not precluded by this section;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) to information which the regulator is required to disclose in pursuance of any EU obligation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) In this section references to disclosure by or to a regulator or by the Bank include references to disclosure by or to any of the following&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) persons who are, or are acting as, officers of, or members of the staff of, the regulator;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) persons who are, or are acting as, officers, employees or agents of the Bank;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) auditors, experts, contractors or investigators appointed by the regulator or the Bank under powers conferred by this Part or otherwise.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) References to disclosure by a regulator do not include references to disclosure between persons who fall within subsection (8)(a) or (b) in relation to that regulator.</quote>
         <quote>(10) Each regulator must take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to prevent the disclosure of specially protected information, in cases not excluded by subsection (7), by those who are or have been&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) its officers or members of staff (including persons acting as its officers or members of staff);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) auditors, experts, contractors or investigators appointed by the regulator under powers conferred by this Part or otherwise;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) persons to whom the regulator has delegated any of its functions.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>153</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>153:</B> After Clause 80, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Disclosure of information by Bank to Regulator</quote>
         <quote>(none) In section 246 of the Banking Act 2009 (information), in subsection (2), after paragraph (c) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(ca) the Payment Systems Regulator (established under section 31 of the Financial Services (Banking Reform) Act 2013);&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>154</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>154:</B> Clause 87, page 72, line 33, after &#8220;system,&#8221; insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) threaten the continuity of core services provided in the United Kingdom,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>155</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>155:</B> Clause 87, page 73, line 7, after &#8220;section&#8221; insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;core services&#8221; has the same meaning as in FSMA 2000 (see section 142C of that Act), and&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>156</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>156:</B> Clause 89, page 73, line 35, after &#8220;direction&#8221; insert &#8220;under section 44&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>157</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>157:</B> Clause 89, page 73, line 36, after &#8220;a&#8221; insert &#8220;generally-imposed&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>158</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>158:</B> Clause 89, page 73, line 36, leave out from &#8220;45&#8221; to end of line 37</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>159</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>159:</B> Clause 92, page 77, line 8, leave out &#8220;requirements imposed&#8221; and insert &#8220;generally-imposed requirements&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>160</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>160:</B> Clause 92, page 77, line 8, leave out from &#8220;45&#8221; to end of line 9</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>161</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>161:</B> Clause 95, page 77, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;CAT-appealable decision&#8221; has the meaning given by section 66(4);</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;CMA-appealable decision&#8221; has the meaning given by section 66(7);&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>162</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>162:</B> Clause 95, page 78, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;&#8220;generally-imposed requirement&#8221; has the meaning given by section 45(3);&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>163</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>163:</B> Clause 104, page 83, line 30, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(f) staff.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>164</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>164:</B> After Clause 113, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Review of the effects of the exemption of certain business and financial contracts from the Gaming Acts</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Treasury must institute a review of the effects of certain business and financial gaming contracts having been made enforceable at law by the repeal of certain provisions of the Gaming Acts pursuant to the Financial Services Act 1986 (as amended).</quote>
         <quote>(2) &#8220;Effects&#8221; shall include the national social, cultural and ethical effects as well as the commercial and economic effects.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Treasury shall appoint one or more persons to undertake the review after consultation with the Bank of England, the PRA and the FCA and such others as it shall decide on such terms as it thinks fit.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The review shall culminate in a report to the Treasury within two and a half years of the coming into force of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Treasury must lay the report before Parliament and thereafter publish the same.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>165</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>165:</B> Before Clause 114, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty of care</quote>
         <IndentOne>At all times when carrying out core activities, a ring-fenced body shall&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) be subject to a fiduciary duty towards its customers in the operation of core services; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) be subject to a duty of care towards its customers across the financial services sector.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>166</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>166:</B> Schedule 8, page 157, leave out lines 11 to 14</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>167</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>167:</B> Schedule 8, page 157, line 26, leave out &#8220;financial sector activities&#8221; and insert &#8220;the provision of financial services&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>168</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>168:</B> Schedule 8, page 158, line 7, leave out from beginning to &#8220;and&#8221; in line 8 and insert &#8220;the acquisition or provision in the United Kingdom of financial services,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>169</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>169:</B> Schedule 8, page 158, line 23, leave out &#8220;financial sector activities&#8221; and insert &#8220;the provision of financial services&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>170</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>170:</B> Schedule 8, page 160, line 24, at end insert&#8212;</quote>&#8220;<quote> In section 348 of FSMA 2000 (restrictions on disclosure of confidential information by FCA, PRA etc), after subsection (6) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) Nothing in this section applies to information received by a primary recipient for the purposes of, or in the discharge of, any functions of the FCA under the Competition Act 1998 or the Enterprise Act 2002 by virtue of Part 16A of this Act.</quote>
         <IndentOne>(For provision about the disclosure of such information, see Part 9 of the Enterprise Act 2002.)&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>171</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>171:</B> Schedule 8, page 160, line 42, at end insert &#8220;; but this sub-paragraph is not to be regarded as limiting the effect of the definition of &#8220;functions&#8221; in paragraph 1.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>172</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>172:</B> After Clause 116, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Arrangements for consulting practitioners and consumers</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 2L of FSMA 2000 (the PRA&#8217;s general duty to consult) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;2LA PRA duty to consider representations from the FCA Consumer Panel</quote>
         <quote>(1) The PRA must consider and respond to representations made by the Consumer Panel established by the FCA under section 1Q of the Financial Services Act 2012.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The PRA must from time to time publish in such manner as it thinks fit responses to the representations.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>173</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>173:</B> Clause 117, page 92, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) In section 3A of FSMA 2000 (meaning of &#8220;regulator&#8221;), in subsection (3)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) omit the &#8220;or&#8221; at the end of paragraph (a), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after paragraph (b) insert &#8220;or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the meaning of &#8220;regulator&#8221; in sections 410A and 410B (fees to meet certain expenses of Treasury).&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>174</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>174:</B> Clause 118, page 92, line 21, leave out from &#8220;(e)&#8221;,&#8221; to end of line 22</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>175</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>175:</B> Before Clause 119, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Leverage ratio</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Treasury must make an order under section 9L of the Bank of England Act 1998 (macro-prudential measures) enabling the Financial Policy Committee to give a direction under section 9H in respect of a leverage ratio for relevant authorised persons.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The direction above may specify the leverage ratio to be used.</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of this section &#8220;leverage ratio&#8221; has the meaning which the Financial Policy Committee considers that it has in European Union Law or procedure from time to time.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The order under subsection (1) must be made within the period of 6 months beginning with the day on which this Act is passed.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In this section, &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221; has the meaning given in section 71A of FSMA 2000.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>176</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>176:</B> After Clause 119, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Other provisions about the FCA and the PRA</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Abolition of strategic objective of the FCA</quote>
         <IndentOne>In FSMA 2000&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) In section 1B, omit&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) in subsection (1), paragraph (a) (and the &#8220;and&#8221; following it)</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>and, in paragraph (b), &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) subsection (2),</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) in subsection (3), &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) omit section 1F,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in subsection (1K), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) omit section 3B(3),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) omit section 3D(4),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) in section 55B(4), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) in section 55H(4), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) in section 55I(5), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(i) in section 55J(1)(c), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(j) in section 55L(6), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(k) in section 55T, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(l) in section 88E, in subsection (1) and in the heading, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(m) in section 89U, in subsection (1) and in the heading, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(n) in section 137A(1), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(o) in section 138A(5), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(p) in section 192C(2), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(q) in section 194(1)(c), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(r) in section 232A, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(s) in section 314(1), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(t) in section 316(1A)(a), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(u) in section 318(3A)(a), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(v) in section 340(8), for the words after &#8220;expedient&#8221; substitute &#8220;for the purpose of advancing any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(w) in section 395(3), for the words after &#8220;procedure and&#8221; substitute &#8220;the regulator considers that, in the particular case, it is necessary in order to advance any of its objectives.&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(x) in paragraph 11(1)(b) of Schedule 1ZA, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(y) in paragraphs 6 and 6B of Schedule 1A, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(z) in paragraphs 3C(1) and 3D(1) of Schedule 6, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>177</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>177:</B> After Clause 119, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Independent Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee of the FCA</quote>
         <quote>(1) After section 1L of FSMA 2000 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;1LA Independent Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee</quote>
         <quote>(1) There is to be a Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee of the FCA (&#8220;the Committee&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The members of the Committee are to be appointed jointly by the FCA and the PRA and hold office in accordance with the terms of their appointment.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The person appointed to chair the Committee must have experience of acting in a senior judicial capacity.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A majority of the members of the Committee must be persons appearing to the FCA and the PRA to have (and to have had) no professional connection with the provision of financial services.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The remaining members of the Committee must include persons appearing to the FCA and the PRA to have extensive experience in senior roles in banking.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The function of the Committee is to exercise the banking regulatory decisions function of the FCA and the PRA.</quote>
         <quote>(7) &#8220;Banking regulatory decisions function&#8221; means the function of taking decisions for enforcing compliance with relevant requirements, within the meaning of Part 14, in cases where the authorised person is a relevant authorised person within the meaning of section 71A of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The banking regulatory decisions function of the FCA and the PRA is delegated to the Committee; and references in this Act to the FCA and the PRA in relation to that function are to be construed accordingly.</quote>
         <quote>(9) The FCA shall meet the reasonable costs of the Committee in discharging its function but the Committee&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is not subject to direction by the FCA or the PRA as to the exercise of its function,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is not accountable to the FCA or the PRA for the exercise of its function, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) may appoint its own officers and staff.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) At least once a year the Committee must make a report to the Treasury on the discharge of its function.</quote>
         <quote>(11) The Treasury must lay before Parliament a copy of each report received by them under subsection (10).&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) The FCA and the PRA must carry out a review of the operation of the Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee of the FCA.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The review must be completed before the end of 2018.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The FCA and the PRA must give the Treasury a report of the review.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The report must include an assessment of whether the function of the Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee would be better discharged by a body that was entirely independent of the FCA and the PRA.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament and publish it in such manner as they think fit.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>178</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>178:</B> After Clause 120, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Unfair relationships</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Unfair relationships</quote>
         <IndentOne>Before a regulated consumer credit agreement, other than an excluded agreement, is made, the creditor shall advise the borrower in writing of his or her rights as a borrower under sections 140A and 140B of the Consumer Credit Act 1974.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>179</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>179:</B> After Clause 120, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Continuous Payment Authorities</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Continuous Payment Authorities: debtor&#8217;s rights</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where a debtor has granted to a creditor a continuous payment authority for payment of any debt arising under a regulated agreement.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Prior to granting the continuous payment authority, a creditor must give the debtor a statement of the debtor&#8217;s rights in relation to the continuous payment authority.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A debtor may at any time cancel or vary a continuous payment authority.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A cancellation or variation of a continuous payment authority must be signed by the debtor and bear the date of the signature.</quote>
         <quote>(5) A bank is obliged to comply with immediate effect to a cancellation or variation of a continuous payment authority signed by the debtor.</quote>
         <quote>(6) A debtor must inform the creditor within 24 hours of signing the cancellation or variation that the continuous payment authority has been cancelled or varied.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In this section &#8220;continuous payment authority&#8221; means an instruction or mandate given by a debtor to a bank to pay a fixed or variable sum to a creditor.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>180</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>180:</B> After Clause 120, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Miscellaneous</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Meetings between regulators and auditors of relevant authorised persons</quote>
         <quote>(1) The FCA and the PRA must make arrangements to meet the auditors of each relevant authorised person at least twice in each calendar year.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The FCA and the PRA may conduct meetings under subsection (1) jointly or separately (but each relevant authorised person&#8217;s auditors must be met separately).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The purpose of each meeting is to discuss matters about which the FCA or the PRA believe that the auditors may have views or information.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A relevant authorised person has a duty to ensure that its auditors attend meetings in accordance with this section (and compliance with that duty may be considered for purposes of the exercise of functions under FSMA 2000).</quote>
         <quote>(5) In this section, &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221; has the meaning given in section 71A of FSMA 2000.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>181</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>181:</B> After Clause 120, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Proprietary trading</quote>
         <quote>(1) The PRA and the FCA must carry out a review of proprietary trading by relevant authorised persons.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The review must be completed before the end of the period of 3 years beginning with the day on which this Act is passed.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The PRA and the FCA must give the Treasury a report of the review.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The report must include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an analysis of any action taken by the PRA and the FCA to monitor whether and to what extent relevant authorised persons engage in proprietary trading and any action taken by the PRA or the FCA to discourage relevant authorised persons from doing so;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an account of any difficulties encountered by the PRA or the FCA in taking that action and an assessment of its efficacy;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) an account of any requirement imposed on relevant authorised persons which the PRA or the FCA consider may be engaging in proprietary trading to publish a statement of the exposure to risk of relevant authorised persons in their trading operations and of the controls applied to limit that risk;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) an assessment of the impact of the ring-fencing rules on proprietary trading by relevant authorised persons;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) an assessment, drawing on experience in countries other than the United Kingdom, of the feasibility of prohibiting relevant authorised persons from engaging in proprietary trading or limiting the extent to which, or circumstances in which, they may do so (having regard, in particular, to any difficulties of definition); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) a comprehensive analysis of the advantages and disadvantages of prohibiting relevant authorised persons from engaging in proprietary trading or limiting the extent to which, or circumstances in which, they may do so.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The PRA and the FCA must publish the report in such manner as they think fit.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The Treasury must, following receipt of the report, make arrangements for the carrying out of an independent review to consider the case for the taking of action in relation to proprietary trading by relevant authorised persons.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The appointment by the Treasury of persons to carry out the review requires the consent of the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons.</quote>
         <quote>(9) The reference in subsection (8) to the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the name of that Committee is changed, is to be treated as a reference to that Committee by its new name, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the functions of that Committee (or substantially corresponding functions) become functions of a different Committee of the House of Commons, is to be treated as a reference to the Committee by which the functions are exercisable;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) The persons appointed to carry out the review must give the Treasury a report of the review once it has been concluded.</quote>
         <quote>(11) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament and publish it in such manner as it thinks fit.</quote>
         <quote>(12) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;proprietary trading&#8221;, in relation to a relevant authorised person, means trading with funds on markets on the relevant authorised person&#8217;s own account (whether or not in connection with business with the relevant authorised person&#8217;s customers),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;ring-fencing rules&#8221; has the meaning given by section 417 of FSMA 2000,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221; has the meaning given by section 71A of FSMA 2000.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>182</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>182:</B> After Clause 120, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Remuneration code</quote>
         <quote>(1) The FCA and the PRA must prepare (and may from time to time revise) a remuneration code.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The remuneration code is to apply to all persons who have approval under section 59 of FSMA 2000 to perform a function in relation to the carrying on by a relevant authorised person of a regulated activity which is designated under subsection (6B) or (6C) of that section as a senior management function.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The remuneration code must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) require that persons to whom the remuneration code applies are, except in specified circumstances, to receive a proportion of their remuneration in the form of variable remuneration,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) require that a specified measure of profits is to be used in calculating any variable remuneration which is calculated by reference to profits,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) require that the nature and amount of variable remuneration is to strike an appropriate balance between risk to the relevant authorised person providing it and fair reward for the recipient of it,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) require a proportion of variable remuneration to be deferred for such period, not exceeding 10 years, as is appropriate to strike a balance between risk to the relevant authorised person providing it and fair reward for the recipient of it,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) require that no, or only a limited amount of, variable remuneration of a person to whom the remuneration code applies is to be calculated by reference to sales made by the person or by any group of persons employed by the relevant authorised person providing it, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) require that non-executive directors of a relevant authorised person are not to receive variable remuneration.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A requirement imposed by the remuneration code is a relevant requirement for the purposes of Part 14 of FSMA 2000.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221; has the meaning given by section 71A of FSMA 2000,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;variable remuneration&#8221; means remuneration (whether in money or in securities or any other form of money&#8217;s worth) the amount or value of which varies in accordance with profits, sales or other matters.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>183</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>183:</B> After Clause 120, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Powers of regulator where relevant authorised person receiving State support</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) all or part of the business of a relevant authorised person has been transferred to a bridge bank under section 12 of the Banking Act 2009,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a relevant authorised person has been taken into public ownership under section 13 of that Act, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the Treasury has acquired shares or other securities in a relevant authorised person or has provided a guarantee in respect of the liabilities of a relevant authorised person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The appropriate regulator may make an order under subsection (3).</quote>
         <quote>(3) An order under this subsection may do all or any of the following&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) cancel any entitlement to deferred remuneration payable (but not yet paid) to persons covered by the Licensing Regime who are employed by the relevant authorised person,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) remove any entitlement of such persons to payments for loss of office or payments on a change in control of the relevant authorised person, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) remove rights to pension benefits to or in respect of such persons which have not yet become payable.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In this section &#8220;the appropriate regulator&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the bank is a PRA-authorised person (within the meaning of FSMA 2000), the PRA, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) otherwise, the FCA.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section, &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221; has the meaning given by section 71A of FSMA 2000.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>184</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>184:</B> After Clause 120, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Special measures</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where the FCA or the PRA&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) has reason to believe that a relevant authorised person&#8217;s systems or professional standards or culture do not provide sufficient safeguards against the commission of actions in respect of which the FCA or the PRA has power to take action, but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) do not have reason to believe that any such action has been committed (ignoring any action which is already being investigated or in respect of which action has been or is being taken).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The FCA or the PRA may give notice to the relevant authorised person of the belief mentioned in subsection (1)(a).</quote>
         <quote>(3) If the FCA or the PRA gives notice under subsection (2), it must invite the relevant authorised person to make representations showing that sufficient safeguards are in place.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Following the giving of a notice under subsection (2) and the receipt of representations under subsection (3) (if any are made), the FCA or the PRA may commission an independent investigation into the relevant authorised person&#8217;s systems and professional standards and culture with a view to establishing whether sufficient safeguards are in place; and for that purpose&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;independent&#8221; means independent of the FCA, the PRA and the relevant authorised person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an investigation may not be commissioned from a person involved in the auditing of companies.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The relevant authorised person must cooperate with the investigation.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Following receipt of the report of the investigation under subsection (4), the FCA or the PRA may by notice require the relevant authorised person to take measures to provide sufficient safeguards and to monitor their effectiveness.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The relevant authorised person must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) comply with the notice, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) appoint an appropriately senior member of the relevant authorised person&#8217;s staff to oversee compliance.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) Compliance by a relevant authorised person with a duty under this section may be considered for the purposes of the exercise by the FCA or the PRA of functions under FSMA 2000.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In this section, &#8220;relevant authorised person&#8221; has the meaning given by section 71A of FSMA 2000.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>185</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>185:</B> Before Clause 121, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Power to impose penalties on persons providing claims management services</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Schedule to the Compensation Act 2006 (claims management regulations) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In paragraph 8 (rules about conduct of authorised persons), in sub-paragraph (2)(b), after sub-paragraph (i) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(ia) provision enabling the Regulator to require an authorised person to pay a penalty;&#8221;.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(3) In paragraph 9 (codes of practice about conduct of authorised persons), in sub-paragraph (2)(b), after sub-paragraph (i) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(ia) enable the Regulator to require an authorised person to pay a penalty;&#8221;.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(4) In paragraph 10 (complaints about conduct of authorised persons), after sub-paragraph (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) Regulations under sub-paragraph (1) may enable the Regulator to require an authorised person to pay a penalty.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(5) In paragraph 11 (requirement to have indemnity insurance), in sub-paragraph (2)(b), after &#8220;Regulator&#8221; insert &#8220;to require the payment of a penalty by an authorised person or&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(6) In paragraph 14 (enforcement), in sub-paragraph (4), for the words from &#8220;impose&#8221; to &#8220;authorisation&#8221; substitute &#8220;require an authorised person to pay a penalty, or to impose conditions on, suspend or cancel a person&#8217;s authorisation,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(7) After paragraph 15 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Penalties: supplementary provision</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>16 (1) This paragraph applies in any case where regulations include provision enabling the Regulator to require an authorised person to pay a penalty.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The regulations&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall include provision about how the Regulator is to determine the amount of a penalty, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may, in particular, include provision specifying a minimum or maximum amount.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The regulations&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall provide for income from penalties imposed by the Regulator to be paid into the Consolidated Fund, but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may provide that such income is to be paid into the Consolidated Fund after the deduction of costs incurred by the Regulator in collecting, or enforcing the payment of, such penalties.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The regulations may also include, in particular&#8212; </quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) provision for a penalty imposed by the Regulator to be enforced as a debt;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provision specifying conditions that must be met before any action to enforce a penalty may be taken.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) In section 13 of the Compensation Act 2006 (appeals and references to Tribunal)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in subsection (1), omit the &#8220;or&#8221; at the end of paragraph (d) and after paragraph (e) insert &#8220;, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) imposes a penalty on the person.&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after subsection (1) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) A person who is appealing to the Tribunal against a decision to impose a penalty may appeal against&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the imposition of the penalty,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the amount of the penalty, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any date by which the penalty, or any part of it, is required to be paid.&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in subsection (3), after paragraph (d) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(da) may require a person to pay a penalty (which may be of a different amount from that of any penalty imposed by the Regulator);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(db) may vary any date by which a penalty, or any part of a penalty, is required to be paid;&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>185A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>185A&#042;:</B> Before Clause 121, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendments to the Legal Services Act 2007</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 173 of the Legal Services Act 2007 (the levy) is amended as follows in relation to the leviable Office of Legal Complaints expenditure.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (7)(a) at the end insert &#8220;except for the purposes of section 161 (in relation to claims management services) which is to be deducted from its expenditure incurred under or for the purposes of the Act (this paragraph, as with the amounts paid into the Consolidated Fund pursuant to paragraph (b)), and&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (7)(b) at the end insert &#8220;except for charges made under section 136 pursuant to section 161 (charges payable in relation to a complaint)&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) After section 161 (extension of Part 6 to claims management services) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;161A Funding for complaints about claims management services</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Lord Chancellor may by order make provision for the arrangements for funding for complaints about claims management services and may by order specify persons who can make charges whether or not they are the designated regulator and person who must pay charges.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>186</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>186:</B> Before Clause 122, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Orders and regulations: general</quote>
         <quote>(1) Any power of the Treasury or the Secretary of State to make an order or regulations under this Act is exercisable by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Subsection (1) does not apply to an order under section 34 (payment systems: designation orders).</quote>
         <quote>(3) An order or regulations made by the Treasury or Secretary of State under this Act may&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) make different provision for different cases, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) contain such incidental or transitional provision as the Treasury or Secretary of State considers appropriate.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>187</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>187:</B> Clause 122, page 94, line 9, leave out subsection (1)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>188</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>188:</B> Clause 124, page 95, line 7, after &#8220;Treasury&#8221; insert &#8220;or Secretary of State&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>189</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>189:</B> Clause 124, page 95, line 9, leave out &#8220;they consider&#8221; and insert &#8220;the Treasury or Secretary of State considers&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>190</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>190:</B> Clause 124, page 95, line 13, leave out paragraph (b)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>191</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>191:</B> Clause 125, page 95, line 18, after &#8220;Treasury&#8221; insert &#8220;or Secretary of State&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>192</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>192:</B> Clause 125, page 95, line 18, leave out &#8220;they consider&#8221; and insert &#8220;the Treasury or Secretary of State considers&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>193</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>193:</B> Clause 126, page 95, line 28, after &#8220;Britain)&#8221; insert &#8220;and section (Power to impose penalties on persons providing claims management services) (power to impose penalties on persons providing claims management services)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>193A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>193A&#042;:</B> Clause 126, page 95, line 28, after &#8220;Britain)&#8221; insert &#8220;and section (Amendments to the Legal Services Act 2007) (Amendments to the Legal Services Act 2007)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>194</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>194:</B> Clause 127, page 95, line 33, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Section (Power to impose penalties on persons providing claims management services) comes into force on such day as the Secretary of State may by order appoint.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>194A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>194A&#042;:</B> Clause 127, page 95, line 33, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Section (Amendments to the Legal Services Act 2007) comes into force on such day as the Secretary of State may by order appoint.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>195</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>195:</B> Clause 127, page 95, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) No order may be made appointing a day for the coming into force of section 4 so far as it inserts section 142VA or FSMA 2000 unless&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the day is later than that on which there is published the report of the review under section 142J of that Act containing a recommendation that section 4 of that Act should be brought into force to that extent, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a draft of the order has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>196</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>196:</B> Clause 127, page 95, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) No order may be made appointing a day for the coming into force of section 4 so far as it inserts section 142VB of FSMA 2000 (general requirement for full corporate separation of core activities) unless&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the day is later than that on which there is published the report of a review under section (Review of operation of legislation relating to ring-fencing) containing a recommendation that section 4 of that Act should be brought into force to that extent, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a draft of the order has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>197</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>197:</B>In the Title, line 6, after &#8220;subsidiaries;&#8221; insert &#8220;to make provision for penalties to be imposed on persons providing claims management services;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>198&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>198&#042;:</B> , line 6, after &#8220;subsidiaries&#8221; insert &#8220;and to join a consumer redress scheme&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>