<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Financial_Services_(Banking_Reform)_(Bill38(c))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 9, leave out lines 26 to 39 and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Reviews</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>142J Reviews of ring-fencing</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Treasury must make arrangements for the carrying out of reviews of the effects of the operation of the provision made by or under this Part in relation to ring-fenced bodies, including ring-fencing rules made by the PRA and the FCA and any rules made by the PRA and the FCA under section 192JA (rules applying to parent undertakings of ring-fenced bodies).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The first review must be completed before the end of the period of 4 years beginning with the date on which section 4 of the Financial Services (Banking Reform) Act 2013, so far as it inserts this section, comes into force.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Subsequent reviews must be completed before the end of the period of 5 years beginning with the date on which the previous review was completed.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Not less than 9 months, nor more than 12 months, before the date on which a review is due to be completed, the PRA and the FCA must publish a joint assessment of the impact of the operation of their ring-fencing rules.</quote>
         <quote>(5) For the purposes of this section a review is completed when the report of it is published.</quote>
         <quote>142JA Persons by whom reviews are to be conducted</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Treasury shall appoint not fewer than 5 persons to conduct a review of whom one is to chair it.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A person may not be appointed to chair a review unless the chairman of the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons has notified the Treasury that, in the chairman&#8217;s opinion, the person is likely to act independently of the Treasury, the PRA and the FCA in carrying out the review.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The persons appointed to conduct a review must include at least one person with substantial experience in central banking or financial regulation at a senior level.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The reference in subsection (2) to the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the name of that Committee is changed, is to be treated as a reference to that Committee by its new name, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the functions of that Committee (or substantially corresponding functions) become functions of a different Committee of the House of Commons, is to be treated as a reference to the Committee by which the functions are exercisable;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.</IndentOne>
         <quote>142JB Reports of review</quote>
         <quote>(1) The persons appointed to conduct a review must give the Treasury a report of the review.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The report must include an assessment of the extent to which the provision made by or under this Part in relation to ring-fenced bodies, including ring-fencing rules made by the PRA and by the FCA, are facilitating the advancement by the PRA of the objective in section 2B(3)(c) and by the FCA of the continuity objective.</quote>
         <quote>(3) If the report is made before section 4 of the Financial Services (Banking Reform) Act 2013, so far as it inserts section 142JD, has come into force it must also include a recommendation as to whether or not section 4 of that Act should be brought into force to that extent.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The report must include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) recommendations to the Treasury as to the provision that should be included in orders and regulations under this Part, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) recommendations to the PRA and FCA about the provision that should be included in ring-fencing rules.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament and publish it in such manner as it thinks fit.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 12, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) The preliminary notice must name an independent reviewer who is to report on the conduct of the ring-fenced body and the members of its group and on the appropriateness of the giving of the preliminary notice by the appropriate regulator.</quote>
         <quote>(4B) A person may not be named as the independent reviewer without the consent of the chairman of the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons; and the reference in this subsection to the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the name of that Committee is changed, is to be treated as a reference to that Committee by its new name, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the functions of that Committee (or substantially corresponding functions) become functions of a different Committee of the House of Commons, is to be treated as a reference to the Committee by which the functions are exercisable;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and any question arising under this subsection is to be determined and any question arising under this subsection is to be determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.&#8221;by the Speaker of the House of Commons.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 13, line 15, after &#8220;if&#8221; insert &#8220;after receiving the report of the independent reviewer,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 17, line 17, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Full separation</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>142VA General requirement of separation</quote>
         <quote>(1) Where the members of any group include one or more ring-fenced bodies and one or more other bodies, the members of the group must, before the end of the period of 5 years beginning with the relevant commencement date, take steps to secure that there are no members of the group that are ring-fenced bodies.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If in the case of any group steps to secure that there are no members of the group that are ring-fenced bodies are not taken within the period specified in subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the end of that period the Part 4A permission of each member of the group that is a ring-fenced body shall be treated as having been cancelled to the extent that it relates to a core activity, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after the end of that period the appropriate regulator must refuse to give any member of the group a Part 4A permission to carry on a core activity.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) At the end of the period specified in subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in section 142H, subsections (1)(b) and (4) to (7) and, in subsection (8), the definition of &#8220;specified&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) sections 142K to 142V,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>cease to have effect.cease to have effect.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (1) &#8220;the relevant commencement date&#8221; means the day appointed for the coming into force of section 4 of the Financial Services (Banking Reform) Act 2013 so far as it inserts this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 29, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) No order may be made appointing a day for the coming into force of section 4 so far as it inserts section 142VA of FSMA 2000 unless&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the day is later than that on which there is published the report of a review under section 142J of that Act containing a recommendation that section 4 of that Act should be brought into force to that extent, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a draft of the order has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 21, page 29, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) No order may be made appointing a day for the coming into force of section 4 so far as it inserts sections 142K to 142V of FSMA 2000 unless the day is later than that on which the report of the first review under section 142J of that Act is published.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>