<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Financial_Services_(Banking_Reform)_(Bill38(a))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 15</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TURNBULL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Court of directors to become board of directors</quote>
         <quote>(1) The court of directors of the Bank of England shall become the board of directors of the Bank of England.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Accordingly, in the Bank of England Act 1998&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in sections 1(1), (2) and (4), 2(1), 4(2), (3) and (4), 9A(1), (4) and (5), 9B(1), 9G(2), paragraphs 8 to 12A and 13(1) and (3A) to (6) of Schedule 1 and paragraphs 5 and 14 of Schedule 3, for &#8220;court&#8221; substitute &#8220;board&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in section 2(2) to (4) for court&#8217;s substitute &#8220;board&#8217;s&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in paragraph 14(2) of Schedule 1, for &#8220;court&#8221; substitute &#8220;board of directors, or former members of the court of directors,&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and any reference to the court in any other enactment or instrument is to be and any reference to the court in any other enactment or instrument is to be read as (as appropriate) being or including a reference to the board.&#8221;read as (as appropriate) being or including a reference to the board.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Constitution of board of directors</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Bank of England Act 1998 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 1(2)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) before paragraph (a) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(za) a non-executive chairman,&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (e), for &#8220;9&#8221; substitute &#8220;4&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Schedule 1 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Before paragraph 1 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(A1) Appointment as the non-executive chairman of the Bank shall be for a period of 4 years, or such shorter period as may be specified in the appointment.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(5) In paragraphs 4 and 7(2), after &#8220;appointed as&#8221; insert &#8220;non-executive chairman,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Before paragraph 5 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;4A (1) The person appointed to be the non-executive chairman of the Bank must have considerable experience of prudential or financial matters.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The persons appointed to be non-executive members of the Bank must have&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) experience in the running of large organisations and financial institutions, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) expertise in prudential policy.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) In paragraphs 5(1) and 6(1), after &#8220;appointment as&#8221; insert &#8220;non-executive chairman,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In paragraph 5(2), after &#8220;appointment as&#8221; insert &#8220;non-executive chairman or&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In paragraphs 6(2) and 8(1), after &#8220;office as&#8221; insert &#8220;non-executive chairman,&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(10) In paragraph 12(2), for paragraphs (a) and (b) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) the non-executive chairman of the Bank, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Governor of the Bank (or in his absence a Deputy Governor).&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(11) For paragraph 13(3) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) Meetings of the board shall be chaired by&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the non-executive chairman of the Bank, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in the absence of the non-executive chairman, a member of the court designated by the Chancellor of the Exchequer to chair meetings of the board in the absence of the non-executive chairman.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(12) In paragraph 13(3A), omit &#8220;(a) or&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(13) In paragraph 15, for &#8220;A&#8221; substitute &#8220;The non-executive chairman or a&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Functions of board of directors etc.</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Bank of England Act 1988 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 2(2), after &#8220;strategy&#8221; insert &#8220;and keep under review the Bank&#8217;s performance in relation to the objectives and strategy&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 2, after subsection (5) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(6) The board must conduct and publish reviews of the Bank&#8217;s performance in prudential and monetary policy.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The board must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) monitor the extent to which the objectives set in relation to financial management have been met,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) keep under review the internal financial controls of the Bank with a view to securing the proper conduct of its financial affairs, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) consider the Bank&#8217;s annual plans as to the allocation of resources and make and publish a report of the nature and extent of any changes in resource allocation in each area of the Bank&#8217;s activities.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) The board must provide to the Treasury and to any committee of either House of Parliament (or both Houses of Parliament) any information relating to the Bank (or any committee of the Bank or sub-committee of the board) requested by the Treasury or any committee of either House (or both Houses).&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(4) After section 2 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;2ZA Reviews</quote>
         <quote>(1) In the discharge of any of its functions, the board of directors of the Bank may arrange&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) for a review to be conducted in relation to any matter by a person appointed by the board, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) for the person conducting the review to make one or more reports to the board.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The persons who may be appointed to conduct a review include an officer or employee of the Bank.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A review under this section is a &#8220;performance review&#8221; if it&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is arranged by the board in the discharge of its function in keeping the Bank&#8217;s performance under review under section 2(2) or its function under section 2(7)(a), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) relates to past events.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) If the person to be appointed to conduct a performance review is an officer or employee of the Bank, the appointment requires the consent of the Governor of the Bank.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In the case of a performance review, the board must have regard to the desirability of ensuring that sufficient time has elapsed&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) for the review to be effective, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to avoid the review having a material adverse effect on the exercise by the Bank of its functions.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The Bank must give the Treasury a copy of any report made to the Board by a person appointed to conduct a performance review.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The Bank must publish the report unless the board of directors consider that to publish any information would be against the public interest (in which case it must not publish that information); and in that case the board must keep under review whether publication of the information remains against the public interest and, if they decide it no longer is, the Bank must publish the information.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The Treasury must lay before Parliament a copy of any report or information published under subsection (7).</quote>
         <quote>(9) If a report makes recommendations to the Bank as to steps to be taken by it, the board must monitor the Banks response and, if and to the extent that the Bank accepts the recommendations, monitor their implementation.</quote>
         <quote>(5) For section 9B(4) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) The board of directors must keep under review, and (where they consider it appropriate to do so) require the modification of, the procedures followed by the Financial Policy Committee; and for that purpose the board may require access to any documents considered, or other information held, by the Financial Policy Committee.</quote>
         <quote>(4A) One or two members of the board of directors may attend any meeting of the Financial Policy Committee, but a person attending by virtue of this subsection may not speak unless invited to do so by the person chairing the Financial Policy Committee.</quote>
         <quote>(4B) Subsection (4A) does not affect&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) anything done in relation to the Financial Policy Committee by a member of the Financial Policy Committee who is also a member of the board of directors, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the powers of the Financial Policy Committee under paragraph 13 of Schedule 2A.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In section 9C, after subsection (4) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) The board of directors shall keep under review the performance by the Financial Policy Committee of the duty under this section.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(7) For section 16 substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;16 Functions of board of directors</quote>
         <quote>(1) The board of directors must keep under review, and (where they consider it appropriate to do so) require the modification of, the procedures followed by the Monetary Policy Committee; and for that purpose the board may require access to any documents considered, or other information held, by the Monetary Policy Committee.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In particular the board of directors must determine whether the Monetary Policy Committee has collected the regional, sectoral and other information necessary for the purposes of formulating monetary policy.</quote>
         <quote>(3) One or two members of the board of directors may attend any meeting of the Monetary Policy Committee, but a person attending by virtue of this subsection may not speak unless invited to do so by the person chairing the Monetary Policy Committee.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Subsection (3) does not affect the powers of the Monetary Policy Committee under paragraph 13A of Schedule 3.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(8) After paragraph 13 of Schedule 1 insert&#8212;</quote>&#8220;Minutes of meetings&#8220;Minutes of meetings<quote>13A (1) After each meeting of the board, the Bank shall publish minutes of the meeting before the end of the period of 6 weeks beginning with the day of the meeting.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The minutes need not include any matters appearing to the board to be confidential but where there is a public interest in any such matters the non-executive chairman must inform the chairman of the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The reference in subsection (2) to the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the name of that Committee is changed, is to be treated as a reference to that Committee by its new name, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the functions of that Committee (or substantially corresponding functions) become functions of a different Committee of the House of Commons, is to be treated as a reference to the Committee by which the functions are exercisable;</IndentOne>and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.&#8221;.&#8221;determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.&#8221;.&#8221;</text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Abolition of Oversight Committee</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Oversight Committee of the court of directors of the Bank of England is abolished.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Accordingly, in the Bank of England Act 1998&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) omit sections 3A to 3F and section 4(2)(a), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph 14(1) of Schedule 1, paragraphs 5 and 9(1) and (2) of Schedule 2A and paragraphs 4(2) and 9(1) of Schedule 3, for &#8220;Oversight Committee&#8221; substitute &#8220;board of directors&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) And in paragraph 15 of Schedule 1ZB of FSMA 2000&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in sub-paragraph (1), for &#8220;Oversight Committee&#8221; substitute &#8220;board of directors&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in sub-paragraph (2), for &#8220;Committee&#8221; substitute &#8220;board&#8221;.</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Additional member of the Financial Policy Committee</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 9B of the Bank of England Act 1998 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (1)(e), for &#8220;4&#8221; substitute &#8220;5&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (3) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) The Chancellor of the Exchequer must secure that one of the persons appointed under subsection (1)(e) is a person with knowledge of financial crises, and other circumstances occurring in the past or present, (in the United Kingdom or elsewhere) which is likely to be relevant to the Committee&#8217;s functions.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 15</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TURNBULL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Abolition of strategic objective of the FCA</quote>
         <IndentOne>In FSMA 2000&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) In section 1B, omit&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) in subsection (1), paragraph (a) (and the &#8220;and&#8221; following it) and, in paragraph (b), &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) subsection (2),</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) in subsection (3), &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) omit section 1F,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in subsection (1K), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) omit section 3B(3),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) omit section 3D(4),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) in section 55B(4), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) in section 55H(4), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) in section 55I(5), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(i) in section 55J(1)(c), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(j) in section 55L(6), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(k) in section 55T, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(l) in section 88E, in subsection (1) and in the heading, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(m) in section 89U, in subsection (1) and in the heading, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(n) in section 137A(1), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(o) in section 138A(5), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(p) in section 192C(2), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(q) in section 194(1)(c), for the words after &#8220;advance&#8221; substitute &#8220;any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(r) in section 232A, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(s) in section 314(1), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(t) in section 316(1A)(a), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(u) in section 318(3A)(a), omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(v) in section 340(8), for the words after &#8220;expedient&#8221; substitute &#8220;for the purpose of advancing any of its objectives&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(w) in section 395(3), for the words after &#8220;procedure and&#8221; substitute &#8220;the regulator considers that, in the particular case, it is necessary in order to advance any of its objectives.&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(x) in paragraph 11(1)(b) of Schedule 1ZA, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(y) in paragraphs 6 and 6B of Schedule 1A, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(z) in paragraphs 3C(1) and 3D(1) of Schedule 6, omit &#8220;operational&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Competition objective of the PRA</quote>
         <quote>(1) FSMA 2000 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 2D insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;2DA Competition objective</quote>
         <quote>(1) In discharging its general functions the PRA must, so far as is reasonably practicable, act in a way which advances its competition objective.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The PRA&#8217;s competition objective is: to promote competition in the relevant markets.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (2) &#8220;the relevant markets&#8221; means the markets for services provided by PRA authorised persons in carrying on regulated activities.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Subsection (1) is subject to section 2B.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 2F&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) after &#8220;general objective&#8221;, in the first place, insert &#8220;and competition objective&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraphs (a) and (b), for &#8220;is a reference to its general objective and&#8221; substitute &#8220;includes a reference to&#8221;.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In section 2H, omit&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) paragraph (b) of subsection (1) (and the &#8220;and&#8221; before it), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) subsection (2).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Independent Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee of the FCA</quote>
         <quote>(1) After section 1L of FSMA 2000 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;1LA Independent Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee</quote>
         <quote>(1) There is to be a Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee of the FCA (&#8220;the Committee&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The members of the Committee are to be appointed jointly by the FCA and the PRA and hold office in accordance with the terms of their appointment.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The person appointed to chair the Committee must have experience of acting in a senior judicial capacity.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A majority of the members of the Committee must be persons appearing to the FCA and the PRA to have (and to have had) no professional connection with the provision of financial services.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The remaining members of the Committee must include persons appearing to the FCA and the PRA to have extensive experience in senior roles in banking.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The function of the Committee is to exercise the banking regulatory decisions function of the FCA and the PRA.</quote>
         <quote>(7) &#8220;Banking regulatory decisions function&#8221; means the function of taking decisions for enforcing compliance with relevant requirements, within the meaning of Part 14, in cases where the authorised person is a bank.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The banking regulatory decisions function of the FCA and the PRA is delegated to the Committee; and references in this Act to the FCA and the PRA in relation to that function are to be construed accordingly.</quote>
         <quote>(9) The FCA shall meet the reasonable costs of the Committee in discharging its function but the Committee&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is not subject to direction by the FCA or the PRA as to the exercise of its function,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is not accountable to the FCA or the PRA for the exercise of its function, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) may appoint its own officers and staff.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) At least once a year the Committee must make a report to the Treasury on the discharge of its function.</quote>
         <quote>(11) The Treasury must lay before Parliament a copy of each report received by them under subsection (10).</quote>
         <quote>(12) In this section &#8220;bank&#8221; has the meaning given by section 2 of the Banking Act 2009.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) The FCA and the PRA must carry out a review of the operation of the Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee of the FCA.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The review must be completed before the end of 2018.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The FCA and the PRA must give the Treasury a report of the review.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The report must include an assessment of whether the function of the Banking Regulatory Decisions Committee would be better discharged by a body that was entirely independent of the FCA and the PRA.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament and publish it in such manner as they think fit.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 16</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TURNBULL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Meetings between regulators and bank auditors</quote>
         <quote>(1) The FCA and the PRA must make arrangements to meet the auditors of each bank at least twice in each calendar year.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The FCA and the PRA may conduct meetings under subsection (1) jointly or separately (but each bank&#8217;s auditors must be met separately).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The purpose of each meeting is to discuss matters about which the FCA or the PRA believe that the auditors may have views or information.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A bank has a duty to ensure that its auditors attend meetings in accordance with this section (and compliance with that duty may be considered for purposes of the exercise of functions under FSMA 2000).</quote>
         <quote>(5) In this section &#8220;bank&#8221; has the meaning given by section 2 of the Banking Act 2009.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Leverage ratio</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Treasury must make an order under section 9L of the Bank of England Act 1998 (macro-prudential measures) enabling the Financial Policy Committee to give a direction under section 9H in respect of a leverage ratio for banks.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The direction above may specify the leverage ratio to be used.</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the purposes of this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;leverage ratio&#8221; has the meaning which the Financial Policy Committee considers that it has in European Union law or procedure from time to time, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;bank&#8221; has the meaning given by section 2 of the Banking Act 2009.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The order under subsection (1) must be made within the period of 6 months beginning with the date on which this Act receives Royal Assent.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Proprietary trading</quote>
         <quote>(1) The PRA and the FCA must carry out a review of proprietary trading by banks.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The review must be completed before the end of the period of 3 years beginning with the day on which this Act is passed.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The PRA and the FCA must give the Treasury a report of the review.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The report must include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an analysis of any action taken by the PRA and the FCA to monitor whether and to what extent banks engage in proprietary trading and any action taken by the PRA or the FCA to discourage banks from doing so;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an account of any difficulties encountered by the PRA or the FCA in taking that action and an assessment of its efficacy;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) an account of any requirement imposed on banks which the PRA or the FCA consider may be engaging in proprietary trading to publish a statement of the banks&#8217; exposure to risk in their trading operations and of the controls applied to limit that risk;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) an assessment of the impact of the ring-fencing rules on proprietary trading by banks;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) an assessment, drawing on experience in countries other than the United Kingdom, of the feasibility of prohibiting banks from engaging in proprietary trading or limiting the extent to which, or circumstances in which, they may do so (having regard, in particular, to any difficulties of definition); and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) a comprehensive analysis of the advantages and disadvantages of prohibiting banks from engaging in proprietary trading or limiting the extent to which, or circumstances in which, they may do so.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The PRA and the FCA must publish the report in such manner as they think fit.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The Treasury must, following receipt of the report, make arrangements for the carrying out of an independent review to consider the case for the taking of action in relation to proprietary trading by banks.</quote>
         <quote>(8) The appointment by the Treasury of persons to carry out the review requires the consent of the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons.</quote>
         <quote>(9) The reference in subsection (8) to the Treasury Committee of the House of Commons&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the name of that Committee is changed, is to be treated as a reference to that Committee by its new name, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the functions of that Committee (or substantially corresponding functions) become functions of a different Committee of the House of Commons, is to be treated as a reference to the Committee by which the functions are exercisable;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be determined by and any question arising under paragraph (a) or (b) is to be determined by the Speaker of the House of Commons.the Speaker of the House of Commons.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) The persons appointed to carry out the review must give the Treasury a report of the review once it has been concluded.</quote>
         <quote>(11) The Treasury must lay a copy of the report before Parliament and publish it in such manner as it thinks fit.</quote>
         <quote>(12) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;proprietary trading&#8221;, in relation to a bank, means trading with funds on markets on the bank&#8217;s own account (whether or not in connection with business with the bank&#8217;s customers),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;bank&#8221; has the meaning given by section 2 of the Banking Act 2009,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) &#8220;ring-fencing rules&#8221; has the meaning given by section 417 of FSMA 2000.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Remuneration code</quote>
         <quote>(1) The FCA and the PRA must prepare (and may from time to time revise) a remuneration code.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The remuneration code is to apply to all persons employed by a bank who are covered by the licensing regime.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The remuneration code must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) require that persons to whom the remuneration code applies are, except in specified circumstances, to receive a proportion of their remuneration in the form of variable remuneration,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) require that a specified measure of profits is to be used in calculating any variable remuneration which is calculated by reference to profits,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) require that the nature and amount of variable remuneration is to strike an appropriate balance between risk to the bank providing it and fair reward for the receipient of it,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) require a proportion of variable remuneration to be deferred for such period, not exceeding 10 years, as is appropriate to strike a balance between risk to the bank providing it and fair reward for the recipient of it,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) require that no, or only a limited amount of, variable remuneration of a person to whom the remuneration code applies is to be calculated by reference to sales made by the person or by any group of persons employed by the bank providing it, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) require that non-executive directors of a bank are not to receive variable remuneration.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) A requirement imposed by the remuneration code is a relevant requirement for the purposes of Part 14 of FSMA 2000.</quote>
         <quote>(5) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;variable remuneration&#8221; means remuneration (whether in money or in securities or any other form of money&#8217;s worth) the amount or value of which varies in accordance with profits, sales or other matters;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;bank&#8221; has the meaning given by section 2 of the Banking Act 2009.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Powers of regulator where Bank receiving State support</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) all or part of the business of a bank has been transferred to a bridge bank under section 12 of the Banking Act 2009,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a bank has been taken into public ownership under section 13 of that Act, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the Treasury has acquired shares or other securities in a bank or has provided a guarantee in respect of the liabilities of a bank.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The appropriate regulator may make an order under subsection (3).</quote>
         <quote>(3) An order under this subsection may do all or any of the following&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) cancel any entitlement to deferred remuneration payable (but not yet paid) to persons covered by the licensing regime who are employed by the Bank,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) remove any entitlement of such persons to payments for loss of office or payments on a change in control of the bank, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) remove rights to pension benefits to or in respect of such persons which have not yet become payable.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;the appropriate regulator&#8221; means&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) if the bank is a PRA-authorised person (within the meaning of FSMA 2000), the PRA, and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) otherwise, the FCA;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(b) &#8220;bank&#8221; has the meaning given by section 2 of the Banking Act 2009.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Special measures</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where the FCA or the PRA&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) has reason to believe that a bank&#8217;s systems or professional standards or culture do not provide sufficient safeguards against the commission of actions in respect of which the FCA or the PRA has power to take action, but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) do not have reason to believe that any such action has been committed (ignoring any action which is already being investigated or in respect of which action has been or is being taken).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The FCA or the PRA may give notice to the bank of the belief mentioned in subsection (1)(a).</quote>
         <quote>(3) If the FCA or the PRA gives a notice under subsection (2), it must invite the bank to make representations showing that sufficient safeguards are in place.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Following the giving of a notice under subsection (2) and the receipt of representations under subsection (3) (if any are made), the FCA or the PRA may commission an independent investigation into the bank&#8217;s systems and professional standards and culture with a view to establishing whether sufficient safeguards are in place; and for that purpose&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) &#8220;independent&#8221; means independent of the FCA, the PRA and the bank, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an investigation may not be commissioned from a person involved in the auditing of companies.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The bank must cooperate with the investigation.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Following receipt of the report of the investigation under subsection (4) the FCA or the PRA may by notice require the bank to take measures to provide sufficient safeguards and to monitor their effectiveness.</quote>
         <quote>(7) The bank must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) comply with the notice, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) appoint an appropriately senior member of the bank&#8217;s staff to oversee compliance.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) Compliance by a bank with a duty under this section may be considered for the purposes of the exercise by the FCA or the PRA of functions under FSMA 2000.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In this section &#8220;bank&#8221; has the meaning given by section 2 of the Banking Act 2009.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Whistleblowers&#8217; compensation</quote>
         <quote>(1) After section 206A of FSMA 2000 (suspending permission to carry on regulated activities) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;206B Whistleblowers&#8217; compensation</quote>
         <quote>(1) If as a result of an investigation carried out in accordance with this Act the appropriate regulator is satisfied that an authorised person has mistreated a whistleblower, the appropriate regulator may require the authorised person to pay to the whistleblower compensation of an amount determined by the appropriate regulator to be appropriate having regard to the financial implications of the mistreatment for the whistleblower.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In this section &#8220;whistleblower&#8221; means an individual who works or worked for the authorised person (whether or not as an employee) and who&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) gave information to the appropriate regulator for the purpose of initiating or facilitating the carrying out of an investigation in accordance with this Act, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) gave to a colleague information relating to any matter which might be relevant if the appropriate regulator were deciding whether to initiate the carrying out of such an investigation or were carrying out such an investigation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In this section a reference to mistreatment includes a reference to any form of discriminatory or unfavourable treatment.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A payment under subsection (1) is to be made only if the whistleblower chooses to accept it; and a whistleblower who accepts compensation under this section may not bring civil proceedings (including, but not limited to, proceedings before an employment tribunal) in respect of, or in reliance on, the mistreatment in respect of which the compensation is offered.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The procedural provisions of this Act in relation to the imposition of a penalty under section 206 apply to an award of compensation under this section.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Abolition of UKFI</quote>
         <quote>(1) All property, rights and liabilities of UKFI are, by virtue of this section, transferred to the Treasury.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Immediately after the transfer effected by subsection (1) UKFI is dissolved.</quote>
         <quote>(3) &#8220;UKFI&#8221; means UK Financial Investments Limited, company registered number 06720891.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>