<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Financial_Services_(Banking_Reform)_(Bill38_II(b))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Second Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 16</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD MCFALL OF ALCLUITH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Restriction on disclosure of confidential information by (FCA, PRA) etc</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 348 of FSMA 2000 (restriction on disclosure of confidential information by (FCA, PRA) etc), after subsection (4)(b) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) it is made available, without imposing any requirement of confidentiality, to a consumer (as defined in section 425A), or to a person imitating a consumer, or to persons who include consumers;&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 16, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Allowing FCA to publish instructions given to firms and their performance against these instructions</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 349 of the FSMA 2000 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(1) If, in the interests of promoting the consumer protection objective or the competition objective, the FCA uses any of its powers under this Act in relation to any firm or requires or agrees with any firm that any steps shall be taken, or cease to be taken, by or in relation to that firm or its business, the FCA shall, unless publication would be appropriate, after the period for making representations in relation to a direction given under this section has ended, give the firm a direction to publish details of the matter in a manner and form specified by the FCA.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If the FCA gives a direction under this section to an authorised person&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) it must give written notice to the authorised person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) if the direction relates to the approval by the authorised person of another person&#8217;s communication, it must also give written notice to that other person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) The notice must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) give details of the direction,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) inform the person to whom the notice is given that the direction takes effect immediately,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) state the FCA&#8217;s reasons for giving the direction, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) inform the person to whom the notice is given that the person may make representations to the FCA within such period as may be specified in the notice (which may be extended by the FCA).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The FCA may amend the direction if, having considered any representations made by a person to whom notice is given under subsection (2), it considers it appropriate to do so.</quote>
         <quote>(5) If, having considered any such representations, the FCA decides not to revoke the direction&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the FCA must give separate written notice to the persons mentioned in subsection (2)(a) or (b), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any such person may refer the matter to the Tribunal.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) A notice under subsection (5)(a) must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) give details of the direction and of any amendment of it,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) state the FCA&#8217;s reasons for deciding not to revoke the direction and, if relevant, for amending it,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) inform the person to whom the notice is given of the person&#8217;s right to refer the matter to the Tribunal, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) give an indication of the procedure on such a reference.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) If, having considered any representations made by a person to whom notice is given under subsection (5), the FCA decides to revoke the direction, it must give separate written notice to those persons.</quote>
         <quote>(8) Nothing in this section requires a notice to be given to a person mentioned in subsection (2)(b) if the FCA considers it impracticable to do so.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>