<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Gambling_Licensing_and_Advertising_(Bill61_R(e))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 6, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(b) after subsection (5) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(6) The Commission may give a direction under this subsection if the Commission reasonably believe that a person or organisation who does not hold a remote gambling licence is providing remote gambling services in the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(7) A direction under subsection (6) may be given to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a particular person operating in the financial sector,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any description of persons operating in that sector, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) all persons operating in that sector.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) A direction under subsection (6) may require a relevant person not to enter into or continue to participate in&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a specified transaction or business relationship with a designated person,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a specified description of transactions or business relationships with a designated person, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any transaction or business relationship with a designated person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) Any reference in this section to a person operating in the financial sector is to a credit or financial institution that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is a United Kingdom person, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is acting in the course of a business carried on by it in the United Kingdom.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;credit institution&#8221; and &#8220;financial institution&#8221; have the meanings given in paragraph 5 of Schedule 7 to the Counter-Terrorism Act 2008;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;designated person&#8221;, in relation to a direction, means any of the persons in relation to whom the direction is given;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant person&#8221;, in relation to a direction, means any of the persons to whom the direction is given.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>