<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Gambling_Licensing_and_Advertising_(Bill61_I)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Power to extend the horserace betting levy to overseas bookmakers</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may by regulations amend any provision or provisions of the Betting, Gaming and Lotteries Act 1963 (at a time when the provisions listed in section 15(1)(a) to (c) of the Horserace Betting and Olympic Lottery Act 2004 (horserace betting levy system) have not been entirely repealed by order under that section), the Gambling Act 2005 and/or the Gambling Act 2005 (Horserace Betting Levy) Order 2007/2159 for the purposes of ensuring that each person who holds an operating licence under the Gambling Act 2005 which authorises that person to provide facilities for betting shall be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) liable to pay the bookmakers&#8217; levy payable under section 27 of the Betting, Gaming and Lotteries Act 1963; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) subject to the provisions of section 120 of the Gambling Act 2005 (as modified in accordance with the Gambling Act 2005 (Horserace Betting Levy) Order 2007/2159) if that person is in default of such bookmakers&#8217; levy.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Regulations under this section must be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A statutory instrument containing regulations under this section may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before and approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Facilities for remote gambling</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 235 of the Gambling Act 2005 (gaming machine) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (2), after paragraph (i) insert &#8220;, and</quote>
         <IndentOne>(j) a machine is not a gaming machine by reason only of the fact that it is remote gambling equipment (within the meaning of section 36) which is made available for use in a casino.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) After subsection (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) The Secretary of State may by regulations provide for the maximum number of machines to which subsection (2)(j) applies that may be made available for use in a casino.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Consultation on and implementation of self-exclusion for remote gambling</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) review and report to Parliament on the significance of the remote gambling market in relation to potential problem gambling;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) within one year of this Act coming into force, consult on a system of standardised self-exclusion for remote gamblers; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) within two years of this Act coming into force and after the conclusion of consultation under this section, introduce a system of standardised self-exclusion for remote gamblers.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>4&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>4&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Licensing of remote gambling: conditions</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies in any case where a remote gambling licence is awarded to an operator of sports spread betting.</quote>
         <quote>(2) It shall be a condition of a licence to which this section applies that the operator shall report to the Gambling Commission and to sports governing bodies any activity (including financial transactions) which the operator considers suspicious in relation to sports spread betting (whether or not that information is relevant to any ongoing criminal investigation).</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Gambling Commisson may require an operator to furnish any information to it if it considers that the provisions of subsection (2) may apply with regard to that information.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The powers of the Gambling Commission under this section substitute for powers of the Financial Conduct Authority in respect of the provisions of this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>5&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>5&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Credit and financial institutions must not accept payments to and from unlicensed remote gambling organisation</quote>
         <IndentOne>In Schedule 7 to the Counter-Terrorism Act 2008 (terrorist financing and money laundering)&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the end of paragraph 1(4) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(4A) The fourth condition is that the Treasury reasonably believe that one or more people or organisations who do not hold a remote gambling licence are advertising unlawful gambling.&#8221;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(b) at the end of paragraph 2(6) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) &#8220;Remote gambling licence&#8221; means a licence under section 67 of the Gambling Act 2005.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>6&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>6&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Gambling Commission can direct financial sector to block financial transactions of organisation without remote gambling licence</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 122 of the Gambling Act 2005 (information), insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;122A Direction by Commission to financial sector to block financial transactions of organisation without remote gambling licence</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Commission may give a direction to a credit institution or a financial institution under this section if the Commission reasonably believe that a person or organisation who does not hold a remote gambling licence is providing remote gambling services in the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;credit institution&#8221; and &#8220;financial institution&#8221; have the meanings given in Schedule 7, paragraph 5 of the Counter-Terrorism Act 2008.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>7&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>7&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Power to make provision about injunctions preventing access to locations on the internet</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 122 of the Gambling Act 2005 (information), insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;122A Power to make provision about injunctions preventing access to locations on the internet</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State must by regulations make provision about the granting by a court of a blocking injunction in respect of a location on the internet which the court is satisfied has been, is being or is likely to be used for the purpose of providing remote gambling services in the United Kingdom by a person or organisation who does not hold a remote gambling licence.</quote>
         <quote>(2) &#8220;Blocking injunction&#8221; means an injunction that requires an internet service provider to prevent its service being used to gain access to the location.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The regulations must provide that a court may not grant an injunction unless notice of the application for the injunction has been given, in such form and by such means as is specified in the regulations, to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the internet service provider, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) operators of the location.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) The regulations may, in particular&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) make provision about when a location is, or is not, to be treated as being used to facilitate access to another location,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provide that notice of an application for an injunction may be given to operators of a location by being published in accordance with the regulations,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provide that a court may not make an order for costs against the internet service provider,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) make different provision for different purposes, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) make incidental, supplementary, consequential, transitional, transitory or saving provision.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The regulations may&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) modify Part 5 of the Gambling Act 2005, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) make consequential provision modifying Acts and subordinate legislation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) Regulations under this section may not include provision in respect of proceedings before a court in England and Wales without the consent of the Lord Chancellor.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Regulations under this section must be made by statutory instrument.</quote>
         <quote>(8) A statutory instrument containing regulations under this section may not be made unless a draft of the instrument has been laid before and approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(9) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;modify&#8221; includes amend, repeal or revoke;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;internet service provider&#8221; has the same meaning as in section 124N of the Communications Act 2003;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;operator&#8221;, in relation to a location on the internet, means a person or organisation who is providing remote gambling services in the United Kingdom;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;subordinate legislation&#8221; has the same meaning as in the Interpretation Act 1978.</quote>
         <quote>(10) In the application of this section to Scotland&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;costs&#8221; means expenses;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;injunction&#8221; means interdict.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>8&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>8&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Licensing powers in relation to Category B gaming machines</quote>
         <quote>(1) In Part 8 of the Gambling Act 2005, after section 166 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;166A  Review of licence</quote>
         <quote>(1) A licensing authority may, at any time after the granting of a remote operating licence in conjunction with a betting premises licence, review the terms of the licence and&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) revoke it with regards to Category B gaming machines; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) reduce the number of Category B gaming machines that the licence authorises the holder to make available to use.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) In exercising its discretion to review a licence under subsection (1), the licensing authority may have regard to the views of those in the local community.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(2) In Part 10 of the Gambling Act 2005, after section 240 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;240A Circumstances of use for Category B gaming machines</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State shall make regulations controlling the circumstances in which a B gaming machine is made available for use in accordance with the provisions of a remote operating licence in conjunction with a betting premises licence.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Regulations under subsection (1) shall, in particular, make provision to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) increase the minimum time between plays on category B gaming machines;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) require category B gaming machines to display information constituting a warning about the amount of time the machine has been used by the user and the aggregate amounts paid to use the machine, including amounts won and lost as prizes;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) require category B gaming machines to enforce breaks between periods of play; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) require that where category B gaming machines are made available for use, at least two members of the licence holder&#8217;s staff are present on the licensed premises while machines are in use.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>9&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>9&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Review of connection between non-paying social networking media gambling activities and use of licensed remote gambling operations</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall conduct a review into whether and how the existence of non-paid for gambling activities on social networking media interacts with use of licensed remote gambling operations, and whether such non-paid for activities can act as an inducement to participate in paying activities.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>10&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>10&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Consultation on self-exclusion</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall review the significance of the remote gambling market in relation to potential problem gambling, and shall consult on a system of standardised self-exclusion for the gambling industry, to include means of addressing exclusion from remote gambling access in the context of other gambling media.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>11&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>11&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Licence compliance, stipulations and control</quote>
         <quote>(1) Notwithstanding the regulation of spread betting by the Financial Conduct Authority, operators licensed for remote gambling by the Gambling Commission shall, to ensure their continued fitness as such, be obliged to comply with Condition 15.1 of the Consolidated Licensing Conditions and Codes of Practice 2011 (or its equivalent from time to time) in relation to all areas of their gambling operations, including spread betting and any other operations not within the jurisdiction of the Gambling Commission.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In the event of any breach of subsection (1) which the Gambling Commission believes calls into question the fitness of the relevant operator, the Gambling Commission may require the operator to provide an explanation of such breach within one month and may, if not satisfied with such explanation, revoke the operator&#8217;s licence.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>12&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>12&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reporting of suspicious activities and power to obtain financial information</quote>
         <quote>(1) In order to promote consistency of sports betting regulation, regulation of remote sports spread betting operators and of sports spread betting as defined herein shall be transferred from the Financial Conduct Authority to the Gambling Commission, which shall thereupon&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) have power to require and obtain from its licensees, including spread betting organisations, information concerning actual or potential suspicious activities in relation to sporting events, and to share such information with the relevant sports governing body;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) have power to require and obtain information on financial transactions by licensees which it reasonably suspects might be germane to the investigation of suspicious betting activity, money laundering or other criminal activities, or the protection of vulnerable individuals.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) &#8220;Sports spread betting&#8221; shall for this purpose mean spread bets in relation to sports as governed under Part 3 of Schedule 6 to the Gambling Act 2005.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>13&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>13&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Enforcement by IP blocking</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall have power to make regulations, in the form of a statutory instrument to be laid before and approved by both Houses of Parliament, permitting the Gambling Commission to block the internet access and internet protocol addresses of any licensed remote gambling operator which is found by the Gambling Commission to be in breach of its licence.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>14&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>14&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Consultation on existing use of financial blocking and IP address blocking</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall procure a process to take place expeditiously whereby each of the current gambling regulatory bodies share information on their financial transaction blocking and IP address blocking powers and activities with regard to remote gambling, and share and implement best practice.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>15&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>15&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Financial blocking</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 122 (information) of the Gambling Act 2005, insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;122A Direction by Commission to block financial transactions of person or organisation without remote gambling licence</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Commission may give a direction under this section if the Commission reasonably believes that a person or organisation who does not hold a remote gambling licence is providing remote gambling services in the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A direction under this section may be given to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a particular person operating in the financial sector;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any description of persons operating in that sector; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) all persons operating in that sector.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) A direction under subsection (1) may require a relevant person not to enter into or continue to participate in&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a specified transaction or business relationship with a designated person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a specified description of transactions or business relationships with a designated person; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any transaction or business relationship with a designated person.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Any reference in this section to a person operating in the financial sector is to a credit or financial institution that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is a United Kingdom person; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) is acting in the course of a business carried on by it in the United Kingdom.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;credit institution&#8221; and &#8220;financial institution&#8221; have the meanings given in paragraph 5 of Schedule 7 to the Counter-Terrorism Act 2008;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;designated person&#8221;, in relation to a direction, means any of the persons to whom the direction is given;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant person&#8221;, in relation to a direction, means any of the persons to whom the direction is given.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>16&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>16&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Dormant accounts</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State shall consult on appropriate ways to require licensed remote gambling operators to disclose (as a condition of their licence) the amounts held by them by way of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) winnings of UK customers unclaimed for a period of more than one calendar year, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) sums in dormant accounts of UK customers.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) A dormant account shall for this purpose be an account which has been inactive for at least one calendar year.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>17&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>17&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Remote gambling licensees and customer protection</quote>
         <IndentOne>Holders of licences for remote gambling operations shall be required to participate in a programme of research into and treatment of problem gambling in accordance with arrangements to be determined by the Secretary of State in regulations in the form of a statutory instrument approved by both Houses of Parliament, and a levy for that purpose may be imposed under section 123 of the Gambling Act 2005.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>18&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>18&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Kite mark</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Gambling Commission shall require all licensed online gambling operators to display a standard kite mark on all their promotional materials, websites and webpages, to indicate that such operators are licensed by the United Kingdom Gambling Commission.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Gambling Commission shall design and determine the form of the kite mark, which will provide a link to information and advice on its website for customers.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>19&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>19&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Review of social responsibility provisions of codes of practice</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Gambling Commission shall review the social responsibility provisions of the codes of practice and technical standards of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) EEA states, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the places to which section 331(2) of the Gambling Act 2005 has applied,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>insofar as they relate to remote gambling.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The Commission shall amend the codes of practice and technical standards issued in pursuance of section 24(2) of the Gambling Act 2005 so that the code and technical standards reflects the strongest social responsibility provisions identified in subsection (1).</quote>
         <quote>(3) In this section, &#8220;social responsibility provisions&#8221; means a provision of the code identified as&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) ensuring that gambling is conducted in a fair and open way,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) protecting children and other vulnerable persons from being harmed or exploited by gambling, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) making assistance available to persons who are or may be affected by problems related to gambling.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>20&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>20&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Advertising watershed</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Secretary of State shall consult on the current regulatory position concerning advertising of gambling and other forms of online gaming activity before the nine o&#8217;clock watershed and shall lay before the House a report of the findings not later than the final sitting day before the Summer Recess of 2014.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>