<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Immigration_(Bill84_II(a))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>54A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>54A&#042;:</B> Schedule 3, page 62, line 28, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Homelessness prevention</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>12A An agreement under which an individual is supported to secure accommodation in order to prevent or resolve homelessness, by&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a local authority;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a registered social landlord;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a charity or voluntary organisation.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66A&#042;:</B> After Clause 34, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Exemption of charging for primary medical services where charging is not cost-effective or poses a risk to public health</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 182 of the National Health Service Act 2006 (remission and payment of charges) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After subsection (1), insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) Insofar as any regulations under section 175 provide for charges to be made for the provision of primary medical services, they shall include provision for the remission in full of any charge that falls below the minimum threshold of service cost.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (2), the &#8220;minimum threshold of service cost&#8221; shall be the cost to the provider of primary medical services below which no charge is to be made for the provision of those services.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Where regulations under section 175 provide for a charge to be made for the provision of primary medical services, the provider of those services may waive the charge where he or she considers that the cost of recovering the charge is not economical or where the consequences of charging may put the public health at risk.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>