<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Immigration_(Bill84(b))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROBERTS OF LLANDUDNO</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In paragraph 16 (detention of persons liable to examination or removal) after sub-paragraph (4) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) A person detained under this paragraph must be released on bail in accordance with paragraph 22 after no later than the twenty-eighth day following that on which the person was detained.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 3, page 3, line 7, leave out subsection (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) In paragraph 22 (bail) at the end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(4) The following provisions apply if a person is detained under any provision of this Act&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Secretary of State must arrange a reference to the First-tier Tribunal for it to determine whether the detained person should be released on bail;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the Secretary of State must secure that a first reference to the First-tier Tribunal is made no later than the eighth day following that on which the detained person was detained;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) if the detained person remains in detention, the Secretary of State must secure that a second reference to the First-tier Tribunal or Commission is made no later than the thirty-sixth day following that on which the detained person was detained;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the First-tier Tribunal hearing a case referred to it under this section must proceed as if the detained person had made an application to it for bail; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) the First-tier Tribunal must determine the matter&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) on a first reference, before the tenth day following that on which the person concerned was detained; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) on a second reference, before the thirty-eighth day following that on which he was detained.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(5) For the purposes of this paragraph, &#8220;First-tier Tribunal&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) if the detained person has brought an appeal under the Immigration Acts, the chamber of the First-tier Tribunal dealing with his appeal; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in any other case, such chamber of the First-tier Tribunal as the Secretary of State considers appropriate.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) In case of a detained person to whom section 3(2) of the Special Immigration Appeals Commission Act 1997 applies (jurisdiction in relation to bail for persons detained on grounds of national security) a reference under sub-paragraph (3)(a) above, shall be to the Commission and not to the First-tier Tribunal.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Rules made by the Lord Chancellor under section 5 of the Special Immigration Appeals Commission Act 1997 may include provision made for the purposes of this paragraph.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 40</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROBERTS OF LLANDUDNO</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 40, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Permission to work</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 3(9) of the Immigration Act 1971 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(10) In making rules under subsection (2), the Secretary of State must have regard to the following.</quote>
         <quote>(11) Rules must provide for persons seeking asylum, within the meaning of the rules, to apply to the Secretary of State for permission to take up employment and that permission must be granted if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a decision has not been taken on the applicant&#8217;s asylum application within six months of the date on which it was recorded, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an individual makes further submissions which raise asylum grounds and a decision to refuse to treat such further submissions as a fresh claim or on that fresh claim has not been taken within six months of the date on which they were recorded.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(12) Permission for a person seeking asylum to take up employment shall be on terms no less favourable than those upon which permission is granted to a person recognised as a refugee to take up employment.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 40, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Support for prescribed groups</quote>
         <IndentOne>Section 4 of the Immigration and Asylum Act 1999 (accommodation) is amended as follows.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(1) In subsection (1), for &#8220;facilities for the accommodation&#8221; substitute &#8220;support&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (2), for &#8220;facilities for the accommodation&#8221; substitute &#8220;support&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In subsection (3), for &#8220;facilities for the accommodation of a dependant of a person for whom facilities&#8221; substitute &#8220;support of a dependant of a person for whom support&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (5)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), for &#8220;accommodation&#8221; substitute &#8220;support&#8221; in both occurrences; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (b), for &#8220;accommodation&#8221; substitute &#8220;support&#8221; in both occurrences.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) In subsection (6)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) in paragraph (a), for &#8220;accommodation&#8221; substitute &#8220;support&#8221;;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in paragraph (b), for &#8220;accommodation&#8221; substitute &#8220;support&#8221;; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in paragraph (c), for &#8220;accommodation&#8221; substitute &#8220;support&#8221; in both occurrences.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) For subsections (10) and (11) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(10) &#8220;Support&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) accommodation appearing to the Secretary of State to be adequate for the needs of the supported person and his dependants;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) food or other essential items;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the means to enable the supported person to meet what appear to the Secretary of State to be expenses (other than legal expenses or other expenses of a prescribed description) incurred in connection with his claim for asylum or leave to remain in the UK;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the means for the supported person and his dependants to attend bail proceedings in connection with his detention under any provision of the Immigration Acts; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) the means to enable the supported person and his dependants to attend bail proceedings in connection with the detention of a dependant of his under any such provision.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(11) If the Secretary of State considers that the circumstances of a particular case are exceptional, such other resources as he considers necessary to enable the supported person and his dependants to be supported.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROBERTS OF LLANDUDNO</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 1, page 56, line 12, leave out paragraph 5</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Schedule 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ROBERTS OF LLANDUDNO</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 3, lord Roberts of Llandudno gives notice of his intention to oppose the Question that Schedule 3 be the Third Schedule to the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>