<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Intellectual_Property_(HLBill33(c))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 20</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 20, page 18, line 19, after &#8220;Kingdom,&#8221; insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>&#8220;(iii) progress has been made in protecting metadata&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 20</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 20, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Lookalikes</quote>
         <quote>(1) A person (&#8220;A&#8221;) shall not, in relation to any goods or services, use any features of packaging, marking, labelling or decoration in such a way that the public is likely to attribute to A&#8217;s goods or services the reputation of another person (&#8220;B&#8221;) or the qualities or reputation of B&#8217;s goods or services.</quote>
         <quote>(2) For the purposes of subsection (1) it is immaterial whether there is any similarity between the goods or services of A and those of B.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Subsection (1) shall not apply to features of packaging, marking, labelling or decoration that are commonplace.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 21</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD CLEMENT-JONES</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Copyright in broadcast</quote>
         <IndentOne>Omit section 73 of the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 (reception and re-transmission of wireless broadcast by cable).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Criminal liability</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 107(4A)(b) (criminal liability for making or dealing with infringing articles, etc) for &#8220;two&#8221; substitute &#8220;ten&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 198(5A)(b) (criminal liability for making, dealing with or using illicit recordings) for &#8220;two&#8221; substitute &#8220;ten&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Private copying exception</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 28 of the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 (introductory provisions), after subsection (4) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) Any provisions of this Chapter relating to an exception for private copying shall not apply where further copies of copyright works are commercially available, under the terms of the acquisition of the copy of the copyright work concerned, by or with the authority of the copyright owner.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>