<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Marriage_(Same_Sex_Couples)_(Bill29(b))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD HYLTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 5, leave out &#8220;Marriage&#8221; and insert &#8220;Union&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 2</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS CUMBERLEGE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 2, page 3, leave out lines 21 and 22</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 2</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS CUMBERLEGE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 2, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Conscientious objection</quote>
         <quote>(1) Subject to subsections (2) and (3), no registrar shall be under any duty, whether by contract or by any statutory or other legal requirement, to conduct, be present at, carry out, participate in, or consent to the taking place of, a relevant marriage ceremony to which he has a conscientious objection.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Nothing in subsection (1) shall affect the duty of each registration authority to ensure that there is a sufficient number of relevant marriage registrars for its area to carry out in that area the functions of relevant marriage registrars.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The conscientious objection must be based on a sincerely held religious or other belief.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In an legal proceedings the burden of proof of conscientious objection shall rest on the person claiming to rely on it.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD TREFGARNE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 10, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Marriages at sea</quote>
         <IndentOne>In Section 26 (Marriages which may be solemnized on authority of superintendent registrar&#8217;s certificate) of the Marriage Act 1949, after subsection (1)(e) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(f) a marriage of a same sex couple conducted by the Master of a British ship registered under the Merchant Shipping Act 1995 while that ship is sailing outside of the territorial waters of England and Wales.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>