<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Mesothelioma_(HLBill3_R(b))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 6, at end insert&#8212; &#8220;and</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) fund research into mesothelioma (through the research supplement under section (Research supplement)&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 13, page 7, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(1A) The regulations must provide for the levy to include a research supplement in accordance with section (Research supplement) (in addition to the amounts set for the purpose specified in subsection (1)).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 13, page 7, line 11, after &#8220;levy&#8221; insert &#8220;(not including the research supplement)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 13, page 7, line 16, after &#8220;levy&#8221; insert &#8220;(not including the research supplement)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 13, page 7, line 18, after &#8220;levy&#8221; insert &#8220;(not including the research supplement)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 13, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Research supplement</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section makes provision about the research supplement mentioned in section 13(1A).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The research supplement&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) must be expressed by regulations under section 13 as a percentage of the amount set for the purpose specified in section 13(1) in accordance with section 13(2) to (5), and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may not exceed 1% of that amount.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Regulations under section 13 must include provision about the application of the research supplement; in particular, the regulations&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) must include provision for amounts raised by way of the research supplement to be applied by way of grants or other financial assistance for research into mesothelioma;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) must require the scheme administrator to make arrangements for the application of the research supplement;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) may allow the scheme administrator to arrange for a body which handles applications for research funding to administer the research supplement on the scheme administrator&#8217;s behalf;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) may allow receipts by way of research supplement in respect of one period to be held for allocation in a later period, and for investment of receipts pending allocation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) Before making regulations in respect of the research supplement the Secretary of State must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) insurers,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) medical charities and research foundations, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) other persons or bodies who the Secretary of State thinks are likely to be interested.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>