<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Offender_Rehabilitation_(HLBill35_I)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1:</B> After Clause 10, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Arrangements for supervision and rehabilitation: female offenders</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 3 of the Offender Management Act 2007 (power to make arrangements for the provision of probation services), after subsection (6) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(6A) The Secretary of State must ensure that arrangements under subsection (2) or (5) for the supervision or rehabilitation of persons convicted of offences&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) state that the Secretary of State has, in making the arrangements, complied with the duty under section 149 of the Equality Act 2010 (public sector equality duty) as it relates to female offenders, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) identify anything in the arrangements that is intended to meet the particular needs of female offenders.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2:</B> After Clause 17, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Provision for veterans&#8217; treatment courts</quote>
         <quote>(1) Within one year of the passing of this Act, the Secretary of State shall report to both Houses of Parliament on the case for establishing veterans&#8217; treatment courts for dealing with ex-service personnel convicted of offences for which non-custodial sentences could be imposed by the trial court (&#8220;relevant ex-service personnel&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The report under subsection (1) shall cover but not be limited to the following&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the statutory basis of veterans&#8217; treatment courts;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the composition and functions of veterans&#8217; treatment courts;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) whether veterans&#8217; treatment courts would be of most effect in diverting, where possible, ex-service personnel from the criminal courts or in overseeing the rehabilitation of ex-service personnel offenders sentenced by the criminal courts;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) an estimate of the impact of veterans&#8217; treatment courts on the rehabilitation of, and in reducing re-offending by, relevant ex-service personnel;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) an analysis of relevant international comparators; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) an account of consultation which shall be undertaken with all relevant parties including magistrates.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Within six months of the laying of the report under subsection (1), the Secretary of State may by statutory instrument make provision for one or more pilot schemes for veterans&#8217; treatment courts, to extend for two years.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A pilot scheme under subsection (3) shall, within six months of its conclusion, be independently evaluated, and a report of that evaluation laid before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Within six months of the laying of the report under subsection (4), the Secretary of State may by statutory instrument make provision for a permanent scheme for veterans&#8217; treatment courts.</quote>
         <quote>(6) A statutory instrument made under subsection (3) or (5) shall be laid before, and be subject to approval by resolution of, both Houses of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>