<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Transparency_of_Lobbying_Non-Party_Campaigning_and_Trade_Union_Administration_(Bill50_II(e))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 12, line 35, leave out &#8220;intended&#8221; and insert &#8220;having as its principal purpose the intention&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 12, line 45, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;unless the expenditure relates to legislation before Parliament during the regulated period&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 13, line 15, leave out subsection (5)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 13, line 17, leave out &#8220;intended&#8221; and insert &#8220;having as its primary purpose the intention&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 13, line 31, after &#8220;return&#8221; insert &#8220;, or</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) that he or she had an honest belief that the principal purpose of the campaign expenditure was other than the purpose specified in subsection (2)(b)&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 14, line 4, leave out &#8220;intended&#8221; and insert &#8220;having as its principal purpose the intention&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 14, leave out lines 28 to 31</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 26 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 27, page 14, line 44, leave out paragraphs (a) and (b) and insert &#8220;for paragraphs (a) and (b) substitute &#8220;£25,000 for each of England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 27, page 15, line 3, leave out &#8220;&#8220;2%&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8220;5%&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 28, lord Hardie gives notice of his intention to oppose the Question that Clause 28 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 29, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Publication of guidelines for third parties regarding regulation of expenditure</quote>
         <quote>(1) As soon as is reasonably practicable after the passing of this Act the Electoral Commission shall publish guidelines to assist third parties to determine what procedures are necessary for them to ensure compliance with the provisions of this Act.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The provisions of this Act regulating expenditure by third parties shall not come into effect until three months have elapsed after the publication of the guidelines mentioned in subsection (1).</quote>
         <quote>(3) In the event that the effect of subsections (1) and (2) is that the period remaining prior to the 2015 general election is less than the relevant period, the limits on expenditure by third parties will be reduced to the relevant proportion of the maximum permitted expenditure.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (3) the &#8220;relevant proportion&#8221; means the proportion of the maximum permitted expenditure represented by</quote>AB<IndentOne>where&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>A is the number of days remaining after the expiry of the three month period specified in subsection (2) until the date of the poll for the 2015 general election and B is 365.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 29, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Resources for Electoral Commission</quote>
         <IndentOne>The Electoral Commission will be provided with sufficient resources to enable it to comply with any additional obligations imposed upon it as a result of this Act.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>