<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Water_(Bill71_II(a))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Second Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 68</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD SHIPLEY</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS PARMINTER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>161ZA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>161ZA&#042;:</B> After Clause 68, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duties of landlords</quote>
         <quote>(1) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;landlord&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) where the relevant premises are occupied under a lease, the person for the time being entitled to the reversion expectant on that lease or who, apart from any statutory tenancy, would be entitled to possession of the premises; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the relevant premises are occupied under a licence, the licensor, save that where the licensor is himself a tenant in respect of those premises, it means the person referred to in paragraph (a).</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;lease&#8221; means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a lease for a term of less than 7 years; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a tenancy for a periodic term; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any statutory tenancy arising out of a lease or tenancy referred to in sub-paragraphs (a) or (b),</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and in determining whether a lease is one which falls within paragraph (a) above&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote/>
         <IndentOne>(a) any part of the term which falls before the grant shall be left out of account and the lease shall be treated as a lease for a term commencing with the grant;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a lease which is determinable at the option of the lessor before the expiration of 7 years from the commencement of the term shall be treated as a lease for a term of less than 7 years;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a lease (other than a lease to which paragraph (b) above applies) shall not be treated as a lease for a term of less than 7 years if it confers on the lessee an option for renewal for a term which, together with the original term, amounts to 7 years or more; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) a &#8220;lease&#8221; does not include a mortgage term.</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;relevant premises&#8221; means premises or any part of premises occupied, whether exclusively or not, for residential purposes (such occupation being in consideration of money or money&#8217;s worth) under&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a lease; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a licence.</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;statutory tenancy&#8221; means a statutory tenancy within the meaning of section 6 of the Rent Act 1977 (dwelling-houses let with other land) and section 7 of the Rent (Agriculture) Act 1976 (discretion of court giving possession).</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;tenant&#8221; means a person who occupies relevant premises being&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) where the relevant premises are so occupied under a lease, the person for the time being entitled to the term of that lease; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) where the relevant premises are so occupied under a licence, the licensee.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Every landlord shall ensure that they hold suitable buildings insurance against damage from flood for the relevant premises.</quote>
         <quote>(3) A landlord shall notify a tenant if the relevant premises appear on the register maintained under section 61.</quote>
         <quote>(4) A record of the insurance held under subsection (2), or a copy thereof, shall be made available upon request and upon reasonable notice for the inspection of any person in lawful occupation of the relevant premises.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 75</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HUMPHREYS</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS PARMINTER</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>165B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>165B&#042;:</B> After Clause 75, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty to provide sewers</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 101A of the Water Industry Act 1991, in subsection (2)(a) leave out &#8220;on which there are buildings&#8221; and insert &#8220;with permanent use and generating domestic effluent&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>