<?xml version="1.0"?>
<amendments>
<header>
<billtitle>Growth_and_Infrastructure_(HLBill85(b))</billtitle>
<headertext>AMENDMENTS TO  BE  MOVED ON  REPORT</headertext>
</header>
<clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD TRUE</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 3, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;( ) In the case of a major development made under this section directly to the Secretary of State, the Secretary of State must&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) make provision to enter into a full consultation with the local residents on the proposed development;</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) ensure that the results of the consultation are displayed for a period of four weeks after completion of the consultation on the Local Planning Authority&#8217;s website; and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(c) meet, or require the applicant to meet, the costs of any such consultation.&#8221;</IndentOne>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>After Clause 12</clausenumber>
<proposer>BARONESS BYFORD</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 12, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Registration of village greens</quote>
<quote>(1) Section 15 of the Commons Act 2006 is amended as follows.</quote>
<quote>(2) In subsection (3)(c) for &#8220;two years&#8221; substitute &#8220;one year&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>After Clause 15</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD TRUE</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 15, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Development orders: development within the curtilage of a dwelling house</quote>
<quote>(1) Section 61 of the Town and Country Planning Act 1990 (development orders: supplementary provisions) is amended as follows.</quote>
<quote>(2) After subsection (3) insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(4) Any development order or amendment to an existing development order made after 1 January 2013 that grants planning permission for development within the curtilage of a dwelling house shall not apply within the jurisdiction of a local planning authority until that authority has resolved that it shall.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
</amendments>

