<?xml version="1.0"?>
<amendments>
<header>
<billtitle>Growth_and_Infrastructure_(HLBill85(d))</billtitle>
<headertext>AMENDMENTS TO  BE  MOVED ON  REPORT</headertext>

</header>
<clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD MCKENZIE OF LUTON</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 9, after &#8220;designated&#8221; insert &#8220;in accordance with subsection (9)&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 14, leave out from second &#8220;is&#8221; to end of line 15 and insert &#8220;a major application of a kind described in regulations&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 2, line 33, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;( ) Before reaching a decision on an application made to him under this section, the Secretary of State must ensure that there has been adequate consultation with the local community.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 2, line 44, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(6A) The Secretary of State shall make a reasonable contribution to the costs incurred by a local authority in carrying out directions given under subsection (6).&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 3, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(9) The criteria for designation and revocation shall be set out in regulations, which shall be laid before both Houses of Parliament and approved by resolution of each House.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 3, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;( ) Before designating an authority under this section, the Secretary of State shall&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) serve a notice of intention to designate, and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) allow a period of four weeks for the local authority, on which notice is served, to make representations to the Secretary of State concerning why designation would be inappropriate.&#8221;</IndentOne>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 4</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD MCKENZIE OF LUTON</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 5, line 25, leave out &#8220;, or of the Secretary of State,&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 6</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD MCKENZIE OF LUTON</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 6, page 6, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(1A) This section only applies in relation to English planning obligations agreed prior to Royal Assent.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<proposer>LORD TOPE</proposer>
<proposer>LORD SHIPLEY</proposer>
<proposer>LORD MCKENZIE OF LUTON</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 6, page 8, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;( ) No applications shall be made under this section once three years have passed from it coming into effect.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 22</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD HODGSON OF ASTLEY ABBOTTS</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 22, page 24, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(4A) For section 130 of the Planning Act 2008 (National Trust land) substitute&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;130 National Trust land and nationally significant waterways</quote>
<quote>(1) This section applies to land&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) belonging to the National Trust which is held by the Trust inalienably, or</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) held in perpetual trust by Canal &#038; River Trust under the terms of The Waterways Infrastructure Trust.</IndentOne>
<quote>(2) An order granting development consent is subject to special parliamentary procedure, to the extent that the order authorises the compulsory acquisition of land to which this section applies, if the condition in subsection (3) is met.</quote>
<quote>(3) The condition is that&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) a representation has been made by the National Trust or Canal &#038; River Trust about the application for the order granting development consent before the completion of the examination of the application,</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) the representation contains an objection to the compulsory acquisition of the land, and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(c) the objection has not been withdrawn.</IndentOne>
<quote>(4) In this section &#8220;held inalienably&#8221;, in relation to land belonging to the National Trust, means that the land is inalienable under section 21 of the National Trust Act 1907 (c cxxxvi) or section 8 of the National Trust Act 1939 (c lxxxvi).</quote>
<quote>(5) In this section &#8220;the National Trust&#8221; means the National Trust for Places of Historic Interest or Natural Beauty incorporated by the National Trust Act 1907 (c cxxxvi).</quote>
<quote>(6) In this section Canal &#038; River Trust means company number 07807276, a company limited by guarantee formed and registered under the Companies Act 2006 (c. 46), acting in its capacity as trustee of The Waterways Infrastructure Trust.</quote>
<quote>(7) In this section, The Waterways Infrastructure Trust means the charitable trust of that name, settled by the Secretary of State for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs, and established by the Trust Settlement made by the Secretary of State on 28th June 2012.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 22, page 24, line 25, leave out &#8220;despite Trust&#8217;s objections&#8221; and insert &#8220;or nationally significant waterways despite National Trust&#8217;s or Canal &#038; River Trust&#8217;s objections&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
</amendments>

