<?xml version="1.0"?>
<amendments>
<header>
<billtitle>Public_Service_Pensions_(HLBill86_I)</billtitle>
<headertext>MARSHALLED LIST  OF  AMENDMENTS TO  BE  MOVED ON  THIRD  READING</headertext>
</header>
<clausenumber>Clause 3</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>1&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>1&#042;:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 9, at end insert &#8220;in relation to the scheme or any provision of this Act&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 9</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>2&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>2&#042;:</B> Clause 9, page 5, line 39, leave out &#8220;the negative Commons procedure&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) the affirmative Commons procedure, if the order specifies a percentage decrease for the purposes of subsection (2), and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) the negative Commons procedure, in any other case.&#8221;</IndentOne>
</text>
</Amendment>
<proposer>LORD EATWELL</proposer>
<proposer>LORD DAVIDSON OF GLEN CLOVA</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>3&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>3&#042;:</B> Clause 9, page 5, line 39, leave out &#8220;negative&#8221; and insert &#8220;affirmative&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 34</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>4&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>4&#042;:</B> Clause 34, page 18, line 13, at end insert &#8220;Part 1 of&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 35</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>5&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>5&#042;:</B> Clause 35, page 18, line 44, after &#8220;in&#8221; insert &#8220;Part 1 of&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 36</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>6&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>6&#042;:</B> Clause 36, page 19, line 13, leave out &#8220;has the meaning&#8221; and insert &#8220;and &#8220;the affirmative Commons procedure&#8221; have the meanings&#8221;.</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 37</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>7&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>7&#042;:</B> Clause 37, page 21, line 46, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;( ) In this Act, the &#8220;affirmative Commons procedure&#8221;, in relation to a Treasury order, means that the order may not be made unless a draft of the instrument containing it has been laid before, and approved by resolution of, the House of Commons.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Schedule 7</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>8&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>8&#042;:</B> Schedule 7, page 37, line 29, leave out from &#8220;service&#8221; to end and insert &#8220;had the new scheme service been old scheme service&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>9&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>9&#042;:</B> Schedule 7, page 38, line 16, leave out from &#8220;service&#8221; to end and insert &#8220;had the new scheme service been deemed transfer scheme service&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>10&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>10&#042;:</B> Schedule 7, page 38, line 38, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<HeadingTwo>&#8220;Final salary link not to apply again to a pension in payment</HeadingTwo>
<quote>5 (1) Scheme regulations may provide that where a pension in payment under a scheme to which section 18(1) or 31(2) applies has been calculated by reference to this Schedule, the pension cannot be recalculated by reference to this Schedule where there is a subsequent period of pensionable public service (within the meaning of paragraph 3).</quote>
<quote>(2) Provision made under sub-paragraph (1) may in particular be made by amending the scheme under which the pension is in payment.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Schedule 8</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD NEWBY</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>11&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>11&#042;:</B> Schedule 8, page 39, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;3A After section 8 of the Pensions (Increase) Act 1971 there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;8A Section 8(2): references to &#8220;service&#8221;</quote>
<quote>(1) In a case where&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) paragraph 1 or 2 of Schedule 7 to the 2013 Act (final salary link for persons who remain in old scheme for past service) applies in relation to a person, and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) the person&#8217;s final salary falls to be determined by reference to that paragraph,</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>references in section 8(2) above to the service in respect of which a pension is payable include the person&#8217;s new scheme service (within the meaning of Schedule 7 to the 2013 Act).</IndentOne>
<quote>(2) In a case where&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) a person is a member of a relevant old scheme by virtue of pensionable service for that scheme (&#8220;the relevant old scheme service&#8221;),</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) the person is also a member of a scheme under section 1 of the 2013 Act or a new public body pension scheme (&#8220;the new scheme&#8221;) by virtue of pensionable service for that scheme (&#8220;the new scheme service&#8221;),</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(c) the relevant old scheme service and the new scheme service are continuous, and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(d) the person&#8217;s employer in relation to the relevant old scheme service is the person&#8217;s employer in relation to the new scheme service (or any other employer in relation to the new scheme),</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>references in section 8(2) above to the service in respect of which a pension is payable include the person&#8217;s new scheme service.</IndentOne>
<quote>(3) In this section&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) &#8220;relevant old scheme&#8221; means a career average revalued earnings scheme (within the meaning of the 2013 Act) to which section 18(1) or 31(2) of that Act applies (restriction of benefits under existing schemes);</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) &#8220;employer&#8221;, &#8220;new public body pension scheme&#8221; and &#8220;pensionable service&#8221; have the same meanings as in that Act.</IndentOne>
<quote>(4) For the purposes of subsection (2)&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) paragraphs 3 and 4 of Schedule 7 to the 2013 Act (continuity of employment etc) apply as they apply for the purposes of paragraphs 1(2) and 2(2) of that Schedule;</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) regulations under section 1 of the 2013 Act (in the case of a new scheme under that section) or rules (in the case of a new public body pension scheme) may provide that where a pension is in payment under a relevant old scheme, references in section 8(2) above to the service in respect of which a pension is payable do not include any subsequent period of pensionable service in relation to a scheme under section 1 of the 2013 Act or a new public body pension scheme.</IndentOne>
<quote>(5) Provision made under subsection (4)(b) may in particular be made by amending the relevant old scheme.</quote>
<quote>(6) In this section, &#8220;the 2013 Act&#8221; means the Public Service Pensions Act 2013.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>12&#042;</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>12&#042;:</B> Schedule 8, page 44, line 27, leave out from &#8220;after&#8221; to end of line 39 and insert &#8220;sub-paragraph (11) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(11A) Where an individual&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) was a member of a relevant LSC scheme immediately before the transfer day,</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) had been a member of that scheme immediately before 1 April 2012, and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(c) becomes, on or after the transfer day, a member of a civil service scheme by virtue of employment in the civil service of the State,</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>the individual is to be regarded, for the purposes of section 18(5) of the Public Service Pensions Act 2013, as having been a member of the civil service scheme immediately before 1 April 2012.</IndentOne>
<quote>(11B) In sub-paragraph (11A)&#8212;&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
</amendments>

