<?xml version="1.0"?>
<amendments>
<header>
<billtitle>Enterprise_and_Regulatory_Reform_(HLBill83(f))</billtitle>
<headertext>AMENDMENTS TO  BE  MOVED ON  REPORT</headertext>
</header>
<clausenumber>After Clause 1</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD TEVERSON</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Interpretation of the green purposes: duty to assess impact on the Climate Change Act 2008</quote>
<quote>(1) In interpreting the purposes set out in section 1(1), it is the duty of the Board of the UK Green Investment Bank to assess whether the implementation of its investment strategy, or similar document outlining or amending the proposed investment portfolio, will as a whole, increase the likelihood of achieving carbon budgets and greenhouse reduction targets under the Climate Change Act 2008.</quote>
<quote>(2) Whether or not an investment strategy will increase the likelihood of achieving carbon budgets and greenhouse gas reduction targets shall be assessed in comparison with a scenario where the identified investments or investment categories did not proceed.</quote>
<quote>(3) In undertaking the assessment required under this section, it is the duty of the Board of the UK Green Investment Bank to have regard to the advice and reports of the Committee on Climate Change required under sections 34, 36 and 38 of the Climate Change Act 2008.</quote>
<quote>(4) The Board must not make a decision to adopt or amend its investment strategy or similar document as set out in subsection (1) unless it is satisfied, as a result of the assessment under this section, that the proposed investment portfolio will, as a whole, increase the likelihood of achieving carbon budgets and greenhouse gas reduction targets under the Climate Change Act 2008.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 4</clausenumber>
<proposer>LORD TEVERSON</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 3, line 13, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>&#8220;(f) a proportion of proceeds due to the UK Government as a result of the auctioning of emission permits under the European Union Emissions Trading Scheme&#8221;</IndentOne>
</text>
</Amendment>
<proposer>LORD TEVERSON</proposer>
<proposer>LORD STERN OF BRENTFORD</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 3, line 24, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(7) It is the duty of the Secretary of State to provide the European Commission with State aid notification concerning the intention to allow the Bank to borrow, including borrowing from the capital markets.</quote>
<quote>(8) The duty in subsection (7) must be fulfilled no later than 31 December 2013.</quote>
<quote>(9) In the event the European Commission approves the State aid notification concerning borrowing, it is the duty of the Treasury and of the Secretary of State to permit the Green Investment Bank to begin borrowing from the capital markets no later than 30 June 2015, or, if State aid approval has not been received by that date, no later than one month from the date of approval.&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>After Clause 59</clausenumber>
<proposer>BARONESS PROSSER</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 59, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Commission for Equality and Human Rights: appointment of Chair and commissioners</quote>
<quote>(1) Schedule 1 of the Equality Act 2006 (the Commission: constitution, &#038;c) is amended as follows.</quote>
<quote>(2) In Part 1, after paragraph 1(1) insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(1A) Appointments shall not take effect until such time as they are approved by a Committee of both Houses of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
<quote>(3) In Part 2, paragraph 7 omit sub-paragraph (2) and insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(2) An appointment under sub-paragraph (1)(a) shall not take effect until such time as it has been approved by a Committee of both Houses of Parliament.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 59, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Commission for Equality and Human Rights: reporting to Parliament</quote>
<quote>(1) Schedule 1 of the Equality Act 2006 (the Commission: constitution, &#038;c) is amended as follows.</quote>
<quote>(2) In Part 2, paragraph 32 omit sub-paragraphs (4) and (5) and insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;(4) The Commission shall lay each annual report before Parliament within 3 months of the end of the financial year to which the report relates.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 59, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Commission for Equality and Human Rights: budget</quote>
<quote>(1) Schedule 1 of the Equality Act 2006 (money), is amended as follows.</quote>
<quote>(2) In Part 3, after paragraph 38 insert&#8212;</quote>
<quote>&#8220;38A The budget fixed under paragraph 38 is subject to approval by a resolution of each House of Parliament.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 59, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Commission for Equality and Human Rights: strategic plan</quote>
<IndentOne>In section 4 of the Equality Act 2006 (strategic plan) omit subsection (4) and insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
<quote>&#8220;(4) The Commission shall lay the plan and each revision before Parliament.</quote>
<quote>(4A) The Commission shall send a copy of the plan and each revision to the Secretary of State.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
</amendments>

