<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><HansardDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print file:/C:/Users/edwardsc/Desktop/LordsHansard_Print2008.xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print"><House name="Lords"><System type="Cover"><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/Cover/1CC797B0062E44223D5D0AE1F3FA00A7A98FB53A" __version__="1.5"><Cover-wrapper><Cover bcoveruri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/Cover/0AE1F3FA00A7A98FB53A1CC797B0062E44223D5D" cdate="12" cday="Friday" cmonth="July" cyear="2013" date="5" day="Friday" htmlBackCoverUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/Html_Index/1CC797B006A7A98FB53A2E44223D5D0AE1F3FA00" htmlIndexUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/Html_Index/0AE1F3FA001CC797B0062E44223D5DA7A98FB53A" indexuri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/Index/2E44223D5D0AE1F3FA00A7A98FB53A1CC797B006" issue="30" maxparts="1" month="July" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" type="back" volume="746" year="2013"><Contents><hs_FPNormal>Extension
of Franchise (House of Lords) Bill
[HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>1407</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Cultural
and Community Distribution Deregulation Bill
[HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>1423</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Written
Statements<I>WS
95</I></hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormal>Written
Answers<I>WA
249</I></hs_FPNormal></Contents></Cover></Cover-wrapper></Fragment></System><System type="Debate" ColStart="1407"><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/416F310B893BEB63112B2B33009BC7F0A4E4412F" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AA-AB1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_Venue UID="13070536000311" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000311">House
of
Lords</hs_Venue><hs_date UID="13070536000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000001">Friday,
5 July
2013.</hs_date><hs_time UID="13070536000228" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000228">10
am</hs_time><hs_Procedure UID="13070536000305" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000305">Prayers—read
by the Lord Bishop of
Truro.</hs_Procedure><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070536000303" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000303">Extension
of Franchise (House of Lords) Bill
[HL]</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13070536000229" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000229">10.06
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13070536000309" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000309">Moved
By
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000246" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000246">Lord
Dubs</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13070536000244" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000244">That the Bill be
read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13070536000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000002"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000247" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000247">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> My Lords, this is not a new issue. It has been going
for several hundred years. But what surprises me—perhaps it
should not—is how many members of the public are not aware that
we cannot vote in general elections. They say, “I am surprised,
I thought you could vote”. I know that the public are not
generally excited by this issue and there are no demonstrations in
Parliament Square supporting my Bill—or even opposing it.
Nevertheless, it is a matter of some
importance.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000003">Many eminent people in
history have argued that Members of this House should be able to vote
in parliamentary elections. I will take just one: Benjamin Disraeli. In
1868, during the debate on the Electoral Petitions and Corrupt
Practices at Elections Bill, the <I>Hansard</I> record—which was
not verbatim at the
time—said:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000202" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000202">“The
Members of that House were now taxed by the Votes of the House of
Commons, and therefore he could not understand why a Peer of the Realm
should not have a right of voting for Members of Parliament and taking
part just as another individual in the general business of a free
country like this, with the view of protecting his property and
guarding his own interests”.—[<I>Official Report</I>,
Commons, 17/07/1868; col.
1383.]</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000004">Perhaps
there is not much more to be said. I am indebted to the House of Lords
Library for its note on this issue, which saved me hours of
research.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000005">Let
me say at the outset that this measure has nothing at all to do with
Lords reform as we normally speak of it. It is an entirely separate
matter and it is quite wrong to link the two. It is a single issue and
does not represent the beginning of a slippery slope. I can assure your
Lordships of that and I made sure that in the Long Title of the Bill
that is the
case.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000006">Over my
years in this House, I have often heard three arguments against change.
One is, “We have always done it this way so why alter it? It has
been good enough for the past 150 years so why change it?”.
Secondly, there is the argument that this is the thin end of the wedge
and dreadful things will inevitably follow if we take such a dangerous
step. The third argument is that we should not make haste on an
important issue. Of course, I reject all these arguments and I think
that most of your Lordships will do so as
well.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000007">During
the debates in October 2011 on the Steel Bill, one Member of this
House—he is present today but I shall spare his
blushes—urged caution in moving  
<?notus-xml column=1408?>too quickly on a very important matter. I realise
that 1868 is only yesterday but even so, we can be too cautious when it
comes to
change.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000008">After
talking informally to Members of this House, the argument against being
able to vote at parliamentary elections appears to be that we are in
such a privileged position in being able to amend and influence
legislation that we have no need to vote at general elections. I find
this a very strange argument. We are the only second Chamber in the
world whose Members are not entitled to vote in elections for the first
Chamber. About 190 countries have a second Chamber, according to the
records. Even in Washington there is no problem: members of the Senate
have the right to vote and it has caused no problems
whatever.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13070536000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000009">In
any case, logic ought to play some part in this. We try to argue
logically. We can vote in local elections, in European elections and
indeed in referenda. Surely it is only sensible and logical that we
should be allowed to vote in parliamentary
elections<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:09:50"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000010"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Foulkes of Cumnock" PimsId="4875" UID="13070536000248" xid="1866" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000248">Lord
Foulkes of Cumnock:</Member></B> Is my noble friend aware that we are
also able to vote in elections to the Scottish Parliament if we reside
in
Scotland<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:10:00"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000011"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000249" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000249">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> I thank my noble friend for that very helpful
intervention<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:10:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000012"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Foulkes of Cumnock" PimsId="4875" UID="13070536000250" xid="1866" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000250">Lord
Foulkes of Cumnock:</Member></B> And
referendums<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:10:10"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000013"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000251" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000251">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> I have said we can vote in referenda. Indeed, of
course, Members of the House of Commons are entitled to vote in
parliamentary elections. Furthermore, the prohibition on voting in
parliamentary elections does not even apply to all Members of this
House—I think we all know who I am talking about. The Lords
spiritual have the right to vote, though they sometimes do not avail
themselves of it. It would not be compulsory to vote; all I am saying
is that we should be on the same basis as the Lords spiritual. The
present position lacks logic and is
unsustainable.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000014">I
have heard a further argument against the change, which has been used
in previous debates, that legislation concerning the House of Lords
should not be introduced in small packages; in other words, do not
change anything until you can change everything. Until recently that
was the position of the Deputy Prime Minister but I think he has moved
away from that. It is absurd to say that we can only change
everything—a sort of big bang theory. In practice, and we know
this, it is usually better to argue for changes on an incremental basis
rather than adopt an all or nothing approach. In any case, the only
change I am suggesting is a vote. I repeat that this is not linked to
any other suggestions about reform of the House of
Lords<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:11:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000015"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Anderson of Swansea" PimsId="4901" UID="13070536000252" xid="1895" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000252">Lord
Anderson of Swansea:</Member></B> Is my noble friend not missing the
main argument, that it is easy to distinguish the Scottish Parliament,
local elections and so on because we in the House of Lords have no say
in those, whereas we do have a say in this House in national
decisions<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:11:47"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000016"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000253" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000253">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> Of course, that would also apply to the Commons but
the point is surely this: it is not a matter of influencing
legislation, which we do and are very 
<?notus-xml column=1409?>privileged to be able to do, but of being able to have some
small voice in deciding who will be the next
Government of this
country<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:12:12"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000017"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness O'Cathain" PimsId="2163" UID="13070536000254" xid="1370" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000254">Baroness
O'Cathain:</Member></B> Surely the point the noble Lord made earlier
about this not being the beginning of the slippery slope is
counteracted by his other statement that it should be incremental, bit
by bit. So is it a slippery slope or is it
incremental?<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:12:33"></hs_TimeCode></hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000018"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000255" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000255">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> I understand what the noble Baroness is saying, but
my point is not illogical. People have argued in this House that we
should not make this change without changing a lot of other things. I
have argued that that is not right; I have argued that we need to
change only this one thing in order to achieve the aim that I am
talking about<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:12:59"></hs_TimeCode>. I
should repeat that this proposal is not linked to any other reforms of
the House. A single change should not be conditional on changing
everything
else.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000019">I admit
that I feel emotional about the issue; perhaps that is an unusual
sentiment to express here. To me, the right to vote is an enormous
privilege, but it is also a crucial aspect of democracy. People have
died for the right to vote in our history—the Suffragettes. This
is not on a level with the right to vote for women, but it is still a
point of
principle.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000020">In<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:13:21"></hs_TimeCode>
most general elections, I have campaigned actively in a number of
constituencies. It is quite frustrating that, having spent my days
knocking on doors and trying to get Labour colleagues elected to the
House of Commons, when it comes to vote, I cannot take part. Sometimes,
if the general election coincides with local elections, I can get one
ballot paper but not the
other<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:13:55"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000021"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13070536000256" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000256">Lord
Cormack:</Member></B> Was the noble Lord not aware of this when he
accepted his
peerage<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:14:04"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000022"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000257" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000257">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> Yes, my Lords, I was aware of it, but one has to
arrive at a balance. Should have I said, “No, I am not prepared
to accept the privilege of being here because I cannot vote in general
elections”? My feeling is that it is better to get here and try
to achieve the changes by using the arguments. I think that that
applies to many of us. Even the noble Lord, I am sure, is not
ecstatically happy about every aspect of our procedures here, but that
did not stop him coming here and he is a very welcome Member of this
House, even though I occasionally disagree with
him<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:14:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000023"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Davies of Oldham" PimsId="2862" UID="13070536000258" xid="1735" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000258">Lord
Davies of Oldham:</Member></B> How solicitous does my noble friend
think returning officers and clerks in polling stations are about
enforcing this position? Every time I have gone to vote in a local
election that has coincided with a parliamentary vote, the returning
officer has seemed oblivious to the fact and I have had to tell them,
“Please don’t give me a vote for the parliamentary
election because it is
illegal<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:15:07"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000024"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000259" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000259">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> Well, I think that there is something in that, but,
in the course of history, Members of this House have voted in general
elections and that vote has been
challenged<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:15:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para> 

<?notus-xml column=1410?><hs_para UID="13070536000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000025"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Hughes of Woodside" PimsId="1055" UID="13070536000260" xid="1276" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000260">Lord
Hughes of Woodside:</Member></B> The other side of the story is that
when I go to vote in local elections that are on the same day as a
parliamentary election, I am frequently told that I cannot vote in
either<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:15:33"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000026"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000261" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000261">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> My Lords, I did not realise that a debate about a
simple matter was going to be quite so wide, but I welcome the
contributions that have been made. No, it is not easy for returning
officers. Sometimes, when we fill in our form to register to vote, it
is not easy to indicate that one is a Member of this House and
therefore one is limited. One can indicate that one is from a
Commonwealth country, from Ireland or whatever it is, and one’s
age, but one cannot indicate that one is a Member of this House. When I
have been to vote either they have known somehow, or I have not tried
to cheat the system, so I felt that the best way is to change the law
rather than to put myself on the wrong side of
it.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000027">The issue
is very simple, and I do not want to take up more time. Of course, it
is an enormous privilege to serve in this House and to influence
legislation—that is why I was very honoured when I became a
Member of this House—but I still find it sad not to be able to
influence, just in a small way, who will be our Government after the
election. I believe that the change that I am arguing for is inevitable
in the longer term, but I would like to see it happen now. I put this
Bill forward not as an idle gesture or a bit of political rhetoric; I
put it forward because I seriously believe that it has a chance of
becoming law. Of course, there will be difficulties in the Commons
about getting this Bill through, but I shall do some lobbying there if
this House passes it. I believe that it has a chance of becoming law
and I beg to
move.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/3988D472A3D155821AD330A56CD19454422FE42E" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AB2-AB2</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13070536000230" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000230"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:17:06"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.17
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:17:04"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000029"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Shutt of Greetland" PimsId="687" UID="13070536000262" xid="1433" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000262">Lord
Shutt of Greetland:</Member></B> My Lords, I support the Bill. I do so
with just a degree of reluctance. Reference has been made already to
the right reverend Prelate the Bishop of Truro, who spoke so clearly at
Prayers. I listened, as I always do, and he said to us, “Laying
aside all private interests, prejudices and partial affections”.
I have to say, I have a partial affection for
voting<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:17:41"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000030" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000030">Like
the noble Lord, Lord Dubs, I do not want to overegg this pudding, but
there are three features to this issue. First, there have been 10
general elections that I have been able to vote in, between 1964 and
1997, and I voted in them all—I voted for myself in half of
them. There have been three general elections since then that I have
not been able to vote
in<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:18:10"></hs_TimeCode>. Many of us
in this House get thoroughly involved in elections. In our campaigning,
we come across many people who say that they will not waste their time
by voting because it does no good—all that sort of thing. It
really goes against the grain that those folk have this precious vote
and will not use it but we are denied that
opportunity<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:18:37"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000031" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000031">Secondly, I could have
seen the point 102 years ago that perhaps we should not have the vote.
But, of course, before 1911, the House had the full panoply  of
powers. Therefore, it could be have been argued that, if you were in
Parliament, you should not have a vote because you were there of right.
But then in 1911, 
<?notus-xml column=1411?>those who served before us were stopped and we have continued not having
influence on money Bills—and we know how cross people in this
House get when they cannot take part in debates on money Bills.
Therefore, the very serious point is that we should be able to
influence those who are able to take part in money Bills, which we are
not able so to
do.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000032">Thirdly<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:19:28"></hs_TimeCode>
and finally, if this Bill were passed, there would be a good dividend,
because I think that the 739 Peers who would get the vote in addition
to the Bishops would use it. Therefore, the Bill would be well worth
passing and I thoroughly support
it.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/5E3A3E28143C10F41094139A6E6B1CC820A8E4C1" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AC-AD1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13070536000231" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000231">10.20
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000034" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000034"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wills" PimsId="5791" UID="13070536000263" xid="2061" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000263">Lord
Wills:</Member></B> My Lords, I admire my noble friend Lord Dubs for
many reasons, and one of them is his persistence in bringing this issue
to your Lordships’ House. I also congratulate him on the
pithiness of the drafting of the Bill. Successive Governments could
have learnt a lot from him on
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:20:12"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000035" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000035">I
am sympathetic to the democratic instincts that lie behind the
Bill—so well articulated by my noble friend and the noble Lord,
Lord Shutt. I understand the frustrations that they both feel, after
lifetimes of distinguished campaigning, that they now cannot use their
votes in parliamentary elections. The Government’s defence of
the current position does not seem to be coherent, as articulated by
the Deputy Prime Minister in his letter to Hywel Francis of 25 January
2011. He states that there is no case for the Lords to elect
representatives as they are able to sit in Parliament any way. If that
is a coherent argument, it is not clear to me why it does not apply
equally to Members of the other place because, in the Deputy Prime
Minister's words, they too “sit in Parliament
anyway<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:21:00"></hs_TimeCode>”.
As the noble Lord, Lord Shutt, said, the argument about money Bills is
archaic now. The Deputy Prime Minister’s words suggest an
after-the-fact justification of an archaic provision which has little
place in a modern
democracy<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:21:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000036" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000036">Your
Lordships’ House, unreformed as it remains, also has, in my
view, no place in a modern democracy. It is for that reason that, with
considerable regret, I feel unable to support my noble friend’s
Bill at this time. It seems to me that this is the wrong time to bring
forward such a measure when there are so many more compelling reforms
that still need to be made to your Lordships’ House. Some,
including me, still want to see the membership of your
Lordships’ House determined by election, but I recognise that I
am in a minority in this place on that issue. However, there is far
more widespread support in your Lordships’ House for reforms
which fall short of election but which are still important and urgently
needed. I think that most Members of your Lordships’ House would
agree, for example, that there should be provisions for expulsion after
conviction for criminal offences, and for retirement and resignation,
among other
things.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000037">Such
measures are needed to enhance the democratic credibility of your
Lordships’ House but, regrettably, there is still no sign of
them being implemented.  I think that they should take priority
over this Bill. I think that the public would find it hard to
understand why we are giving greater priority to something which 
<?notus-xml column=1412?>primarily benefits the Members of this House rather than measures which
improve the democratic credibility of your Lordships’ House and
the way that it serves the
public<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:22:46"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000038">I
am not opposed to incremental change, and I agree with all the
arguments in favour of it that my noble friend put forward. It is not
an argument against incremental change. It is an argument about the
order in which such incremental change should take place. If my noble
friend were to bring forward this proposal again in the context of
further reforms of your Lordships’ House, I would then be happy
to support
it<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:23:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13070536000232" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000232">10.23
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000039" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000039"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Brown of Eaton-under-Heywood" PimsId="2326" UID="13070536000264" xid="1727" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000264">Lord
Brown of Eaton-under-Heywood:</Member></B> My Lords, since universal
suffrage was introduced, I thought, pace the noble Lord, Lord Dubs,
that the only adults barred from voting in general elections were, as
they used to be known, convicts, lunatics and Peers—in modern
parlance, prisoners, mental patients and the Members, Peers temporal,
of this House. Mental patients, unless also convicted offenders, in
fact obtained the vote in 2000—subject, theoretically, to having
the requisite mental capacity. Some prisoners, at least, will, I
hope—assuming that Her Majesty’s Government sufficiently
respect the rule of law and their now clearly established obligations
under international law—shortly get the vote.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000040">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:25:14"></hs_TimeCode>
take this opportunity to say that, personally, I would give all
prisoners the vote by post, regardless of their crimes and regardless
of the length of their sentences. It is surely in all our interests as
part of the process of their rehabilitation to instil in them, so far
as may be, a sense of civic responsibility—to give them a stake
in the lawful governance of this country. I should perhaps point out
that even those with the longest sentences may well have children or
other dependents whose education and general well-being they have a
legitimate interest in promoting. I speak as the judge who, in 2001,
was responsible for bringing a final end to the attempts by Mr Hirst
and other prisoners to establish in our domestic courts the right to
vote. Refusing them leave to appeal to the Court of Appeal, I said that
it was for Parliament, if Parliament thought fit, to abolish or narrow
the ban on prisoner voting. I ended my very brief judgment in that case
thus. I
said:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000203" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000203">“Politically
I am not unsympathetic to the applicants’ cause.
Jurisprudentially, however, I regard it as
doomed”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000183" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000183">That
ruling opened the prisoners’ way to Strasbourg, where the court
eventually showed that I was wrong jurisprudentially. A few years
later, Strasbourg held a blanket ban to be impermissible and, twice
since, the Grand Chamber has confirmed that
position.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000041" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000041">In
the present context, that may be thought to be something of a
digression. I return, therefore, to the Members of this House, because
we remain disenfranchised. It is perhaps difficult to suppose that
Strasbourg will too readily be coming to our help. The rationale for
our becoming disenfranchised is, I have always understood—I
think this in common with the noble Lord, Lord Anderson—that
even when Parliament is prorogued, Members of this House remain members
of a central legislative body, unlike Members of 
<?notus-xml column=1413?>Parliament, who have to submit themselves to re-election if they wish to
continue. I share with other noble Lords real scepticism as to whether
that actually provides any sound or sufficient basis on which to deny
us the chance to influence by our vote the composition of the House of
Commons as the primary legislative Chamber. Others will no doubt make
that argument more effectively than I
can<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:27:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000042">Rather,
I want to focus on a narrower but, I suggest, altogether more obvious
grievance that a few of us—admittedly, only a very
few—have with regard to the present arrangements. Here I speak
as someone who, for two and a half years, was, electorally speaking, in
an even worse position than any other noble Lord participating in this
debate. Not only was I, in common with all temporal Members of the
House, disqualified by virtue of that post from voting at elections for
the House of Commons, but, in addition, by virtue of my appointment as
a justice of the Supreme Court, as long as I continued in that office,
I was disqualified even from speaking or voting in your
Lordships’ House. Accordingly, from October 2009 when, as Law
Lords, we were banished across the square and recreated there as a new
Supreme Court, until my retirement in April last year, on age grounds
at 75 when I reached, in the words of the late Lord Bridge of Harwich,
“statutory senility”—fortunately not a concept
which applies in my present surroundings—I had no vote and no
voice in national political life at
all<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:29:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000043" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000043">I
well recall, at the time of the Constitutional Reform Act in 2005,
pointing that out to the  then Permanent Secretary of the Lord
Chancellor’s Department. I said that, having lost our say in
Parliament, we should now have the vote restored to us at general
elections. I was assured that a team of lawyers would immediately be
put on the case to overcome that obvious legislative oversight. It
never was corrected and there remain five members of the Supreme Court
who are still totally disenfranchised. The other seven members of the
court are of course not yet Members of this House, although I hope that
they will become so when, one by one, they eventually come to retire.
They presently enjoy courtesy titles only and therefore can vote at
general elections whereas the five most senior members of the court,
including the president and vice-president, cannot. That, I suggest, is
a bizarre situation indeed.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000044" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000044">Whatever the outcome of
the wider issue today, that anomaly surely must now be corrected. I
wonder whether that possibly provides a peg upon which to hang a wider
benefit for all Members of the House, because surely that requires
legislative change. Certainly, my preference, in common with most,
although I recognise not all, of your Lordships, would be that the
wider grievance, too, should now be
corrected.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/765832CABD35D4F6EDB92540EE1E3A0ED5867AC2" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AD2-AD2</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13070536000233" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000233">10.31
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000045"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Parekh" PimsId="101" UID="13070536000265" xid="1380" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000265">Lord
Parekh:</Member></B> My Lords, I support the Bill introduced by my
noble friend Lord Dubs. Ever since I became a Member of your
Lordships’ House, I have asked myself why we are not allowed to
vote in parliamentary elections. In fact, the first Question that I
asked, on  17 January 2001, was precisely this: that on the
grounds 
<?notus-xml column=1414?>of human rights and equality of treatment, we ought to be able to vote.
The debate that took place following that Question makes interesting
reading, because many of the points being made
today seem to rehearse some of those made at that
time.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000046" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000046">Generally,
there seem to be two arguments as to why we cannot vote. One is that it
is an established practice, reference being made to immemorial law and
common-law practice. The other has to do with the fact that we are
already here, present and in person, and therefore do not need to be
represented. I find both arguments somewhat flimsy. Let me take them
one by one.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000047" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000047">On the first argument,
how did this become an established practice? It is not a law or
something to which the House of Lords ever consented. It was a House of
Commons resolution passed in 1699. If one looks at the debate
surrounding the passage of that resolution, it is clear that in those
days of rotten boroughs the Commons were very concerned that the Lords
should not be able to influence local elections. It was designed to
stop us interfering in the election. The Lords never agreed, were never
consulted and were never involved. That resolution is not sacrosanct
because it has been amended, first in the Peerage Act 1963 and then in
the House of Lords Act 1999. Under the resolution of 1699, no Peer
could vote. That was changed in 1963 so that Peers could vote, provided
that they were not Members of the House of Lords—and for years,
hereditary Peers have been able to vote without any kind of objection,
legal or otherwise, so that practice is not sacrosanct. It has been
changed and if it could be changed once, it could be changed again
provided we are convinced that there is a reason to do so.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000048" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000048">I want to argue that
there is a reason to do so. That leads me to the second defence of this
practice, which is that we are here in person. When I asked that
question on 17 January 2001, I was told by my noble friend Lord Bassam
that, since we are already here in person and are entitled to voice our
feelings and express our views, to allow us to vote in the election
would be to give us a unique privilege which is not given to others. I
found that argument unpersuasive but during Question Time we are not at
liberty to pursue the debate any further. I want to do that
now<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:34:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000049" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000049"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord McFall of Alcluith" PimsId="5780" UID="13070536000266" xid="2053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000266">Lord
McFall of Alcluith:</Member></B> My
Lords<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:34:03"></hs_TimeCode>—</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000050" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000050"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Parekh" PimsId="101" UID="13070536000267" xid="1380" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000267">Lord
Parekh:</Member></B> I am sorry. May I just finish this argument? When
we are told that we are here in person and therefore need not be
represented by the parliamentary election, we are making an important
assumption: that the two Houses have equal powers. If they do not have
equal powers, that argument collapses. If the Commons could do certain
things that this House cannot do, then the fact that we are here in
person does not give me a unique privilege if I should be entitled to
vote for the other place. For example, the Commons can make and unmake
Governments. It has the power to impose taxes and deal with money
Bills, which we do not have. Equally importantly, under the Salisbury
convention, if a particular measure of a Government or political party
has been approved by the majority, the party concerned has a right to
enact it—irrespective of what we think.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1415?><hs_para UID="13070536000051" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000051">I am suggesting that the
Commons has far greater power, and rightly so as it is the pre-eminent
body. If it is the pre-eminent body then our simply being here in
person but unable to vote deprives us of the opportunity to do many of
the things that the Commons does and which we cannot. I therefore
suggest that not being allowed to vote deprives us of the equality of
treatment to which all citizens are entitled. I will give way. I just
wanted to make sure that I made that point
straight<hs_TimeCode time="2000-01-01T00:00:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000052" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000052"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord McFall of Alcluith" PimsId="5780" UID="13070536000268" xid="2053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000268">Lord
McFall of Alcluith:</Member></B> As a Member of the other place for 23
years, I was both here in person and proud to vote for myself in every
general election. Is it not the case that House of Lords Members are
disadvantaged, and would be allowed to vote in future for someone other
than
themselves<hs_TimeCode time="2000-01-01T00:00:00"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000053"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Parekh" PimsId="101" UID="13070536000269" xid="1380" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000269">Lord
Parekh:</Member></B> If we were allowed to stand, we could certainly
vote for ourselves too. Logically, the argument that we are here in
person and therefore should not be allowed to vote because we do not
need to be represented is a flawed one. Once you undermine that
argument, there seems to be no logical basis for us not being allowed
to vote.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000054" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000054">There are of course
other arguments: that one should not make a piecemeal change, as it
should be part of a larger change. Well, larger changes are made up of
small changes and unless you start by taking the first step somewhere,
you would not be able to cover the journey. We are also being told that
this is not the time. When is the right time? Who decides that and by
what criteria? If, for the past 250 years, we have been saying
“Let’s change this”, given that I asked that
Question in 2001 and my noble friend Lord Dubs has introduced this
Bill, there is already a feeling of momentum—a groundswell of
opinion—that if citizenship consists in being able to have a say
in shaping the Government of the country, we are not citizens if we do
not have that say. Symbolic as it is, that simple point is of great
significance and I strongly urge the House, as and when the time comes,
to vote for the
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:37:36"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000055" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000055"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Seccombe" PimsId="627" UID="13070536000270" xid="1425" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000270">Baroness
Seccombe:</Member></B> My Lords, does the noble Lord not accept that
Parliament consists of two Houses: a House of Lords where Peers are
appointed for life and a House of Commons where Members are elected
until the next election, which is up to five years ahead? Does he not
accept that we are already Members of Parliament? That is the
difference between us and Members of the House of
Commons<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:38:18"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000056" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000056"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Parekh" PimsId="101" UID="13070536000271" xid="1380" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000271">Lord
Parekh:</Member></B> The noble Baroness makes a fascinating point but
there are two simple answers. She says that we are already Members of
Parliament. Technically, I am but I cannot say that I am an MP.
“Parliament” is used in two senses, one in the narrow
sense of the House of Commons and one in the wider sense of both
Houses. More importantly, if we say that we are Members of Parliament
the point I would make is that membership seems to be a matter of
degree. To be a Member of the House of Commons means that one can do
lots of things, whereas a Member of the House of Lords cannot do
certain things, such as censuring 
<?notus-xml column=1416?>or removing the Government, or dealing with matters of taxation and so
on. Therefore this abstract equality that is being
emphasised—that we are all Members of Parliament
alike—conceals a
fallacy.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/AC8C2BF0E7AF202CB49D0E271C5DE175038676AE" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AE-AF1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13070536000234" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000234"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:40:00"></hs_TimeCode>10.39
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:40:00"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000057" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000057"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13070536000272" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000272">Lord
Cormack:</Member></B> My Lords, I am speaking in the gap, with
permission. My noble friend made a significant point: we in this House
are indeed all Members of Parliament. We are Members of the second
Chamber and we have our own particular role and responsibilities. If we
are allowed to vote, should we be allowed to stand for election to
another place? I do not believe that we should. While I have the
greatest possible personal admiration for the noble Lord, Lord Dubs,
and while I disagree profoundly with the noble Lord, Lord Wills, for
whom of course I also have admiration, I agree with him on this point.
This measure should not commend itself to your Lordships’ House.
We are an undying House—the current situation is that we are
here for life—so we are part of Parliament. Although the next
general election will be the first in my adult lifetime that I have not
voted in, or indeed voted for myself in, I will still accept the
privilege, look with reluctance at those going to the polling booths
and with little reluctance at those who are knocking at doors, and know
full well that, God willing, I will come back at the beginning of the
new
Parliament.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000058">I
understand the motivation of the noble Lord, Lord Dubs. I also
understand the frustration of the noble and learned Lord, Lord Brown,
although I must say that I was moved by his touching faith that a team
of lawyers could come to a speedy conclusion on anything, but I find
myself in disagreement with someone else for whom I have great
regard<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:41:17"></hs_TimeCode>. The
essence of debate is that one can disagree, and I disagree profoundly
with this minor measure. I will certainly seek to move amendments at
future stages if the Bill is given a Second Reading
today<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:41:30"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000059" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000059"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Davies of Oldham" PimsId="2862" UID="13070536000273" xid="1735" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000273">Lord
Davies of Oldham:</Member></B> My Lords, has the noble Lord taken on
board the very strong argument that has been put before the House today
that we are clearly not Members of Parliament pari passu with the other
place? To take the most obvious point, at the next general election a
great deal will revolve around the conduct and direction of the
economy, the comprehensive spending review and the proposals that
affect our citizens so grievously in this time of great austerity, and
yet this House has no power to affect that position. We will have
influence, perhaps, and will debate the issue to a limited extent, but
power we do not have. Yet that is the most cardinal of election
decisions on which the nation will vote. That inequality is why there
is a strong argument that we should have the right to vote in general
elections<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:42:33"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000060" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000060"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13070536000274" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000274">Lord
Cormack:</Member></B> There might be, according to the noble Lord, but
I just do not agree with him. I could argue that Members of Parliament
in the other place also have very little power. We need a rebalancing
of the powers within our parliamentary system so that we do not have an
overweening Executive. To paraphrase Dunning’s Motion,
“The power of the Executive has 
<?notus-xml column=1417?>increased, is increasing and ought to be diminished”. We can play
our part in that by the influence that we wield in this place.
Influence can be tantamount to power when we have the sort of people
that we have in this place, with their great knowledge of economic
affairs. I rest my
case.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13070536000235" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000235"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:43:17"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.43
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:43:17"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000061" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000061"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hayter of Kentish Town" PimsId="5755" UID="13070536000275" xid="2032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000275">Baroness
Hayter of Kentish Town:</Member></B> My Lords, I think we owe my noble
friend Lord Dubs thanks not just for his Bill but, I have to say, for
this educational and entertaining Friday morning. I congratulate him on
the Bill. I am somewhat aghast that my very dear long-standing noble
friend is so keen to add nearly  300 government supporters to
the electoral role as against a mere 217 from the Labour side, which is
a 3:2 majority. That just goes to show what a very fair-minded and
honourable man he is. As the noble Lord, Lord Shutt, suggested, his
proposal would no doubt help national turnout and raise the batting
average, because we as a group tend to be rather dutiful and have an
excellent record on
voting<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:44:23"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000062" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000062">Before
turning to the Bill, I will take 20 seconds somewhat belatedly to wish
the noble and learned Lord, Lord Brown of Eaton-under-Heywood, a happy
75th birthday. I also wish the NHS a happy 65th birthday. It was 5 July
1948 when that great institution came into existence, which for mining
families like mine in south Wales made an enormous difference to their
lives<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:44:57"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000063" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000063">The
Labour Party has traditionally held the view that Peers are stopped
from voting in general elections because, as a number of noble Lords
have mentioned, they are very well represented in Parliament, albeit by
themselves, and that any such change should take place within the
context of a proper and fully reformed form of your Lordships’
House. That, of course, is something that we still await. The
Government’s clumsy attempt to reform this House without proper
consultation—no proper thought about the role of the House, the
respective powers of the two Houses, the 15-year term of office or the
ban for those who had political aspirations in another
place—means that serious reform has been put not on to the back
burner but into a rather deep, cold fridge. Worse, in a way, is that
the truculence of Mr Clegg over the burying of his half-baked ideas
means that he and the Government will not countenance some necessary,
albeit more gradual but we believe essential, modernisation of your
Lordships’ House. I speak of course of the excellent work
undertaken by the noble Lord, Lord Steel, and now by the noble
Baroness, Lady Hayman, in her House of Lords Reform Bill, which she
presented in
May.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000064" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000064">Surely<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:46:29"></hs_TimeCode>
the priority, as my noble friend Lord Wills has said, and which even Mr
Clegg should be able to understand, is some rather immediate changes.
The first, which I had been completely unaware of until about 15
minutes ago, is to give five Supreme Court judges their vote. The
second is to enable erring Peers to be waved off from your
Lordships’ House and to find a sensible way of fostering the
retirement of those who have served their country well but now wish to 
<?notus-xml column=1418?>step aside. Perhaps offering them the opportunity to vote in the general
election is the carrot that we have been
seeking<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:47:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000065" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000065">Of
course, if we were granted a vote at a general election and a Peer were
subsequently imprisoned and thus lost their seat here, and if the
amendment of the noble and learned Lord, Lord Brown, had not come
through, they would get their vote and immediately lose it as the
prison doors swung shut behind them. Still, that seems to be a matter
for another
day<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:47:49"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000066" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000066">My
noble friend Lord Dubs is of course not without friends. Some of them
are here today, some of them are in the past, as he mentioned. Benjamin
Disraeli in 1868 is an example, although whether that was just to dish
the Whigs is not recorded in the history books. In 1936 there was Lord
Ponsonby of Shulbrede, the grandfather of today’s Member of your
Lordships’ House and father of my former and much missed boss.
Prior to joining your Lordships’ House, the Hon. Tom Pon, as he
was known, including to the noble Lord, Lord Roper, was general
secretary of the Fabian Society when I was assistant general secretary.
That Lord Ponsonby, remembered, I am sure, by many in your
Lordships’ House today, succeeded in his other wish, which was
for hereditary Peers to be able to forgo their seat here and thus to be
able to stand for the Commons. However, voting in general elections
remains on the to-do
list<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:48:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000067">We are going to be very
interested to hear the Minister’s views today on this matter. It
was of course raised by my noble friend during consideration of the
Parliamentary Voting System and Constituency Boundaries Bill on 8
December 2010. The other Lib Dem Minister, the noble Lord, Lord
McNally, responding on that occasion to my noble friend Lord Dubs,
said:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000204" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000204">“I
encouraged the noble Lord keep on with his campaign. As they say where
I come from, a nod is as good as a wink”.—[<I>Official
Report</I>, 8/12/10; col.
290.]</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000184" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000184">We
know where the noble Lord, Lord McNally, comes from, other than
Blackpool. He was of course assistant general section secretary of the
Fabian Society, again when Lord Ponsonby was general secretary.
Presumably it remains his policy, along with that of the noble Lord,
Lord Shutt, and the Liberal Democrat party, that all Members of your
Lordships’ House and not simply the spiritual Members should be
able to vote in general elections, just as they can in the elections
for the Scottish and European Parliaments, as we have been reminded,
the London and Welsh Assemblies and local government and in various
referendums, although I have yet to hear from the other place whether
we are to have an in/out referendum on
Europe.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000068" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000068">For
our part, we are very content for this Bill to get its Second Reading
today, but we would much prefer action on the composition of the
House—by which I do not mean the Government stuffing it
more—that deals with its size and retirements or expulsions.
Alas we must await government action on that. Perhaps in responding,
the Minister could give us some indication of his Government’s
current thinking about this House, apart from any immediate
enlargement. We await his words with
interest<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:50:52"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/329A1E85D34FFBCD29E40DCB40685174102D34A3" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AF2-AG</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">

<?notus-xml column=1419?><hs_time UID="13070536000236" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000236">10.51
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000069" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000069"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070536000276" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000276">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> My Lords, the noble Lord, Lord Dubs,
said to me in the corridor the other day, “I hope you
won’t disappoint me”. I am very sorry to say that I have
to disappoint him on a number of grounds. In his opening speech, he
said that this measure has nothing to do with Lords reform, so it is a
non-Lords-reform Lords reform, if I understand what he is putting
forward. Of course it has a great deal to do with Lords reform. It is
one of many small items that we might consider if we go to a smaller
package of Lords reform in what is being discussed within Her
Majesty’s Government and outside as “a number of
housekeeping measures” for both Houses that might be introduced
next Session.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000070" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000070">For the best of
reasons, the noble Lord wishes to cherry-pick one of the changes that
would carry through on Lords reform without accepting some of the
others. I say this particularly because he remarked that Bishops in the
House of Lords can vote without remarking that that is because they do
not have permanent membership of your Lordships’ House. They
retire at 70, well before the onset of statutory senility. Had the
noble Lord, Lord Dubs, linked regaining the right to vote with a
statutory retirement age, the Government might perhaps, I think, have
looked on this rather more, although it would be very interesting to
know what retirement age noble Lords would have accepted—whether
it would have been 70, 75, 80, 85 or perhaps
95.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000071" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000071">The
argument for noble Lords not having the right to vote has partly been
that we are permanent Members of your Lordships’ House. I recall
that when we were discussing the major House of Lords Reform Bill last
year a number of Labour Peers—and I am looking at one or two of
them—were arguing in the corridors that they sit in the Lords by
royal summons and by right of the sovereign’s appointment and
that means that they are not entitled to retire. That is part of our
medieval, fundamentally illogical constitution, which is part of what
we are here for.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000072" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000072">The noble Lord, Lord
Parekh, talked about citizenship. Of course, in the British
constitution under which we all sit here in this wonderfully illogical
House, we are subjects of the Crown. It is the Crown that appoints us,
so it is as subjects that we sit here. That is one of the many reasons
why the citizenship debate in British still has a degree of weakness
because we have not quite worked out what that splendidly republican
concept “citizenship” should mean for all of
us.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13070536000073" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000073">The noble
Lord also advanced the argument that logic should play some part in
this. If we were to redesign the British constitution on logical
grounds, we would have a very different British constitution. Some
noble Lords will have noted that the noble Lord, Lord Lexden, and other
noble Lords signed a letter in the <I>Times</I> the other day which was
a passionate defence of the tradition of common law and its conventions
and traditions against the threat of logical, rational, Roman law from
across the channel, institutionalised in Brussels and Strasbourg. There
is a sense that there is an existential threat to our tradition of
Englishness through the logical, rational principles of Roman law which
come from across the channel, although many 
<?notus-xml column=1420?>people do not recognise that they are also there in Scotland. So many
people who talk about the defence of distinctive British institutions
appear to forget that Scotland is a central part of the United
Kingdom.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000074" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000074">If we
are to introduce common sense rather than common law, we are moving
into a fairly radical change in the way the British constitution
works<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:55:47"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000075" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000075"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Farrington of Ribbleton" PimsId="3193" UID="13070536000277" xid="1108" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000277">Baroness
Farrington of Ribbleton:</Member></B> The Minister referred to the fact
that we are already Members of Parliament. Does he accept that in
certain areas defined by law this is a unicameral system in that we are
excluded from areas of activity that are for the Commons? Throughout
history, there have been quite a lot of battles about no taxation
without representation. That is an area in this House that could be
looked at. I suspect that if my noble friend began the argument a
different way, your Lordships’ Chamber would be packed and the
Press Gallery would be full, because he could have argued that given
that we have no say on taxation, and therefore do not have
representation, we should not be taxed. I think that would incite the
public much more.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000076" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000076">My noble friend could
instead argue that we regain equality of powers with the House of
Commons. That would have Members of the House of Commons up in the
Gallery. The noble Lord is, I think, being a little less clear than is
his usual
practice.<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:57:24"></hs_TimeCode></hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000077" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000077"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070536000278" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000278">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> My Lords, I do not accept that we are
in any sense a unicameral Parliament. This is one of the more
influential second Chambers around the world. The fact that we are now
definitely the second Chamber and that there are areas in which we have
very much less influence than the House of Commons is one of the things
that makes this clearly a second Chamber, but some of the other second
Chambers, as I note, very definitely have less influence over the
breadth of
legislation<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:57:52"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000078" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000078"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Farrington of Ribbleton" PimsId="3193" UID="13070536000279" xid="1108" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000279">Baroness
Farrington of Ribbleton:</Member></B> I would be grateful if after the
debate on the Second Reading, which I hope will be granted, the
Minister would write to me giving examples of where this Chamber has
insisted to the point of the House of Commons backing down on
legislation over the past few
years<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:58:13"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000079" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000079"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070536000280" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000280">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> I am happy to promise to write to the
noble Baroness on that. I think the record is that a full 40% of
amendments moved in this House are accepted by the Government, but I
will check the figure and come back to
her.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000080" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000080">I do not
wish to detain the House for too long. I have made the point that the
permanence of Lords membership has to be linked with the right to vote.
On Lords reform, we have to look at a package. Last year, we presented
a large-scale package to the House, and the House, for many diverse
reasons, did not like it. The Government are considering whether to
present a more modest housekeeping
package<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:59:10"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000081" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000081"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness McIntosh of Hudnall" PimsId="1817" UID="13070536000281" xid="1765" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000281">Baroness
McIntosh of Hudnall:</Member></B> As far as I recall, this House was
never asked to give any opinion on the Bill. It was simply ditched
before it got
here<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:59:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1421?><hs_para UID="13070536000082" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000082"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:59:08"></hs_TimeCode><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070536000282" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000282">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> Having sat through several two-day
debates, I think the House has made its opinion relatively
clear. I am looking at the noble Lord, Lord Richard, who
laboured extremely conscientiously and at considerable length to
produce a package which this House would like. Certainly, the sense of
the House was, I think, not particularly favourable towards the
Government’s proposals. I will leave it at
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T10:59:52"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000083" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000083">Again,
I am sorry to have to disappoint the noble Lord, Lord Dubs. We will of
course be returning to this issue. I say to the noble Baroness, Lady
Hayter, that as she was speaking I thought of the noble Baroness, Lady
Symons. The noble Baroness, Lady Symons, has on many occasions used the
doctrine of mandate against me: that once a party has in its manifesto
a clear commitment, it has the right and duty to carry it through. I
think the Labour Party’s manifestos over the past three or four
elections have called for an elected second Chamber. I was disappointed
that the noble Baroness, Lady Hayter, went a little behind
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:00:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000084" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000084"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hayter of Kentish Town" PimsId="5755" UID="13070536000283" xid="2032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000283">Baroness
Hayter of Kentish Town:</Member></B> I was actually quoting the
Minister’s noble friend from a very recent debate in your
Lordships’ House. I made no mention of Labour Party
policy<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:00:53"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000085" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000085"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070536000284" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000284">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> Perhaps the noble Lord, Lord Dubs,
will come back but, unfortunately, the Government resist this small,
partial proposal for reform of the
Lords<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:01:05"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000086" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000086"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000285" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000285">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> Before the noble Lord sits down, perhaps I may ask
him one question. Given what he has said—and I will deal with
that in more detail when I wind up—will he give one small
undertaking? Assuming that the Bill gets through this House and goes to
the Commons, will he undertake that the Government will not use their
strength to block the Bill but will give it free passage and let the
Commons decide on its
merits<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:01:35"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000087" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000087"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070536000286" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000286">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> My Lords, I cannot give that
commitment immediately. We would clearly have to consider that. Private
Members’ Bills make their way, sometimes with the
Government’s blessing and occasionally without, first through
one House and then the other. Let us see how we go on this.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13070536000237" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000237">11.02
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:01:53"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000088" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000088"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000287" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000287">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> My Lords, it has been an interesting Friday morning.
The debate has been good tempered, but has extended well beyond the
very narrow purpose of the Bill. I suppose, if one says anything about
the future of the House, one can get into a debate about everything to
do with the future of this House, which is something I have tried to
resist<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:02:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000089" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000089">I will comment briefly
on one or two of the contributions. My noble friend Lord Wills argued
that this change should be part of a wider package of changes, and that
I should add it to another Bill. That is, of course, exactly what I did
when the Steel Bill went through. I did precisely what he said before I
had 
<?notus-xml column=1422?>the benefit of his advice and it was rejected on the grounds that it
would make the passage of the Steel Bill too difficult and my proposal
should stand on its own. I am getting conflicting advice on that. I did
what he suggested some time ago and it did not work, which is why I am
doing it this
way<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:02:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000090" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000090">The noble and learned
Lord, Lord Brown, rightly put forward an argument of which I was not
aware, about members of the Supreme Court. It is yet another instance
of where we are in an entirely illogical position. In arguing for a
little bit of logic, I do not think that I am being out of order. My
noble friend Lord Parekh gave us a good historical sweep and was the
first—apart from Disraeli—to talk about money
Bills<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:03:27"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:03:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000091">I
have very high regard indeed for the noble Lord, Lord Cormack—I
have known him for a long time—but I am not sure that the
slippery-slope argument is a good one. It has been used by opponents of
change since the beginning of
time<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:03:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000092" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000092"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13070536000288" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000288">Lord
Cormack:</Member></B> I just point out that if that argument has been
used, it was not used by
me<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:03:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000093" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000093"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000289" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000289">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> In that case, I misunderstood; I thought that the
noble Lord was using the argument himself. However, I very much agree
about the power of the Executive and that it is up to both Houses to
contain the power of the Executive—so I am with him on that,
even if we have a difference of opinion about the Bill
itself<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:04:07"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000094" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000094">I am delighted that my
noble friend Lady Hayter was supportive of the Bill. I pay tribute to
her long political experience, with the Fabian Society and elsewhere.
She said something about the 5 July anniversary of the start of the
National Health Service. If I may trespass on the time of the House, I
was in hospital on that day, in Stockport Royal Infirmary. I was quite
ill, and I was the only child in the ward. In those days, when the
consultant came around, one had either to stand or lie to attention
because that was the discipline. A consultant and his big team came
along and looked at me, and I asked, “Are we having a
party?”. He looked at me as if to say, “How dare you
speak before I have spoken to you?”, and then said,
“Why?”. I said, “Well the hospital is ours today.
We should have a party”. He gave me a dirty look and walked on.
I felt that I had made my contribution to the health service at that
time. I apologise for digressing a little but, but other noble Lords
have digressed as
well<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:05:08"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000095" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000095">Finally, I did not
think that the noble Lord, Lord Wallace of Saltaire, would disappoint
me quite as much as he did. Without wishing to be impertinent in any
way, I feel that his heart was not in it. I think that, in his heart,
he knows that I am right and he is wrong. It showed. I know what it is
like being a government Minister. One has to defend things that are
sometimes difficult; I have done it myself, although never quite to the
extent that the noble Lord has done it
today<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:05:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000096" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000096">On the cherry-picking
argument, and this is nothing to do with the Bill, I understand that if
we were to move to an elected second Chamber, of course we would have
to deal with issues like the primacy of the Commons, methods of
election and so on. It would be a whole package of measures, as was
evidenced in the 
<?notus-xml column=1423?>Government’s Bill that did not get anywhere. However, if we had
the vote in parliamentary elections, nothing would change in this House
except that we would have the right to vote. It would not affect the
way in which we operate, it would not affect our legitimacy and it
would not affect our debates or anything else. It stands entirely on
its own, so as to the argument that I was cherry-picking: if there are
only cherries on the tree, that is all that one can do. That is not a
valid
argument<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:06:32"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000097" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000097">This issue stands
entirely on its own. It need not, should not and does not have any
connection with any other aspects of Lords reform. We might throw it
into a wider Bill on Lords reform, as I have tried to do, but I would
argue that we should get on with it. Let us make this change. I believe
that there is overwhelming support in this House and in the Commons for
this. Of course, the difficulty is that it only takes one government
whip to say, “Object” on a Friday, and that has killed
the Bill. That is the problem in the Commons. If the Commons was
allowed by the Government to have a go at this, I believe it would
overwhelmingly support it, as I believe that this House would
overwhelmingly support it. However, the difficulty with Private
Members’ Bills is that they can be too easily blocked in an
undemocratic
manner<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:07:21"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000098" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000098"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070536000290" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000290">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> My Lords, the noble Lord is not
responding to my suggestion that if he perhaps linked the introduction
of voting to a limitation of tenure and a retirement age, this might be
more acceptable. He is not rising to that particular
float<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:07:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000099"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Dubs" PimsId="3031" UID="13070536000291" xid="1109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000291">Lord
Dubs:</Member></B> Give me time. I have got it down here to comment on.
If I had put forward a Bill saying the statutory retirement age from
this House is 75 or 80, of course many Members of this House would have
got incredibly excited about it, which would have diverted attention
away from my purpose. It would have made it, as a Private
Members’ Bill, totally unmanageable. The Minister knows that; I
know that; we all know that. It just would not have got through. The
point about a Private Member’s Bill is to keep it very simple if
it is to have any chance of getting through. Once it gets complicated
it has no chance. That is why I have brought it forward in this
way<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:08:25"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000100" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000100">Finally, the Minister
disparaged the idea of logic. The position at the moment is inherently
illogical. It is illogical by any standard, and I urge the House to
give the Bill a Second Reading.</hs_para>
<hs_Procedure UID="13070536000306" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000306">Bill read a second
time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/945804B42DA7EA67EFC0FF09457FB378805AB673" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AH-AJ1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070536000304" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000304">Cultural
and Community Distribution Deregulation Bill
[HL]</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13070536000238" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000238">11.09
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13070536000310" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000310">Moved
By
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Clement-Jones" PimsId="2634" UID="13070536000292" xid="1164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000292">Lord
Clement-Jones</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13070536000245" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000245">That the Bill be
now read a second time.</hs_Question></NewDebate> 
<?notus-xml column=1424?><hs_para UID="13070536000101" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000101"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Clement-Jones" PimsId="2634" UID="13070536000293" xid="1164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000293">Lord
Clement-Jones:</Member></B> My Lords, up and down the country, local
authorities, using powers granted by the Clean Neighbourhoods and
Environment Act 2005, which amended the Environmental Protection Act
1990, have been restricting leafleting for cultural events, including
performances at comedy clubs, theatres, music venues, art galleries and
even village halls. Under powers introduced by the 2005 Act, local
authorities can designate areas within which people must buy a licence
if they want to hand out leaflets. The Act gives local authorities
powers to designate land on which people require a licence to
distribute free printed matter, makes it an offence to distribute
leaflets on this land without obtaining the consent of the local
authority, and permits the local authority to refuse consent or to give
or limit consent, for example with reference to the time and place of
distribution or the material distributed. It requires a person
distributing leaflets to produce, on demand, written evidence of the
local authority’s consent, and permits authorities to charge a
fee for the issuing of
licences.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000102" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000102">A
survey by the Manifesto Club, the organisation that first identified
the issue, found that 27% of local authorities restrict leafleting,
including Nottingham, Leicester, Brighton, Swindon, Wolverhampton,
Oxford, Bournemouth, Newcastle, Middlesbrough, Manchester, Leeds,
Derby, Doncaster, East Hertfordshire, Colchester, Basildon, North West
Leicestershire, Sheffield, Rushmoor, Oldham, Kirklees, Birmingham and
seven London councils. This means that leafleting restrictions cover
the country’s key metropolitan centres and many smaller
towns.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000103" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000103">Licence
fees are prohibitively expensive for small groups. In Basildon, a
licence costs £150 for one day, £350 for a Saturday or
Sunday and £800 for one  week. Oldham charges £50
and Brent £55 per day. Wolverhampton charges £262 per
distributor. Some boroughs, such as Hammersmith and Fulham, and
Kensington and Chelsea, have a number of separate leafleting zones,
each of which requires a separate licence. Hammersmith and Fulham
charges £250 for each of its eight zones, so it costs
£2,000 to leaflet freely throughout the borough. The Manifesto
Club’s research found that these leafleting restrictions fall
most heavily on grass-roots art and community events, including comedy
clubs, theatres, music performances and art exhibitions. Larger-scale
events have the option of more commercial advertising channels, and can
afford leafleting licences if they so
choose.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000104" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000104">However,
there is a paradox here. The Local Government Association, as recently
as March, extolled the benefits of the contribution of the arts to
local communities. Its press release
stated:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000205" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000205">“Arts
investment can bring in £4 for every £1 spent ... From
international festivals and museums that attract hundreds of thousands
of visitors, to street entertainment revitalising high streets and
theatres supporting young people to gain new skills, thriving arts
create great destinations, vibrant places to live and have many
valuable economic spin-offs. A theatre, museum or festival draws
visitors who do not simply spend money on their ticket or entrance fee,
but also buy meals in local restaurants, go to local shops, or perhaps
stay in hotels as part of their visit. These people might never have
visited that location without the pull of its cultural attractions.
Businesses also choose to invest in places with a vibrant arts scene
because they offer their employees a high quality of
life”.</hs_quote> 
<?notus-xml column=1425?><hs_para UID="13070536000105" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000105">Quite contrary to this
enlightened statement, leafleting licence rules have been catastrophic
to grass-roots arts organisations, local theatres, jazz nights, comedy
nights and arts shows in venues such as theatres, village halls, comedy
clubs and small nightclubs, which rely on leafleting to build an
audience but cannot afford the high licence fees. In Leicester, a
one-off licence application fee is £103, on top of which an
organisation must pay £26 per distributor per day. The Leicester
Comedy Festival has 200 small comedy acts. It would cost an
unaffordable £5,200 per day to allow them all to leaflet. These
rules in effect mean that only the most commercial operations are able
to freely leaflet in
Leicester.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000106" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000106">Oxford
student societies were asked to pay £100 per month to hand out
leaflets, as was the Oxford Jazz Festival. A flyer ban in Leicester
Square, London, caused the collapse of several comedy nights and the
reduction of many audiences from 75 to 25. A Newcastle jazz club owner
said that leafleting restrictions reduced his audiences by 50%. The
Sawbridgeworth Evening Women’s Institute was threatened with a
fine for handing out leaflets about its annual art exhibition. It no
longer leaflets for the
event.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000107" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000107">Leafleting
licence schemes have had a widely recognised adverse effect on the
music and arts scene in key British cities, reducing the grass-roots
scene and limiting opportunities for emerging artists to win themselves
an audience. Leafleting restrictions have had a severe effect on the
music and experimental arts scenes in cities such as Leeds, Manchester,
Nottingham and Brighton, and on the fringe comedy scene in Brighton and
Leicester.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000108" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000108">One
unintended consequence of leafleting licence schemes has been the
commercialisation of the leafleting of the arts scene. In Brighton, for
example, the leafleting licence led to the decline of smaller,
experimental music nights, and the growth of bigger mainstream club
nights. Several comedy festivals, including those in Brighton and
Leicester, now have a diminished number of fringe acts, because only
those who can afford to take out brochure adverts or pay the leafleting
fee are able to reach an audience. Perversely, the more commercial
operations, which employ full-time leafleters, tend to leaflet more
indiscriminately and create most
litter<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:15:45"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000109"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Phillips of Sudbury" PimsId="181" UID="13070536000294" xid="1827" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000294">Lord
Phillips of Sudbury:</Member></B> I am sorry to interrupt my noble
friend’s flow. If a number of small acts get together and put
out a single leaflet, will they be charged separate licence fees or a
single licence
fee<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:16:06"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000110" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000110"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Clement-Jones" PimsId="2634" UID="13070536000295" xid="1164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000295">Lord
Clement-Jones:</Member></B> If it is a single leaflet, the fee will be
for a single licence, but these acts are small organisations with very
different timings for their events during a festival, and they all have
different audiences, so they want to put out their own material and
find the target audience most appropriate to
them.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000111">As I
said, commercial operations that employ full-time leafleters tend to
leaflet more indiscriminately and create the most litter. Small groups
leafleting on their own behalf will leaflet more selectively and
responsibly and create very little litter. The leafleting licence
scheme 
<?notus-xml column=1426?>punishes the small events and organisations that leaflet most
responsibly and cause minimal litter. McDonald’s can leaflet
freely, but the local arts centre
cannot.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000112" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000112">The
importance of flyering for grass-roots arts was summed up by David
Mulholland, a comedian and promoter for the Soho Comedy Club. He
said:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000206" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000206">“Flyering
is a life and death issue for small clubs that are just starting up.
The birthplace of alternative comedy in the UK, the Comedy Store,
started above a strip club in 1979 and relied heavily on flyerers to
attract audiences until 1993. If flyering had been prohibited in 1979
there would be no alternative comedy scene in the
UK”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000185" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000185">Supporters
of the Bill have received testimonies from a variety of organisations,
stating that leafleting is the primary way in which they can reach a
local audience. They include folk music societies, theatre groups,
chamber music and early music groups, church choirs, amateur
orchestras, amateur dramatics societies, village halls, experimental
DJs, unsigned bands who play in pubs, and small comedy
clubs.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000113" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000113">The
Cultural and Community Distribution Deregulation Bill 2013 would exempt
small-scale cultural and neighbourhood events from leafleting
restrictions. It would reform the Environmental Protection Act 1990 to
allow a greater exemption from leafleting restrictions for grass-roots
arts and community events. Currently, leafleting for religious,
political or charitable purposes is exempt from legislation. The Clean
Neighbourhoods and Environment Act 2005
states:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000207" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000207">“Nothing
in this paragraph applies to the distribution of printed matter
… by or on behalf of a charity within the meaning of the
Charities Act 1993, where the printed matter relates to or is intended
for the benefit of the
charity”,</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000186" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000186">or,</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000220" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000220">“where
the distribution is for political purposes or for the purposes of a
religion or
belief”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13070536000187" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000187">This
means that religious, charitable and political groups do not have to
buy a leafleting licence. A wide exemption would avoid the unnecessary
penalisation of the informal events that are so valuable to community
life.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000114" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000114">The
Bill would introduce a further exemption that would exclude leafleting
restrictions,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000221" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000221">“where
the distribution is for the purposes of an event which consists wholly
or mainly of live entertainment and takes place in the presence of an
audience of no more than 600
persons”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13070536000188" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000188">Live
entertainment is defined as arts and music events and other cultural,
social or recreational events of a similar nature, so the exemption
would cover arts, music and theatrical events, as well as local events,
such as talks, shows, fetes or coffee
mornings<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:19:37"></hs_TimeCode>. This
reform would be compatible with the current regulation on street
advertising, which exempts events of this nature from regulations. The
Town and Country Planning (Control of Advertisements) (England)
Regulations 2007 states that posters will have deemed consent and
exemption from planning laws if they announce a local event of
religious, educational, cultural, political, social or recreational
character<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:19:59"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000115" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000115">This
reform of leafleting restrictions would recognise the value of local
events and free up the arts and music scenes in key British cities from
this unnecessary restraint. The strength of British comedy, music and
the arts ultimately depends on the health of the grass roots, which
allows new talent to emerge and win an audience. 
<?notus-xml column=1427?>This reform would also recognise the importance of free speech in public
places, a liberty
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:20:25"></hs_TimeCode> has existed
for several hundred years in this country, embodied in our strong
tradition of pamphleteers. Leafleting is a key civic freedom, with a
long tradition in this country going back at least to the late 17th
century, when the requirement for printers to be licensed was lifted,
and should not be restricted without very good
reason<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:20:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000116" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000116">Problems
with litter should be dealt with through the provision of litter bins
and other common-sense measures, not by placing restrictions on our
civil rights. Leaflets advertising cultural events, an important
expression of our community activity, should not be treated in the same
way as a burger wrapper or a crisp
packet.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000117" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000117">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:21:05"></hs_TimeCode>
campaign to change the law is supported by a great range of artists
across the spectrum, comedians such as Al Murray and Simon Evans, the
directors of the Oxford Jazz Festival, the Leicester Comedy Festival,
Rick Wakeman and Radiohead’s
manager<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:21:16"></hs_TimeCode>, all of
whom recognise the importance of the grass-roots scene to producing new
talent. A whole host of organisations are in support, including Equity.
The Musicians’ Union says that it has supported the campaign
against leafleting bans from its inception and that it is vital to
musicians that events where they perform can be advertised and promoted
through unhindered and responsible
leafleting.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000118" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000118">UK<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:21:46"></hs_TimeCode>
Music, the organisation that represents the music industry in the UK,
supports the Bill, as do the Association of Independent Festivals, the
Association of British Orchestras and the Association of Festival
Organisers, which says that this Bill is too modest. It says that the
amendment to get free leafleting for up to 600 people works
fantastically well for clubs and societies, small concerts and even
fund-raising events, but does not do much for a festival that is trying
to attract 2,000 people. If I thought that I would get support for
going further than I have, I would have
done<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:22:18"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000119" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000119">The
Concert Promoters Association supports the Bill, as does the
Agents’ Association. The English Folk Dance and Song Society
says that it fully supports the Bill and that a large majority of folk
events are presented by amateur and community groups, as well as small
folk clubs and local festivals, which are not in a position to pay
their local authorities for permission to distribute leaflets about
their activities. Their activities should be encouraged, as they bring
people together and encourage community cohesion, and they should not
be hampered or discouraged in their efforts. The International
Association for the Study of Popular Music supports the Bill, as do the
Stand Comedy Club and Jazz
Services<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:23:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000120" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000120">In
conclusion, I have a few quotes from individuals, which I think are
telling. Alison Honour, the head of the School of Arts at Oxford
Brookes University
says:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000208" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000208">“I
am writing in support of the campaign against leafleting bans. Arts
organisations and artists of all disciplines rely on self-promotion in
order to publicise their practice, whether it be exhibitions,
performances or events. These activities contribute to
communities’ coherence, well-being and positive engagement, and
bring a cultural landscape often reaching out to the most remote places
and
spaces”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000189" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000189">Liam
Gardiner Webber<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:23:36"></hs_TimeCode>,
a band and youth theatre member in Nottingham says:</hs_parafo> 
<?notus-xml column=1428?><hs_quote UID="13070536000209" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000209">“I’m a
member of a small, unsigned band. If we were able to leaflet for our
gigs, it would make a huge difference to the numbers who would come and
see us. The lack of ability for small venues to leaflet has meant that,
as a member of a band and youth orchestra, being able to expand the
audience of either beyond family and friends is very difficult.
Leafleting would allow for much greater presence for such activities
and would in turn boost the culture side of the
city”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000190" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000190">An
independent promoter
said:</hs_parafo><hs_quote UID="13070536000210" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000210">“It
has been difficult to promote small events, as it seems only the larger
companies can afford such licences and therefore get more business,
which does affect independent
promoters<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:24:18"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_quote><hs_para UID="13070536000121" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000121">All
this is powerful testimony and very powerful support for the Bill.
There is no doubt that this legislative change would boost the arts and
local economy at no significant cost to national or local government.
Political, religious and charitable events are exempt from the need to
buy a leafleting licence, which means that small cultural events are
being unfairly penalised. It is unjust that the Church of England and
political parties can leaflet for free but the village fete or local
theatre group must pay. The grass-roots arts are fundamental to
community life and the local economy as well as producing talent of
international renown. The deregulation of entertainment licensing was,
of course, of great benefit, but groups need to be able to promote
themselves. Unless we act quickly, irreparable damage will be done to
the grass roots across the
UK<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:25:09"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000122" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000122">I
very much hope that the Government will heed these calls for reform and
back the Bill. I beg to
move<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:25:22"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:25:10"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:24:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/0F1C9B5E5F9547BE81CA210CA3292DF24E59E133" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AJ2-AK1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13070536000239" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000239"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:20:02"></hs_TimeCode></I>11.25
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:20:02"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000123" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000123"><B><Member ContinuationText="The Earl of Clancarty" PimsId="2608" UID="13070536000296" xid="2038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000296">The
Earl of Clancarty:</Member></B> My Lords, I support  this Bill,
the arguments for which the noble  Lord, Lord Clement-Jones,
has set out so expertly and comprehensively. This is a modest and
reasonable Bill, yet one significant for those who will be directly
affected by this change, as well as for local communities and the
public at large. The Bill is reasonable in that, in one sense, it does
no more than iron out an inconsistency that exists in the current
legislation<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:25:49"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000124" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000124">Like
the noble Lord, this problem came to my attention via the campaigning
group, the Manifesto Club, which has a particular sensitivity towards
how the loss of civil liberties affects the arts. The arts are as much
a valid means of expression as the expression of political and
religious views which, with regards to leafleting, are exempted by the
2005 legislation. Indeed, as the Minister will no doubt be aware, there
is often in practice considerable overlap between all three of these
areas. At heart, this is a civil liberties issue before anything else,
and it is worth emphasising that the present exemptions for leafleting
are already the recognition of the principle of free speech and free
expression. With the addition of cultural purposes, the noble
Lord’s Bill correctly positions the missing part of the jigsaw
puzzle.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000125" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000125">By
excluding arts and entertainment from the exemptions, the current law
has in effect discriminated against the arts, and in a very real way.
It is perhaps all too easy, in this age of the internet and social
media, to greatly underestimate the continuing importance of leafleting
for local and community events, which for many events is the prime
means of advertising. It is  
<?notus-xml column=1429?>perhaps gratifying proof of the vibrancy, or potential vibrancy, of our
public places and spaces that this is as true of
the big city as of the village or small
town<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:27:09"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:26:46"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000126" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000126">As
the noble Lord, Lord Clement-Jones, has outlined, there are clearly big
problems everywhere that restrictions have been introduced. Cindy
Oswin, London-based writer and director,
says:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000211" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000211">“I
have worked for many years in small-scale theatre productions where the
advertising budget is limited, so hands-on leafleting is necessary to
reach a potential
audience”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000191" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000191">Martha
Littlehailes, chair of a music society in Hackney
says:</hs_parafo><hs_quote UID="13070536000212" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000212">“We
are a tiny organisation and need the publicity that flyering
brings”.</hs_quote><hs_para UID="13070536000127" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000127">Outside
London, Daniel James, conductor of an amateur orchestra in Manchester
says
that,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000222" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000222">“publicising
our concerts has been hampered by being unable to obtain a flyer
licence”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13070536000192" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000192">Elspeth
Barnett of Eastbourne, who sings in a local choir, says that they
leaflet people as they leave other concerts, or at farmers’
markets. Folk singer Derek Gifford leaflets events organised by local
folk clubs in the north-west, all of which, he
says,</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000223" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000223">“have
limited budgets and would find difficulty in affording to pay licensing
fees for such an
activity”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13070536000193" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000193">Independent
music promoters have been particularly hard hit by the need for
licences. Others make the point that it is a vicious circle in that you
need the leafleting to build the audience, but you cannot afford the
licence until you do
so.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000128" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000128">The fact
is that leaflets or flyers are a low-cost alternative, which ought in
straitened times to be an ideal solution for emerging artists and
performers. There are also, of
course<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:28:42"></hs_TimeCode>, the
instances of blanket bans on flyering, such as has happened
controversially in Leicester Square in London, and in Liverpool, in
some cases where the legal basis for such bans is more than dubious.
Comedian Nick Doody has said of the Leicester Square ban that
it,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000224" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000224">“had
an immediate, tangible and devastating effect on small and medium-sized
comedy clubs in central
London”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13070536000194" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000194">Comedian
Stuart Goldsmith has said that
it,</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000225" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000225">“makes
it impossible for smaller clubs to thrive, and penalises
enterprise”.</hs_quotefo><hs_para UID="13070536000129" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000129">I
suggest to the Minister that the DCMS should be as much aware of this
debate as Defra, and that he might pass that message on. Last month, we
had a significant debate on the arts led by the noble Baroness, Lady
Wheatcroft, in which a recurring theme was innovation and support for
the arts at the grassroots level, so this debate is germane to
that<hs_TimeCode time="2000-01-01T00:00:00"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:29:30"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:29:30"></hs_TimeCode>.
The other point that the DCMS should be aware of is that we need to
keep as much of an economic edge as possible in music, theatre and
other areas. Any help that can be given at the grass-roots level will
in the long run be hugely important to the
economy<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:29:42"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000130" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000130">The
events most affected by these restrictions are those most integral to
the local community and cultural scene, whereas the more commercial
operations are able to pay for the licences but often have fewer local
loyalties. The Minister will perhaps recognise that there is a
significant distinction to be made between the highly commercial
advertising of a high street chain and a leaflet telling you
about events as varied as the 
<?notus-xml column=1430?>village fête, local choir event or folk or jazz night, which is
often handed to you by one of the performers themselves. Additionally,
the informality and spontaneity of many local cultural events also make
them unsuitable for licences which may have complicated tariffs as well
as being prohibitively expensive—an expense whose payment has to
be decided upon well in advance. These licences are overkill. We are
not talking about major pop concerts. The modest audience cap of 600
included in the Bill ensures that this is so. These events are often
run on a not-for-profit basis or on a tight budget which may help
artists, comedians, musicians, writers and others at the beginning of
their careers. As Josie Appleton, director of the Manifesto Club,
says:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000213" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000213">“We
have a strong tradition of pamphleteers in this country who would be
turning in their graves if they could see theatre groups charged
hundreds of pounds to hand out a few
flyers<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:31:12"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_quote><hs_para UID="13070536000131" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000131">It
should be borne in mind that leaflets are not litter until they are
discarded, and strategically placed bins ought to do that job. Indeed,
far from being mere pieces of litter, flyers can also be an extension
of an event aesthetically. This can be particularly true of music
events, just as CD covers are for CDs. Emma Webster, expert on live
music promotion,
states:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000214" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000214">“As
well as being portable information carriers … flyers form part
of the promoter’s ‘branding’ of an event through
their design and distribution. The design of flyers … can be an
important signifier as to the nature of the event, and is an
opportunity for the promoter to creatively market their
event<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:39:25"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000195" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000195">Anyone
who has attended any of the music memorabilia auctions in recent years
will know how much the promotional material for now famous bands will
go for, and often by designers such as Jamie Reid who have themselves
become well known through this work, all of which started at local
venues. Flyer and poster design is an industry in this country in its
own right and public spaces are their gallery. It is ironic that at a
time when this work is being shown in museums, its contemporary
practitioners are effectively being banned by so many local
authorities.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000132" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000132">Finally,
within the larger context surrounding this Bill, the long-term crucial
question which needs to be asked is: what should we be now be expecting
and demanding of our urban centres? Clare Fischer, artistic director of
The Red Hedgehog arts centre at Highgate, makes the
point:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000215" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000215">“Arts
and local events provide a kind of cultural and social
‘glue’ which is vitally important in providing and
maintaining a shared identity in the
community”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000196" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000196">Do
we want our public places to become increasingly prohibitive in
character, or do we facilitate them as properly shared spaces? For that
to happen, of course, they must also remain publicly owned and within a
local authority control that is dedicated to the public good above all
else. In an era of council sell-offs and partnerships, a question mark
hangs over this. However, that is going beyond the scope of this Bill,
being a debate for another time, although one that is urgently
required.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000133" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000133">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:33:22"></hs_TimeCode>
do not believe that the previous Administration intended to penalise
either the arts or local communities when they passed the 2005
legislation. I think rather that it was an oversight which all sides of
the House can now easily work together to rectify. I hope very much
that that is what will
happen.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/7D6867B15150100674F735F95385B20A56D9C584" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AK2-AK2</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">

<?notus-xml column=1431?><hs_time UID="13070536000240" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000240"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:33:43"></hs_TimeCode></I>11.33
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:33:43"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000134" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000134"><B><Member ContinuationText="Viscount Colville of Culross" PimsId="2685" UID="13070536000297" xid="2157" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000297">Viscount
Colville of Culross:</Member></B> I applaud the noble Lord, Lord
Clement-Jones, for introducing the Bill and for bringing this issue to
the attention of the House in a number of Questions for Short
Debate.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000135" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000135">It
seems to me that there is a really pressing need to amend the Clean
Neighbourhoods and Environment Act 2005 to regenerate our town centres.
We have all seen the headlines and know from our own experience the
dire state of our town centres across the country. As the Government in
their policy document setting up the Portas pilot regeneration schemes,
point
out,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000226" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000226">“our
high streets and town centres are facing serious challenges from
out-of-town shopping
centres”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13070536000197" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000197">The
document goes on to offer a way forward for the high streets. It
says:</hs_parafo><hs_quote UID="13070536000216" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000216">“They
need to offer an experience that goes beyond retail—the high
street should be a destination for
socialising”,</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000198" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000198">and
culture—a sentiment expressed by my noble friend Lord
Clancarty.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000136" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000136">It
seems strange that
just<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:34:43"></hs_TimeCode> as the
Government are spending taxpayers’ money to create this buzz,
local councils across the country are thwarting their work by strictly
controlling leafleting advertising cultural events in city centres.
According to the Manifesto report, mentioned by the two previous
speakers, councils are regulating spaces where you can leaflet and
levying a variety of charges. As the noble Lord, Lord Clement-Jones,
said, in some cases licences are extremely expensive and fines for
breaking the code can be up to £2,500, which, frankly, would
break a small venue. Of course, local authorities want to stop litter
and need to charge a small sum from distributors to pay for leaflets to
be cleared up and for the scheme to be administered. However, too many
councils charge exorbitant fees to license
leafleting.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000137" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000137">I
should like to draw the attention of your Lordships’ House to a
particularly blighted town, the centre of which is going through a hard
time, part of which I believe is due to the council’s policy on
leafleting. Wolverhampton is one of the town centres highlighted in the
Department for Communities and Local Government document as being in
need of special attention from the television retail guru Mary Portas,
who has chosen it as one of the initial 12 town centres to benefit from
her help. I am very glad that she has done so as the city centre is in
crisis. Thirty years ago it was prosperous, but now one in four retail
shops are empty and some streets look like scenes from a
post-apocalypse movie. Much of the damage was done several years ago
when compulsory purchase orders were put on a third of the town centre
commercial properties to make way for a £300 million shopping
centre. Guess what happened. Of course, the shopping centre was never
built and the properties were all blighted. Now there is not much
shopping and no shopping mall. Since then, the council has made
strenuous attempts to improve the situation. It has one of the fastest
turnaround times for planning applications and has announced a big
regeneration scheme for the town centre. However, as I have already
pointed out, many councils charge high prices for leaflet distribution
licences—much higher than the cost of clearing up the litter. By
doing so, I am sure they hope to raise revenue 
<?notus-xml column=1432?>from the scheme. However, Wolverhampton has one of the most expensive
leaflet distribution licences in the country. It used to cost
£250 per person. However—I would like to correct the
noble Lord—it has gone up to £300 per person for a year
and a one-off licence for one person for one evening costs £50.
Frankly, that is an absurd cost for a small venue which may want to
dish out only about 150 leaflets as that is all it can afford, and yet
that is the cost of the licence. This seems to be having a deleterious
effect on the city’s cultural venues and places for
socialising<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:37:47"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000138">I
spoke to Steve Harrington, the owner of the Fixxion warehouse project,
an arts, film and music venue in the town centre. Apparently, he
advises bands coming to play at his venue not even to try to hand out
leaflets. The cost of the licence is far too high and if they try to do
so without a licence, the council is extremely zealous in prosecuting
offenders and usually ends up fining the venue owners as they are the
easiest ones to get to. Mr Harrington explained to me that you must do
all you can to promote your event and advertise it but Facebook has
limited value. To get through to the people who might come to the
venue, you have to leaflet them face to face. He used to do that by
going to nearby venues, finding queues of would-be customers who might
want to come to his venue the following night and handing them
leaflets. Now he cannot do that and says that the inability to leaflet
is destroying the interaction between venues and the public. He says
that, as a result, clubs are leaving the area. Revolution, a
country-wide chain of music bars, has just left, saying that its branch
in the city had the worst takings in the country. He himself is
planning to shut up shop and go to nearby Birmingham, where apparently
the city council has a much more enlightened view of how to promote
small venues and the small bands coming to those venues. Of course, the
expense of leafleting is not the only problem these venues face, but it
is a definite problem all the
same.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000139">The only
people who seem to be able to afford to leaflet in Wolverhampton city
centre are the commercial leafleting companies acting on behalf of big
businesses, which have the money. They obviously bring revenue to the
council but at a heavy cost to regenerating the high street. However,
even that stream of money will be threatened if there are no customers
using the city centre for them to leaflet. I also spoke to Henry
Carver, who runs a non-political business group that is trying to
regenerate the city centre. He said:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="13070536000217" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000217">“We vie with
Hull as the unemployment capital of England. What we need to do is to
do anything to encourage businesses in the city so that people can be
employed”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000140" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000140">This
Bill would be one way of doing so. He does not want the council to have
to subsidise small businesses for leafleting but wants the cost to be
covered in some way. All the same, he believes that the current rules
are restrictive.</hs_parafo>
<hs_para UID="13070536000141" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000141">Wolverhampton<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:40:12"></hs_TimeCode>
is a bad case but, as the noble Lord, Lord Clement-Jones, said, the
situation is echoed in other city and town centres across the country,
from Leicester to Basildon. Freeing up the ability of cultural centres
to leaflet will certainly not solve all their problems. We have to do
everything possible to regenerate our high streets. They are the
centres of our communities 
<?notus-xml column=1433?>and the cultural engines of our country. To lose them will be to lose an
important part of our national life. I urge the Minister to help this
Bill to become
law<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:40:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/3A49C039583137478170F1BEA3004FE808F54404" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AL1-AL1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13070536000241" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000241">11.41
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000142" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000142"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Stevenson of Balmacara" PimsId="5801" UID="13070536000298" xid="2067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000298">Lord
Stevenson of Balmacara:</Member></B> My Lords, I thank the noble Lord,
Lord Clement-Jones, for introducing the Bill. He and I have been locked
in closed rooms a number of times recently, dealing with intellectual
property. It is nice to see that he is not a one-club golfer and has
other strings to his bow. I am sorry about the mixed metaphors. I am
reminded of the brilliant game that he played last Session when he
brought the Live Music Bill before your Lordships’ House. He
entranced us with his arguments there and attracted the attention and
support of the Government. He is clearly trying to do the same again
here. We wish him well with
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:41:23"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000143" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000143">I thank the other
speakers in the debate, which has been of high quality. I am
particularly grateful to the noble Earl, Lord Clancarty, and the noble
Viscount, Lord Colville, for bringing in the wider context, which is
important to this issue. After all, it is about the way in which we
want our city centres to operate, and they are in danger if the widest
possible range of activities cannot take place there to bring people
back to them and to use
them<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:41:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000144" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000144">It is clear that the
very excellent speech of the noble Lord, Lord Clement-Jones, which I
thought was one of the best that I have heard since I joined your
Lordships’ House, covered all the aspects that needed to be
brought into play. He did so with passion and rigorous argument
throughout. His point seems to be that the existing law is imperfectly
achieving its objectives. It disadvantages good and valuable work in
local areas, involving the arts, culture and social provision. As a
result, we all lose. It encourages commercialisation of activities that
depend on a more informal and relaxed use of space and the bringing in
of new groups and activities to refresh and innovate. It also does not
solve the litter problem that the legislation was intended to address.
As other noble Lords have said, other measures would probably be more
effective in that
regard<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:42:46"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000145" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000145">As was said, leaflets
are not litter until they are discarded. Perhaps there is a thought
there. It is surprising how widely the legislation has been used, and
one did not perhaps realise that until it was brought up in debate.
That seems to be counterintuitive in the age of the internet. One would
think that most of the groups and activities that we are talking about
might have used social media and others to attract their audiences.
However, it is clear from the evidence that the way in which this
activity operates involves a direct link with customers. There is a
vicious circle whereby if you cannot make contact by direct leafleting
you cannot grow the venue or activity to the extent that it would be
able to pay for a licence when that was
appropriate<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:43:34"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000146" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000146">The argument, of
course, is that it is not appropriate. The licences are not cheap and
their costs vary across the country. It is not surprising to hear that
Brighton is one of the most egregious examples. The Green Party would
obviously leap on to such a proposal that 
<?notus-xml column=1434?>could be dressed up as a way of trying to accentuate a green activity by
banning litter. However, it is a brave Government who attempt to
restrict the activities of the Women’s Institute. If that is
their purpose, I wish them
luck<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:44:04"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000147" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000147">The
Government have a responsibility to review the effectiveness of
legislation that has been passed, even legislation passed by a previous
Administration. It is clear that this law is causing difficulties in an
area that we all hold dear. I look forward to hearing the views of the
Minister in
response.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/0E4BB5D520BB85F1874779C90F704BF754758BA1" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AL2-AN1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13070536000242" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000242"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:44:20"></hs_TimeCode>11.44
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000148" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000148"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord De Mauley" PimsId="4732" UID="13070536000299" xid="1856" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000299">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Environment,
Food and Rural Affairs (Lord De Mauley):</Member></B> My Lords, let me
begin by thanking my noble friend, to whom I have listened
carefully—as I have listened to other noble Lords—for
bringing this issue to the attention of your Lordships.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000149" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000149">I clearly understand
that community events underpin many aspects of what creates the social
cohesion of our society, and one should never underestimate how
important they are in bringing people together. I strongly support such
endeavours. However, my noble friend will understand that my
ministerial interest stems from the potential by-product of littering
caused by advertising leaflets being dropped in public area. While I
agree that local authorities should not unduly interfere with the
organisation and promotion of these kinds of community events, it would
be wrong of me not to explain why I have some reservations about my
noble friend’s proposition.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000150" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000150">My noble
friend’s Bill seeks to limit the restrictions that local
authorities are presently able to impose on the distribution of free
printed matter in their areas of responsibility. As your Lordships will
be aware, local authorities have a statutory duty to keep their
relevant land free of litter and refuse under the Environmental
Protection Act 1990. The Clean Neighbourhoods and Environment Act 2005,
which the noble Lord, Lord Stevenson, generously admitted was put in
place by the previous Administration, subsequently gave local
authorities the power to restrict the distribution of free printed
matter such as leaflets and flyers in specified areas if the
distribution of such material is causing a problem.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000151" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000151">The Bill could
constrain those same local authorities that previously could utilise
this provision in the Clean Neighbourhoods and Environment Act. They
could argue that the positive action they have taken to reduce
littering will be undone because their resources will have to be
diverted once again into dealing with the extra littering that my noble
friend’s Bill could inadvertently
cause.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000152" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000152">On the
other hand, and in line with my noble friend’s train of thought,
I can say that the Anti-social Behaviour, Crime and Policing Bill,
which is currently being considered in the other place, will make some
changes to local authority powers in respect of litter which will
require us to review our accompanying guidance. I am happy to make an
offer to my noble friend that in the course of that review we will also
look for opportunities to review the guidance to local authorities on
their powers in respect of leafleting in 
<?notus-xml column=1435?>exactly the situation that he contemplates. We are willing to work with
the Manifesto Club and others to draw up best-practice guidelines. It
would be easy to present the local authority powers as an unnecessary
erosion of a citizens’ freedom. This is indeed the argument of
the Manifesto Club in its report of last year, <I>Leafleting: A
</I><I>Liberty</I><I> Lost</I><I>?</I>, which argues that leaflets
cause no more mess than burger wrappers or crisp packets and implies
that there are far more compelling reasons for the restriction of
leafleting.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000153" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000153">Perhaps
I may take your Lordships back to the 1990s, when trials of similar
powers to limit leafleting were run in London and Newcastle.
Westminster City Council had particular littering issues over the
distribution of free magazines in the Oxford Street area and, more
significantly, with the distribution of free material by language
schools. This in turn encouraged a range of other businesses such as
tattoo parlours, amusement arcades and nightclubs to do the same.
Westminster put up notices to highlight this issue but also hit the
problem at source by challenging those language schools that had not
registered with Companies House. This approach was welcomed by other
residents, businesses and visitors to the area.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000154" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000154">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:49:41"></hs_TimeCode>
leafleting problem in Newcastle centred on  a large build-up of
litter in the early hours of the morning, consisting mostly of flyers
advertising  bars and nightclubs. Since May 2002,
Newcastle’s licensing department, in consultation with local
trade representatives, has issued consents to enable individuals to
distribute flyers within the city, showing what I hope noble Lords will
accept is a constructive and helpful approach. These consents undergo
regular checks to ensure that individuals adhere to the conditions and,
if they do not, distributors risks having their flyers
confiscated.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000155" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000155">These trials showed
that the restriction of leafleting activity in specific problem areas
had a marked effect in both reducing litter and helping local
authorities to limit their street-cleansing costs. The evidence
gathered through these trials led to an efficient piece of drafting as
part of the Clean Neighbourhoods and Environment Act.
However<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:50:17"></hs_TimeCode>, that
does not mean that we have stood still.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000156" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000156">My noble
friend’s proposal would undermine local authorities’
ability to address a problem which they already know exists. With the
best will in the world, not everyone who is handed a leaflet or flyer
wants to keep it, and it is a sad fact that many people still think
that it is acceptable simply to drop the unwanted flyer a few paces
further down the street. Under current legislation, controls on
leafleting can be introduced only where there is evidence of a
pre-existing problem with leaflet litter. Without these controls, there
is a risk of the level of littering rising again in these areas, thus
increasing the costs to local authorities of complying with their
statutory duty to keep the streets clean. These costs would come at a
time when local authority budgets were already under pressure and so
would be likely to have a knock-on effect on the ability of local
authorities to deliver other local and community
services.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000157" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000157">The
current arrangements enable local authorities to develop appropriate
solutions to local issues. If a problem arises, local authorities have
the flexibility to 
<?notus-xml column=1436?>consider and consult on an approach which tackles the specific problem
and which does not unreasonably inconvenience law-abiding citizens. I
put it to your Lordships that the creation of a further exemption, as
proposed by my noble friend, would serve only to reduce the flexibility
that local authorities currently have to tailor their response to the
problem, and this would be directly contrary to this
Government’s commitment to
localism.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000158" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000158">As
my noble friend mentioned, exemptions exist  to the Clean
Neighbourhoods and Environment Act to protect well understood and
fundamental rights. A local authority cannot apply restrictions to
leaflets distributed for political purposes or for purposes of religion
or belief, or for or on behalf of a charity. Feedback from local
authorities is that they welcome clear delineation regarding to whom
these provisions
apply.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000159" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000159">However,
my noble friend seeks to extend the proposed definition of the events
to which the exemption would apply. My concern with extending the
exemption is that it could open the floodgates to commercial operators
putting on events that could potentially attract huge audiences from
far beyond the local community. While my noble friend paints a picture
of community events or performances by local amateur dramatic
societies, in some areas there may be numerous events taking
place—for example, in city centres—where the number of
leaflets frequently being dropped could be significant. This in itself
would create a problem for the local authority enforcement officers.
There is certainly no way of policing that only 600 people will see the
leaflet, especially now that information of this kind is able to go
global at the click of a
button.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000160" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000160">The
focus on leafleting within this debate should not distract us from
thinking about the overall issue of littering. In 2011-12, local
authorities spent a staggering £840 million on street cleansing,
and in the coalition we committed to working to reduce littering.
Littering is a criminal offence which imposes unnecessary costs on the
public purse and on society as a whole. Dealing with this supposedly
victimless crime takes away from valuable services money which could
otherwise be provided to the people who need them. We do not accept
that more legislation is the only answer to the problem of littering,
or even the best solution. If we are to tackle this problem
effectively, we need to change people’s
behaviour.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000161" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000161">It
would be remiss of me not to join the noble Lord, Lord Stevenson, in
drawing noble Lords’ attention to the role of digital
technology. Let us remember that leaflets and flyers are not the only
method of advertising events. The cultural and arts sector is often at
the forefront of the innovative use of technology. We encourage such
organisations to make full use of digital technology to promote their
offer, and indeed to join forces with other, similar organisations
to  share marketing costs. Arts Council England has 
made money available for research and development in digital
innovation, which could include promoting events through digital mobile
technology. This approach  has the additional benefit of
reducing paper use, which is inevitably better for the
environment.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1437?><hs_para UID="13070536000162" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000162">I am sure that even if
my noble friend does not tweet himself, he will have dipped into his
own party’s Twitter account and seen at first hand the speed at
which a message can be conveyed via a digital platform. Many
forward-thinking promoters are increasingly using media such as the
quick response, or QR, code, in which interested parties use their
smartphones to scan an advertised barcode to gain information about
promotions or to book tickets for events. Surely these and other
emerging and exciting digital tools are the way forward, and the
old-fashioned paper leaflet or flyer will soon become an exhibit on the
“Antiques
Roadshow”.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000163" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000163">My
noble friend raised the issue of charging by local authorities. These
powers are not about raising money for local authorities or placing
barriers in the way of grass-roots arts organisations. The licensing
fees that local councils can charge for permission to distribute
leaflets must not exceed the cost of administering the licensing
scheme. Not all councils charge a fee for a licence to distribute
leaflets, and many councils have no restrictions at
all<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:56:55"></hs_TimeCode>. My noble
friend mentioned some which, he suggested, were charging quite a lot of
money. I am happy to look at those at the upper end  of what he
mentioned in case they exceed the cost of administering the power. To
be clear, they can charge only the reasonable costs of enforcing the
powers under Schedule 3A that do not extend to
clean-up<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:57:20"></hs_TimeCode>.
Associated with that point, we have made informal soundings of councils
across England. Pretty well all of them that responded expressed
concern about the extra costs of cleaning up the litter generated and
the damage to the
environment<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:57:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000164">The noble Earl, Lord
Clancarty, asked me to pass on the content of this debate and the Bill
to the DCMS. I am happy to say to him that we have certainly been in
touch about this debate, and he is quite right that we should do
so<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:57:54"></hs_TimeCode>. The noble
Earl also referred to the possibility of more bins being put out to
deal with the problem. Through the guidance that we have published for
local authorities, we are encouraging them to look at their bin
provision and to think about where they might want to provide
additional
facilities<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:58:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000165" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000165">Therefore, I assure
noble Lords that it is not the aim of the powers in the existing
legislation to impose unintentional, unnecessary and burdensome
restrictions on the organisation of community and cultural events,
which we see as very important. We want to see vibrant, thriving
communities with a strong arts and cultural scene, and we would
certainly be concerned if we heard that local authorities were using
these powers inappropriately or
disproportionately<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:58:42"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000166" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000166">I hope that my noble
friend is pleased by my offer, in the course of the review of local
authority guidance in the context of the Anti-social Behaviour, Crime
and Policing Bill, to look for opportunities to review guidance to
local authorities, specifically on their powers in respect of
leafleting, and that he is pleased that we are willing to work with the
Manifesto Club and others to draw up best-practice
guidelines.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13070536000167" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000167">I
do not believe that the legislation as it stands places undue
restrictions on civil liberties; rather,  it enables local
authorities to limit their exposure to 
<?notus-xml column=1438?>unnecessary street-cleansing expenses and to develop controls which are
appropriate to their local circumstances. I therefore express
significant reservations about my noble friend’s Bill, which has
the potential both to increase local authority costs and to make
existing controls harder to enforce.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000168" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000168"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:59:35"></hs_TimeCode><B><Member ContinuationText="The Earl of Clancarty" PimsId="2608" UID="13070536000300" xid="2038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000300">The
Earl of Clancarty:</Member></B> My Lords, in terms of the exemptions,
does the Minister believe that artistic expression is not as important
as religious and political
expression<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T11:59:51"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000169" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000169"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord De Mauley" PimsId="4732" UID="13070536000301" xid="1856" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000301">Lord
De Mauley:</Member></B> I hoped I had made my position clear on that
point. I see cultural and artistic expression as extremely
important<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:00:01"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/2AB8C28361C6BCD1532F260C8A131E890A1A6AFD" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AN2-AO</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13070536000243" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000243">Noon</hs_time><hs_para UID="13070536000170" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000170"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Clement-Jones" PimsId="2634" UID="13070536000302" xid="1164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000302">Lord
Clement-Jones:</Member></B> My Lords, I thank all noble Lords who have
spoken. In particular, I thank the noble Earl, Lord Clancarty, who
really got into the detail of the local arts scene, which he knows so
much about, and the noble Viscount, Lord Colville, who has done
extremely interesting research into the Wolverhampton situation, which
is replicated up and  down the country. Taking an example in
that way becomes very powerful. I also thank the noble Lord, Lord
Stevenson, for his support and his interrogation of why we have this
legislation despite the fact that, as he acknowledged, these provisions
were passed under the previous Government but have had these unintended
consequences<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:00:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000171" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000171">I
thank the Minister for his reply. He had a pretty miserable hand to
play in this debate. It had some positive elements but was broadly
disappointing. One of his phrases, I think, was that he would be
concerned to hear that the powers were being used disproportionately.
There is a thick booklet from the Manifesto Club, which details in
extenso all the ways in which these powers are being used
disproportionately. There are ways of playing a miserable hand but I
can tell the Minister that he did not turn it into a silk
purse<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:01:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000172" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000172">I
cannot help feeling that if a different department were
involved—if the DCLG or the DCMS, praise the Lord, were to have
responsibility for this legislation—the response would have been
very different, as it was, of course, in such a positive way to my Live
Music Bill last year. We really have to lift our eyes from the pavement
and noble Lords speaking in the debate made that very clear. I am
really disappointed that Defra seems to regard the faint risk of extra
litter as more important than our cultural and community
life<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:02:31"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000173" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000173">The Minister raised a
number of objections, including the claim that it will lead to
increased street-cleansing costs and divert resources for local
government. It is probable that the width of definition of live
entertainment underlies what the noble Lord said, as well as in terms
of opening the floodgates to all the commercial operators and
McDonald’s going mad all over our streets. Other objections in
discussions have been made, including that it is difficult to say in
advance what size an audience will be. But that is absolutely standard
in health and safety, licensing and so on. It is not an
issue<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:03:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=1439?><hs_para UID="13070536000174" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000174">In the debate, the
Minister set us the task of changing human behaviour. Let us start with
small steps. I do not think that, in order to defend culture and
community life at local level, I first have to change human behaviour
to justify this very small but significant Private Member’s
Bill. Then we all have to be beamed up in some way. I do not know
whether we have any “Star Trek” enthusiasts around here,
but let us all hang on a star and get digital. We can all use Twitter,
e-mail and so on but physical bits of paper handed out to people who
happen to be in the right place at the right time is extraordinarily
important<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:04:15"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070536000175" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000175">On the cost of litter
collection, when the original leafleting restrictions were introduced,
the Government’s impact assessment said that the leafleting
licensing schemes might or might not save councils money because there
would be costs to set it up. It is therefore highly moot whether in a
particular case a licensing scheme is cost-effective and, therefore,
whether its demise would cost anything in certain cases. The impact
assessment said
that,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13070536000227" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000227">“the
total set-up cost to local authorities would be between £450,000
and £750,000; and taking account of the costs of enforcement and
the cleaning costs saved, on an annual basis there would be somewhere
between a net cost of £37,500 and a net cost saving of
£525,000”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13070536000199" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000199">We
all know what impact assessments are like across government, which may
sound particularly broad-brushed. I do not believe that those figures
are any more reliable than the dire consequences the Minister has
predicted in this case. It goes on to
say:</hs_parafo><hs_quote UID="13070536000218" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000218">“This
illustrates that it is not certain whether there would be a net
financial cost or benefit to this
measure”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000200" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000200">If
they were uncertain then, I am sure that they are uncertain
now<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:05:34"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000176" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000176">We
then got into the nether regions of tattoo parlours, free magazines,
night clubs, bars and so on. Let us throw the kitchen sink at this
problem. I can assure  the Minister that the Bill is not
designed to deal with tattoo parlours. As the noble Viscount, Lord
Colville, made plain, there are additional economic benefits which
outweigh the disbenefits of a little bit of extra litter from a poetry
club or a comedy store. The noble Viscount demonstrated exactly those
points<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:06:17"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000177" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000177">As
a result of the Bill, local businesses and cultural activity would
almost certainly thrive. As I have mentioned, Brighton audiences have
plummeted. If the Brighton music scene, for instance, returned to its
former size, more people would come to Brighton, spend more money, the
council’s arts budget would go further and so on. Surely, in the
light of the benefits of deregulation, is it not worth the
candle<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:06:45"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000178" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000178">As
to the second objection—the question of the width of
“live entertainment”—as I said, we can clearly
work on the definition. Amendments could be agreed 
<?notus-xml column=1440?>in Committee if there was the political will. As regards the size of
audience issue, this works for licensing so why not for leafleting. If
that does not find favour  in terms of audience, it could find
favour in terms of capacity. The term capacity is used in other
forms  of legislation, such as that on health and
safety<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:07:23"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000179" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000179">However,
I am heartened by part of the Minister’s response. He seems to
accept that there is a problem. He may not think that there is enough
of a problem—I am sure he has not read the Manifesto
Club’s report and I urge him to do so—but he has
undertaken to  sit down and talk about it with the Manifesto
Club.  I hope he will also sit down with DCLG and DCMS. I have
seen a ministerial letter from the Creative Industries Minister to that
effect in the DCMS and I welcome it. I hope that revised guidance will
be agreed for the application of these provisions in the way that he
said<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:08:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000180" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000180">We
need to make the Minister’s assurances concrete. Is it an
absolutely firm commitment that the guidance will be changed? When will
meetings take place? Can we expect to agree new draft guidance? When
can we do that? When will this be consulted on? When can we expect it
to be implemented? There are a number of concrete issues and I hope the
Minister will follow that up in writing after the
debate<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:08:39"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070536000181" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000181">I
wish to end by returning to the time when the 2005 Act went through and
the actions of the Labour Minister, Alun Michael, for whom I had great
respect as a Minister. His original outline of the religious,
charitable and political exemptions emphasised that they were necessary
to protect human rights and political expression. He
said:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13070536000219" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000219">“The
purpose of the exception is to ensure that the human rights of
individuals and their legitimate political and democratic activities
are not affected by the provisions. By allowing the exemptions, we
protect the rights of freedom of expression and freedom of thought,
conscience and religion”.—[<I>Official Report</I>,
Commons, Clean Neighbourhoods and Environmental Bill Committee,
20/1/05; col.
143.]</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13070536000201" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000201">This
shows that, contrary to the localism argument used by Defra, exemptions
are necessary to protect the rights of different groups. It was not all
left to council’s
discretion<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-05T12:09:28"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13070536000182" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000182">Surely
grass-roots cultural expression needs to be similarly protected. It
makes cultural, social and economic sense and I look forward to further
discussions with the Minister. I ask the House to give this small but
significant Bill a Second
Reading.</hs_para><hs_Procedure UID="13070536000307" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000307">Bill
read a second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure><hs_Procedure UID="13070536000308" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-0001.htm#13070536000308">House
adjourned at 12.10
pm.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment></System><System type="WMS" ColStart="95"><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/1AA056D432477F7BCFED2588D73DAA04303D1816" __version__="1.2"><Header><House>0</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date="5 July 2013">Friday
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>Header-9-177</Section><TransformationVersion>0.5</TransformationVersion></Header><Body><hs_HoL UID="13070537000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000002">Written
Statements</hs_HoL><hs_date UID="13070537000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000001"><I>Friday
5 July
2013</I></hs_date></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/8EA97E049A157396C06C99945E43107ED415A021" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>3</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>LordsWMSSection</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070537000046" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000046">Azelle
Rodney</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13070537000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000003"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord McNally" PimsId="1843" UID="13070537000041" xid="1331" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000041">The
Minister of State, Ministry of Justice (Lord McNally):</Member></B> My
right honourable friend the Lord Chancellor and Secretary of State for
Justice (Chris Grayling) has made the following Written Ministerial
Statement.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000004">Sir
Christopher Holland has today published the report of the inquiry which
he has conducted under the Inquiries Act 2005 into the death of Azelle
Rodney. The inquiry’s terms of reference
were:</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000005">“To ascertain by
inquiring how, where and in what circumstances Azelle Rodney
came by his death on 30 April 2005 and then to make any such
recommendations as may seem
appropriate.”</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000006">The
Metropolitan Police and the Independent Police Complaints Commission
will consider the Inquiry’s findings and recommendations
carefully and will respond
appropriately.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000007">I
would like to take this opportunity to record my appreciation to Sir
Christopher and his team for all the work they have done over the last
three years in conducting the
inquiry.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070537000047" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000047">Banks:
British Business
Bank</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13070537000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000008"><B><Member ContinuationText="Viscount Younger of Leckie" PimsId="4709" UID="13070537000042" xid="2037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000042">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Business,
Innovation and Skills (Viscount Younger of Leckie):</Member></B> My Rt.
Hon Friend, the Secretary of State for Business, Innovation and Skills
(Dr Vince Cable), has today made the following
statement;</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000009">I
would like to update the House on progress made to set up a new British
Business Bank to support the provision of finance to small and
medium-sized firms in the UK.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000010">Inadequate access to
finance remains one of the biggest risks to the UK’s economic
recovery. The business bank will manage £3.9bn of Government
resources and bring together management, budgets, spending authorities
and the power to alter or create new schemes into one place.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000011">I announced in December
the formation of an Advisory Group, led by Sir Peter Burt, former chief
executive of the Bank of Scotland, which would advise Government in the
design phase of establishing the business bank. Under Sir
Peter’s leadership, the group has made rapid progress. Their
recommendations and overview paper are attached to this statement and
cover the following issues:</hs_para> <hs_WAIndent>• Coverage of
the Business Bank’s
activities</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>• Role of wider business
advice and the links to the Business
Bank</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>• Corporate form of the Business
Bank</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>• Performance
measures</hs_WAIndent> 
<?notus-xml column=96?><hs_WAIndent>• Building on the existing capacities in Government
and its agency</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>• Resource
allocation</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>• Risk management
systems</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>• Use of
evidence</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>• Leadership including the
recruitment of the Chair</hs_WAIndent>
<hs_para UID="13070537000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000012">I warmly welcome the
Group’s advice and have today begun the recruitment of the Chair
and Senior Independent Director for the British Business Bank. They
will have the unique opportunity to bring together the wide range of
finance interventions that will help support the UK’s businesses
and economic
recovery.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000013">I
would also note that the Business Bank Investment Programme launched on
10 April has received a number of applications for funding. I hope to
be able to announce the first investments in the
Autumn.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000014">The
Advisory’s Group signed recommendations letter and overview
paper mentioned above, will be placed in the Libraries of the
House.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070537000048" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000048">Elections:
Individual Electoral
Registration</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13070537000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000015"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Wallace of Saltaire" PimsId="4501" UID="13070537000043" xid="1482" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000043">Lord
Wallace of Saltaire:</Member></B> My Honourable friend the Minister for
Political and Constitutional Reform (Chloe Smith) has made the
following Written Ministerial
Statement:</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000016">I
am pleased to announce that the Government is making available up to
4.2 million pounds this year to maximise the rate of voter registration
ahead of the transition to Individual Electoral Registration in 2014.
Organisations, neighbourhoods and communities have been asked to come
up with ideas to get people involved in the democratic process locally
and nationally, with the best ideas being awarded funding from the new
innovation fund. I welcome Parliament’s scrutiny and
encouragement of such ideas, and urge parliamentarians to consider what
could be done in their areas and
constituencies.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000017">Funding
is also being made available to local authorities who have solid and
creative ideas to get as many people onto the electoral register as
possible in their area.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000018">The introduction of
Individual Electoral Registration (IER) in 2014 will modernise our
electoral registration system, removing the notion of the head of the
household being responsible for the registration of others. IER will
also introduce online registration making it more convenient for people
to register to vote while also delivering a register that is more
secure and engenders greater trust in politics.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000019">A major benefit of IER
is that electors will be individually contacted and encouraged to
register. This will enable local authorities to aim to get the maximum
number of people on the register, including hard to reach and
under-registered groups.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000020">Currently some people,
such as those in shared housing and frequent home movers are some of
the most under-represented on the register.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=97?><hs_para UID="13070537000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000021">The funding will be used
to support a range of initiatives to be carried out by local
authorities and other organisations, such as the Voluntary, Charity and
Social Enterprise sector, which will work together with the aim of
increasing levels of voter registration among under-registered groups.
These include:</hs_para><hs_WAIndent>• The targeted canvassing
fund: a fund which will enable Electoral Registration Officers to carry
out intensified canvassing activity in areas with a high proportion of
under-registration.</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>•
The ERO registration fund: a fund which will support
proposals for activities from Electoral Registration Officers who will
use their knowledge of the needs of their local populations to
customise their measures</hs_WAIndent> <hs_WAIndent>• Innovation
Fund: We will be looking to fund innovative bottom up
approaches to increase representation of under-registered groups (URGs)
on the electoral register. We are particularly interested in new
innovative approaches to engage communities and increase voter
registration.</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>•
Schools Outreach: We will be looking for
organisations to deliver a set lesson framework, Rock Enrol, which has
been developed and piloted with Bite the Ballot, to a number of schools
across England and Wales. This is also available to organisations in
Scotland, although we will be looking to ensure that proposals take
account of planned activity in schools ahead of the independence
referendum.</hs_WAIndent><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070537000049" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000049">NHS
England:
Mandate</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13070537000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000022"><B><Member ContinuationText="Earl Howe" PimsId="1035" UID="13070537000044" xid="1749" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000044">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department of Health (Earl
Howe):</Member></B> My Rt hon Friend the Secretary of State for Health
(Jeremy Hunt) has made the following written ministerial
statement.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000023">Today
the Government is launching the consultation on the refresh of the
Mandate to NHS England for 2014/15. The consultation will close on 27
September in readiness for the publication of the refreshed Mandate in
the autumn to fit with the NHS planning round for 2014/15.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000024">The Mandate sets the
Government’s ambitions for the NHS as well as the funding
available to achieve and deliver the kind of care people need and
expect. The first Mandate set an ambitious agenda and was published in
November 2012. It covered the period April 2013-March 2015. The
Government expects NHS England to demonstrate significant progress
against all 24 objectives by March 2015 and will hold them to account
for doing so. The Health and Social Care Act 2012 requires the Mandate
to be reviewed on an annual basis to ensure that it remains up to date.
It is important to provide the NHS with stability and continuity of
purpose and we therefore propose to carry forward all the existing 24
objectives.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000025">At
the same time, the scale of the challenge facing the NHS and wider
health and care system is becoming increasingly clear. There have been
crucial developments and new evidence that has emerged since the
publication of the first Mandate, which calls on Government and NHS
England to act. The key proposed changes reflect these core
priorities:</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=98?><hs_WAIndent>- the actions being taken forward by NHS England in
response to the Francis Report to transform the care people
receive;</hs_WAIndent> <hs_WAIndent>- working with
NHS England to develop a vulnerable older people plan, which will
improve support for older people and those with long term conditions,
particularly through reform of primary care given their pivotal role
within communities; and</hs_WAIndent> <hs_WAIndent>- the
need for the NHS to contribute to securing the
recovery of the economy and make better use of resources in light of
the challenging fiscal
climate.</hs_WAIndent><hs_para UID="13070537000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000026">On
the second of these priorities, the Government is also launching today
dedicated engagement on the vulnerable older people plan, working
jointly with NHS England. The engagement will seek views from staff,
patients and the public on how to achieve the ambition of how more
integrated out-of-hospital care, building on the strong tradition and
values of the family doctor.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000027">In addition to the
three priorities, the Government is also proposing to make a number of
targeted changes to the current objectives which are thought to be
essential to deliver the improvements in people’s care. The
consultation document sets out where the Government is proposing to
make these changes for the period April 2014-March 2015.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000028" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000028">The Government welcomes
views on the proposals and invites comments through the consultation
process.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000029"><I>Refreshing the
Mandate to NHS England: 2014-15 Consultation</I> has been placed in the
Library. Copies are available to hon Members from the Vote Office and
to noble Lords from the Printed Paper
Office.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070537000050" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000050">Transport:
Bus
Services</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13070537000030" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000030"><B><Member ContinuationText="Earl Attlee" PimsId="3822" UID="13070537000045" xid="1061" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000045">Earl
Attlee:</Member></B> My Honourable friend the Parliamentary Under
Secretary of State for Transport (Norman Baker) has made the following
Ministerial
Statement.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000031" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000031">I
am pleased to announce today our plans to reform the bus subsidy
system. We intend to implement a package of measures designed to
improve services by making the subsidy provided to bus companies - Bus
Service Operators Grant (BSOG) - more targeted and
accountable.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000032">In
2012 there were 4.7 billion bus passenger boardings made in England and
over 60% of all public transport trips were made on local buses. Given
the crucial role the bus network plays in supporting social inclusion,
linking people to places of commerce and providing employers with
access to labour markets, buses deserve to be recognised as the
backbone of our public transport system and key to a healthy, growing
economy.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000033" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000033">However,
despite pockets of strong growth, overall bus patronage has been in
long-term decline. Added to this, the way in which subsidy is used to
support the bus market has become increasingly poorly targeted. This
economic context, however, makes it imperative to push for improved bus
services that are more locally accountable and provide better value for
passenger and taxpayer. This is why we intend to reform bus subsidy by
making the following changes:</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=99?><hs_WAIndent>• creation of a new local government
fund—Better Bus Areas;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>•
devolution to Transport for London/the Greater London Authority of the
BSOG paid to London bus operators who operate services under contract
to TfL;</hs_WAIndent> <hs_WAIndent>•
tightening the existing rules defining which bus
services can claim BSOG, so that the available funding is put to the
best possible use;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>•
paying BSOG to local authorities, rather than
operators, where funding relates to services they
support.</hs_WAIndent><hs_para UID="13070537000034" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000034">The
first three of these changes will take effect from 1 October this year.
However, I have decided to allow more time for local authorities and
operators to prepare for the paying of BSOG for supported services to
authorities outside London. Therefore this change
will not come into force until 1 January
2014.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000035" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000035">We
consulted widely on these proposals in late 2012, and our consultation
response which we are publishing today—copies of which are being
placed in the library of the house—sets out the
Government’s commitment to each of the above measures.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13070537000036" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000036">Devolving funding for
supported services to local authorities will give communities more
control over how money is spent. At the same time, I am keen this
change should not cause temporary instability to local services. The
majority of both bus operators and local authorities have asked for an
extended period of ring fencing, and I believe that the case is a
strong one. The funds which we devolve will, therefore, be ringfenced
until the end of 2016/17. In turn, we expect local authorities to take
due account of the tendered BSOG foregone by bus companies operating
non-commercial services in managing existing contractual arrangements
with them for these services and when agreeing new contracts.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=100?><hs_para UID="13070537000037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000037">A further key reform is
the introduction of Better Bus Areas. I was delighted to designate
Sheffield as the first BBA in February. Other local authorities had
until today to bid to become BBAs with announcements on further
designations to be made this autumn. BBAs offer an opportunity to
explore how bus subsidy can be better used by local authorities,
working with local operators, to attract more people onto buses and
ensure better value for the
taxpayer.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000038">Management
of bus services in London is the responsibility of Transport for London
and most of the substantial funding from central Government to support
transport in London is currently paid to TfL in a single grant. In line
with this, from October a sum broadly equivalent to the BSOG for London
services will be paid directly to TfL and the Greater London
Authority.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000039" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000039">Finally,
BSOG was designed to support local bus services, but over time a wider
range of services than was intended laid claim to some of the subsidy.
So, we have tightened the rules so that certain services are no longer
eligible for BSOG. In particular, the removal of eligibility from rail
replacement buses will also serve as a message to the rail industry
that we expect them to use trains rather than buses wherever
possible.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13070537000040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705-wms0001.htm#13070537000040">The
Government recognises that this package of reforms represents
significant change for the industry. Local authority and bus industry
views have therefore been vital to the development of our proposals and
I am grateful for the input we have received. The reforms announced
today mark an opportunity to reshape the support we provide for the bus
industry for the better, using a long-standing subsidy in a targeted
manner in order to improve services, encourage partnership working and
deliver better value for money. I look forward to the improvements that
these reforms will
bring.</hs_para></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Writtens" ColStart="249"><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/05F37E2AA47EE5B7B63C523ABD626AA3CC7A6303" __version__="1.2"><Header><House>0</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date="5 July 2013">Friday
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>Header-10-887</Section><TransformationVersion>0.5</TransformationVersion></Header><Body><hs_HoL UID="13070538000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000002">Written
Answers</hs_HoL><hs_date UID="13070538000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000001"><I>Friday
5 July
2013</I></hs_date></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/BFD9F3EAF035DC038C510E1FD8BF91656046C924" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>1</System><Sitting short-date=" 5 July 2013">Friday,
5 July
2013</Sitting><Section>Section</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070538000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000019">Children:
Disabled
Children</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13070538000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000021">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Touhig" PimsId="5769" UID="13070538000011" xid="2045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000011">Lord
Touhig</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13070538000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000007">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what is their estimate of
the number of children with one or more
disability who live in overcrowded
accommodation. <hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1099]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13070538000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000003"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Freud" PimsId="5439" UID="13070538000012" xid="2007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000012">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Work and
Pensions (Lord Freud):</Member> The information is not readily
available and has not previously been published as official statistics.
We will consider whether it is feasible to produce the statistics
requested within the disproportionate cost limit, and if so, will issue
them in an official statistics release in accordance with the Code of
Practice for Official
Statistics.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13070538000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000020">UK
Export
Finance</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Questions</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13070538000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000022">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Stevenson of Balmacara" PimsId="5801" UID="13070538000013" xid="2067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000013">Lord
Stevenson of Balmacara</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13070538000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000008">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether UK Export Finance conducted an
assessment of the environmental, social and human rights impacts of
London Mining Company Ltd's iron ore mine in Sierra Leone before
guaranteeing a £4.6 million loan; and whether they
will publish any such
assessment. <hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1232]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13070538000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000004"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Green of Hurstpierpoint" PimsId="5871" UID="13070538000014" xid="2091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000014">The
Minister of State, Department for Business, Innovation and Skills &amp;
Foreign and Commonwealth Office (Lord Green of
Hurstpierpoint):</Member> It is The Export Credit Guarantees’
Department (ECGD’s) policy to comply with all International
Agreements which apply to the operations of Export Credit Agencies
(ECAs). This includes the <I>OECD Recommendation on Common Approaches
for Officially Supported Export Credits and Environmental and Social
Due Diligence</I> (the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and
Development (OECD) Common Approaches), which informs the way in which
member ECAs should address the environmental social and human rights
(ESHR) impacts of projects they are asked to support. The support
provided was under ECGD’s Contract Bond Support Scheme. And the
OECD Common Approaches does not require an ESHR impact assessment to be
carried out in respect of this category of export
transaction.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=250?><hs_TabledBy UID="13070538000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000023">Asked by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Stevenson of Balmacara" PimsId="5801" UID="13070538000015" xid="2067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000015">Lord
Stevenson of Balmacara</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13070538000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000009">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether UK Export Finance conducted an
assessment of the environmental, social and human rights impacts of the
supply of intelligence equipment to the government of Indonesia's
Ministry of Defence before guaranteeing a £4.2 million loan; and
whether they will publish any such
assessment.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1233]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13070538000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000005"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Green of Hurstpierpoint" PimsId="5871" UID="13070538000016" xid="2091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000016">Lord
Green of Hurstpierpoint:</Member> It is Export Credit Guarantees
Department’s (ECGD’s) policy to comply with all
International Agreements which apply to the operations of Export Credit
Agencies (ECAs). This includes the <I>OECD Recommendation on Common
Approaches for Officially Supported Export Credits
and Environmental and Social Due Diligence</I> (the Organisation for
Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Common Approaches), which
informs the way in which member ECAs should address the environmental
social and human rights (ESHR) impacts of projects they are asked to
support. The OECD Common Approaches does not require an ESHR impact
assessment to be carried out in respect of this category of export
transaction.</hs_para><hs_TabledBy UID="13070538000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000024">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Stevenson of Balmacara" PimsId="5801" UID="13070538000017" xid="2067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000017">Lord
Stevenson of Balmacara</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13070538000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000010">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether an assessment of the environmental,
social and human rights impacts of Reliance Industries Ltd will be
conducted by UK Export Finance in relation to the Jamnagar petroleum
and petrochemical complex in India; and whether any such assessment
will be published before committing UK Export Finance support to the
project.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1234]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13070538000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000006"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Green of Hurstpierpoint" PimsId="5871" UID="13070538000018" xid="2091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130705w0001.htm#13070538000018">Lord
Green of Hurstpierpoint:</Member> It is Export Credit Guarantees
Department (ECGD’s) policy to comply with all International
Agreements which apply to the operations of Export Credit Agencies
(ECAs). This includes the<I> OECD Recommendation on Common
Approaches for Officially Supported Export Credits
and Environmental and Social Due Diligence </I>(the Organisation for
Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Common Approaches), which
informs the way in which member ECAs should address the environmental
social and human rights (ESHR) impacts of projects they are asked to
support. A review of the potential ESHR impacts on the Jamnagar
Petroleum and Petrochemical complex will be carried out to inform a
decision, still to be taken, as to whether or not ECGD should support
exports to this project. If support is provided UKEF will publish on
its website a notice of support with information about the ESHR impacts
and applicable international
standards.</hs_para></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Index"><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/Index/2E44223D5D0AE1F3FA00A7A98FB53A1CC797B006" __version__="1.2"><Index cdate="12" cday="Friday" cmonth="July" cyear="2013" date="5" day="Friday" issue="30" maxparts="1" month="July" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="746" year="2013"><tocdate col="WS95">Friday 5 July 2013</tocdate><title>ALPHABETICAL
INDEX TO WRITTEN
STATEMENTS</title><level1 col="WS95">Azelle
Rodney</level1><level1 col="WS95">Banks:
British Business
Bank</level1><level1 col="WS96">Elections:
Individual Electoral
Registration</level1><level1 col="WS97">NHS
England:
Mandate</level1><level1 col="WS98">Transport:
Bus Services</level1><tocdate col="WS95">Friday 5
July 2013</tocdate><title>ALPHABETICAL INDEX TO WRITTEN
ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA249">Children: Disabled
Children</level1><level1 col="WA249">UK
Export Finance</level1><title>NUMERICAL INDEX TO
WRITTEN
ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA249">[HL1099]</level1><level1 col="WA249">[HL1232]</level1><level1 col="WA250">[HL1233]</level1><level1 col="WA250">[HL1234]</level1></Index></Fragment></System><System type="Back_Cover"><?date 2013-07-05?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_05_PT_1/Cover/0AE1F3FA00A7A98FB53A1CC797B0062E44223D5D" __version__="1.3"><Contents cdate="12" cday="Friday" cmonth="July" cyear="2013" date="5" day="Friday" issue="30" maxparts="1" month="July" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="746" year="2013"><citicont1 col="1407">Extension
of Franchise (House of Lords) Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="1423">Cultural
and Community Distribution Deregulation Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="WS 95">Written
Statements</citicont1><citicont1 col="WA 249">Written
Answers</citicont1></Contents></Fragment></System></House></HansardDoc>