<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><HansardDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print file:/C:/Users/edwardsc/Desktop/LordsHansard_Print2008.xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.parliament.uk/lords/hansard/print"><House name="Lords"><System type="Cover"><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/Cover/84D54C2B6BF40BCA22CDF95F0C3C8B3F22212C6D" __version__="1.5"><Cover-wrapper><Cover bcoveruri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/Cover/F95F0C3C8B3F22212C6D84D54C2B6BF40BCA22CD" cdate="26" cday="Friday" cmonth="July" cyear="2013" date="19" day="Friday" htmlBackCoverUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/Html_Index/84D54C2B6B3F22212C6DF40BCA22CDF95F0C3C8B" htmlIndexUri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/Html_Index/F95F0C3C8B84D54C2B6BF40BCA22CD3F22212C6D" indexuri="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/Index/F40BCA22CDF95F0C3C8B3F22212C6D84D54C2B6B" issue="39" maxparts="1" month="July" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" type="back" volume="747" year="2013"><Contents><hs_FPNormal>Littering
from Vehicles Bill [HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>981</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Alan Turing
(Statutory Pardon) Bill [HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>1006</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Clean
Neighbourhoods and Environment (Amendment) Bill
[HL]</hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormalIndent><I>Second
Reading</I>1024</hs_FPNormalIndent><hs_FPNormal>Written
Statements<I>WS 149</I></hs_FPNormal><hs_FPNormal>Written
Answers<I>WA
153</I></hs_FPNormal></Contents></Cover></Cover-wrapper></Fragment></System><System type="Debate" ColStart="981"><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/82D981C81DFB5526006905BEFA2762D17D3AA3E9" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AA-AC1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_Venue UID="13071970000406" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000406">House
of Lords</hs_Venue><hs_date UID="13071970000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000001">Friday, 19 July
2013.</hs_date><hs_time UID="13071970000322" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000322">10
am</hs_time><hs_Procedure UID="13071970000400" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000400">Prayers—read by
the Lord Bishop of
Norwich.</hs_Procedure><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071970000397" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000397">Littering
from Vehicles Bill [HL]</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13071970000323" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000323">10.06
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13071970000403" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000403">Moved by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Marlesford" PimsId="1697" UID="13071970000356" xid="1138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000356">Lord
Marlesford</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071970000353" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000353">That the Bill be read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13071970000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000002"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Marlesford" PimsId="1697" UID="13071970000357" xid="1138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000357">Lord
Marlesford:</Member></B> My Lords, in moving the Second Reading of this
Bill, I would like to say how grateful I am for the widespread
interest, help and support that I have received, especially
from the Campaign to Protect Rural England, of which I was once
chairman. I should declare an interest as president of the Suffolk
Preservation Society, and perhaps also as chairman of Marlesford Parish
Council, whose seven members have for many years been picking up litter
in our village, especially from the A12 which unfortunately still
passes through the centre of our community. However, we hope that
Marlesford will be bypassed when the third nuclear power station is
constructed at
Sizewell<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:07:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000003">We English, to our
shame, are an appallingly messy
nation<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:07:09"></hs_TimeCode>, which is
why this Bill is needed. Let me first outline its purpose. It is to
support local authorities in tackling the serious problem of littering
from vehicles. The Bill proposes a simple and modest change to the law
to achieve this. It would make three substantive changes to the law. In
brief, it would introduce a civil penalty for littering from vehicles,
make the registered keeper of a vehicle from which the litter has been
thrown the automatic recipient of the penalty, and require local
authorities to publish details of the contracts they give relating to
litter clearance. The Bill is designed to deliver behaviour change. It
is primarily a deterrent and we would not expect lots of penalty
notices to be issued.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000004">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:08:14"></hs_TimeCode>
Minister, my noble friend Lord De Mauley, himself recognised the
problem of roadside rubbish, as he put it, at the conference of the
Chartered Institute of Wastes Management in June this year. It is
estimated that seven out of the 10 pieces of litter blighting the
countryside are dropped from cars. In 2011, some 9 million
drivers threw litter from their cars. The cost of clearing up roadside
litter contributes to a bill for local councils that in 2010-11 reached
£863 million, not to mention additional spending to clear up
litter along motorways and trunk roads. The Bill has the support of the
Campaign to Protect Rural England, and since the last election more
than 1,000 members have written to their MP to request action in this
area. A 2012 poll showed that 75% of the members of the AA believe that
roadside litter is a serious problem. The Local Government Association
supports the provisions of the Bill that relate to the creation of a
new civil penalty for roadside
litter<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:09:29"></hs_TimeCode>ing.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=982?><hs_para UID="13071970000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000005">I shall now explain the
Bill. Clause 1 provides that a littering contravention has
taken place if a person throws litter from a vehicle, and it allows a
civil enforcement officer to impose a civil penalty if this
contravention takes place. It also makes the registered keeper of a
vehicle the recipient of the penalty, whether or not they gave
instructions or allowed the contravention to take place. It provides
for passengers in certain types of vehicles to be exempted from the
penalty. Finally, it provides for other matters relating to the penalty
to be set out in
regulations<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:10:08"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000006">Clause 2 defines who
the registered keeper of a vehicle is for the purposes of the Bill.
Clause 3 sets out who a civil enforcement officer is for the purposes
of the Bill. Clause 4 defines a vehicle for the purposes of the
Bill. Clause 5 requires responsible authorities to publish yearly the
names of any organisations which it has contracted to collect litter on
its behalf, the amount paid to the organisation for this service, the
geographical areas covered by the contract and performance monitoring
data relating to the contract, including the authority’s own
assessment. Clause 6 defines a responsible authority for the purpose of
Clause 5. Clause 7 sets out the commencement, Short Title and extent of
the Bill, which would commence on the day that it is passed and extends
to England
only<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:11:08"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000007">The existing law, the
Environmental Protection Act 1990, contains a criminal offence which
allows people who throw litter from cars to be fined for doing so. The
problem is that, in practice, councils have found it very difficult to
use this power as it is often impossible to prove who within the
vehicle was responsible for throwing the litter. In 2011, during the
passage of the Localism Act, I proposed an amendment to address this
problem by allowing councils to issue fines to the registered owners of
the vehicle, who would then be responsible for paying the amount unless
another person were nominated by the driver to pay the fine. The
amendment was warmly received, including by the opposition
Front Bench, the noble Lords, Lord Beecham, Lord Cameron of Dillington
and Lord Judd, two former Environment Secretaries—my noble
friends Lord Jenkin of Roding and Lord Deben—and by the late
Lord Reay. I pay especial tribute to our late colleague Lord Reay. He
was a close friend and a much loved and respected Member of this House.
Hugh was a real countryman and a knowledgeable and balanced
environmentalist<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:12:41"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000008">In response to my
amendment, the noble Lord, Lord Shutt, for the Government, said that
it,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000309" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000309">“raises
issues of fairness and
proportionality”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13071970000285" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000285">He
referred to the London Local Authorities Bill, which is now an Act,
which he said would allow local
authorities,</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000310" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000310">“to
issue a civil penalty to registered keepers where enforcement officers
witness littering from a vehicle. It makes sense to learn the lessons
from the application of that approach in London before moving to wider
legislation”.— [<I>Official Report</I>, 10/10/11;
col.
1370.]</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13071970000286" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000286">Two
years on, that prevarication will no longer wash. The civil penalty has
now been in place in London for more than a year, since 18 June
2012<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:13:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo>
<hs_para UID="13071970000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000009">I have listened to the
Government’s concerns. The Littering from Vehicles Bill which I
bring forward today takes into account the Government’s comments

<?notus-xml column=983?>on my amendment during the passage of the Localism Act. It creates a new
civil penalty for littering in England, which has now been in place in
London for over a year, and which the Government seem to favour as much
more proportionate. Crucially, it makes the registered keeper of the
vehicle the automatic recipient of the
penalty<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:14:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000010">The Environmental
Protection Act presents all littering offences, including littering
from vehicles, as criminal offences and therefore fixed-penalty notices
can be issued. In London, littering from vehicles is now a civil
offence, and therefore a penalty charge notice can be issued. For the
Government, the issue of proportionality between civil and criminal
offence will surely need to be debated. From the analysis that I have
seen from London Councils, it seems that some councils have different
preferences from others. I myself declare a strong preference for using
civil penalties rather than the criminal law whenever possible,
especially when trying to moderate behaviour to benefit local
communities<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:14:57"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000011">For the recipient of a
fine, the distinction is often unclear and/or meaningless; they are
simply paying a financial penalty for doing something wrong. It is
likely that this effective enforcement of a law, whether civil or
criminal, will result in positive behaviour change, both in the
recipient of the fine and in their peer group. What I
emphasise is the legal change which makes the owner of the vehicle
responsible for any litter from it, with reasonable exemptions applying
to, for example, littering by passengers in a taxi. Local authorities
should be able to issue fines against those who litter. That is the
purpose of the law. At the moment, under the EPA, this is not possible
as the burden of proof is too
great<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:15:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000012">More than 100 local
councils, supported by organisations such as the CPRE and the Local
Government Association, have campaigned for many years for the existing
law to be made workable. Successive Governments have prevaricated and
resisted this most logical and most necessary change. If local councils
can effectively enforce the law, they can change the behaviour of
litterers. If people refrain from littering, the significant economic
cost of clearing up roadside litter can be reduced. If the public know
who is responsible for litter clearing of particular roads, that will
put pressure on contractors to do their jobs properly, which they do
not always do at the moment. The Highways Agency estimates in its
latest annual report that it spends £10 million annually to
clear litter from our major roads. The latest annual street cleansing
bill for England was £863 per year. Again, having to spend these
huge and unsustainable amounts for which there is no real return,
because it is unnecessary to litter in the first place, is neither
satisfactory nor acceptable, especially as the roads are still not
clean. Indeed, 75% of the members of the AA, who are surely most
affected by the continuous rise in roadside litter levels, believe that
it is a serious problem, and 94% believe that it gives a bad impression
of Britain and spoils local
communities<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:17:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000013">Despite delivering on
its commitment to host a roadside litter summit in 2012, Defra’s
approach has not dealt with this issue in any meaningful way over the
past six years at least. How can a department be 
<?notus-xml column=984?>content that a law designed to forward its
objectives is unworkable? Why has it not responded to the clear call
from local councils and their representatives to make this small
change? How can a Government hope to be recognised as competent, let
alone tinged with green, if they cannot, after three years in power,
even tackle something as simple as our shamefully dirty
roads<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:18:33"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000014">Defra’s
disappointing approach is exemplified by the consultation it carried
out with local authorities on the changes proposed by the Bill. I have
seen a copy of this consultation, which was sent by a central
government official on 4 June asking for a response to questions just
two days later on 6 June. I hope that, when the Minister replies, he
does not suggest that this was in any way a meaningful consultation.
Why was an artificial deadline set for more than a month before this
debate was scheduled to take place? Perhaps the Minister can tell us
how many authorities responded in the two-day
window<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:19:12"></hs_TimeCode>. It is a
perversion of the Government’s much-trumpeted
localism<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:19:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000015">I
have certain questions for the Minister. Has the experience in London
thrown up any major problems that suggest that extending the powers to
all English authorities would be unworkable? Does the Minister agree
that, whether we have a criminal or civil offence, we must ensure that
those who drop litter from vehicles can be effectively held to account?
Does he share my desire to make the existing laws on littering usable
for councils? How long will the Minister wait before making a decision
on whether to roll out the London approach across the whole of
England<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:20:00"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000016">Many<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:19:55"></hs_TimeCode>
noble Lords on all sides of the House have expressed to me their strong
support and their regret at not being able to be here to speak today.
The noble Baroness,
Lady<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:20:04"></hs_TimeCode> Masham,
asked me to mention in particular the fire danger from cigarettes
thrown from
vehicles<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:20:17"></hs_TimeCode>. I hope
that the Minister will resist pressure to parrot the prevarications
with which his officials will have sought to sustain him. What I
believe will be unacceptable to the House and to the public, who really
mind about litter on our roads, is any further delay. I hope that the
Minister will offer political support for this modest but important
measure to be enacted. I beg to
move<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:20:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/4BCF6B05577678045A4E39E498FD60FBEDAC8006" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AC2-AD1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000324" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000324">10.20
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000017"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Lawson of Blaby" PimsId="1435" UID="13071970000358" xid="1513" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000358">Lord
Lawson of Blaby:</Member></B> My Lords, I am very glad that the luck of
the draw has enabled me to speak after my noble friend Lord Marlesford.
I think I speak for most noble Lords in this House in
congratulating him on bringing forward this measure. It is a
modest measure, but one that will undoubtedly improve the quality of
life in this country. Far from costing any public money, it would save
it. Above all, it would improve, quite simply and straightforwardly,
the quality of life in this country. I also congratulate him on his
persistence. For at least a decade, if not longer, and under
Governments of both parties, he has been banging away at this issue.
That is the only way in which you can ever get anything done. I think
we all congratulate him most warmly on
that<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:21:52"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000018">There
is no need for me to speak at any great length because the noble Lord
has said everything that needs to be said. The resistance that has been
put up over the years is quite extraordinary. There has never been any 
<?notus-xml column=985?>objection in principle or because of the
costs—there could not be, as this would save public
money—to the measures that my noble friend Lord Marlesford has
put forward on a number of occasions and has now brought forward in
this excellent
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:22:29"></hs_TimeCode>. All that
happens is procrastination, which is unacceptable and
intolerable<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:22:45"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000019">When
the Minister responds to this, I am sure that he will have been briefed
by officials to resist it; that is what always happens. I know my noble
friend to be a man of discernment, judgment, common sense and
independence of mind, so I very much hope that he will tear up his
brief—although not, of course, to announce that he will accept
the Bill. That would be going too far; we know that the officials take
great pride in their authorship. I am sure that my noble friend Lord
Marlesford will be perfectly content if, as I hope, the Minister will
say, “Of course, we cannot accept Lord Marlesford’s Bill,
but we will bring forward, without delay, a government Bill to enact
precisely what he is proposing”. I hope that he will do that
and, incidentally, that he will also speak personally to the Secretary
of State for the Environment—I charge him with this, and I shall
check up on it—show him the report of this debate in our House
this morning and make sure that my right honourable friend is fully
aware of the views of all noble Lords in this House who will speak in
this
debate<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:24:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000020">That,
therefore, is what my noble friend has to do: tear up his
officials’ brief and speak to our right honourable friend Owen
Paterson—I am glad that he has got the message. The time of
procrastination must stop; the time for action is
now<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:24:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000325" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000325">10.24
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000021"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Judd" PimsId="1230" UID="13071970000359" xid="1143" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000359">Lord
Judd:</Member></B> My Lords, I join noble Lords in congratulating the
noble Lord, Lord Marlesford. He is a very civilised man and he does not
come to this subject out of the blue. He comes to it from a background
of deep commitment to countryside and qualitative concerns about our
environment; he was a very distinguished president of
CPRE<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:25:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000022">Before
I get to the main part of my speech I have one specific point on which
I hope the Minister may be able to help us. I understand that sometimes
there are a few issues about new estates and merging them into local
authority responsibility. Sometimes practical issues such as who has
responsibility for clean streets and litter can fall between two
stools. It would be very interesting to know whether the Government
have this problem in focus and what their proposals are for making sure
that it is
right<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:26:09"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000023">This issue is important
because it is both a rural and an urban issue. The thoughtlessness,
selfishness and inconsiderate behaviour of a very few people in the
countryside can have an immense impact. I think of the dedicated work
done by the short-staffed and excellent personnel and volunteers from
organisations such as the National Trust and other organisations that
care for the countryside. Just a few motorists or cyclists who throw
away a bit of litter can spoil the effect of a great deal of care and
concern. This last spring, when it eventually came, there was a
glorious flourishing of wildflowers and the rest, but in the lanes near
where I live it was just sad to see the disfiguration caused by just a
very few thoughtless
people<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:27:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=986?><hs_para UID="13071970000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000024">In
our concern about this we must not overlook the very considerable
number of highly responsible people who take this issue seriously. The
other night a midnight walk, exclusively for ladies, took place in
Whitehaven to raise money for the West Cumbria Hospice at Home. It was
quite a long six-mile walk that started at midnight. The
walkers were all issued with water bottles and the rest. I was very
impressed to see the concern with which those people, who must have
been tired on that warm evening, having done that walk, made sure that
their bottles were going into litter
bins<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:27:59"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:28:03"></hs_TimeCode>.
We must encourage responsible citizenship because there is a great deal
in it.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000025">In<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:28:31"></hs_TimeCode>
our urban areas, of course we take tourism extremely seriously for the
well-being of our economy. How on earth do we encourage tourism if our
streets look a mess? Incidentally, that does not encourage the best
behaviour by tourists themselves. Again, it can be caused by the
thoughtlessness of a very few people, but it certainly spoils the whole
effect. We all know of countries we have visited where one of the
striking things—it strikes us because it is so
different—is that there is civic pride and an absence of litter.
We have to look at that and think, “Surely we can do
better<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:29:02"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000026">This
brings me to the issue of what lies behind the problem. A lot lies
behind it. First, it can be argued that it is symptomatic of a society
that has for too long been led down the road of egocentric
materialism—“It’s me that matters”. There
is no sense of social belonging or social involvement, and so on.
Therefore we have two look at our education system and our value
system, and at the examples we set in Parliament and elsewhere, and ask
whether we are encouraging a culture of mutual social responsibility,
care and concern. That is central, because we will not get this
right just by legislating to control it—although I commend the
noble Lord on his courage and persistence in insisting that we face up
to the issue in legislative terms. It must happen in a context that is
different from the prevailing one. We have to take that
seriously.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000027">There
are other hard-headed arguments that matter. There is a great deal of
strong evidence from excellent organisations such as Living Streets,
which I have come across only recently. I was struck by the research
and other work that it is doing, and by its commitment. Such
organisations are producing a great deal of evidence about why the
issue matters. First, they emphasise that the transformation of our
streets into welcoming spaces helps build communities and improves the
happiness and well-being of everyone. They argue that strong
communities are built around active and busy streets. Living
Streets’ experience has shown that making streets attractive and
safe encourages more people to use them actively. Evidence suggests
that when our streets are transformed into welcoming public spaces,
local communities thrive, neighbourhoods become safer and we all become
fitter and
healthier.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000028" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000028">Public
perceptions on this issue are interesting. A YouGov poll in March 2012
asked people what problems they saw in their locality and found that
66% reported litter or dog fouling. The figure was more pronounced in
Wales; it was 76%. In Scotland it was 75% and in the north, where I
live, it was 69%. In addition, the survey revealed that people would
walk more if their streets were in a better state. Some 39% of British 
<?notus-xml column=987?>adults said that they would walk more in their local
area if the streets were kept in better condition. Some 46% of 18 to 24
year-olds and 51% of 25 to 34 year- olds would walk more if the streets
were safer and more attractive. Keep Britain Tidy found that 62% of
people in England were concerned about the appearance of their area,
and 57% considered litter to be a
problem.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000029">There
are other hard-headed arguments. The absence of attractive streets can
have a negative impact on issues such as health and well-being. It is
interesting to note that people who walk linger longer and spend more.
Making town centres better for walking can boost trading by up to 40%.
Good street management and maintenance could also alleviate the
significant economic and societal costs related to poor health such as
cardiovascular disease, high blood pressure, obesity and mental ill
health. The costs of these to the British economy are significant:
£29 billion for care costs and lost productivity associated with
cardiovascular disease; £5 billion for obesity; and £106
billion in 2009-10 for care costs, lost productivity and reductions in
quality of life resulting from mental health
problems.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000030" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000030">Tackling
this issue effectively will have a great number of social benefits and
positive knock-on effects. We have to look at the issue in a wider
social context. We have to look at why it happens. I come
back to my opening point. Like many other issues, this will not be
something that we can get right until we have a prevailing culture in
this country that is about caring for other people, caring for the
community and the environment in which we live, and taking this
seriously. That puts a heavy responsibility on education. It is not
just about me succeeding at school but about how I can grow as a person
to become a fuller citizen: not just a participant in a market economy
but a citizen who cares about, participates in and wants to shape a
decent society. Education is central to this. So, also, is the value
system—and of course, the value system very much starts with the
community at Westminster and with our
responsibilities<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:35:30"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/1CB68F8493D1D1FB5B508F0344F14C418A03F124" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AD2-AF1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000326" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000326">10.35
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000031" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000031"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13071970000360" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000360">Lord
Cormack:</Member></B> My Lords, as always I am glad to follow the noble
Lord, Lord Judd. I do not come armed with a battery of convincing
statistics—and convincing they were—but I am sure that we
were all grateful to him for them. I pay tribute to my noble friend
Lord Marlesford for the admirable, moderate and modest way in which he
introduced a very important measure. My only criticism of his Bill is
that it is perhaps too moderate. However, it can be amended in
Committee.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13071970000032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000032">I
endorse everything that my noble friend Lord Lawson said to the
Minister. I hope that any negative brief has already been destroyed and
that his reply will indicate an understanding of the problem
and a determination both to get on with it and not to produce
meaningless consultation exercises that give two days for people to
reply. That sort of thing reinforces the scepticism of those of us who
regard the Localism Act as a tokenism
Act.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000033" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000033">This is a
serious problem. My noble friend Lord Marlesford was right to say that
it is a question of behavioural attitudes. We need to moderate
behaviour. 
<?notus-xml column=988?>We discussed this in a couple of debates in this House in recent weeks.
I had the privilege of introducing one on citizenship three weeks ago.
The debate the following week was introduced by my noble friend Lady
Shephard. We talked about the need for young people to grow into
citizens who have a sense of community and of their responsibilities as
well as their rights. I advocated a citizenship scheme and a ceremony,
and had great support from all parts of the House. My noble friend Lady
Shephard, and those of us who supported her, talked about the need for
educating school leavers into feeling that they were going out into a
world in which they would be able to play a constructive part.
Attitudes and behaviour are
crucial.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000034" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000034">When
I was a young schoolboy at a choir school in Grimsby in 1947, I was
summoned to the headmaster’s study. “Cormack, you were
looking in the toy shop window in the Bull Ring yesterday”.
“Yes, sir”. “While you were there, a funeral
passed you. You did not turn round, take off your cap and stand in
silent respect”. “No, sir”. “If I ever see
you doing that again, you know what will happen”. “Yes,
sir”. That is perhaps an extreme example, but we were brought up
with an attitude of real respect for those with whom we lived and for
the society in which we lived. Not one of us would have thought of
dropping anything on the ground without picking it
up.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000035" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000035">When I was
a Member of Parliament for South Staffordshire, which I had the honour
to represent for 40 years, litter became a terrible problem,
particularly in the latter two decades. I lived in a particularly
glorious part of the country. The surrounding lanes were frequently
fouled by litter: not just lemonade bottles and cigarette packets but
suites of furniture and white goods such as refrigerators dumped in
lay-bys. The cost to the local council was enormous, but what was so
terrible was that some beautiful and absolutely lovely countryside was
despoiled and fouled, sometimes for weeks on
end<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:39:43"></hs_TimeCode>. Any society
that can tolerate that does not deserve the epithet
civilised.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000036" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000036">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:39:55"></hs_TimeCode>
have the privilege of living in the Minster Yard, in the Cathedral
Close, in the great city of Lincoln. Only last week, coming back from a
service with a friend who was staying with us, we found on one of the
greens—and Lincoln works very hard to keep itself
tidy—that people had been picnicking, and there were bottles and
cartons which we picked up and put in my dustbin. Any society that can
have that attitude towards its surroundings does not, as I say, deserve
to call itself
civilised<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:40:32"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:40:28"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000037">This
modest measure is about changing attitudes, but it will work only if
there is an enforcement of the sort of measures that my noble friend is
advocating and a determination in our schools to teach our children
that there are certain things that you just do not do—and one of
them is spoiling the environment in which we live for your neighbours,
your friends and your family and, in a sense, above all, for those
visitors, if you live in a part of the world that attracts tourists,
who come to enjoy it. So let us hope that, when my noble friend comes
to reply from the Front Bench, he will indicate that the Government
regard this matter as a high priority. He is nodding furiously, so we
are all waiting for his
speech<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:41:31"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=989?><hs_para UID="13071970000038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000038"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness O'Cathain" PimsId="2163" UID="13071970000361" xid="1370" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000361">Baroness
O'Cathain:</Member></B> He is shaking his
head<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:41:31"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000039" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000039"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Cormack" PimsId="5885" UID="13071970000362" xid="2099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000362">Lord
Cormack:</Member></B> If he is shaking his head, by Jove we are going
to be plunged into gloom at the end of this debate. I hope that he will
show that the Government accept that this is a real problem which my
noble friend has underlined and, above all, ensure that it is tackled
rather more quickly than the appalling problem of Parliament Square. We
saw the centre of the greatest city in the world despoiled and defaced
by litter, year after year. Now, thank God, it has gone—and let
us hope that when Marlesford, or Marlesford in the government version,
passes into law, we shall be on the way to seeing lanes, byways and the
streets of our country and county towns as clean as Parliament Square
is today. I am delighted to support my noble friend’s
Bill.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000327" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000327"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:42:39"></hs_TimeCode></I>10.42
am<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:42:39"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000040"><B><Member ContinuationText="Viscount Falkland" PimsId="3181" UID="13071970000363" xid="1668" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000363">Viscount
Falkland:</Member></B> My Lords, extravagant praise has been given to
the noble Lord, Lord Marlesford, for introducing this Bill, and I join
in that. I put my name down for the debate, knowing full well that the
details of his very precisely architected Bill would be dealt with more
ably by others. My interest in the subject leads on to wider matters,
which I hope the noble Lord will agree are suitable for a Second
Reading
debate<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:43:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000041" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000041">Why
is it that people nowadays behave in the way they do, having won the
freedoms as individuals that they have? Why does the balance between
individual freedom and the common good seem to have got out of kilter?
Yesterday I drifted into the Chamber, as one sometimes does when there
is a debate, thinking that there might be something helpful in the
debate on civil society. I had nearly dropped off to sleep when
suddenly, to my surprise, I heard the most astonishing speech by the
right reverend Prelate the Bishop of Derby. I recommend that all those
noble Lords in this debate who are interested in why people behave in
the way that they do, and something of the culture and history behind
that, should read his excellent speech. It is quite short. Surprise,
surprise, he mentioned TS Eliot—and I thought, “Things
are really improving here in the House. We are moving to different
levels of intellectual gravitas”. I did not know that TS Eliot
was so concerned
with,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000311" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000311">“the
building blocks of a civil
society<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:44:30"></hs_TimeCode>”.</hs_quotefo><hs_para UID="13071970000042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000042">The
right reverend Prelate
added:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13071970000300" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000300">“The
more we are concerned about individual good, the bigger the problem
with the common good. The more people have individual freedom, the more
chance there is of becoming isolated, lonely and
marginalised”.—[<I>Official Report</I>, 18/7/13; col.
931.]</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13071970000287" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000287">I
think that the right reverend Prelate is absolutely right. How many of
us have walked down the street—those of us of a certain age, and
I think that I am roughly of the same generation as the noble Lord,
Lord Marlesford —and really been astonished, on a fine day in a
street with fine buildings, to see young people walking with an
electronic apparatus screwed firmly into their ear, with a glazed look
in their eye, completely disassociated from what surrounds them? This
is something that is quite alien to me, with the way I was brought up,
because, of course, we did not have all those electronic
gadgets. Nowadays, when one walks along the street
and one sees what I have described, one has to
avoid 
<?notus-xml column=990?>people engaged in sending text messages on the
pavement, zigzagging in and out without looking where they are going.
So there is a problem with our society, because these people are much
worse mannered than they were when I was growing
up<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:46:02"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:44:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13071970000043" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000043">As
the noble Lord, Lord Cormack, has said, we were encouraged to be aware
of litter. In fact, there was advertising about litter bugs and people
of that kind, and people were aware of it. Local government should be
involved in engaging people more with their local society, but how can
it, with the constraints placed on it, take up the social
responsibilities of getting more engaged in people’s lives so
that they are less likely to be ill? Depression nowadays among the
young is a very big problem; I have had it in my own family, with one
son. With his friends and colleagues at school—I do not know
what brought it on—he became enormously lacking in confidence.
He is quite a talented boy, actually, but he began to lack confidence
and become, frankly, neurotic and depressed. So I have
become very interested in this
subject<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:47:31"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000044" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000044">In
yesterday’s debate, another noble Lord introduced the concept of
the three legs of the stool, which used to govern our behaviour in our
society—the nation, the family, and the church. We may have
rebelled against some or all of what was contained in those three legs
of the stool, but we knew where we were. There were always rebels and
miscreants in society but, generally speaking, people worked according
to what was expected of them in that
way<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:48:10"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:47:24"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000045">I
think that I know what the Minister who is answering the debate will
say, despite the encouragement of his neighbour. I realise how
difficult it is for government to legislate for individual behaviour.
In his usual elegant and polite way, I am sure that he will find a very
good way round that with his brief and, perhaps, one or two comments of
his
own<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:48:48"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000046" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000046">We
all travel now during the holidays, I think, although I do not travel
far; I usually go to France. I confess that I am rather a Francophile.
It is quite noticeable in France, and in other European countries, that
they are markedly cleaner than we are in terms of what we are
discussing today. Normandy, for example, which I particularly like, and
where I go to wander round the countryside and go to the seaside and
the races in the short time that I spend there, is a very enjoyable
experience<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:49:34"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:49:33"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:48:36"></hs_TimeCode>.
Of course, the French know that this is an important issue because
France relies on tourism, albeit that is a decreasing contributor to
its economy. According to the old American economic mantra, every
dollar that is spent by people coming to an area becomes $7
through the economic activity generated in that area. I think there is
an element of truth in that. I know that we do not like learning from
the French but it is a question of political will and priorities and of
trying to make life more agreeable so that people become less depressed
and more
hopeful<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:50:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000047" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000047">It
is no good the Government coming out with meaningless slogans such as
“the big society”. That is wrong in every respect. Things
in Britain which are big are usually a problem. Someone should tell the
Mayor of London that. People are now calling London
Dubai-on-Thames—I did not make that up—because of the
plans to build skyscrapers and the like here which will dwarf our
wonderful domestic
architecture<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:51:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>

<?notus-xml column=991?><hs_para UID="13071970000048" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000048">The
most cheerful thing this week for me was listening to a debate on
television on the butchery of the Buckinghamshire countryside to create
a fast rail link which will cut 15 minutes off the journey to
Birmingham in the hope that that will lead to an increase in economic
activity to the north of that fine city. However, it has now been
discovered that the estimated cost of that project, which will be
completed long after we are all dead, certainly after my
death, is complete nonsense. We should get away from big
projects and stop talking about the big society. As regards the slogan,
“We are all in this together”, we are not all in this
together. How can we be when you have the kind of bankers’
bonuses that are being paid, people in the public sector being rewarded
for failure and the BBC in the vanguard of people throwing money about
hither and thither, and yet, at the other end of the scale, some people
hardly have enough money in their pockets to feed themselves and their
children? We are not all in this
together<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T10:52:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000049" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000049">I
see a friend of mine in the House who I sensed was becoming rather a
Francophobe. I suggested that he might go to Normandy for a holiday. He
did so and was so taken with it that he bought a house there. He thinks
that it is a beautiful place and has told me, “It is absolutely
marvellous. They take the rubbish away six days a week”. There
is a different picture in different countries and we do not look good
in comparison. We should not dance to the tune of the
Government’s advertising slogans but get back to local
government and listen to the comments of people such as the right
reverend Prelate who spoke yesterday. I thank the noble Lord
for introducing the Bill. I hope that it makes progress but I would not
like to bet on it becoming law. I thank him for letting me hang my
remarks on
it.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/2EDD1B9EAB13055CB7A4144B5779F5592C929B73" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AF2-AG</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000328" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000328">10.53
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000050" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000050"><B><Member ContinuationText="The Earl of Shrewsbury" PimsId="686" UID="13071970000364" xid="1611" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000364">The
Earl of Shrewsbury:</Member></B> My Lords, I, too, congratulate my
noble friend Lord Marlesford on securing this important debate this
morning. Depositing litter is a wanton act of vandalism which ruins our
towns and cities and especially our rural areas. Litter is not only
unsightly but can be extremely dangerous to wildlife. It is, of course,
a very serious form of pollution to water courses and
rivers.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000051" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000051">To rid
ourselves of this plague—and it is a plague of very considerable
proportions—we need not only to educate people but to use a
pretty heavy-handed approach to control this disgusting practice. I
agree entirely with the comments of my noble friend Lord Cormack about
teaching discipline. A few years ago, I was walking with my son in the
high street in Uttoxeter in the middle of the week. In front of us were
some schoolchildren aged about 13 or 14. One of the girls dropped a
sweet paper on the floor, so I picked it up and gave it back to her,
saying, “I believe this is your property”. Her boyfriend
then went for me. He told me that I could do something with my body
which I thought was physically impossible. He was 14 years old. I
thought that I knew more about these things than he did but that was
obviously not correct. In that instance, is it not parents and schools
who should instil discipline in these youngsters and teach them that
dropping litter is abhorrent, anti-social and very unpleasant for Earls
who pick it up?</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=992?><hs_para UID="13071970000052" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000052">By
way of example, I live in the foothills of the Peak District National
Park, a place of breathtaking beauty. The nearest McDonald’s
outlet is 12 miles away in Uttoxeter, yet every single day of the year,
litter mainly consisting of fast-food packaging is dumped from vehicles
in Birdsgrove Lane outside my house. It leads down to Okeover Park,
which is a stunningly beautiful place. The litter finds its way down
into the River Dove, which is some of the finest dry fly trout water in
the country. It is our equivalent of the River Test; it is stunning. We
get cans, bottles and a range of other items. If one sees a car from
which somebody is dumping litter, it is exceptionally unwise to
approach it as the tirade of abuse one is likely to receive is
considerable. If there is more than one person in the vehicle—it
does not matter what age they are—it is highly probable that one
will be subjected to threatening
behaviour.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000053" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000053">I
also live close to Alton Towers. I declare an interest in that my
father’s trustees sold it in 1924 and it became the
mega-playground of youth that it is today. Of all the thousands of cars
using our local lanes to go to and from Alton Towers, 95% of them
behave properly as regards disposing of litter. I think that is
probably because Alton Towers has lots of facilities for people to get
rid of it.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000054" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000054">As
regards bottles and cans, we should carefully consider the approach
used by numerous states in the United States—namely, Oregon and
10 others. The Wikipedia entry on the Oregon legislation currently
states:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13071970000301" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000301">“The
Oregon Bottle Bill is a container-deposit legislation passed in the
U.S. state of Oregon in 1971 and amended in 2007. It requires cans,
bottles, and other containers of carbonated soft drink, beer, and
(since 2009) water sold in Oregon to be returnable with a minimum
refund value. It is administered and enforced by the Oregon Liquor
Control
Commission.</hs_quote><hs_quote UID="13071970000302" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000302">The
law is credited with reducing litter and increasing container
recycling. As a result, items which used to make up around 40% of
roadside litter now represent about 6%. With return rates averaging
90%, another major benefit is in waste reduction and resource
conservation, particularly for aluminum. By comparison, states without
similar bills recycle on average 28% of their containers. Beverage
distributors retain all deposits not reclaimed by
consumers”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13071970000288" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000288">Surely,
that makes sense, and perhaps that sort of idea could be translocated
to fast-food outlets such as Kentucky Fried Chicken, McDonald’s
and all the other disgusting foods that there are in this
life.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13071970000055" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000055">When
it comes to littering from vehicles, I do not think that my noble
friend goes far enough with his ideas for a fine. The fine should
really hurt, because that is what really gets to people—when it
hits their pockets. For instance, as he suggested, one
should be able to go for the registered owner of the vehicle,
whether they were the culprit or not, and fine them. Should they fail
to pay the fine, their vehicle should be impounded until such time as
the fine is satisfied—that would stop them. It is time we put an
end to this vandalism. I commend my noble friend’s Bill to the
House.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000329" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000329">10.58
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000056" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000056"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Mawson" PimsId="5197" UID="13071970000365" xid="1953" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000365">Lord
Mawson:</Member></B> My Lords, I support the Private Member’s
Bill of the noble Lord, Lord Marlesford, because he has highlighted an
important issue that has concerned me for some years. It is my view
that a local context often reflects the wider world in which we live: 
<?notus-xml column=993?>the micro is the way into the macro. Small acts can
tell us a great deal about emerging social trends. In my opinion, the
UK’s litter problem is just one of many national signs that
illustrate the disconnection between political PR-speak and the reality
on the
ground.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000057" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000057">When I
first arrived in east London 30 years ago, in the middle of a rundown
housing estate, I was greeted by an urban environment full of discarded
litter: everywhere you looked there was rubbish. It was the canary in
the cage singing its song and warning anyone who had ears of much
bigger social issues. A dependency culture was being generated that was
destroying any sense of personal responsibility or ownership of the
problems that stared us in the face. The state ran 97% of everything
but in fact no one was responsible for anything—a social and
environmental
disaster.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000058">Getting
a hold of our patch of east London involved the weekly practical task
of picking up the rubbish dumped on the street outside and within the
curtilage of our church buildings. I was determined that our bit of
turf would look clean and tidy, and send out a clear message that we
existed and were intent on taking some personal responsibility for our
local environment. Actually, the mornings that I spent clearing up the
rubbish turned out to be an important opportunity through which, as a
young clergyman, I could engage with members of the local community.
This simple interface with residents led to some crucial conversations
and the development of important relationships with the neighbours.
Litter was a radar; others noticed that one piece of terra firma had
improved and started to join in tidying up the area. Today, the Bromley
by Bow Centre owns and runs a three-acre site. Visitors often comment
how beautiful and inspiring the park and gardens are. Free of litter,
they lift the human spirit and breathe life into the local
community.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000059" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000059">Our
rubbish problem is not confined to east London or inner-city areas.
Litter is fast becoming the most noticeable feature of the conservation
area in the Cotswolds where both the Prime Minister and I have houses.
I was asked 12 years ago by the then sub-dean of Westminster Abbey to
take responsibility for Stanton Guildhouse in the Cotswolds, a
conference facility influenced by the arts and craft movement and
situated in one of the most beautiful villages in England. Here, I must
declare an interest. I therefore spend a great deal of time travelling
between my house in Hackney and our family cottage in the Cotswolds. On
a winter’s day, when the grass is short and the leaves are
not on the trees, the A40 west of Oxford, near Witney, is
framed by rubbish hanging from these trees and large pieces of litter
clearly ejected from cars lie every few metres. I recently spent an
afternoon walking a few miles down one of the country lanes off the
main road near to the Prime Minister’s home. These quiet side
roads are nearly as bad as the A40. Every 20 feet, I discovered in the
grass verges a piece of litter clearly thrown from passing cars. This
road is situated within the constituency of our Prime Minister, who is
a self-proclaimed environmentalist; a tree is the emblem of his
party.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000060" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000060">None of
the three main party leaders is getting a grip on litter. Rubbish scars
their constituencies. Keep Britain Tidy estimates that around 33
million tonnes of litter are collected from Britain’s roads
every year 
<?notus-xml column=994?>and that local authorities spend £1 billion
each year picking it up. The social and environmental costs take that
figure even higher, as do the costs to business and tourism. This is a
serious problem; socially, culturally and economically. We need an
urgent culture change if we are to properly address this matter, as
other noble Lords have said. I have submitted two Questions about the
A40 litter problem in the House in recent years. The responses I
received were not encouraging. The last Minister who spoke on this
subject in your Lordships’ House told us that research was being
conducted but I have yet to see any action in response to that
research.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000061" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000061">I
decided to take personal action and follow up the matter with the local
council responsible for collecting litter along the A40. A senior
official there provided me with some real insight as to why litter is
increasing and not decreasing. He told me that the EPA—the
Environmental Protection Act 1990, as amended in 2003—gave
authorities many additional powers to deal with all elements of
littering. A series of performance indicators were set which basically
measured councils on how they responded to the problems. In particular,
litter, graffiti, fly tipping and detritus were all measured. Councils
that achieved high standards of cleanliness were given incentive
funding. This performance indicator showed who was doing what on the
ground and was, in the official’s opinion, “one of the
most important indicators around at the time”. The significance
of this indicator was recognised when it became a national indicator
and data was collected three times a year through a simple system of
measurement. However, the Government have in recent years removed this
indicator. The obligation to act no longer
exists.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000062" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000062">I
appreciate the desire of this Government to remove unnecessary red
tape. I understand that some indicators are ineffective and resource
hungry but we should be careful that in cutting bureaucracy we do not
overburden those who we are trying to enable. Individuals such as the
official I spoke to, who are trying to take personal responsibility and
play an active role in society, are feeling cut loose by government.
This official, responsible for litter collection, now has no way of
challenging colleagues and other councils on current standards because
many councils are managing litter collection information in different
ways, so there is no clear way to measure and compare their
effectiveness.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000063" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000063">The
Keep Britain Tidy campaign, whose meetings I attend in your
Lordships’ House, likewise tells me that despite promising
action on preventing litter in the coalition agreement, the Government
have stepped away from this agenda. Whitehall seems to be leaving the
problem to cash-strapped local authorities and other land managers to
deal with. In a recent survey, nearly nine in every 10 local land
managers across England, 87% of them, do not think that the coalition
Government have achieved their commitment to reduce litter; 72% of the
public agreed that the Government should do more.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000064" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000064">Small actions such as
those proposed in the Bill of the noble Lord, Lord Marlesford, could,
importantly, enable communities to take control of their litter
problem. This Bill points the finger of responsibility to a named and
known person: the registered keeper of the vehicle. People used to
laugh at Mrs Thatcher roaming across St James’s Park picking up
litter with a 
<?notus-xml column=995?>specially designed stick, but she knew the
importance of personal responsibility. If our political leaders want to
be seen as credible, they need the ability to deliver on small
practical matters that count for the general public. The noble Lord,
Lord Marlesford, is offering them an opportunity today to prove
themselves.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000065" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000065">Clearly,
given that 62% of people in England drop litter, government is not
solely to blame. However, political leaders should lead and government
should govern. I fear the Minister is going to tell us that the
approach that the noble Lord, Lord Marlesford, proposes does not work
and that it has been tried in two London boroughs but there is an
insurmountable problem. Litter is an issue that is both divisive and
decisive; you are either part of the problem or part of the solution.
Let us be part of the solution and either back this Bill or hear from
the Minister what practical solution will instead be
introduced.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000066" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000066">The
second argument that I fear the Minister will make is that there has
always been rubbish on our streets and that we are in a better
situation nationally than other parts of Europe. This argument will not
do either. We should see this problem in the round. Not only is it
costing the public purse dearly to pick up 33 million tonnes
of rubbish each year but the consequential effects are enormous;
highways have to be closed and numerous health and safety policies
complied with as litter pickers are put at risk.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000067" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000067">Of far more concern is
the social impact of litter. It is one of the first signs of social
decay. Keep Britain Tidy’s motto
is,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000312" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000312">“caring
for the environment is the first step to a better
society”.</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="13071970000289" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000289">Respect for the
planet begins with the respect we hold for our neighbourhoods. It is a
sign that you care about the world that our children will inherit. It
is my view that human beings are the environments we live, work, and
play within. Our environmental credentials will be measured by our
actions. The actions we take in the environment around us define who we
are and who we will become. Next time we ride out west through the
Prime Minister’s constituency, I hope that his environmental
credentials will be there for all to see, even to the unassuming walker
who is looking at the
verges.</hs_parafo></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/D11145AD609BAFF4A05EF5F237A0A9F44011E8E5" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AH-AH</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000330" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000330">11.09
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000069" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000069"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Selsdon" PimsId="642" UID="13071970000366" xid="1428" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000366">Lord
Selsdon:</Member></B> My Lords, I am extremely grateful to my noble
friend Lord Marlesford for two reasons. First, I support what he is
doing, and, secondly, as we are having a general debate about litter,
it means that my own Bill, which will be taken as the last business
today, will, in the quickest possible time ever, go through its Second
Reading<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:09:56"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000070" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000070">I shall try to
introduce a little bit of internationalism into this debate. I like
driving cars. My father spent his life motor-racing, including in a
great Talbot, which my noble friend here may well recall, and I have
worked internationally. I do not like going by train; I drive probably
hundreds of thousands of miles across the continent of Europe. The
biggest single change that I have noticed has been the improvement in
the quality of the roads, the cleanliness of the roads and the greater
facilities for disposing of rubbish. More than that, whereas we would
have thought that our 
<?notus-xml column=996?>French cousins were a little bit lackadaisical in
these matters, they have now become some of the toughest people in
Europe. The fines imposed on the spot can be very severe as
well<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:10:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000071" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000071">I am assuming that this
Bill covers things such as what falls off the back of a lorry. Things
dropping off the back are, to some extent, litter and are extremely
dangerous, particularly when empty lorries, usually from
eastern Europe, are moving at extremely high speeds. That leads to more
chipped and broken windscreens, and of course there are companies which
believe that, even if you have a microchip in your windscreen, you can
claim for a new one on your insurance, and that automatically puts up
your insurance
premium<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:11:30"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000072" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000072">However,
it is the general attitude to cleanliness that I find intriguing. Your
Lordships will know that much of continental Europe—Germany,
France and Italy—has weekly, or often twice-weekly, markets
within local communities. At one time, they would remain relatively
uncleaned, but now, within a matter of hours of shutting down, they are
cleaned completely. People who bring in lorries and other vehicles are
punished very severely if they do not stick to the rules. It is quite a
simple punishment: everybody sneaks on their neighbours, a little man
from the environment department turns up and, before you know it, you
are given a little fine, which you have to pay at the post office
within a very short period. If you do not, the fine doubles and doubles
and doubles and, before long, you find that another person turns up
suggesting that they should take your car
away<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:12:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000073" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000073">I happen to be a wine
producer in France. We have a major problem there, which I had not
realised. When you deliver grapes to be pressed, you may have juice
running off the back of the trailer. You are now required to clean that
up. Every single bit and piece must be collected, and the rubbish
collections are superb. We have to admit that here in the London area
in the UK there has been a dramatic improvement in rubbish collecting.
However, the problem that we have with cars is: what do you put the
rubbish in before you dispose of it? My wife gave me a whole range of
nappy bags. I carry three or four of them—I have two in my
pocket at the moment; I had not realised—in which to put things
that I may have in my car. You drive a long distance eating wine gums
and so on, you put the packet in the bag and when you stop for petrol
you find that there are bins in which to dispose of it. That is now
true of most garages in the United Kingdom. Because they are selling
food and other items, they have bins in which to dispose of the
rubbish. Therefore, dealing with these issues is purely a matter of
organisation<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:13:45"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000074" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000074">Looking at the
international scene, I also find that now, believe it or not, some of
the most badly behaved people are British families in large 4x4s
driving to the Alps to ski. I have followed them occasionally and, for
a bit of fun, have taken a note of their vehicle registration numbers.
Occasionally, because I have friends in the DVLA, I manage to find
their telephone number and I give them a ring. I just say, “I
happen to be involved in the political world a bit, and it was noticed
that at a particular point you did this”. Most of the
continental motorways have a sign every kilometre or half-kilometre, or
even more frequently, so you know exactly where you are, as do the
spies. If the police decide that they 
<?notus-xml column=997?>may be a little short of income for Christmas,
the number of fines seems to go up. There is of course
absolutely no connection between the two issues, but this is
self-interest<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:14:47"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000075" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000075">There is something that
I suggest should happen in this country. If you are travelling a long
distance, you switch on the radio. Usually, I switch on a programme
that broadcasts a mixture of music at my level, which is relatively
low, and it then provides me with information. Usually a voice will
say, “It’s Gloria here. Watch out. A bit has fallen off
the back of a lorry at so-and-so”. You are given a complete
report of what is happening. This occurs with smaller roads as well. If
you have the new systems that you plug in, you can get everything you
want. There is no reason why greater controls cannot be introduced
effectively by using those systems. I suggest that one way of doing
this is to get the radio stations, which are listened to by people
travelling in cars, to point these things
out<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:15:37"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000076" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000076">I am really grateful to
my noble friend Lord Marlesford, and I am also looking forward to being
able
to<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:15:42"></hs_TimeCode>—</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000077" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000077"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Lea of Crondall" PimsId="1443" UID="13071970000367" xid="1309" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000367">Lord
Lea of Crondall:</Member></B> According to the noble Lord’s
logic, would the answer be that all the Brits should go and live in
France and all the French should come and live
here<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:15:52"></hs_TimeCode>?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000078" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000078"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Selsdon" PimsId="642" UID="13071970000368" xid="1428" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000368">Lord
Selsdon:</Member></B> The noble Lord has raised an interesting point.
One worry is that most of the rich French seem to want to come and live
here, but in general they are among the tidiest people of all. I am
grateful to the noble Lord for making that point. We are in an
international world and one of the difficulties has been in training
tourists and others in how to behave when they come here, because there
are inadequate bins in which to dispose of rubbish. Noble Lords might
like to ask themselves: where in Parliament is there a bin to dispose
of something? It is quite difficult to find
one<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:16:28"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000079" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000079">I am grateful to my
noble friend. He has done his usual Marlesford job: he is really nice
and gentle but, when it gets down to it, he sticks the knife
in.</hs_para> <hs_time UID="13071970000331" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000331">11.16
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000081" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000081"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Brabazon of Tara" PimsId="2250" UID="13071970000369" xid="1088" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000369">Lord
Brabazon of Tara:</Member></B> My Lords, like other noble Lords, I
congratulate my noble friend Lord Marlesford on introducing the Bill,
and indeed I fully support his motives. A lot of discussion has taken
place as to what the Minister’s reaction to the Bill might be
but I think that I can give my noble friend Lord Marlesford a little
bit of encouragement. As he said, these measures have already been
introduced in London local authorities by means of a private Bill. My
experience of private Bills is that often some of the measures in them
have come into national law within a year or two. Therefore, there is
sometimes
hope<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:17:17"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000082" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000082">Not very long ago, I
saw a child throwing litter out of a car and this was done in full view
of its parents, with the connivance of its parents and probably with
the encouragement of its parents. That left me profoundly depressed,
and it touches on the points that the noble Lord, Lord Judd, made at
the beginning of his remarks. No responsibility was being taught and it
left me thoroughly depressed about what the future might
hold<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:17:54"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=998?><hs_para UID="13071970000083" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000083">In
my few remarks, I want to stick very closely to the content of the Bill
because most of what can be said about rubbish has been said today.
Most noble Lords have spoken about local areas, whether urban or rural,
but this is also a problem on national roads—motorways and trunk
roads—which are the responsibility of the Highways Agency. I
therefore hope that when we come, in Clause 3, to the definition of
civil enforcement officers and, in Clause 6, to the definition of a
responsible authority, the Highways Agency, which patrols these
roads—we have all seen it doing so—will be included in
that
category<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:18:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000084" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000084">That is really all that
I have to say about the Bill. I very much congratulate my noble friend
and I hope that the Bill gets a fair
wind.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/DA058E3AE3C139DC05573D6EB5158A7689999C80" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AJ-AK1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13071970000332" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000332"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:18:53"></hs_TimeCode>11.19
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000085" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000085"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Knight of Weymouth" PimsId="5757" UID="13071970000370" xid="2049" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000370">Lord
Knight of Weymouth:</Member></B> My Lords, I have no wish to disrupt
the consensus that congratulates the noble Lord, Lord Marlesford, on a
good Bill and on seeking to address a serious problem which, clearly,
your Lordships care greatly about, judging by this debate and the
passion with which some addressed it. We are also grateful to the noble
Lord for garnering support for his Bill from a number of organisations
and for reflecting that support. I am also grateful for the briefings
we have had, and have heard in part quoted, from CPRE and Living
Streets<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:19:42"></hs_TimeCode>. He is
right about the need for a culture change, which was reflected by my
noble friend Lord Judd and
others<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:19:48"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000086" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000086">There is a danger in
over-romanticising the past. We heard a flavour of that in some of the
contributions today. It is probably true that we have cleaner air and
bathing water. We are even seeing some culture change around
people’s attitude to dog fouling, although not among everyone.
It is still a problem but less of a problem than it was when I was
growing up. However, I find it very odd when I see people hanging from
trees bags containing dog mess that they have picked up. I do not
understand what that is about. I am happy to say that none of them
appears to be nappy bags, so I do not think that they were anything to
do with the noble Lord, Lord Selsdon, and his nappy bags. It is a
strange habit that leaves me completely perplexed as I walk
around the countryside occasionally walking my
dog<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:20:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000087" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000087">It
is true that the problem of littering from vehicles is getting worse. I
noted the comments made by the noble Earl, Lord Shrewsbury. The
drive-through restaurant is a problem that has increased littering from
vehicles. Perhaps the corporate social responsibility of
McDonald’s, Kentucky Fried Chicken and others that he mentioned
can be pricked to help councils deal with that. In some areas, those
organisations try to do a little to deal with it. Certainly, where I
live in Dorset, we see the same sort of rubbish that the noble Earl
sees where he lives and much of it appears to be generated by the
drive-through
restaurants<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:21:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000088" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000088">I
wholeheartedly support this Bill and want to see it progressed. I have
four points to make. The first, to repeat what the noble Lord, Lord
Marlesford, said, is to hear about the effect in London. We will be
interested to hear what the Minister has to say on that. In Committee,
we should explore whether this proposal will apply just to the road and
verges off the road, as 
<?notus-xml column=999?>implied in Clause 6. Clause 1 refers to Section 87
of the Environmental Protection Act 1990, which refers to any place
“open to the air” in the area of the
authority. We need to clarify the
definitions<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:22:16"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000089" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000089">I
am also interested in how we can enforce this Bill. We can learn from
the noble Lord, Lord Selsdon, and his experience travelling around the
continent. Will we end up being able to use technology? I am not one to
romanticise the past. Sometimes I romanticise the future and perhaps
there are aspects of technology that we can use in terms of our
smartphones that know where we are to take pictures of people if we can
catch them in the act. But catching people in the act, as we know when
trying to discourage dog fouling, is quite tricky. Indeed, the act of
dog fouling tends to take a little longer than throwing something from
a moving vehicle. I especially am interested in whether local
authorities with CCTV would be able to use that technology in enforcing
these measures and whether the latest code of practice generated by the
Protection of Freedoms Act would allow that to happen, particularly
given that this is the enforcement of a civil offence. That is
something else we might want to explore in
Committee<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:23:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000090" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000090">Finally, I am
interested in what would happen to the proceeds of these fines.
According to the Bill, the levels would be set in regulations, which of
course is right. Would a council be able to generate a surplus? Should
it be effective in enforcement? Would it cover just the cost of the
administration of prosecuting people for these civil offences? Could it
also cover the cost of litter clearance? Those are interesting issues.
There are some people who wanted this Bill to be more aggressive. They
may want more aggressive fines and would be very comfortable with
councils generating a
surplus<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:24:01"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000091">I
do not wish to detain the House. The noble Lord, Lord Marlesford, and,
certainly, the noble Lord, Lord Lawson, were very keen that we should
see an end to any procrastination from the Government on this issue. I
look forward to hearing from the Minister whether he will accept the
invitation made by the noble Lord, Lord Lawson, to bring forward a
government Bill to bring into effect the intentions of the noble Lord,
Lord Marlesford, whom we support
wholeheartedly<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:24:26"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000333" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000333">11.24
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000092" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000092"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord De Mauley" PimsId="4732" UID="13071970000371" xid="1856" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000371">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Environment,
Food and Rural Affairs (Lord De Mauley):</Member></B>
My Lords, I thank my noble friend Lord Marlesford for
introducing his Bill. Like my noble friend Lord Lawson, I congratulate
him on his persistence. I know that this is an issue he cares deeply
about, as do other noble Lords, and I share that concern. Like him and
the noble Lord, Lord Mawson, I regularly collect litter along the road
which runs past my house. Let me make clear that it is thoroughly
irresponsible to throw litter from vehicles, as it is to litter in any
other way. It is important that we find an effective way to bring home
to people that throwing litter from car windows is unacceptable
behaviour<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:25:23"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000093" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000093">I
agree with my noble friend that roadside litter is a blight on some
areas of England. I travel around the country carrying out my role and
clearly notice that 
<?notus-xml column=1000?>while some parts of the country are clean, others
are regrettably less so. This reinforces the fact that those
responsible for tackling littering all take slightly different
approaches to fulfilling their responsibilities and that some are more
successful than
others<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:26:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000094" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000094">What
has come out of this debate today, among other important things, is
that littering from vehicles has always been a difficult problem to
solve. The sense of anonymity that the litterer appears to feel while
encased in his car only serves to accentuate that problem.
Unfortunately, for many people it seems that it is almost second
nature. When confronted with an empty drinks can or a chocolate wrapper
in their box on wheels, they see throwing it out of the window as an
acceptable course of action, rather than, as they should, taking it
home with
them<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:26:39"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000095" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000095">The high-profile case
of the broadcaster Alice Arnold who, like my noble friend Lord
Shrewsbury, took matters into her own hands and delivered a discarded
plastic bottle back to its owner while at a set of traffic lights near
Hampton Court, led to her being hailed a national heroine. This
highlighted the strength of feeling that many of us have about this
matter and the need for
action<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:27:12"></hs_TimeCode>. We also
need to ensure that any such action is based on sound evidence in order
for it to be effective and to make a
difference<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:27:20"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000096" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000096">Throwing
litter from vehicles is already a criminal offence under Section 87 of
the Environmental Protection Act 1990. There already are considerable
penalties for those who litter, including prosecution in a
magistrates’ court where an offender can be fined up to
£2,500 and acquire a criminal record. As an alternative to
prosecution, a local authority enforcement officer can issue offenders
with an on-the-spot fixed penalty of up to £80. The threat of a
criminal record for throwing away a piece of litter can act as a strong
deterrent, especially as it could have implications for the
offender’s career and
finances<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:28:07"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000097" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000097">However,
the seriousness of these consequences also means that it is important
that enforcement officers have good evidence which would stand up in
court before issuing a fixed penalty notice for littering. When litter
is thrown from a vehicle I know that it is not always easy for
enforcement officers to know exactly who threw it, especially if the
vehicle is
moving<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:28:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000098" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000098">As he explained,
through his Bill, my noble friend seeks to enable local authorities to
issue civil penalties to the registered keeper of a vehicle if someone
inside his vehicle jettisons litter. The key point in his proposal
would remove the problem currently faced by enforcement officers of
identifying the littering offender with the degree of certainty that
would be required for a criminal prosecution. Essentially, this Bill
says that we do not quite know who committed this crime but someone
should pay, so we will punish the only person we can
identify<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:29:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000099" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000099">The Bill is similar to
provisions brought in under the ninth and 10th London Local Authorities
Acts, to which several noble Lords have referred, which apply only in
London. These powers, which were introduced with the support of London
Councils and came fully into force in June 2012, allow London boroughs
to issue a civil penalty to the registered keeper of a vehicle where
enforcement officers witness littering from it. My department is
closely watching this new 
<?notus-xml column=1001?>approach. We have already started the process with
London Councils of examining how effective this legislation is and
whether it provides a viable way forward in tackling this issue
nationally<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:29:52"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000100" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000100">However, I have to tell
my noble friend that London Councils tells us that there are some
emerging questions. Most importantly, as yet none of the London
boroughs has issued a single civil penalty notice for
littering using the new powers. As a result, as yet we have
no data on whether the civil penalty for littering from vehicles in
London has been effective in reducing littering behaviour. As the
London boroughs have been aware that these powers were coming since the
ninth London Local Authorities Act was passed in 2007, this delay in
beginning to use the powers in itself seems to suggest that setting up
and operating this new approach is not quite as simple as it may
seem<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:30:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000101" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000101">We
understand that two boroughs were expected to begin piloting the new
approach late last year but they seem to have faced some delays,
particularly in setting up the new appeals system. Other boroughs have
mentioned difficulties in identifying littering offences using CCTV
cameras—the noble Lord, Lord Knight, asked about that—or
the need to reorganise their back office functions to handle
enforcement of both civil contraventions and criminal littering
offences<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:31:13"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:31:07"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:31:06"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000102" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000102">Another
borough mentioned the anomaly that the new powers create in that
littering is a criminal offence if it occurs outside in the open air
but it is decriminalised once it occurs from inside a vehicle. We know
that some motoring organisations have expressed concern that making the
owner of a vehicle responsible for all littering from it regardless of
who committed the offence could be seen as an infringement of an
owner’s civil liberties, which of course we want to
avoid<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:31:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000103" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000103">I
sympathise strongly with my noble friend’s impatience. We all
want to see a reduction in this problem. The approach taken in London
may ultimately show us the way forward but, until it has had
significant practical use, we will not know for sure whether it makes
it easier for enforcement officers to take effective action and whether
that, in turn, would lead to a reduction in litter on our
streets<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:32:11"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000104" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000104">However,
the issuing of fines is not and cannot be the only answer. With
the best will in the world, enforcement officers cannot be everywhere
at once and the use of CCTV does not appear to be a magic bullet.
Apprehending those who litter at night, at speed, in isolated areas or
on quiet rural roads, which many noble Lords were concerned about, will
remain
difficult<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:32:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000105" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000105">If
we are to tackle the problem effectively, changing people’s
behaviour is essential, as my noble friend Lord Cormack said. If people
did not feel it to be acceptable to throw their litter out of their car
windows, the problem would not exist. As I said in response to the
proposals of my noble friend Lord Clement-Jones on leafleting a couple
of weeks ago, we believe that the most effective way to change
people’s behaviour is to change their attitudes to littering.
Changing legislation is not the only answer or even the best
solution<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:33:18"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000106" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000106">The
fact that littering is a criminal offence reflects the unacceptable and
harmful nature of this behaviour and it has a certain deterrent effect.
Treating littering from vehicles as a civil contravention may make it 
<?notus-xml column=1002?>easier for local authorities to tackle the problem
but there is also a risk of sending the wrong message about the
seriousness of this
conduct<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:33:41"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000107" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000107">Of
course, the balance between taking action against polluters, criminals
and those who persistently behave in an anti-social way while
protecting the civil liberties of law-abiding citizens is a delicate
one, but we must do our best to get it right. Ultimately, we believe in
treating people as adults and providing the freedom to do the right
thing, rather than simply making it easier for enforcement officers to
fine someone—anyone— whether or not they have got the
real
culprit<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:34:13"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000108" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000108">I
referred to the need to change people’s attitudes, as did the
noble Lord, Lord Judd, very sensitively. We continue to back Keep
Britain Tidy’s call to action. The Love Where You Live
initiative works with businesses, local authorities and civil society
organisations to make an important contribution to behaviour change on
littering in all its forms and to enable local authorities, civil
society groups and communities to take local action together to improve
their neighbourhoods and engender renewed civic pride.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000109" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000109">As<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:35:13"></hs_TimeCode>
part of the Love Where You Live initiative, a meeting of
representatives from the vehicle sector, trade associations, the
Highways Agency, local authorities and civic society groups convened
last year to discuss littering from vehicles in general with a view to
agreeing a voluntary commitment to raising its profile. Actions arising
included commitments by bodies such as the Society of Motor
Manufacturers and Traders, the British Parking Association and the
British Vehicle Rental and Leasing Association to carry anti-littering
messaging on their websites and vehicles; to build an anti-littering
message into their training programmes; and to provide more facilities
for disposing of litter, whether it be in cars or outside the wall of a
pub or coffee house. These changes are simple and achievable and I
thank all of those who got involved at the time and are continuing to
do so
now<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:35:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/2A17C12FD1989BB52D71126FC9334DB097563C31" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AK2-AL</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_para UID="13071970000110" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000110">We
have also raised awareness with other government departments. This
collaborative approach, with, for example, the Highways Agency, can be
seen in the electronic message signs over a number of motorways or the
large banners at motorway slip roads advising drivers to dispose of
their litter in a responsible manner. Of course, still more could be
achieved by vehicle hirers, motoring associations, manufacturers and
service
stations<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:36:22"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000111">I should like to
comment briefly on Part 2 of the Bill, which would require local
authorities to publish, at least once in a financial year, the names of
any organisations with which they are contracted to collect litter and
the amount paid for this service. I understand that one aim of this
proposal is to enable anyone with a complaint about a particular
problem to contact the relevant contractors directly. This
proposal would constitute a move in the opposite direction from the
decision made by the Government in 2010 to relieve local authorities of
the burdensome requirement to report information about street cleaning
to central government. This requirement had until then been part of a
national indicator set for local authorities to report against,
which we have now abolished. To reintroduce such a requirement, as the
Bill would do, would be an added administrative and financial burden 
<?notus-xml column=1003?>on local authorities and would undermine the principles of localism for
very uncertain gains. Much of this information is already published or
available through existing access to information legislation, with
suitable safeguards to protect commercially sensitive information.
Forcing the blanket publication of contracts in this way could also
undermine a local authority’s ability to negotiate competitive
contracts for street cleansing and waste management, thereby further
increasing the cost of these services to the
taxpayer<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:37:50"></hs_TimeCode>. It is
surely also reasonable for local authorities to determine for
themselves how and to whom people should report concerns. If people are
reporting incidents directly to cleaning contractors, it may make it
more difficult for the local authority to monitor the performance of
its contractor’s
obligations<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:38:15"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000112" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000112">Turning to noble
Lords’ questions, my noble friend Lord Marlesford ragged me and
suggested that there had been a too brief consultation on the Bill.
These are not government proposals so, of course, we have not conducted
a consultation. However, we wanted to know what some local authorities
thought about this Bill and views were sought via the Keep Britain Tidy
membership network, the Association of Directors of Environment,
Economy, Planning and Transport and London Councils. We were pleased
that we received 27 responses within the time available. The
views they expressed were mixed. Some local authorities think that it
is too costly and complicated to pursue offenders for littering from
vehicles. Others were concerned that the potential for different fines
for the same offence depending on whether it was criminal or civil, or
that the increase in enforcement action, would lead to fewer fines
being paid. Some also expressed concern at disclosing details of
contracts, citing commercial confidentiality
issues.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000113" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000113">My
noble friend Lord Lawson charged me with speaking to my right
honourable friend the Secretary of State about this debate—of
course I will. The noble Lord, Lord Judd, referred to difficulties in
moving new estates into local authority responsibility. I will talk to
the Department for Communities and Local Government about that and
write to him, if I
may.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000114" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000114">My noble
friend Lord Shrewsbury suggested deposits on bottles and referred to
legislation in place in certain states in America. I seem to remember
that in my youth there were deposits on Ribena bottles. We have looked
at this idea, which is in use in several US states, as part of our
consideration of our packaging recycling targets. Unfortunately, the
costs identified by the review appeared to outweigh the benefits, but I
am happy to meet my noble friend to discuss this research further if
that would be helpful to
him.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000115" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000115">The noble
Lord, Lord Mawson, referred to the removal of national indicators. As I
said earlier, a decision was taken in 2010 to relieve councils of the
burden of reporting. Of course, a statutory duty on councils to clear
litter and refuse remains. The standards to be achieved are set out in
the Code of Practice on Litter and Refuse. As a matter of interest,
Keep Britain Tidy’s annual local environment survey for England,
which is based on the same set of indicators, shows that litter levels
have remained much the same over the past decade.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1004?><hs_para UID="13071970000116" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000116">The noble Lord, Lord
Knight, asked who would enforce the Littering from Vehicles Bill. Of
course, it is my noble friend Lord Marlesford’s Bill but
my understanding is that the powers will be enforced by a civil
enforcement officer, who would be either an employee of the local
authority or the employee of a contractor of that authority employed to
act as a civil enforcement officer. The noble Lord also asked whether
local authorities would be able to keep the income and what would
happen to it. My noble friend’s Bill says how penalty charge
receipts are to be used. Under Schedule 4 to the London Local
Authorities Act 2007, London boroughs are required
to,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000313" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000313">“keep
an account of their income and expenditure in respect of the
administration and enforcement of section 61 (penalty charges) of this
Act”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13071970000117" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000117">At
the end of the financial year, any deficits should be made good out of
the council’s general rate fund. If there is a surplus, the
borough is required to apply
this,</hs_parafo><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000314" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000314">“to
purposes connected with the improvement of the amenity of the area of
the council or any part of that
area”.</hs_quotefo><hs_para UID="13071970000118" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000118">I
assure my noble friend that we are not closed to the
possibility of national legislation to tackle littering from vehicles
but, as I hope I have explained, a number of significant issues need to
be resolved before we decide to roll out the powers in the London Local
Authorities Act to the whole country. So far, London local authorities
have had more than five years to prepare for the introduction and
implementation of these changes but it has evidently not proven as
simple as might have been hoped. As a result, we still do not know
whether the new powers actually work effectively to reduce littering.
Until we have that evidence—until we are sure that simply
issuing more fines for littering from vehicles will change
people’s behaviour and lead to a real reduction in littering,
and that decriminalisation does not send the wrong message about the
seriousness of the offence in question—it would be premature to
extend these potentially controversial powers nationwide.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000119" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000119">I must express my
reservations about my noble friend’s Bill. However, my noble
friend has made and continues to make a really important point: litter
is a blight and litter from vehicles is an
important element of that. My noble friend wants to deal with
it. I want to deal with it. I would be more than happy to arrange a
meeting in my office for my noble friend to meet the relevant
people from the local authorities trying out this method in London so
that we can explore it together and see whether this is the best way to
tackle
it<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:43:43"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000334" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000334">11.44
am</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000120" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000120"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Marlesford" PimsId="1697" UID="13071970000372" xid="1138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000372">Lord
Marlesford:</Member></B> My Lords, one of the big privileges afforded
to Back-Bench Members of either House is to be able to initiate Private
Members’ Bills. One of the great purposes of initiating such
Bills is to prod Governments into action when action is needed. There
can seldom have been a better illustration of both sides of the coin
than in this debate, where we have had virtually 100% support from all
speakers from the Back Benches and the opposition Front Bench, and a
virtually 100% negative response from the Government’s Front
Bench.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1005?><hs_para UID="13071970000121" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000121">I was very glad that my
noble friend Lord Lawson, with his experience and the great offices he
has held, challenged the Government to act on this and to do something;
in particular, his appeal to the Secretary of State over the heads of
the officials who have taken the line that my noble friend the Minister
has so faithfully read out. I hope that some of us will continue on
that track
anyway.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000122" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000122">I am
very grateful to the noble Lord, Lord Judd. He and I came to this House
on the same day and we have always been close friends and colleagues. I
am very glad he spoke in the way he did, emphasising the extent to
which litter represents a cultural deficit and the fact that by
tackling it we are improving
culture.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000123" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000123">My
noble friend Lord Cormack pointed out that we do not want the
Government to allow their trumpeted localism to be expressed as mere
tokenism. I am afraid that we have not got very far with that, going by
my noble friend the Minister’s speech.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000124" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000124">I was very interested
in the speech of the noble Viscount, Lord Falkland, particularly the
psychological element. Actually, picking up litter is very therapeutic.
If you pick up litter, it is an enjoyable process. You can see the
result. You know you are doing something not only for yourself but for
other people, and it is very satisfactory. I am not a fisherman but I
am always told that fishing is wonderfully therapeutic. To me, picking
up litter has that
role.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000125" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000125">My noble
friend Lord Shrewsbury pointed out that it is a lack of discipline
which results in litter being dropped and that is something that needs
to be tackled. I am very glad that he referred to Oregon and what
happens in America. I know Oregon very well. I used to go there every
year for many years for work purposes. It is an advanced state, from
which we can learn a lot. What actually happens with its rule about
litter being returnable for a small fee is that in as far as the more
affluent may dispose of it, the less affluent will collect it up, so it
generates income and it is a rather neat method. Oregon is an extremely
pleasant state as a result. The rule has been in force for a long
time.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000126" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000126">My noble
friend Lord Selsdon told us about Europe. I so agree with him. Europe
is in general a great deal cleaner than the United Kingdom. I am
grateful to my noble friend Lord Brabazon for also talking
part.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000127" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000127">I was
very encouraged by the opposition Front Bench and I hope that we shall
continue to get its support. My noble friend the Minister’s
argument that delay is always a good excuse for further delay is a
fascinating one, if not one that I accept. Churchill once
said:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13071970000303" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000303">“Don’t
argue the matter. The difficulties will argue for
themselves”.</hs_quote>
<hs_parafo UID="13071970000290" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000290">Of course, we can
rely on officials to find the difficulties and argue frantically for
them, and to look for the negative rather than the positive. My noble
friend said that he backs the call to action, but the last thing he was
going to take was any
action.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13071970000128" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000128">I am
most grateful to all who have taken part in this debate and I ask the
House to give the Bill a Second
Reading.</hs_para><hs_Procedure UID="13071970000401" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000401">Bill
read a second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/C3D201E5FC2065478812FE267F279307CCC4A9F4" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AM-AN1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill">

<?notus-xml column=1006?><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071970000398" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000398">Alan
Turing (Statutory Pardon) Bill
[HL]</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13071970000335" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000335">11.49
am</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13071970000404" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000404">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Sharkey" PimsId="5886" UID="13071970000373" xid="2100" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000373">Lord
Sharkey</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071970000354" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000354">That the Bill be
read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13071970000129" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000129"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Sharkey" PimsId="5886" UID="13071970000374" xid="2100" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000374">Lord
Sharkey:</Member></B> My Lords, on 6 August 1885, late at night in the
Commons debate on the Criminal Law Amendment Act, Henry
Labouchère suddenly produced an amendment to the Bill before the
House. This amendment criminalised homosexual acts. The only discussion
was over the penalty to be imposed. Labouchère had proposed a
maximum of one year. Sir Henry James suggested two years and
Labouchère agreed. The whole debate had four speakers, including
Labouchère. It lasted four minutes and consisted of a total of
440 words, but 75,000 men were convicted under this amendment, and Alan
Turing was one of
those.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000130" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000130">Sixteen<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:50:45"></hs_TimeCode>
thousand of those men are still alive, and under the terms of the
Protection of Freedoms Act which we passed last year, they can all now
apply to have their convictions disregarded. This will provide real
comfort for them, their families, their relatives and their loved ones
and will help to put right a little a serious historical injustice. As
the Protection of Freedoms Bill went through this House, I tried to
amend it to extend this disregard posthumously to the 49,000 men
similarly convicted but now dead. I felt strongly that we should
provide the same comfort and partial rehabilitation to the families,
friends and loved ones of those convicted but now dead as we have to
those convicted but still
alive<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:50:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000131" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000131">The
Government did not agree with us. They pointed out that, among other
things, it would not always be possible in very old cases to know when
sexual activity was non-consensual or under age. I think that the
Government were wrong then and I think that they are wrong now. I think
that it would be simple to grant a posthumous disregard only when the
applicants can provide compelling evidence that there
was consensual, age-of-consent sexual activity involved, but
the Government were
firm<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:51:29"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000132" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000132">I
then turned to the issue of a pardon for Alan Turing. It seemed to me
that if we could persuade the Government that this was the right thing
to do, it would be a symbolic first step towards a disregard for the
49,000 others convicted and now dead, and perhaps a step forward
towards successfully amending the Protection of Freedoms Act to that
effect when the opportunity arises.
I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:51:54"></hs_TimeCode> knew about
Turing. Turing only ever had one doctoral student. This was a man
called Robin Gandy, who was Turing's closest friend and the executor of
his will. Robin Gandy taught me mathematics when I was an undergraduate
at Manchester University in the 1960s, and I was familiar with the
Turing story from an early age. However, the Government
were not to be persuaded about a pardon for Turing. The
Government, like their predecessor, acknowledged Turing's contribution
to the war effort at Bletchley Park, they acknowledged his contribution
to computing and they acknowledged the injustice and terrible
cruelty of what was done to him. They were absolutely right to
acknowledge all these things. They are all true.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1007?><hs_para UID="13071970000133" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000133">Turing led the way in
cracking the Enigma code. This alone probably turned the Battle of the
Atlantic. Respected commentators estimate that this shortened the war
by two years, saving many, many thousands, perhaps even hundreds of
thousands of lives. This was Turing's work. Turing is also one of the
fathers, if not the father, of computer science. Every time anyone,
anywhere, uses a computer for any purpose there is a kind of debt to
Turing. And Turing was treated with terrible cruelty, as were all
convicted under the Labouchère
amendment.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000134" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000134">My
noble friend Lord McNally said in February last
year:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13071970000304" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000304">“It
is tragic that Alan Turing was convicted of an offence which now seems
both cruel and absurd—particularly poignant given his
outstanding contribution to the war effort”.—[<I>Official
Report</I>, 2/2/12; col. <I>WA</I><I> </I><I>341</I>.].</hs_quote>
<hs_parafo UID="13071970000291" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000291">However, the
Government could not be persuaded to exercise the royal prerogative of
mercy in Turing's case. They argued that a posthumous pardon was not
considered appropriate as Alan Turing was properly convicted of what at
the time was a criminal offence. He would have known, they argued, that
his offence was against the law and would be prosecuted. This is not a
strong argument. The royal prerogative of mercy has been exercised
quite recently in exactly these
conditions.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13071970000135" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000135">As
part of the Good Friday Agreement in Northern Ireland, 18 convicted
terrorists, some of them murderers, were granted pardons. These people
were presumably aware that their offences were against the law and
would be prosecuted. And everyone acknowledges that the previous
Government had bravely and rightly granted a statutory pardon to all
those British soldiers—304 of them—executed in the First
World War for what were then seen as military crimes. So it was
suggested that it would be better trying to pursue a parliamentary
pardon, a statutory pardon, rather than pressing the Government to
exercise the royal prerogative of mercy. That is what this Bill sets
out to
do.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000136" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000136">People
recognise that Turing was a hero and a very great man. As long ago as
1999, <I>Time</I> magazine named Turing as one of the 100 most
important people of the 20th century. In 2002, Turing was ranked 21st
in the BBC’s poll of the 100 greatest Britons. Last year, in the
centenary of Turing’s birth, there were a very large number of
events all over the world celebrating Turing's life and his
achievements. More than 40 countries were involved in those
celebrations.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000137" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000137">Here
in the UK, there were a large number of events, including an exhibition
on his work and times at the Science Museum, now extended by popular
demand until October this year. The Royal Mail issued a commemorative
stamp and in March, Turing's universal machine—the theoretical
basis for all computers everywhere—was voted the greatest
British invention of the 20th century. The head of GCHQ, Sir Iain
Lobban, said publicly
that,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000315" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000315">“we
should remember that the cost of intolerance towards Alan Turing was
his loss to the nation”.</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="13071970000292" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000292">Last September, the
Information Commissioner's Office inaugurated the Alan Turing lecture
series. The first lecture was delivered by Professor Christopher
Andrew, 
<?notus-xml column=1008?>the official historian of M15, who spoke of Turing's greatness and his
inexcusable persecution. Last year, Turing's papers were saved for the
nation by a last-minute intervention by the National Heritage Memorial
Fund, which made a donation of
£200,000.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13071970000138" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000138">There
is now a statue of Turing in Manchester, where he lived, worked and
died. There is now a statue of Turing in Paddington, where he lived for
a while. The statue stands alongside statues of Mary Seacole and
Paddington Bear. All three statues were voted for by the residents and
it strikes me as a peculiarly and encouragingly British set of
choices.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000139">At
the end of last year a group of very distinguished scientists and
mathematicians and Members of this House wrote to the <I>Telegraph</I>
asking the Prime Minister to pardon Alan Turing. This letter was signed
by Professor Stephen Hawking, Sir Paul Nurse, president of the Royal
Society, Dr Douglas Gurr, chair of the Science Museum Group and Sir
Timothy Gowers, the Rouse Ball Professor of Mathematics at the
University of Cambridge. The letter was also signed by, among other
Peers, the noble Lords, Lord Faulkner and Lord Rees of Ludlow
and the noble Baroness, Lady Trumpington. I am very glad to see them in
their places today and very much look forward to hearing them speak in
a few
moments.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000140" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000140">There
has also been a successful musical of Turing's life, and next year at
the Barbican there will be the world premiere of a new choral work
celebrating his life, composed by James McCarthy and commissioned by
the Hertfordshire Chorus. Soon there is to be a new film of Turing's
life. Benedict Cumberbatch is to play Turing and Keira Knightley is to
play his girlfriend—which might seem a little odd, because of
course, Turing was gay, and it was because he was gay that he was
treated so appalling by the Government of the
day.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000141" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000141">As I
think everybody knows, he was convicted in 1952 of gross indecency and
sentenced to chemical castration. He committed suicide two years
later.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000142" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000142">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T11:58:35"></hs_TimeCode>
Government know that Turing was a hero and a very great man. They
acknowledge that he was cruelly treated. They must have seen
the esteem in which he is held here and around the
world.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000143" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000143">There
are two quotations which, for me, sum up Turing's greatness and
establish him as a British hero. The first is from Professor Jack Good,
who was at Bletchley Park with Turing and who died last year
at the age of 91. Professor Good said
that,</hs_para><hs_quotefo UID="13071970000316" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000316">“it
was a good thing the authorities hadn’t known Turing was a
homosexual during the war, because if they had, they would have fired
him .... and we would have
lost”.</hs_quotefo><hs_para UID="13071970000144" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000144">The
second quote is from the very distinguished Harvard professor Steve
Pinker in his book <I>The Better Angels of </I><I>O</I><I>ur
Nature</I>. Professor Pinker
says:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13071970000305" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000305">“It
would be an exaggeration to say that the British mathematician Alan
Turing explained the nature of logical and mathematical reasoning,
invented the digital computer, solved the mind-body problem and saved
Western Civilization. But it would not be much of an
exaggeration”.</hs_quote><hs_para UID="13071970000145" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000145">It
is not too late for the Government to pardon Alan Turing. It is not too
late for the Government to grant a disregard for all those gay men
convicted under the dreadful Labouchère amendment and similar
Acts. I hope that the Government are thinking very 
<?notus-xml column=1009?>hard about doing both those things. But while they
are thinking, Parliament can act. We can start by granting a pardon to
Turing, and we can continue by finding a way to amend the Protection of
Freedoms Act to extend the disregard to all who were treated as cruelly
as Turing was simply for being gay. We can start that process today
with this Bill, and I beg to
move.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/9708D8C145EFF2A760F83FCA463C426C35A30AD7" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AN2-AO1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13071970000336" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000336">Noon</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000146" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000146"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Trumpington" PimsId="4341" UID="13071970000375" xid="1165" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000375">Baroness
Trumpington:</Member></B> My Lords, my mother had a friend called Lady
Winifred Renshaw, who looked and sounded like the late Queen Mary. I
well remember her saying: “Mr Asquith was a man I would never
have travelled alone with in a taxi”. I tell this vignette to
remind people that it was not Mr Asquith’s possible taxi
behaviour which is remembered but what he actually achieved for this
country.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13071970000147" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000147">I
wish to make it clear that I support the noble Lord’s Bill to
grant a pardon to Alan Turing. Although in 2009, the then Prime
Minister, Gordon Brown, issued an apology for Turing’s
treatment, this Government should do more. This is not about legal
issues but about recognising the debt that this country owes to Alan
Turing. There are many ways in which one could compensate for the time
that has gone by without that being done.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000148" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000148">Alan Turing followed a
distinguished degree with a fellowship at King’s College,
Cambridge, and the Smith’s Prize for work in pure mathematics.
His life and work were exceptional even before he went to Bletchley.
The University of Surrey has already honoured Turing, by creating a
road and having a statue named after him. If the university can do it,
why can we not?</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000149" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000149">When I arrived at
Bletchley in 1941, there were about 400 people. When I left, there were
6,000, including the Americans. The mansion, known to us as “the
other place”, and never gone into, stood bare. None of the white
buildings or other Nissen huts existed. Only the Nissen hut known as
Hut 4 remained—and still does, although it is now a small bar.
One did not wander around the buildings. One went to the room one
worked in on shifts and, apart from a visit to the canteen, one did
one’s work and was then transported to one’s billet. Thus
one really met new or different people only in one’s transport
to and from work. Unless asked by a senior member of the section to
deliver a message, one remained in the same room year after year. The
block I worked in was devoted to German naval codes. Only once was I
asked to deliver a paper to Alan Turing, so although I knew that he had
invented “Colossus”, which turned the war around in our
favour, I cannot claim that I knew him. However, I am certain that but
for his work we would have lost the war through starvation.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000150" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000150">I commend to your
Lordships a small exhibition of Alan Turing’s work,
about which you will probably hear a great deal more and which is
presently on show at the Science Museum. I will make one small extra
point, if I may: in my section, we were all employed by the Foreign
Office. Next door, Wrens worked on shifts, like us. At the end of the
war, the Wrens all received the service medal commonly known as the
EOBGO. We got nothing. After a lot of arguing and annoyance we were
graciously issued with a slightly ridiculous badge which simply said:
“I also served”.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1010?><hs_time UID="13071970000337" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000337">12.05
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000151" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000151"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Dean of Thornton-le-Fylde" PimsId="2913" UID="13071970000376" xid="1194" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000376">Baroness
Dean of Thornton-le-Fylde:</Member></B> My Lords, it is indeed a
wonderful pleasure and delight to follow the noble Baroness, Lady
Trumpington. It is one of the unique benefits of this House that we
have the noble Baroness, who worked as part of that team at Bletchley
which was, for us, part of our saving in the Second World
War.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13071970000152" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000152">I
support this Bill and I thank the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, not only
for introducing it but for the detail and content that he went into. We
owe a huge debt to Alan Turing, and debts have to be paid. Ours has
been too long in the paying and now is the time to do it. It is
important that we do it.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000153" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000153">The code of practice at
Bletchley was utmost secrecy and such were the standards in those days
that people actually followed it. It does not happen today but it did
in those days and the many people who worked at Bletchley never told
anyone in their families, even to their dying day. When Alan Turing was
charged in 1952, the public had very little idea of the work he had
done at Bletchley. They had very little idea about Bletchley at all; it
was only in the 1960s that it started to seep out just what our debt
was to the people who worked there. He was given the choice between
going to jail and having chemical castration. He chose the latter,
which meant treatment for a year. The year after that, he took his own
life. He was 42 years of age. One cannot but help wonder, had he lived
his full term of life, just what benefits we and the rest of the world
would have seen from this man. After working on the Enigma code at
Bletchley, he went on to Manchester and the first computers in this
country, which matched anything that they had in the States. He has
been compared with Crick, Einstein and many others.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000154" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000154">I feel very strongly
that the apology in 2009 by Gordon Brown, the then Prime Minister, who
so rightly called Alan Turing’s treatment appalling, is not
enough. We need to take this Private Member’s Bill that the
noble Lord has put forward and pass it. As the noble Lord, Lord
McNally, did in a previous debate, on the basis of what he had from the
civil servants, no doubt the Minister will give a whole host of
reasons, including legal ones, why it cannot be done. This place is
full of legal expertise and I am sure there are ways in which we can
meet the requirements of the Bill without causing the huge problems
that may well have been pointed out to the Minister. We are certainly
not hoping today to hear him say, “We will go back and have a
meeting”.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000155" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000155">Now is the time to act
on this: 37,000 people signed a petition that this be reviewed and that
Alan Turing be given a pardon. Manchester and Bletchley have recognised
him. As we have heard just now, what he did for this country has been
recognised throughout the areas of work that he carried out. Law is
important, yes, but doing the right thing is as important. It is the
right thing to give this pardon to Alan Turing. There are many ways in
which it can be done that I am sure would not cause added difficulties.
As we found after many years of campaigning for those people executed
in the First World War, when your nose is to the grindstone you can
find a way. I believe that the noble Lord has presented us with a way
of recognising  
<?notus-xml column=1011?>Alan Turing and that there is unanimity that we should do so.
If barriers are in the way, perhaps a way needs to be found around
them.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13071970000156" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000156">I
support the Bill. I hope that the Minister will confirm that the
Government will give it the necessary time. I have little doubt that if
it goes down the Corridor, it will get the support in another place
that it has had
here.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000338" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000338">12.10
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000157" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000157"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Rees of Ludlow" PimsId="4984" UID="13071970000377" xid="1909" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000377">Lord
Rees of Ludlow:</Member></B> My Lords, I join other speakers in
complimenting the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, on his determined advocacy,
which has led, despite setbacks, to this Bill. The fact that 37,000
people signed the petition seeking a pardon for Turing testifies to the
public interest in this cause. The petition triggered an apology from
Prime Minister Gordon Brown, which was welcome, but supporters of the
Bill feel that it would be appropriate for Parliament itself to make a
gesture on behalf of the country as a whole, to recognise formally that
we deplore the way in which our legal system in the 1950s treated a man
who not only was one of the country’s greatest scientists but
did the state great service during World War
Two.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000158" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000158">Many of
us—including the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, I think—regard
this Bill as in some sense a second- best or interim option, in
that we would have preferred a measure that offered the same
comfort and recompense to the families and admirers of any of the many
thousands of other individuals, now deceased, who were convicted under
the same law. Still, we are where we are, and in Turing’s case
the facts and his character are well documented. I would hazard a guess
that others whose family members were victims of the same obsolete law
and cruel sentence would, albeit as second best, welcome a gesture
towards an especially prominent but symbolically representative
individual.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000159" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000159">We
are privileged to have heard from the noble Baroness, Lady Trumpington,
bearing direct witness to Turing’s work at Bletchley Park. I
will therefore say nothing about that except to reiterate that one of
the especially tragic consequences of Turing’s premature demise
is that he was no longer alive when the veil of secrecy was lifted and
the public could express belated gratitude for the achievement of the
code-breakers, and particularly to him as a leading
participant.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000160" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000160">What about his other
scientific work, both before and after the war? He never received
enough credit for that either, but that was for a different reason:
because his greatest insight, in a paper published back in
1936—his study of the scope and limits of a general purpose
computer—was so far ahead of its time that its implications took
decades to be fully appreciated. His visionary contributions to
computer science, along with those to artificial intelligence and
developmental biology, have crescendoed in their impact as computers
have become ever more pervasive in our lives. Indeed, there would now
be a consensus that Turing belongs in the pantheon of the very greatest
20th-century scientists. It would be easy to expand on these
achievements and speak at length, but I am not going to do that. The
important point is that there is a consensus today that 
<?notus-xml column=1012?>he is a major figure in the history of 20th-century science,
something quite apart from his very special key role at Bletchley
Park.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000161" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000161">Turing’s
code-breaking work makes him a specifically British hero but his
scientific contributions are acclaimed throughout the rest of the world
just as much as they are here. Anyone who has done a course in computer
science, be it in the US, Japan, Brazil or anywhere else, will know his
name. They will know about the Turing machine and perhaps the Turing
test. It is likely that many will have been curious enough about him to
have learnt the main facts of his biography. Even educated people in
Asia and the Americas know little about the English penal system, but
if they know of any individual cases then Turing’s is likely to
be among them. It has, after all, featured in plays, best-selling books
and will soon feature, as we have heard, in musicals and films. He has
become an icon of gay rights as well as among scientists. Millions
around the world know how he was treated, how he was convicted and the
bizarre and cruel penalty that he suffered. Gordon Brown’s
apology was welcome but, although it registered in this country, it did
not register internationally in the way that a declaration by
Parliament would. That is why a formal pardon redressing the damaging
perception would be widely received and welcomed
internationally.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000162" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000162">I
note that the president of the Royal Society and others in similar
roles have lent their support to this cause. Turing is one of those who
laid the foundations of the modern world, and the global interest in
his centenary testified to that. We cannot undo the wrong done to him
by the cruel operation of the pre-1967 law—he is perhaps the
best known victim of it. A pardon would be acclaimed not
only by those in Britain who deplore his shameful treatment but
worldwide. Turing’s own reputation is assured but, as British
citizens, surely we should do all that we can to erase the stain on the
reputation of our own criminal justice system. That is why I support
the
Bill.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/6EEF848839E53FDFA52B4347DBCD5380C4FB9ECD" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AO2-AR1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000339" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000339"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:10:00"></hs_TimeCode></I>12.16
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:10:00"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000163" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000163"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Faulkner of Worcester" PimsId="3199" UID="13071970000378" xid="1216" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000378">Lord
Faulkner of Worcester:</Member></B> My Lords, I join others in
congratulating the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, on the way in which he has
introduced his Bill today and his persistence in pursuing this very
good cause. It is particularly appropriate that we should be debating
this Second Reading just two days after the announcement of Royal
Assent to the Marriage (Same Sex Couples) Act—as it were, the
ending of a particular chapter of which the Labouchère Act, to
which the noble Lord referred, was the shameful
beginning<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:10:00"></hs_TimeCode>. The
case that he made for granting a statutory pardon to Alan Turing is
compelling, and I wholeheartedly support the
Bill.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000164" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000164">I am
pleased to declare an interest as a trustee of the Science Museum
Group, which, as the noble Lord said, has staged an astonishingly
successful exhibition called “Codebreaker—Alan
Turing’s Life and Legacy”, which has already won first
prize in the British Society for the History of Science’s Great
Exhibitions competition. It opened on 21 June 2012, and has been
visited by many thousands of people. It commemorates the centenary of
Turing’s birth by telling the story of how he helped lay the
foundations of modern computing and, of course, at Bletchley Park,
broke the Enigma 
<?notus-xml column=1013?>codes of the Nazis, which, as everyone now accepts,
certainly shortened the Second World War, perhaps by as much as two
years. An Enigma machine is indeed on display in the exhibition; it
belongs to Sir Mick Jagger, who has kindly lent it for the
purpose of the
exhibition<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:10:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000165" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000165">Turing’s first
major contribution to science had been a paper written in
1936, when he was just 24, on an abstruse theoretical problem in the
philosophy of mathematics. That work brought Turing to the attention of
a small group of mathematicians and philosophers, but it was its
theoretical description of a universal computing machine, capable of
carrying out any computable task, which was later seen as the
conceptual basis of today’s stored-program
computers.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000166" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000166">For
Turing, his 1936 universal machines were simply thought experiments,
but for others they signalled the future of computing—and the
beginning of computing. Turing himself wrote one of the first practical
designs for a stored-program computer, later realised as the Pilot ACE,
which is on display in the Science Museum
exhibition.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000167" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000167">Apart
from describing Turing’s astonishing achievements in Cambridge,
Manchester and Bletchley Park, there is, obviously, some very poignant
material about his private life and his shameful treatment at the hands
of the state, which, instead of honouring him as a war hero, subjected
him to judicial punishment so appalling that it is hard to comprehend,
and which indeed is the reason for this Private
Member’s Bill
today.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000168" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000168">Being
gay at Cambridge in the 1930s and, indeed, at wartime Bletchley Park,
did not seem to be too much of a problem for Turing, but the mood
changed in post-war Britain and a new repressive morality emerged.
Homosexual people, both men and women, were increasingly characterised
as deviant and harmful to the fitness of the race, and their presence
in society became a matter of national concern. The Cold War
intensified these concerns as gay people were assumed to be at risk of
blackmail, thus endangering the security of the
nation.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000169" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000169">In
1952, following what was then an unlawful sexual relationship, Turing
was tried and convicted of gross indecency under Section 11 of the
Criminal Law Amendment Act 1885—the same statute, of course,
that was used against Oscar Wilde. Turing was stripped of his security
clearance and his post-war consultancy to the successor of Bletchley
Park, GCHQ, was brought to a sudden end. He was offered the choice of
imprisonment or a one-year course of hormone treatment to suppress his
libido, and he took the latter. As has been said, it amounted to
chemical
castration.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000170" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000170">On
7 June 1954 he ingested a large amount of cyanide solution at his home
in Wilmslow, Cheshire, and was found dead the next day by his
housekeeper. The coroner recorded a verdict of suicide, saying that
Turing’s mind had become unbalanced. He did not leave a suicide
note and the full circumstances of his death are still not
known.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000171" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000171">Among
the more than three-quarters of a million people who have been to see
the Codebreaker exhibition at the Science Museum was a group of Members
of your Lordships’ House, who made a special visit on 27
November led by the noble Baroness, Lady Trumpington. Being with her in
the Codebreaker exhibition was a real privilege—as, indeed, was
hearing 
<?notus-xml column=1014?>her speak in this debate today. Winston Churchill described the
Bletchley Park cryptanalysts as his “golden geese that never
cackled”. I have never considered the noble Baroness as a goose,
golden or otherwise, but I am sure that Churchill meant it as a
compliment<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:22:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000172" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000172"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Trumpington" PimsId="4341" UID="13071970000379" xid="1165" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000379"><B>Baroness
</B><B>Trumpington</B><B>:</B></Member> May I just say I have laid a
few eggs in my
time?</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000173" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000173"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Faulkner of Worcester" PimsId="3199" UID="13071970000380" xid="1216" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000380">Lord
Faulkner of Worcester:</Member></B> It is marvellous to see the noble
Baroness here today.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000174" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000174">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:22:28"></hs_TimeCode>
noble Lord, Lord Starkey, referred to the letter from some very
distinguished people—and some less distinguished people, such as
myself—published in the <I>Daily Telegraph</I> on 14 December
last year, in which we called for a posthumous pardon for Alan
Turing. We said:</hs_para>
<hs_quote UID="13071970000306" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000306">“We write in
support of a posthumous pardon for Alan Turing, one of the most
brilliant mathematicians of the modern era. He led the team of Enigma
codebreakers at Bletchley Park, which most historians agree shortened
the Second World War. Yet successive governments seem incapable of
forgiving his conviction for the then crime of being a homosexual,
which led to his suicide, aged 41 … It is time his reputation
was
unblemished”.</hs_quote><hs_parafo UID="13071970000293" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000293">Since
then, the Government have been presented with an online petition with
tens of thousands of signatures, but they have still not pardoned
Turing. I hope that when the Minister replies, he will be able to say
that they have changed their mind, and that they will accept
this Bill which is in front of us
today.<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:20:00"></hs_TimeCode></hs_parafo>
<hs_time UID="13071970000340" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000340">12.23
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000175" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000175"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Warwick of Undercliffe" PimsId="4528" UID="13071970000381" xid="1488" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000381">Baroness
Warwick of Undercliffe:</Member></B> My Lords, I, too, congratulate the
noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, on his determined commitment in introducing
this Bill. I have been involved in the university and research world
for a good part of my working life, and one of the jewels in the crown
of UK research is information technology and artificial intelligence,
in which we are now a world leader. Alan Turing is rightly regarded as
the father of modern computing. Without Turing’s seminal,
innovative work we would almost certainly have been overtaken in this
field by scientists from other countries who were on the same
track.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000176" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000176">He<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:24:07"></hs_TimeCode>
was based in Manchester University, in the heart of the industrial and
commercial north of England, over the Pennines from Yorkshire, where I
was born. It was at school there—surprisingly, I
guess—that I first came across the names of MHA Newman and the
Colossus electronic machine, Pat Blackett and positrons, and
Turing’s universal machine concept. I suspect that it was
unusual, but we had a very dynamic maths teacher who must have been
interested in the early days of computing, or maybe just had a maths
friend at
Manchester.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000177" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000177">It
was only later that I learnt of Turing’s involvement at
Bletchley Park, and later again that I realised just how significant
his work was for the war effort when my husband, a mathematician and
engineer, became very engaged with Enigma and the codes and
codebreaking efforts of the war years at Bletchley Park, and I suspect
that he has one of the more comprehensive collections on the subject
outside specialist libraries. He explained to me the seminal role
played by the 
<?notus-xml column=1015?>team at Bletchley Park in developing the ideas that
would produce the computer I used every day. He also tried to help me
to understand the genesis of the internet, but that is a very different
story.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13071970000178" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000178">I am
so happy to be speaking in the same debate as the noble Baroness, Lady
Trumpington, who has given the House, not just today but on other
occasions as well, such rich memories of those times at Bletchley Park,
having been there at the same time as Alan Turing. She has set his
legacy in such a vivid
context.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000179" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000179">From
the work he started at Bletchley Park, and continued later at the
National Physical Laboratory and Manchester University, Turing laid the
foundation for modern academic computer science, an area where over the
years British universities have made an outstanding contribution, and
which has led, additionally, to a great deal of effective technology
transfer which has contributed significantly to the UK
economy.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000180" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000180">It is
worth saying that neither Turing himself, nor indeed anyone else at the
time, would have been able to predict the eventual outcomes of his
work, and I cannot think of a better argument for continued public
funding and national support for blue skies research, where outstanding
scientists and thinkers are given free rein to pursue fascinating and
compelling ideas. But for his criminal prosecution, which it seems
certain led to his untimely death, it is reasonable to assume that Alan
Turing would have made even greater contributions to mathematical
science and advanced our understanding of human ingenuity yet further.
Others have described the circumstances of his death, but in the week
where this House has agreed legislation on same-sex marriage, it is
tragic to reflect that only 60 years ago, and in my
lifetime, it was possible, indeed legal, to prosecute and criminalise a
man for having consensual sex with another
man.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000181" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000181">Anyone
who saw Hugh Whitemore’s play “Breaking the
Code”—I was fortunate to see Derek Jacobi as
Turing—which thematically linked Turing’s cryptographic
work with his homosexuality, could not fail to be moved by the
poignancy and horror of his story.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000182" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000182">Alan<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:27:19"></hs_TimeCode>
Turing was a wartime hero. He was credited with breaking the German
Enigma code and with an astonishing number of insights which changed
our world and inspired scientists and mathematicians to explore ideas
which led to the explosion of technological developments we benefit
from today; yet his life and further work were destroyed by the
anti-homosexuality laws at the time, laws which the previous Prime
Minister Gordon Brown condemned as “horrifying”,
“inhumane” and “unfair”. In 2009, he gave
an unequivocal apology on behalf of the Government for the way in which
Turing had been treated.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000183" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000183">So
<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:27:55"></hs_TimeCode>my instinctive
reaction when I saw this Bill was to assume that it was
uncontroversial. However, when the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, introduced
a similar Bill last year, the centenary of Turing’s birth, the
Ministry of Justice called Turing’s fate,</hs_para>
<hs_quotefo UID="13071970000317" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000317">“a sad
indictment of the attitudes prevailing at the
time”,</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="13071970000294" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000294">but rejected the
proposal of a pardon. I thought this extraordinary and pusillanimous. I
want to support the noble Lords, Lord Sharkey and Lord Rees, the noble
Baroness, Lady Trumpington, and others in their efforts to
gain a positive sign of redress.</hs_parafo> 
<?notus-xml column=1016?><hs_para UID="13071970000184" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000184">The
issue was raised last June in a Commons debate, so I looked at the
ministerial statement in last year’s Commons debate and at other
government statements made over the past few years to understand how it
was that someone who had received an official apology from the
Government could be denied a pardon. It seems that the Protection of
Freedoms Act 2012, which enables those convicted of consensual
homosexual activity to have their convictions disregarded, applies only
to the living—so if Alan Turing were alive today, he would have
redress. A pardon can be given by Her Majesty under the royal
prerogative of justice, but the noble Lord, Lord McNally, has said that
it is government policy that this should be used only where someone is
innocent of the offence and not to undo the effects of legislation
which we now recognise as wrong. So there is at least one remedy
available, but the Government are unwilling to use it,
perhaps to avoid creating a
precedent.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000185" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000185">However,
the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, has said that he is seeking a statutory
pardon, not a royal pardon, something that was quite common
historically. In fact, a recent example was referred to by the noble
Lord, Lord Sharkey, and drawn to our attention in the Library
briefing—the Armed Forces Act 2006, which pardoned servicemen
convicted and executed for cowardice or desertion. So, far from being
impossible or unconstitutional, there is a remedy which has been used
quite recently and could be applied in the case of Alan Turing.
However, there has been no movement from the Government here either.
Horror of horrors, were this to be done for one man, Alan Turing, it
might encourage the relatives or friends of others who were treated
just as appallingly to seek the same redress. As a matter of fairness
and justice, that seems a pretty cowardly argument and one for a petty
jobsworth rather than an honourable Government.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000186" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000186"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:30:15"></hs_TimeCode>The
Government described the statutory pardon given under the Armed Forces
Act 2006 as a recognition that execution was not a fate that the
individual deserved, irrespective of the fact that it was lawful at the
time. The conviction and awful punishment was not deserved either by
Alan Turing, and that included the humiliation of being categorised as
a security risk after everything he had done during the Second World
War. Let us at least put this case right, and if in doing so we can
offer a means of redress to others who have suffered a
similar fate, I personally would be happy to see that happen.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13071970000341" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000341"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:30:52"></hs_TimeCode></I>12.31
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:30:53"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000187" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000187"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Quirk" PimsId="275" UID="13071970000382" xid="1402" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000382">Lord
Quirk:</Member></B> My Lords, I am proud to speak in support of the
Bill of the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, and glad, too, of the chance it
gives me to add my tribute to a man who had long been accepted as a
genius of rare character and quality long before his dreadful death at
the age of 42. As a past president of the British Academy, I am further
glad to join my noble friend Lord Rees of Ludlow, a past president of
the Royal Society, who has spoken of Turing with far greater authority
than I could ever muster. Both of us might well have hoped that Alan
would have graced either of these great learned bodies for many
triumphal years. Indeed, he might have become one of the microscopic
number to be elected, like the noble Lord, Lord Rees, himself, to both
bodies. By 1951, as a newly elected FRS, Turing was already
well on track.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1017?><hs_para UID="13071970000188" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000188">In a very different
Second Reading debate on 3 June, to which the noble Lord,
Lord Faulkner, has alluded, I spoke of the gay minority suffering cruel
and vicious treatment not only in centuries long past, but in many
societies even today. Alan Turing was, of course, one of that minority
and he endured, as we have heard, especially from the noble Lord, Lord
Faulkner, prosecution and conviction and, instead of imprisonment, the
“mercy” of treatment for his disorder. In consequence he
was hounded and ostracised until he died by his own hand in June 1954,
only three years before John Wolfenden successfully proposed the
decriminalisation of the kind of acts for which Turing had been
indicted. Unsurprisingly, I and no doubt many others have had Alan very
much in mind during recent weeks. Indeed, his ghost seemed to stalk
both Houses of Parliament during those
debates<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:34:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000189" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000189">Turing’s
parents both belonged to families of some importance in Raj-era India,
and this meant that their two sons, Alan and John, faced years of
separation from them so that they could be educated in the UK. English
boarding schools were not the best incubators of scientific talent, but
Alan seems to have thrived at Sherborne, and in 1931 he entered
the prized embrace of King’s College, Cambridge,
becoming a fellow in 1935. By then he was a polymath in areas bordering
both the British Academy and the Royal Society. How could he not, with
such luminaries as Bertrand Russell and John Maynard Keynes at hand? He
was familiar with the work of two Austro-Hungarian thinkers, Johann von
Neumann and Kurt Gödel. My noble friend Lord Rees has told us of
the significance of the 1936 paper on the Entscheidungsproblem and the
enormous influence that that was to have for many years. Incidentally,
it led to the first quote used by the <I>Oxford English
Dictionary</I> for its long entry on the Turing machine, a concept, as
we have heard from the experts, which became not merely the
foundation for computational science and theory, but for generative
linguistics. Noam Chomsky, for example, made much of the Turing machine
in his <I>Syntactic Structures</I> of 1957. By then, sadly, Turing was
dead. However, the years between included lengthy, successful war years
at Bletchley, about which we have heard from none other than the noble
Baroness, Lady Trumpington, who knows more about the Bletchley days and
Turing’s contribution there than anybody else in this House.
None of us in this debate can do more than merely outline the vast
amount which the world at large owes to this young man. No one can
remotely guess how much more we would have owed to him if he had become
an old
man<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:37:55"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000190" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000190">I end
by noting something surely perverse, if constitutionally sound enough,
about this Bill. It would grant Alan a pardon, when surely all of us
would far prefer to receive a pardon from
him.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/262B2D6A69403C49F98183E6B37B386408192531" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AR2-AT1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_time UID="13071970000342" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000342">12.38
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:38:25"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000191" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000191"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Lea of Crondall" PimsId="1443" UID="13071970000383" xid="1309" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000383">Lord
Lea of Crondall:</Member></B> My Lords, this campaign has been going on
a long time. I remember at Cambridge, from 1957 to 1961—1957
being the year of the Wolfenden report—that we had a campaign
for the rehabilitation of Alan Turing. As somebody said to me just
the other day, some campaigns take longer than others. 
<?notus-xml column=1018?>We are familiar with that in the trade union movement. I am quite sure
this one will come to fruition very
soon<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:38:57"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000192" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000192">As
my noble friend Lady Warwick of Undercliffe has pointed out, the
government line seems to be at once technical and legal but, in
practice, an objection to “opening the floodgates”. The
logic is clear that the law which we have at the moment does not apply
posthumously and there are many thousands of people
involved<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:39:47"></hs_TimeCode>. If the
Government wish to press that argument, the one thing which must be
borne in mind is that under the Protection of Freedoms Act 2012 there
is no equivalent legal provision in other fields. The floodgates
argument is to do with this
field<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:40:22"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000193" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000193">Allowing deceased
persons to apply under the disregarding procedure would somehow be the
equivalent in reverse of what the Russians seem to have as a reasonable
statute at the moment. Something like that might be the best long-term
solution. I ask the Government and the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, to
respond to a parallel method of achieving what we all want. That is to
give national recognition in a quite dramatic way, which would be a
pardon in practice and a huge change in people’s perception to
his having been a national hero. That would constitute a collective and
representative
pardon<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:41:44"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000194" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000194">I have considered over
the past few days how, as my noble friend Lady Dean of
Thornton-le-Fylde put it in a striking way, this is a debt of honour.
Michael Foot wrote rather a good book called <I>Debts of Honour</I>,
and he was the sort of person who would immediately think in these
long, historic terms about his great heroes—Shelley, Hazlitt and
people like that. You could say the same in the field of science. If
you look up Whitehall, Trafalgar Square and so on, you will see our
national heroes; and even outside here, there is Marochetti’s
statue of Richard I, the Lionheart, at the start of the first crusade.
Well, that is fair enough—or not, as you might say. However, we
could make our debt of honour to Alan Turing somehow representative of
the need to put our heroes of science and creativity—Newton and
so on—on the national plinth. Of course, there is a plinth going
spare at the moment in Trafalgar Square. I add to this campaign one
which I am sure Whitehall will take a bit of time to get used to.
Nevertheless, it would be a striking gesture, and I put that forward in
relation to the Bill.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13071970000343" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000343"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:43:39"></hs_TimeCode>12.44
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000195" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000195"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness McIntosh of Hudnall" PimsId="1817" UID="13071970000384" xid="1765" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000384">Baroness
McIntosh of Hudnall:</Member></B>
My<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:43:35"></hs_TimeCode> Lords, I will
speak briefly in the gap. I declare a sort of interest, which is that
Naval Section VI, of which the noble Baroness, Lady Trumpington, was
such a distinguished member, was run by my father, Geoffrey Tandy, and
my mother was one of those WRNS in the next-door hut. I did not know
that they were treated in a discriminatory way—or rather that
the noble Baroness herself was treated in discriminatory a
way—but I have learnt something today on which I shall ponder.
However, that is not my
point<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:44:15"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000196" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000196">Will
the Minister, in considering his answer, take into account something
that has struck me as this debate has gone on? The late Lord Britten,
who was a Member of this House although I do not believe he 
<?notus-xml column=1019?>ever took his seat—I refer, of course, to Benjamin
Britten —is being celebrated this year. Born in 1913, he was
almost an exact contemporary of Alan Turing and lived his entire adult
life in a homosexual relationship with the distinguished tenor Sir
Peter Pears. Everybody who knew them knew that that was the
relationship of both their lives. They were accepted—perhaps
without it being declared explicitly, but accepted all the
same—as distinguished members of this society.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000197" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000197">The<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:49:42"></hs_TimeCode>
recognition that Benjamin Britten had when he was elevated to your
Lordships’ House very shortly before his death was in despite of
that knowledge. It is particularly important, as we think about what we
do about Alan Turing now, that we recollect that. It is at least
possible, is it not, that had he not suffered the gross and undignified
punishment he endured, as a consequence of which he took his own life,
he, too, might have ended up on these red Benches? Had he been so
elevated, it would have been no less than his due. I hope that when the
Minister comes to reply he will bear in mind that comparison in
thinking about how he responds to the
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:46:05"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000344" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000344">12.46
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000198" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000198"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hayter of Kentish Town" PimsId="5755" UID="13071970000385" xid="2032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000385">Baroness
Hayter of Kentish Town:</Member></B> My Lords, what a morning. What a
privilege to be here today to debate the Bill. There are many reasons
for supporting this Bill, so ably and movingly introduced by the noble
Lord, Lord Sharkey, but I will suggest three good ones. However,
perhaps the noble Lord, Lord Quirk, is right, and we should seek a
pardon from, rather than for, Alan
Turing.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000199" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000199">Of my
three reasons on which I will comment, the first is the belated
recognition, which all noble Lords have described, of the extraordinary
contribution made by Alan Turing during the Second World War. As other
noble Lords have said, it has been a privilege today to hear something
of that direct from the noble Baroness, Lady Trumpington, who also
served, and whose presence in this debate is a fitting tribute to all
those Bletchley Park warriors who fought there throughout the
war.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000200" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000200">In<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:47:23"></hs_TimeCode>
relation to the noble Baroness, Lady Trumpington, I will make two short
comments. One is to acknowledge the role that she and her many
colleagues played during the war, in ways that at the time were kept
very secret. The other is to acknowledge the role that she still plays
in your Lordships’ House and has done for some 33 years. When I
entered your Lordships’ House, I was given lots of very good
advice. One of those pieces of advice was—as with actors, who
are told never to appear with children or animals—not to appear
in a debate with the noble Baroness, Lady Trumpington, as I would be
outclassed and out-performed. Clearly, it was good advice. Her renowned
sense of fun must have been much on display during those war years and
I am sure that it added to the pleasure and reduced the strain caused
by the nature of the work
there.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000201" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000201">It is
very fitting that today’s debate, as we have been reminded by my
noble friends Lord Faulkner of Worcester and Lady Warwick, follows so
closely that on the Third Reading of the Marriage (Same Sex
Couples) Bill 
<?notus-xml column=1020?>here on Monday. The irony that Alan Turing was prosecuted for his
sexuality when he had helped fight Hitler, who had prosecuted and
gassed homosexuals, was surely not lost on him. How he might have
smiled to find us in the same week legalising same-sex marriage and
seeking to pardon him. It is to be hoped that both will come into
effect by 2014, 60 years after his untimely death.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000202" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000202">Secondly<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:49:17"></hs_TimeCode>,
this gives an opportunity for those noble Lords who have yet to visit
the special exhibition in the Science Museum, described by my noble
friend Lord Faulkner, which commemorates Alan Turing, to acknowledge
that he was a brilliant young mathematician —a genius in the
words of the noble Lord, Lord Quirk —whose revolutionary pre-war
concept of a “universal computing machine” underpins
computers as we know them, as was described by the noble Lord, Lord
Rees of Ludlow. The noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, called him the father of
computing sciences. That is why Scientists for Labour and many other
scientists have written to urge support for the
Bill.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000203" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000203">Sadly,
as we have heard, Turing’s post-war research was constrained by
his prosecution and then curtailed by his untimely death, as my noble
friend Lady Dean said. The Bill also allows us to make good the sadly
ignored 2011 recommendation of the Commons Science and Technology
Select Committee that the network of technology and innovation centres
should be called Turing Centres, after the founder of computer science.
The committee
stated:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13071970000307" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000307">“We
consider that this country owes him a debt of obligation for the way in
which he was
treated”.</hs_quote><hs_para UID="13071970000204" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000204">There
is a third reason, which goes beyond this single case. Rectifying the
discrimination and intolerance of the past—I understand why some
feel that we should not concentrate on just one victim when there were
so many others—not only enables us to try to redress that wrong
but may give hope to others, here and around the world, who today
suffer from intolerance, injustice and prejudice, whether for their
religious, social, racial, artistic, cultural or other way of
life.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000205" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000205">Society
moves on—whether over slavery, women’s rights, sexual
mores, child labour and exploitation or the denial of human
rights—but before it does, there are individuals who suffer,
sometimes from the prejudice itself and sometimes for their courage in
speaking out. We are picking out just one person today, but it may give
hope to others that one day the injustice of their suffering will
similarly be recognised. As the noble Lord, Lord Rees, said, it is
perhaps symbolically
representative.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000206" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000206">The
distinguished professor, Graham Zellick, with whom I often agree,
advised against the Bill as he thinks that a pardon would be
misconceived. He
wrote:</hs_para><hs_quote UID="13071970000308" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000308">“History
should not be rewritten but allowed to speak of the misuse of the
criminal sanction, the intolerance and cruelty of earlier times and the
evolution in cultural and moral norms”.</hs_quote>
<hs_parafo UID="13071970000295" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000295">I draw a different
conclusion. The acknowledgement by today’s decision-makers, and
the persistence of new norms and acceptance, are surely a beacon to
those who continue to suffer today. Even though we cannot right the
wrong to Alan Turing, we can acknowledge that while our society has not
always trumpeted human rights and equality, we can all learn and can
improve 
<?notus-xml column=1021?>society for the benefit of all. We support the Bill
and wish the noble Lord, Lord Sharkey, every speed as he takes it
though its coming
stages<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:53:12"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_parafo></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/738EF3C3302846E0FE5EDEB1B77BCBB305FDC191" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AT2-AW1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000345" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000345">12.53
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000207" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000207"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Ahmad of Wimbledon" PimsId="5907" UID="13071970000386" xid="2117" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000386">Lord
Ahmad of Wimbledon:</Member></B> My Lords, first, on behalf of the
Government, I congratulate my noble friend Lord Sharkey on bringing
forward the Bill and securing its Second Reading. I also formally
acknowledge the incredible contributions we have heard today, which I
will come to in a moment and which give us cause to reflect and
contemplate. In preparing to answer the debate on Alan Turing, I
reflected that when I joined your Lordships’ House, I was not
far from his age when he died. I said in my speech at the time that I
looked on the House as a place of great learning, and also a place of
great wit and wisdom. I am sure that all noble Lords will agree that
today’s debate demonstrated all those
attributes.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000208" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000208">Alan
Turing’s achievements were immense. As many noble Lords have
acknowledged, he was a brilliant mathematician and one of the
world’s most original thinkers about the possibilities offered
by computing. How casually we take our iPhones, iPads and BlackBerrys
as a means of communication. Perhaps we do not spend time contemplating
and reflecting on how these things arrived in our pockets and purses.
It was Alan Turing who talked at that time about a concept that many
found inconceivable, that of artificial intelligence. In what were to
prove his last few years, he developed new thinking on morphogenesis,
the study of growth and form in biology. In a 1951 paper, he posited
the theory that sunflower seeds conformed to the Fibonacci sequence
and, rightly, in honour of the centenary of his birth last year,
scientists at Manchester University decided to test this theory. With
the help of volunteers around the world, they were able to study 557
sunflowers, and—you know what—found that the Turing
theory appears to have been correct, which I am sure is not a surprise
to us in your Lordships’
House<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:55:51"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000209" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000209">To
me, this demonstrates three things: first, Turing’s remarkable
and original mind, capable not only of understanding highly complex
concepts, but of making connections between them which illuminate both;
secondly, it is yet another instance of Turing being well ahead of his
time, as in the example of the Turing’s test of artificial
intelligence, which requires a machine to pass for a human in
conversation, and despite annual contests has not yet been won;
thirdly, and finally, the sunflower research is testimony to the huge
respect in which Alan Turing is rightly still held by scientists and
those with an interest in science throughout the
world<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:56:02"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:56:45"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:56:34"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000210" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000210">As
has been widely illustrated in today’s debate, Turing was not
only a great scientist. When his country needed him, he stepped forward
to play his part in ensuring the democracies and freedoms that we all
enjoy today. During the Second World War, Alan Turing put his
intelligence and understanding of computers at the service of his
country, leading one of the code-breaking teams at Bletchley Park. It
is therefore particularly poignant, for me as a Minister in government,
to have the great honour of participating in this debate with my noble
friend Lady Trumpington, who has once again not only informed and
educated the House but entertained it with her usual insight and
expertise. 
<?notus-xml column=1022?>In her intervention, she said that she had laid many an egg. She has
also provided great pearls of wisdom, and today is no
exception.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000211" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000211">It
is no<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:57:45"></hs_TimeCode>
exaggeration to say that, without the fantastic work done by Alan
Turing and his team, including that of my noble friend Lady
Trumpington, the war would have lasted significantly longer and many
more lives would have been lost. After the war, Turing continued to
work for the intelligence services at what was to become GCHQ, doing
nationally important work. However, his conviction for gross indecency
resulted in his categorisation as a security risk, and his exclusion
from GCHQ and from the work where his brilliance could have continued
to benefit these
nations.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000212" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000212">All<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:58:57"></hs_TimeCode>
these achievements contrast starkly with the appalling punishment which
Alan Turing suffered, of chemical castration, as a result of his
conviction for homosexual conduct, and which may well have led to his
suicide at the age of only 42. This is something that we now, rightly,
regard as totally and utterly abhorrent. As has been said before, what
he did was a crime, and he was convicted as a result of due process at
that time. The noble Baroness, Lady Dean, spoke of the petition. I pay
tribute to other noble Lords who have been involved in this campaign
for a long time, and others outside your Lordships' House, including
eminent scientists such as Stephen Hawking, and who have called for
Alan Turing to be pardoned for the offence for which he was convicted.
Understandably, as we have seen today—and rightly so—this
matter raises strong and passionate feelings, as the noble Lord, Lord
Sharkey, demonstrated in drafting his
Bill<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:59:39"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:59:17"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:57:48"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:59:40"></hs_TimeCode><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:59:40"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000213" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000213">I
commend the work of the noble Lord, Lord Rees, on this campaign. Many
will have read the article in yesterday’s <I>Times</I> by my
noble friend Lord
Ridley<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T12:59:50"></hs_TimeCode>, who said
that this is not just about pardons but about recognising the
achievements of someone who was not only a code-breaking hero but truly
one of the greatest scientists our country has ever
seen<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:00:14"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000214" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000214">No
pardon can undo what was done to Alan Turing or, indeed, wipe out the
facts of his appalling treatment. As several noble Lords have pointed
out, were Alan Turing still alive today—I believe that he would
be about 101—he would be entitled to have his conviction
disregarded under the provisions in the Protection of Freedoms Act
2012. As several noble Lords have noted, the effect of those provisions
is to remove from the public record any reference to a conviction for
certain homosexual activity which would not be deemed criminal today.
As noble Lords have also pointed out, these provisions are available
only to the living. However, the fact is that the disregard is there in
the 2012 Act. I think we all recognise that the world in which we live
today is a very different place. Our world has changed and our laws
have changed. Indeed, as was acknowledged by several noble Lords,
events earlier in the week demonstrated just that. We have talked about
appropriateness and I think it is particularly apt that I am joined on
the Front Bench by my noble friend Lady Stowell, who was central to
those
events<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:01:32"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000215" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000215">Alan
Turing himself believed that homosexual activity would be made legal by
a royal commission. In fact, appropriately, it was Parliament which
decriminalised the activity for which he was convicted. The Government 
<?notus-xml column=1023?>are very aware of the calls to pardon Turing, given his outstanding
achievements, and have great sympathy with this objective, and with the
objectives of my noble friend’s Bill. That is why the Government
believe it is right that Parliament should be free to respond to this
Bill in whatever way its conscience dictates and in whatever way it so
wills<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:02:16"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000216" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000216">If
I may seek noble Lords’ indulgence, I speak not only as a
Minister but as a Whip. The noble Baroness, Lady Dean, said she hoped I
would say that I would not take this away. I am taking away a great
deal but I am not taking away what we will be doing next. If nobody
tables an amendment to this Bill, its supporters can be assured that it
will have speedy passage to the House of Commons. If no amendments are
tabled for Committee, there does not need to be a Report stage, so the
Government can table Third Reading by the end of October. This will
take place on the Floor of the House. If no amendments are tabled for
Third Reading, it is formal and the Bill immediately goes to the
Commons<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:02:59"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000217" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000217">I
end how I began by saying that your Lordships’ House is a place
of great learning and wisdom. Today’s debate is testament to
that
quality.</hs_para><hs_time UID="13071970000346" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000346"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:03:13"></hs_TimeCode></I>1.03
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:03:13"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000218" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000218"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Sharkey" PimsId="5886" UID="13071970000387" xid="2100" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000387">Lord
Sharkey:</Member></B> My Lords, this has been a very interesting and
stimulating debate. I thank all noble Lords who have spoken for their
knowledgeable and thoughtful contributions. I particularly thank my
noble friend Lady Trumpington for her contribution. I know that the
whole House listened, as I did, with rapt attention to everything she
had to say. I am sure that the whole House joins me in thanking her for
being here today and speaking to
us<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:03:44"></hs_TimeCode>. My own link
to Turing is only at one remove and I found it very moving to listen to
direct contemporary
experience<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:03:37"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000219" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000219">Many
points were made in today’s debate and there is no need for me
to try to recapitulate them. However, I have taken note of them all,
including, of course, the comments about a plinth in Trafalgar square.
I wish to make a few remarks about the Government’s response,
although they are not the ones I was expecting to make. Before I do so,
there is one other person to whom I owe a debt of gratitude and that is
my noble friend Lord McNally. He has consistently encouraged me, in the
face of difficult odds, to press ahead with my request for a pardon for
Turing and for a disregard for all those convicted, as Turing was. The
noble Lord is in Lithuania today on government business. I am sorry
that he could not be with us to respond to the debate and I am sure
that we would have all enjoyed hearing him carrying out his ministerial
duties. However, there is no loss in him not being with us today, and I
want briefly to turn to the Government’s
response<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:05:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000220" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000220">I am encouraged by the
response, which is generous and timely, and I am very grateful. I am
sure that I speak for most people in the House when I say
that. I thank the Minister for his words in the closing part of
his speech. This seems to be a situation in which the merits of the
argument are slowly permeating government attitudes and thinking.
Perhaps they will resolve into a clear and decisive outcome before too
long. I very 
<?notus-xml column=1024?>much hope that the Government will continue to think
carefully about Turing and others who were similarly convicted, and
that the merits of a pardon and disregard will seem to the Government
to be increasingly compelling. I hope that when the Bill reaches the
Commons, the Government will be, at the very worst, sympathetically
neutral to
it<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:06:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000221" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000221">As
a noble Lord mentioned, the noble Viscount, Lord
Ridley<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:06:00"></hs_TimeCode>, pointed
out in an article in yesterday’s <I>Times</I> that
Turing’s first major contribution to mathematics was a solution
to the so-called “halting problem”—in other words,
knowing when to stop, which is a problem occasionally seen in your
Lordships’ House as well. Therefore, in the spirit of Turing,
this is where I now stop, and I urge your Lordships to give the Bill a
Second Reading.</hs_para>
<hs_Procedure UID="13071970000222" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000222"><I>Bill read a
second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</I></hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/50C64FBB06977B95F690DC53C607CBAFEEBB93C0" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AW2-AY1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Bill"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071970000399" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000399">Clean
Neighbourhoods and Environment (Amendment) Bill
[HL]</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Second
Reading</hs_DebateType><hs_time UID="13071970000347" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000347">1.07
pm</hs_time><hs_TabledBy UID="13071970000405" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000405">Moved
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Selsdon" PimsId="642" UID="13071970000388" xid="1428" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000388">Lord
Selsdon</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071970000355" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000355">That the Bill be
read a second
time.</hs_Question></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13071970000223" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000223"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Selsdon" PimsId="642" UID="13071970000389" xid="1428" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000389">Lord
Selsdon:</Member></B> My Lords, this is a relatively simple Bill that
began in my life almost as soon as I joined the House 50 years ago. One
of the things that I found, not having rubber soles on my shoes, was
that when walking backwards and forwards as a most junior Member I
collected a large amount of chewing gum on my feet. I have never chewed
gum and I find it extremely difficult to get rid of. Some time later, I
was asked whether I would make an issue of it, because I did not smoke
or chew gum. I asked a simple Question on chewing gum, way back in, I
suppose, 2009, which the Government could not
answer.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000224" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000224">Chewing gum and
cigarettes are defined as litter under the 1990 Act, and litter is what
we have been debating today. I am grateful to my noble friend Lord
Marlesford for there being enough people to discuss the subject,
because there is no need for an enormous Second Reading debate about
something that is quite obvious. It is simply a matter of considering
what regulations could be introduced to make the system work.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000225" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000225">I suppose that I ought
to try to explain to your Lordships why chewing gum and
cigarettes—or rather the nuisance value they create—are
of such importance. Chewing gum is used by 28 million people in the
United Kingdom. One might have thought, when smoking was restricted,
that cigarettes would become less of a problem. However, they are still
more than a problem, with 200 million cigarette butts thrown away each
day in the United Kingdom. More than 1 billion packs of chewing gum are
sold every year, and chewing gum and cigarettes account for 40% of
street litter. However, it is small litter, which is irritating. The
problem is that the gum sticks to the paving stones, and 92% of all
paving stones have had gum on them.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1025?><hs_para UID="13071970000226" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000226">When
I started on this issue, I suggested to Black Rod that we should make
Parliament a chewing gum-free zone. I produced some posters to go
outside and suggested that there should be little bins in which to put
things. I did not get very far. There was a cynical look on his face,
as there usually is when I make cynical suggestions.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000227" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000227">I then set out on a
campaign. I realised that most cigarette butts and gum appear near
public buildings. In fact, there is a conflict of interest in that we
want more and more people, particularly tourists, to visit public
buildings but we therefore have more and more gum. I was moved out of
the third floor here a little while ago because my room was too hot and
too small and I was given a grand office in Millbank, which I share
with my noble friend Lord Coe. He is never there, so I have a larger
office than I am probably entitled to. I found walking backwards and
forwards a bit of a nuisance, and sometimes it took longer than six
minutes if you were going to avoid being run over on the way. I
therefore started to think of other things to do and began counting the
number of blobs of chewing gum on the pavement between here
and 1 Millbank. The largest number I found was 1,020—roughly
five or six per square foot.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000228" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000228">This is not necessarily
the fault of the chewing gum people. I discussed this issue with
Wrigley, which immediately thought that we were trying to get rid of
chewing gum. However, Wrigley advised me only yesterday that it is
fairly far advanced in producing a biodegradable gum—gum
currently takes five years to degrade. Removing the gum is quite an
expensive exercise. Up to 3.5 billion deposits of gum have been either
spat or dropped on to the streets. For an average town centre, the cost
of cleaning it up is only about £20,000 but the situation in the
inner areas is different. It takes 17 weeks to remove
chewing gum from Oxford Street but only 10 days for the streets to be
covered with it again. Therefore, it seems that there is a simple
lesson of organisation to be
learnt.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000229" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000229">As I
said, chewing gum and butts are litter and they account for 40% of all
litter. Talk of cleaning up litter follows on logically from the
earlier Bill, and I am grateful to my noble friend Lord Marlesford, who
has saved me the trouble of giving an enormous great speech or
monologue on the subject. However, I just want to ask for a little
guidance.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13071970000230" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000230">The
Bill does not try to introduce any new legislation; it simply seeks to
amend existing legislation to increase the littering fine for dropped
cigarette butts from £75 to £100. However, what is the
point of having those sorts of regulations if there is nowhere to put
the butts or the gum? One immediately comes to the question of where
the disposal units are. Your Lordships will know that this is a major
tourist area and it is possible to work out where the children and
others are. If you go to a bus stop, you will find lots of butts and
lots of gum; if you go to a school you will find the same.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000231" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000231">One day, I walked here
from Sloane Square and counted up to 10,000 butts as I went, although I
suddenly found that I was staggering as I tried to cross the road. The
butts and gum stick on the concrete and do not go away, even if they
are cleaned up. It erodes over time but leaves a bit of a mess.
Therefore, the Bill very simply says that local authorities should be
required 
<?notus-xml column=1026?>to put bins in place. There are now special types of
bin. This would require competitive tendering and so on, but cigarette
butts and gum could be placed in them and they could be cleaned out.
The cleaning systems are working quite well. The City of London has
started on this and now finds that it has much cleaner streets. The
question is what legislation can be put in place to make the provision
of bins possible. I am told that the bins could, with relevant local
authority approval, have advertising on them and thus be
self-funding.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000232" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000232">The idea of this Second
Reading was that nobody would speak except for my noble friend Lord
Erroll, so that we could jump very quickly to the Committee stage in
the autumn. I had not intended that the Bill should be here today but
the Government said, “We’ve got a bit of space. Could you
jump in?”. I wish that sometimes they would say that I did not
always have to jump in at the last minute. However, I am one of those
last-minute Lords. The thought is very simple: we do away with a
detailed debate at Second Reading and move straight to Committee as
soon as possible in the autumn.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000233" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000233">Here comes the wild
card. I have had a lot of pressure put on me to deal with a third
ingredient that causes everyone anxiety. I am not sure how to describe
it, but it relates to four-legged animals who pollute the streets. I
cannot use the normal term, which I discussed with the clerks. Noble
Lords who are professors in health said that the solution is very
simple: one should revert to the old Latin words. We are talking of
canine excreta, which is causing quite a lot of problems around the
area. There is a need for bins for that as
well.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000234" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000234">When
fouling by dogs takes place, local authorities have the opportunity to
fine people. I complained bitterly to one local authority that it did
not have enough signs, and it suddenly decided to increase the penalty
from, I think, £150 to £2,500. We have a small dog in our
house in London who I look after quite well. Suddenly, secretly in the
night, a sign was put on the house opposite that said: “Fouling,
£2,500”. I do not know under what licence the local
authority can impose that. This is an interesting issue and we want the
Government simply to agree with the Bill. I am sure that I will get a
favourable response and we can discuss it later at some point in the
autumn.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000235" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000235">We
have been in touch with all the local authorities around the country.
The plan was that they would all come to a joint meeting, maybe with up
to 100 people, where we would ask Ministers and others to discuss the
matter. You do not want to put pressure on local authorities that
cannot afford to do something, but you find some way to do it. One of
the ideas discussed is that those who put up the bins might get tax
allowances. There are all sorts of formulas to work out how
economically it can be done. I have said enough so I will sit down for
the moment. I beg to
move.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/0EC51D583445AEFCA2FCB245F08875540BF607AD" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AY2-AZ1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000348" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000348">1.16
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000236" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000236"><B><Member ContinuationText="The Earl of Erroll" PimsId="3125" UID="13071970000390" xid="1212" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000390">The
Earl of Erroll:</Member></B> My Lords, I want to make a couple of
points. This may be a very worthy cause but will it work? I would like
to see greater flexibility in fines. I suspect that a £5 fine, a
quick rap on the knuckles, might work to modify behaviour.
However, in recent 
<?notus-xml column=1027?>history, we have seen that £75 a time is infuriating people and
getting them very cross with local authorities. This high level of
fines is losing public sympathy because many people see this as a
trivial
offence<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:17:34"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000237" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000237">People, particularly
pensioners, are poor. We get idiotic behaviour from petty officials. A
71 year-old grandmother was given a £75 on-the-spot fine for
dropping a thread on the pavement when she had not even realised that
she had dropped it or, in fact, whether she had dropped it. Someone
else was fined £75 after a tissue she was using to wipe her nose
while running for a bus got blown away in a strong
wind<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:18:06"></hs_TimeCode>. Another
problem is that these fines apply to any form of litter under the
Environmental Protection Act. We have discovered that it also
applies to bananas. In 2010, a woman was fined £50 when her baby
dropped a piece of banana which rolled into a puddle. The council said
that the fine was “standard procedure”.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000238" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000238">As<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:17:49"></hs_TimeCode>
regards my next point, a woman was fined £75 after a bite-sized
piece of sausage roll fell from her four year-old daughter’s
mouth on to a street in Hull city centre. She appealed and the case was
dismissed. She was lucky because a pigeon ate the sausage roll. In the
end, it was not considered to be
littering<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:18:52"></hs_TimeCode>.
However, there is a problem with appealing against these fines. Here is
the trap—if you pay your fixed-penalty notice within 14 days,
that is okay. No criminal proceedings can be brought. But if you do
not, you could get a criminal conviction. I presume that if you appeal
and the case ends up in court, and you lose, you could end up with a
criminal conviction. That would show up in a CRB check. We know how
some people, to cover their backside, were firing people from quite
prestigious positions. For example, a schoolteacher failed to get a
fishing rod licence and as a result had a criminal conviction. So we
can see that, in covering themselves, various organisations are causing
complications<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:19:47"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000239" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000239">It
will also mean that you can no longer take part in the US visa waiver
scheme. So accidentally dropping a bit of litter and having someone
trying to take £100 off you in the street could end up with you
having lifelong
problems<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:19:57"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000240" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000240">Sometimes
we do not look at the unintended consequences of some of these
measures. They sound great up front but it is not always as simple as
that. I think that a rap on the knuckles would be far more effective
and I would impose £5 fines here and there. People would hate
having to pay the fine, but it would be hardly worth making a fuss
about and would modify behaviour.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13071970000349" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000349"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:20:21"></hs_TimeCode></I>1.20
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:20:17"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000241" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000241"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hooper" PimsId="1011" UID="13071970000391" xid="1273" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000391">Baroness
Hooper:</Member></B> My Lords, I, too, wish to take this opportunity to
speak in the gap and to express my wholehearted support for my noble
friend’s Bill and the intentions behind
it<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:20:35"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000242" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000242">Anyone
who walks along Whitehall, as I do each day, and looks at the pavement
will see that it is covered with butts and chewing gum. I remember how
beautiful the paving stones were—they were laid in recent years
at great expense—and how awful they look today as a result of
the butts and the chewing
gum<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:21:10"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1028?><hs_para UID="13071970000243" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000243">I
was astounded to hear from the noble Earl, Lord Erroll, that anyone has
ever been fined for littering. From his examples, it is obvious that
all the wrong people are being chased and fined and so implementation
will be extremely
important<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:21:27"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000244" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000244">However,
there are simple solutions. I know that in the past there have been
difficulties with litter bins because they have been stolen, carried
away, moved around or used as weapons. In the days when we were worried
about terrorists and bombs, litter bins were obviously suspect. In
Paris they use plastic bags—which would not have the same
deleterious effect as large iron litter bins if explosions took place
inside them—and they seem to work
effectively<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:22:16"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000245" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000245">My
solution to the problem of public buildings, to which my noble friend
referred, where sometimes you feel that you are walking through an
ashtray if you go outside, is that anyone who exercises a non-smoking
policy in a building should issue portable ashtrays. It would not be
difficult for someone to carry a small tin and put their cigarette ends
in that container. There could be a public campaign to the effect that
anyone who smokes should be required to carry a portable ashtray with
him or
her<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:22:58"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000246" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000246">My
noble friend said this is a simple Bill. I hope the Government will
accept it and that it will lead to a simple
solution<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:23:03"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/6785B723790044F5C2299050F2045D2C233F0794" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>AZ2-BB1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000350" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000350"><I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:23:03"></hs_TimeCode></I>1.23
pm<I><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:23:05"></hs_TimeCode></I></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000247" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000247"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Smith of Basildon" PimsId="5786" UID="13071970000392" xid="2058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000392">Baroness
Smith of Basildon:</Member></B> My Lords, I thank the noble Lord, Lord
Selsdon, for introducing this Bill today. He is seeking to address a
long-standing, expensive and unpleasant problem. I am grateful to the
noble Earl, Lord Erroll, and the noble Baroness, Lady Hooper, for their
comments<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:23:28"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000248" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0001.htm#13071970000248">I have a confession to
make. I do not smoke but I have been known occasionally to chew gum.
However, I promise that I dispose of it responsibly at all
times<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:23:38"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000249" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000249">Over the years, in your
Lordships’ House and in the other place, a number of questions
and debates have been raised on this issue and we have seen legislation
to deal with the problem of litter. However, still there are people who
persist in irresponsibly disposing of their litter in unhygienic and
unpleasant ways. All litter is bad, a point made by the noble Earl, and
the cost to local authorities is enormous, as the noble Lord, Lord
Selsdon, said<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:24:07"></hs_TimeCode>. I
would like to see local councils publishing in their annual accounts
how much it costs per resident for them to clean up other
people’s mess. I call them litter louts, although some of them
do not like that
description<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:24:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000250" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000250">As the noble Earl, Lord
Erroll, has said, the Bill seeks to address the two specific areas that
have been targeted—chewing gum and cigarette butts. I had not
realised that there is a significant industry devoted to chewing gum
removal and disposal. Just a quick trawl on the internet identifies
several companies selling products to businesses, councils and
individuals, all to deal with chewing gum. There are disposable
wrappers that can be carried in pockets or handbags; there are
solutions to try to remove chewing gum from clothes, which is extremely
unpleasant; there are also industrial-strength machines, to which the
noble Lord, Lord Selsdon, referred, that remove flattened and dirty
chewing gum from pavements.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1029?><hs_para UID="13071970000251" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000251">I first saw one of those
machines in operation when I was Environment Minister in Northern
Ireland. It was a huge expense and effort for the local authority, but
it was an absolute necessity because the sight of the very dark
pavements in the town centre against the dirty, off-white used chewing
gum was pretty disgusting. I also recall my husband joining me on a
visit to a school at which I was speaking as part of the Lord
Speaker’s outreach programme, and the school was very
embarrassed when he left with his trousers covered in chewing gum from
a school chair. I can tell the school that I put the trousers in the
freezer and managed to get it off
later.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000252" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000252">Clearly,
this is a problem. It is an unpleasant and ugly problem and innovative
ways are being sought to address it, and have been for many years. As
early as 1959, Lonnie Donegan reached number three in the pop charts
with a solution to the problem of chewing gum disposal, with the hit
song, “Does Your Chewing Gum Lose Its Flavour (On the Bedpost
Overnight?)”. Noble Lords may not be aware that the problem goes
back even further, to 1924, when the original version, “Does the
Spearmint Lose Its Flavor on the Bedpost Overnight?” was a hit
in the USA. I suspect that that chewing gum from 1924 has lost its
flavour.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000253" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000253">When
the Labour Government set up the Chewing Gum Action Group in 2003, they
brought together charities, government and the chewing gum industry to
change public behaviour and alert people to the penalties that can be
imposed. I am grateful that this Government continue to support that
body. The chewing gum industry is committed to playing its part in the
group and provides financial support to help tackle the problem. When
it is active, it can achieve great results. In one area there was a 93%
reduction in the problem. But I was disappointed to note from the
group’s website that this year only 14 local authorities have
signed up to it. Clearly many more would benefit from doing
so.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000254" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000254">Last year
in your Lordships’ House, the noble Lord, Lord Skelmersdale,
asked the Minister, the noble Lord, Lord Taylor of Holbeach, for an
update on dissolvable chewing gum—which apparently has been
invented—because,</hs_para>
<hs_quotefo UID="13071970000318" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000318">“chewing gum
is the most horrendous litter problem on our
streets”.</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13071970000255" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000255">The
Minister replied that he was meeting Wrigley that very afternoon, and
that he hoped that his noble friend was,</hs_parafo>
<hs_quotefo UID="13071970000319" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000319">“reassured
that this matter is under control and I will stick to the
solution”.—[<I>Official Report</I>, 9/7/12; col.
903.]</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13071970000296" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000296">It
would be interesting to know what further progress has been made since
then. I understand that one UK company has invented a chewing gum that
can be removed from pavements just with water but I am not aware that
it is in widespread use with all the companies. My one reservation
about dissolvable chewing gum is that it might make some people even
more reckless in disposing of it if they think it can be removed so
easily.</hs_parafo><hs_para UID="13071970000256" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000256">Of
course, the other problem that the Bill seeks to address is that of
cigarette butts. I commend efforts to tackle this problem but
there is a debate to be had as to whether the imposition of fines and
such duties 
<?notus-xml column=1030?>as suggested by the Bill is the best way forward, as
the noble Earl, Lord Erroll, indicated. I will use an example from my
own local authority, Basildon District Council. The council hired a
security company, Xfor, to police the town centre and issue fines of
£75—the current maximum—to those it witnessed
dropping cigarette butts. Xfor charged the council £45 for every
fine it issued. There was no request to pick it up, no warning, just
the fine of £75. I think the idea was that immediate harsh
action would be an effective deterrent. In the first three months of
the scheme, 1,460 fines were issued but 495 were not paid, leaving the
council £17,000 out of pocket. Obviously, the private security
company could not verify names and addresses; nor could it check that
the names and addresses it was given were those of the people to whom
the fines had been issued. At the time the company was quoted as saying
that it was trying to make it cost-neutral for council tax payers but
it seemed that the more fines it issued, the greater the loss and
expense to the council. My understanding is that as a result the
contract had to be terminated; it just was not working. The point made
by the noble Earl, Lord Erroll, reinforces the example I have
here.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000257" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000257">Last
week a teacher in Northern Ireland was fined for throwing an apple core
from his car window into a hedge because he thought it was
biodegradable and would not cause the same kind of problem as throwing
a cigarette packet or chewing gum out of the
window.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000258" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000258"><hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:29:44"></hs_TimeCode><B><Member ContinuationText="The Earl of Erroll" PimsId="3125" UID="13071970000393" xid="1212" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000393">The
Earl of Erroll:</Member></B> Just because it is biodegradable does not
mean that it is not litter, unfortunately. I think the noble Baroness
will find that under the Act it is waste the moment that it is not
being used for the purpose for which it was intended. It is therefore
litter even if an animal eats
it<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:30:05"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000259" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000259"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Smith of Basildon" PimsId="5786" UID="13071970000394" xid="2058" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000394">Baroness
Smith of Basildon:</Member></B> My Lords, the noble Earl is correct
about the legislation. The point I was making is about
misunderstanding: people not believing that they are committing an
offence. A very responsible citizen, a local teacher, now has a fine
and a criminal
record<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:30:19"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000260" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000260">Litter
disposal points are very welcome, but we have all read, and we heard
from the noble Baroness, Lady Hooper, about local authorities who have
got rid of many regular litter bins, in some cases citing security and
in others because they cannot afford the staff to empty the bins. All
across London, there are cigarette disposal units on the side of
buildings—often pubs, sometimes offices, anywhere where people
congregate to smoke. They are sponsored by a London-based company, but
so many of them are either overflowing or damaged and the area
underneath and around them is littered with stubs. That itself is a
problem in
disposal<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:30:57"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000261" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000261">I
am very fire safety aware. Many of your Lordships will have received a
letter from me about your fire safety training, which I hope that every
Member of your Lordships' House has undertaken. I found through
trawling the internet that, as the noble Baroness, Lady Hooper, said,
it is possible to buy a small, almost disposable ashtray. It is a fully
closeable box so that smokers can safely keep their stubs until they
can get home and properly dispose of
them<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:31:28"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1031?><hs_para UID="13071970000262" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000262">The
objectives behind the Bill are wise and seek to address a problem that
costs us all. However, I think that more debate is needed on the
effectiveness of the measures we have in place and what measures could
be effective in future. It is helpful that the noble Lord, Lord
Selsdon, is engaging with local authorities. Clearly, further debate
will be helpful to find a way forward to tackle what is a nasty,
unpleasant
problem<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:31:55"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/CC9648FEFC82E3B57AB3FD71D80C3FD9AA4804AC" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>BB2-BC1</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><hs_time UID="13071970000351" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000351">1.32
pm</hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000264" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000264"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord De Mauley" PimsId="4732" UID="13071970000395" xid="1856" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000395">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Environment,
Food and Rural Affairs (Lord De Mauley):</Member></B> My Lords, I start
by thanking my noble friend for introducing the Bill and giving us a
further opportunity to debate the important issue of litter. I also
thank all noble Lords who have given up their Friday to speak when they
would much prefer to have been out in the sun—perhaps, like my
noble friend, counting gum spots on the pavement or, even better,
picking up
litter.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000265" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000265">As I
have emphasised in several recent debates, litter is a blight on our
streets and on our landscape. More than that, it is an entirely
avoidable problem. It is never necessary to drop litter, and most
people are aware that it is a criminal offence to do so, but that
knowledge does not seem to stop them. My noble friend gave us some
statistics; here are some more. Research by Keep Britain Tidy suggests
that almost two-thirds of people in Britain drop litter, but
less than a third admit to it.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000266" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000266">Despite<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:33:33"></hs_TimeCode>
that rather worrying statistic, there is also a great depth of public
feeling about litter and the need for firmer action to tackle it. More
than 10,000 people joined Keep Britain Tidy during Love Where You Live
month in June this year to take part in clean-ups in their local areas.
My department receives a fairly constant stream of correspondence on
the subject, suggesting any number of actions that the Government
should take, including those proposed by my noble friend in his Bill:
to increase fines or provide more
bins<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:33:34"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000267" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000267">As
I have said several times recently, solutions to this pernicious
problem are rarely straightforward. My noble friend’s first
proposal is that the minimum fine for littering should be increased. At
present, local authorities may set fines for littering and similar
environmental offences of anywhere between £50 and £80,
with a default of £75 if they do not set a local amount. My
noble friend proposes that the minimum fine should rise to £100
without a statutory maximum.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000268" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000268">I<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:34:13"></hs_TimeCode>
fully understand my noble friend’s desire to send a message to
the public about the seriousness of littering as an offence. Not only
does the problem add to everyone's council tax bill in cleansing and
enforcement costs, the very presence of dropped litter can lead to an
increase in antisocial behaviour. This in turn increases people's fear
of crime and discourages them from going out to use our wonderful and
varied public
places.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000269" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000269">Litter
also has environmental impacts: on wild animals and birds which eat it,
and on pollution levels in our water courses. However, research by Keep
Britain Tidy conducted in 2011 showed that public opinion is divided
over whether fixed penalties are an effective 
<?notus-xml column=1032?>way to change people’s behaviour and that in areas where more
fixed penalty notices are issued, the public satisfaction with levels
of cleanliness is often still low. An increase in the fine for
littering is of course only as effective as the enforcement action
which leads to the fine being issued. As we discussed earlier when
debating my noble friend Lord Marlesford’s Bill on littering
from vehicles, enforcement officers cannot be everywhere at once. The
more often that people drop their litter without facing any
consequences, the less effective a deterrent—the seemingly
remote possibility of a fine—becomes, however high it may
be.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000270" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000270">Enforcement is also
expensive. While higher fines might help to pay for more enforcement
officers, the fine will be paid only if the offender can afford it. If
he cannot, the case is likely to go to court and will result in even
greater costs to all concerned, without ever improving the
offender’s ability to pay or the likelihood of those costs being
recovered.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000271" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000271">The absence of a
maximum fine may also leave the system open to potential abuse. The
noble Earl, Lord Erroll, shared some of those concerns. We already hear
stories in the popular press of individuals who are justifiably
indignant about having been fined by overzealous enforcement officers
for so-called littering when they have accidentally dropped a
£10 note, or for feeding the ducks in the park. The public are
already suspicious that some local authorities use these enforcement
powers to raise additional revenue. I would hope that it is obvious to
your Lordships that we do not expect local authorities to use
fixed-penalty notices for trivial incidents in this way at all, but I
can only imagine how more aggrieved and suspicious those individuals
would feel if faced with a fine of more than £100. Some of the
local authorities that my officials have spoken to, informally, have
expressed concern that this proposal could put enforcement officers at
increased risk of challenge or even violence.
</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000272" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000272">What is more,
the increase that my noble friend proposes would, I suggest, be
disproportionate in comparison with other offences. For example, fines
for criminal damage, for making nuisance calls or for possession of
class B drugs are all set at £80 and are payable in 28 days,
while this Bill proposes fines of at least £100 which are
payable in 14 days. With no statutory maximum the perverse situation
could even arise where the on-the-spot fine exceeds the maximum penalty
which could be imposed if the case went to court. I assure my noble
friend that if there is evidence of the current fines being too low to
enable successful enforcement I am open to requests from local
authorities to review the regulations which set the minimum and maximum
limits. However, I have significant reservations about the blanket
approach proposed in the Bill.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000273" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000273">However, it is the
second part of my noble friend’s Bill which gives me most
concern. The Bill would require local authorities to “provide
appropriate disposal” points,</hs_para>
<hs_quotefo UID="13071970000320" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000320">“for chewing
gum and cigarette litter”,</hs_quotefo>
<hs_parafo UID="13071970000297" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000297">within four metres of
the entrance to any building,</hs_parafo>
<hs_quotefo UID="13071970000321" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000321">“for which
the local authority is
responsible”,</hs_quotefo><hs_parafo UID="13071970000298" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000298">and
at least one disposal point per 100 square metres throughout the area
for which the local authority is the responsible litter
authority.</hs_parafo> 
<?notus-xml column=1033?><hs_para UID="13071970000274" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000274">The
Explanatory Notes to the Bill which my noble friend has
helpfully provided suggest that, by making provision for local
authorities to finance the provision of these disposal units through
advertising, this proposal could be implemented at zero cost to
local authorities. This type of litter is indeed a persistent problem,
as my noble friend suggested. In the most recent Local Environmental
Quality Survey of England, smoking-related litter was found to be the
most prevalent form of litter and present on 82% of sites surveyed.
Staining from discarded chewing gum was found on 68% of sites, down a
small percentage from the previous year, and is known to be one of the
most difficult and costly local environmental quality problems to
tackle.</hs_para></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/1B38D0A93F450C19F788FC32334FE76189A08FB4" __version__="1.5"><Header><House>1</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>BC2-BE</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve">
<hs_para UID="13071970000275" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000275">However, your Lordships
will appreciate that what is proposed in the Bill adds up to a truly
staggering number of bins. While potentially appropriate in some busy
urban areas, the number of bins required by the Bill is likely to be
vastly disproportionate to actual demand in rural areas, on
council-owned open spaces or on land with very limited public access.
For example, placing one bin every 100 square metres would mean that
more than 70 would be required on a council-owned village green the
size of a regulation football pitch. This, presumably, does not include
the bins that my noble friend mentioned in his speech for what
he calls “dog excreta”. Even if supported by
income from advertising, the costs of installing such a vast
number of bins and their ongoing maintenance and emptying would, I am
afraid, be prohibitive to local authorities.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000276" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000276">Moreover<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:40:00"></hs_TimeCode>,
even if they were well maintained, the provision of more disposal
points might not even resolve the underlying problem because research
shows that those who discard their chewed gum or their cigarette stubs
often do not perceive them to be litter, so people may not think to
look for or use these bins even if they were available. At present,
local authorities have the power and, most importantly, the discretion
to make their own decisions about how many and what types of bins
should be provided throughout their areas to address the specific
issues that occur. This is consistent with our commitments on localism,
and surely has to be the right
answer<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:40:00"></hs_TimeCode>. Of
course, my reservations about my noble friend’s Bill do
not mean that I do not share his concerns about this blight on our
landscape. However, as I have said several times in recent debates, we
do not believe that further regulation is necessarily the right
approach to this issue.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000277" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000277">Your Lordships may be
aware that my department has for some years chaired the Chewing Gum
Action Group, which is made up of chewing gum manufacturers and is
supported by Keep Britain Tidy and its equivalent organisations in the
devolved Administrations. We are of course grateful for the support
that chewing gum manufacturers have shown over several years for
campaigns aimed at reducing the amount of chewed gum that is dropped on
our streets and elsewhere. These have certainly produced a benefit in
reduced chewing gum litter, at least for the period of the campaign, in
some cases achieving reductions of up to 90% in gum drops in the
campaign area. However, in many cases it seems that chewing gum litter
levels rise again once the effect of the campaigns has worn
off.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=1034?><hs_para UID="13071970000278" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000278">Chewing<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:40:00"></hs_TimeCode>
gum remains much harder to remove than other forms of litter, as
several noble Lords have mentioned, given the way in which it bonds to
pavement surfaces. As a consequence, local authorities still spend tens
of millions of pounds a year in laboriously clearing it up, and this
cost is much higher per tonne of chewing gum litter than for other
kinds of litter. More work is clearly needed, and research shows that
the public agree. Recent work by Keep Britain Tidy found that 82% of
the British public think that businesses should do more to prevent
litter. Work that KBT has done has shown that when a business’s
product and brand is seen in the gutter as litter, that can have a
real, negative impact on that business’s bottom line, and many
businesses are starting to recognise this.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000279" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000279">One obvious solution,
on which I would like to see much more emphasis, and this was mentioned
by the noble Baroness, Lady Smith, is the bringing to market of
non-stick chewing gums that do not bond to the surface on which they
are dropped—although, to address directly one of the points
raised by the noble Baroness, I am not sure whether it would still
stick to the bedpost. I understand that there are several kinds of
non-stick chewing gum that have already been shown to be technically
feasible and which could therefore be quickly made available. They
could have a taste and texture almost identical to current brands. If
these could rapidly replace existing formulations then no one would
lose out, and local council tax payers would save the tens of millions
of pounds a year that are currently diverted towards tackling this
avoidable
problem<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:40:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000280" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000280">Of
course education must continue to discourage the extremely antisocial
habit of dropping chewing gum, but I believe that manufacturers and
retailers could and should play a bigger part in helping here, without
the need for government regulation to bring that
about<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:40:00"></hs_TimeCode>. The noble
Baroness, Lady Smith, asked specifically what happened following the
debate last year; my noble friend Lord Taylor mentioned a meeting.
Manufacturers assure us that they have spent a significant amount of
resources on developing a biodegradable or non-stick gum. Part of the
problem in developing it, I understand, is that the same ingredients
that make it gum also make it sticky. The product has to meet safety
standards and be pleasant to consume, and these requirements have not
to date been met by a cleaner gum. Ultimately, the choice of material
is a commercial decision but we would welcome design solutions
to the problem of chewing gum litter. However, behaviour change, as the
noble Baroness said, is also important in the battle against
litter<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:40:00"></hs_TimeCode>.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000281" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000281">I
have a great deal of sympathy for my noble friend’s depth of
feeling on this subject. I agree with him that local authorities should
be encouraged to make it as easy as possible for people to do
the right thing and to dispose of their litter responsibly.
Unfortunately, though, as I have explained, I must express reservations
about his Bill.</hs_para>
<hs_time UID="13071970000352" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000352">1.45
pm<hs_TimeCode time="2013-07-19T13:44:59"></hs_TimeCode></hs_time><hs_para UID="13071970000282" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000282"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Selsdon" PimsId="642" UID="13071970000396" xid="1428" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000396">Lord
Selsdon:</Member></B> My Lords, I am most grateful to the Minister
because he has fallen into the trap of assuming that I have not done
more research than his department. He gave a classic ministerial
response which was well 
<?notus-xml column=1035?>delivered and charming. It is, of course, wrong, but that does not
matter. He referred to another Bill about unsolicited phone calls. I am
sure he has read my Bill on that subject, which will be coming before
the House very shortly.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071970000283" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000283">I take fully the points
made by the noble Earl. The objective of the Bill is to raise the
issue. We will do that through the Chewing Gum Action Group and all the
local authorities. It costs them £415 million a year to clean up
the streets at the moment. Having worked in that sort of economic
world, one would not even suggest things unless it was economic so to
do. It is not just the nuisance value. There is an education programme
that the Minister could perhaps advance. It is in front of public
buildings—government and others—that the biggest amount
of dropping takes place. That requires 
<?notus-xml column=1036?>only a schoolteacher to say, “Put it in a bin” or for
schools to have bins there, because that is where it takes place, or
outside concert halls. It is not a difficult
problem.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071970000284" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000284">I am
very grateful for the support I have here and outside. The idea is that
we move this on to the Committee stage when various issues can be
debated. I will arrange for everyone who is interested to be able to
attend the meeting. I have the latest brief from Wrigley on the
progress it is making. It was delivered this morning. When I was an
economist in an advertising agency, Wrigley was one of our
clients.</hs_para>
<hs_Procedure UID="13071970000299" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000299"><I>Bill
read a second time and committed to a Committee of the Whole
House.</I></hs_Procedure>
<hs_Procedure UID="13071970000402" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-0002.htm#13071970000402">House adjourned at
1.47 pm.</hs_Procedure></Body></Fragment></System><System type="WMS" ColStart="149"><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/17CB06D64273A3C8C8A9F8E4D7D2C54CE06D4807" __version__="1.1"><Header><House>0</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date="19 July 2013">Friday
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>Header-9-119</Section><TransformationVersion>0.5</TransformationVersion></Header><Body><hs_HoL UID="13071961000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000002">Written
Statements</hs_HoL><hs_date UID="13071961000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000001"><I>Friday
19 July
2013</I></hs_date></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/0A4CF762F48291930A71915D860D683A1816EECB" __version__="1.2"><Header><House>1</House><System>3</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>LordsWMSSection</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071961000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000017">Energy:
Shale
Gas</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13071961000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000003"><B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Hanham" PimsId="3741" UID="13071961000015" xid="1742" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000015">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department for Communities and
Local Government (Baroness Hanham):</Member></B> The coalition
Government believe shale gas has the potential to provide the UK with
greater energy security, growth and jobs. While shale gas in the UK is
in the very early stages of development, scientists from the British
Geological Survey have estimated that the total volume of gas in the
Bowland Hodder shale in northern England at some 1,300 trillion cubic
feet. The British Geological Survey is doing further work to establish
the amount of shale gas in the Weald Basin in the south-east of
England.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071961000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000004">Effective exploration
and testing of the UK’s unconventional gas resources is
therefore key for understanding the potential of this industry. The
Government are creating the right framework to accelerate shale gas
development in a responsible and sustainable way.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071961000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000005">As the shale gas
industry develops, the Government want to ensure an effective, locally
led planning system is in place. We have already made it clear that
responsibility for determining planning applications for onshore oil
and gas activities, including for the exploration of shale gas, will be
with local authorities. Decisions will therefore continue to be taken
in accordance with local plans and the National Planning Policy
Framework.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071961000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000006">Today, the Department
for Communities and Local Government is publishing planning guidance
for industry, minerals planning authorities and local communities on
how shale gas (and other onshore oil and gas) developments should
proceed through England’s planning system. I hope this will
provide clarity for business, councils and local residents. I am
placing a copy in the Library of the
House.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071961000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000007">This
guidance has been prepared in line with the recommendations of the
External Review of Planning Practice Guidance. It will be kept under
review and should be read alongside other planning guidance and the
National Planning Policy
Framework.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071961000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000008">The
Government are minded to amend existing secondary legislation in
relation to application requirements and fees for onshore oil and gas
development. We believe that greater clarity in law  
<?notus-xml column=150?>will help provide certainty to councils and encourage investment. We
will undertake a short consultation on our suggested approach, before
putting our proposals before Parliament. The Government will also set
out their position in due course on any issues that impinge on reserved
matters.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071961000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000009">The
guidance provides clarity on the role of the planning system and
interaction with the separate environmental and health and safety
regimes. Other regulators, including the Department of Energy and
Climate Change, the Environment Agency and the Health and Safety
Executive, will address sub-surface issues to protect against seismic
disturbance or pollution of groundwater. Close working between all
regulatory bodies will ensure that there remains a robust,
comprehensive and safe regulatory regime in
place.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Statement"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071961000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000018">Taxation:
Shale
Gas</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Statement</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_para UID="13071961000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000010"><B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Deighton" PimsId="7002" UID="13071961000016" xid="2168" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000016">The
Commercial Secretary to the Treasury (Lord Deighton):</Member></B>
Following the announcement at Budget 2013 that the Government would
introduce a generous new tax regime for shale gas, HM Treasury is today
publishing a consultation document, <I>Harnessing the potential of the
UK’s natural resources: a fiscal regime for shale
gas</I>.</hs_para> <hs_para UID="13071961000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000011">The
shale gas industry is in its early stages in the UK and work is needed
to assess how much of our substantial shale gas resource is technically
and commercially recoverable. The Government are committed to
supporting the industry during the critical exploration phase and
providing it with the long-term certainty it needs on the structure of
the shale gas fiscal regime. This will help ensure we maximise the
potential benefits from this resource in terms of jobs, investment and
energy
security.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071961000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000012">The
consultation outlines a proposal for a pad allowance (where a pad
refers to the drilling and extraction site) and an approach to the
extension of the Ring Fence Expenditure Supplement from six to 10
accounting periods to help encourage early investment. It closes for
responses on 13 September 2013. Where appropriate, legislation will be
brought forward in Finance Bill 2014.</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071961000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000013">The consultation
document is available
here:</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071961000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719-wms0001.htm#13071961000014">https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/harnessing-the-potential-of-the-uks-natural-resources-a-fiscal-regime-for-shale-gas</hs_para></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Writtens" ColStart="153"><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/ECFACB1AD94DDE2E352495F28D916902071682EC" __version__="1.2"><Header><House>0</House><System>0</System><Sitting short-date="19 July 2013">Friday
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>Header-10-119</Section><TransformationVersion>0.5</TransformationVersion></Header><Body><hs_HoL UID="13071962000002" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000002">Written
Answers</hs_HoL><hs_date UID="13071962000001" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000001"><I>Friday
19 July
2013</I></hs_date></Body></Fragment><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/527DE673634CF0E53DB637DF3A7E3DBD9C8764FE" __version__="1.3"><Header><House>1</House><System>1</System><Sitting short-date=" 19 July 2013">Friday,
19 July
2013</Sitting><Section>Section</Section><TransformationVersion>0.7</TransformationVersion></Header><Body xml:space="preserve"><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000072" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000072">Climate
Change</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000084" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000084">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Donoughue" PimsId="3000" UID="13071962000046" xid="1809" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000046">Lord
Donoughue</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000032" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000032">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government by how many degrees they forecast global
temperatures will be reduced, compared with a baseline case of what
would happen without intervention, as a direct result of the emissions
reductions mandated by the Climate Change Act 2008 by (1) 2050, and (2)
2100. <hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1483]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000003" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000003"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Verma" PimsId="5081" UID="13071962000047" xid="1929" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000047">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department of Energy and
Climate Change (Baroness Verma):</Member> The United
Kingdom's 80% emissions reduction target for 2050 is derived from
estimates of the UK's share of the global effort needed in order to
keep the increase in global average temperature to below 2 Degrees
Celsius above pre-industrial levels. The UK does not have emissions
reduction target set for 2100. The UK's emissions reductions alone
would result in a small but crucial proportion of total global
emissions reductions, as all countries need to contribute to achieving
the 2 degree goal. It is vital that we show leadership and
demonstrate that the shift to a low carbon model is achievable in order
to influence other major emitters to take
action.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000073" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000073">Education
Act
1996</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000085" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000085">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Whitaker" PimsId="4578" UID="13071962000048" xid="1494" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000048">Baroness
Whitaker</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000033" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000033">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government, further to the Written Answer by Lord Nash
on 11 July (<I>WA 68</I>), whether they will publish on the
Government website the responses to their consultation document on the
repeal of section 444(6) of the Education Act
1996.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1668]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000004" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000004"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Nash" PimsId="7004" UID="13071962000049" xid="2171" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000049">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State for Schools (Lord
Nash):</Member> A summary of responses will be published on the
Department's website, alongside the Government's response to the
consultation,
shortly.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000074" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000074">Elections:
Northern Ireland
Assembly</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000086" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000086">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Kilclooney" PimsId="189" UID="13071962000050" xid="1660" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000050">Lord
Kilclooney</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000034" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000034">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what was the percentage participation in
the last Northern Ireland Assembly election; and what proposals they
have to increase participation in the next Assembly
election. <hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1634]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000005" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000005"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Randerson" PimsId="5929" UID="13071962000051" xid="2139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000051">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Wales Office (Baroness
Randerson):</Member> The turnout at the Northern Ireland Assembly
election in 2011 was 55.71%.</hs_para> 
<?notus-xml column=154?><hs_para UID="13071962000006" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000006">The Government is
committed to engaging the electorate in elections and wider democratic
activity. We have provided additional funding to the Electoral Office
for Northern Ireland to support efforts to improve the accuracy and
completeness of the electoral register, including through a canvass of
electors in autumn
2013.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000007" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000007">The
Government does not directly promote turnout in elections; that is
primarily the role of the political parties and candidates. The
Electoral Commission's functions include promoting public awareness of
electoral systems in the UK and it seeks to make sure people understand
the importance of registering to vote, and know how to
vote.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000075" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000075">Gaza</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000087" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000087">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Tonge" PimsId="4873" UID="13071962000052" xid="1888" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000052">Baroness
Tonge</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000035" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000035">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what is their assessment of the current
situation with regard to medical supplies in Gazan
hospitals.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1670]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000008" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000008"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Northover" PimsId="2142" UID="13071962000053" xid="1368" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000053">Baroness
Northover:</Member> The ongoing restrictions on movement of people and
supplies to and from the Gaza Strip continue adversely to affect the
quality of medical
services.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000009" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000009">The
UK is supporting the UN Access Coordination Unit to work with the World
Health Organisation, Israel, the Palestinian Authority and aid agencies
to facilitate the transfer of medical equipment and supplies and
patient referrals in and out of Gaza. We also continue to work
alongside other donors, including the EU, to raise our concerns about
movement and access restrictions with the Israeli
Government.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000076" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000076">Government:
Ministerial
Visits</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000088" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000088">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Stern" PimsId="4123" UID="13071962000054" xid="1447" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000054">Baroness
Stern</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000036" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000036">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government which institutions of the secure youth
estate (1) the Secretary of State for Education, and (2) Ministers in
the Department of Education, have visited since May 2010; and on what
date each such visit took
place.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1632]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000010" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000010"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Nash" PimsId="7004" UID="13071962000055" xid="2171" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000055">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State for Schools (Lord
Nash):</Member> On 9 February 2012, Tim Loughton MP, former
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State (Children and Families) visited
Beechfield Secure Children's Home, Effingham Road, West
Sussex.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000077" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000077">Israel
and
Palestine</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000089" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000089">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Tonge" PimsId="4873" UID="13071962000056" xid="1888" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000056">Baroness
Tonge</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000037" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000037">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what discussions they have held with the
government of Israel concerning the implications of Palestinian natural
growth needs within East
Jerusalem.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1674]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question>

<?notus-xml column=155?><hs_para UID="13071962000011" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000011"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Northover" PimsId="2142" UID="13071962000057" xid="1368" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000057">Baroness
Northover:</Member> In the last year we have raised the issue of
adequate planning for Palestinians in East Jerusalem with the Jerusalem
municipality, the Prime Minister's office and the Ministry of Foreign
Affairs.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000012" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000012">The
UK also supports long-term planning for Palestinian communities in East
Jerusalem and the West Bank through the Conflict
Pool.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000078" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000078">Local
Enterprise
Partnerships</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000090" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000090">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Berkeley" PimsId="3972" UID="13071962000058" xid="1072" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000058">Lord
Berkeley</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000038" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000038">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether Local Enterprise Partnerships are
subject to the Freedom of Information Act 2000 and the Environmental
Information Regulations
2004.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1413]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000013" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000013"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Northover" PimsId="2142" UID="13071962000059" xid="1368" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000059">Baroness
Northover:</Member> Local Enterprise Partnerships (LPs) are voluntary
strategic partnerships between business and civic leaders and their
exact legal status has been a matter for LEPs themselves to
determine.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000014" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000014">The
Department for Business (RIB) considers that LEPs are not generally
subject to the FoI Act and the EIR, on the basis that LEPs do not
generally fall within the definition of public authority for the
purposes of either piece of
legislation.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000079" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000079">NHS
Leadership
Academy</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000091" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000091">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Gould of Potternewton" PimsId="3514" UID="13071962000060" xid="1245" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000060">Baroness
Gould of Potternewton</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000039" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000039">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government who are the members of the NHS Leadership
Board; and what are the criteria to which they
work.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1415]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000015" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000015"><Member ContinuationText="Earl Howe" PimsId="1035" UID="13071962000061" xid="1749" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000061">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Department of Health (Earl
Howe):</Member> We understand the noble Lady may be
referring to the programme board of the NHS Leadership Academy. The
members of this programme board are as follows:</hs_para><hs_WAIndent>-
Martin Barkley, Chief Executive of the Tees, Esk and Wear Valley NHS
Foundation Trust;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Michael Coughlin,
Executive Director of the Local Government
Association;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Dr Gordon Coutts, Chief
Executive, Colchester Hospital University NHS Foundation
Trust;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Ian Cumming, Chief Executive of
Health Education England;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- David Flory,
Chief Executive of the NHS Trust Development
Authority;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Richard Gregory, Chairman of the
Chesterfield Royal NHS Foundation Trust;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Dr
Sunil Gupta, Clinical Chair of Castle Point and Rochford Clinical
Commissioning Group;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Julian Hartley,
Managing Director of NHS Improving Quality;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>-
Bart Johnson, Chief Executive of Virgin
Care;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Karen Lynas, Deputy Managing Director
and Head of Programme and Practice of the NHS Leadership
Academy;</hs_WAIndent> 
<?notus-xml column=156?><hs_WAIndent>- Charlie Massey, Director General of the Department of
Health;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Dr Tim Moorhead, Clinical Chair of
Sheffield Clinical Commissioning Group; - Sir David Nicholson, Chief
Executive of NHS England;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Deborah McKenzie,
Director of Organisational Development, Public Health
England;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Jan Sobieraj, Managing Director of
the NHS Leadership Academy;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Tracey Taylor,
Chief Executive of Birmingham Community NHS Trust; and</hs_WAIndent>
<hs_WAIndent>- Jo-Anne Wass, National Director of Human Resources, NHS
England.</hs_WAIndent><hs_para UID="13071962000016" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000016">The
criteria to which the members of the NHS Leadership Academy programme
board work are set out in the following programme board terms of
reference.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000017" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000017">NHS
Leadership Academy programme board terms of
reference</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000018" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000018">The
role of the NHS Leadership Academy (Academy) programme board is
to:</hs_para><hs_WAIndent>- Inform and endorse the Academy
strategy;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Ensure accountability through
robust and reliable assurance;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Seek synergy
with partners;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Consider
longer term infrastructure requirements;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>-
Shape a positive culture based on the principles of the NHS
Constitution; and</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Give priority to
engagement with key stakeholders and opinion
formers.</hs_WAIndent><hs_para UID="13071962000019" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000019">It
will do this by:</hs_para><hs_WAIndent>- Agreeing an annual strategic
framework supported by a business plan;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>-
Maintaining a risk register;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Reviewing
quarterly progress on performance;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>-
Providing a strategic view on leadership development; and</hs_WAIndent>
<hs_WAIndent>- Championing and promoting the
Academy.</hs_WAIndent><hs_para UID="13071962000020" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000020">Reporting
Arrangements:</hs_para><hs_WAIndent>- Papers will be issued one week in
advance;</hs_WAIndent><hs_WAIndent>- Deputies may attend by exception
only and with the Chairs approval only; and</hs_WAIndent>
<hs_WAIndent>- Minutes will be distributed within 2 weeks of the
meeting.</hs_WAIndent><hs_para UID="13071962000021" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000021">Frequency
of Meetings:</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000022" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000022">-
The Academy programme board will meet quarterly for up to two
hours.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000023" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000023">Review:</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000024" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000024">-
The terms of reference will be reviewed annually from September
2013.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000080" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000080">Northern
Ireland Parades
Commission</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Questions</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000092" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000092">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Laird" PimsId="1388" UID="13071962000062" xid="1304" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000062">Lord
Laird</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000040" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000040">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government whether they will make available all the
information considered by the members of the Northern Ireland Parades 
<?notus-xml column=157?>Commission in deciding upon the determination at Ardoyne on Friday 12
July; and whether they can further indicate whether such information is
available under the Freedom of Information Act
2000. <hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1658]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_Question UID="13071962000041" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000041">To
ask Her Majesty’s Government which Northern Ireland Parades
Commissioners attended the meeting that applied a determination on a
parade at Ardoyne on Friday 12 July; which way they voted; and whether
that information is available under the Freedom of Information Act
2000.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1659]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000025" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000025"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Randerson" PimsId="5929" UID="13071962000063" xid="2139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000063">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Wales Office (Baroness
Randerson):</Member> The Parades Commission for Northern Ireland
operates independently of Government. The Noble Lord may wish to write
to the Commission directly on these
matters.</hs_para><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000093" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000093">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Laird" PimsId="1388" UID="13071962000064" xid="1304" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000064">Lord
Laird</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000042" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000042">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what qualities are specified in the job
description of members of the Northern Ireland Parades Commission; and
whether that information is available under the Freedom of Information
Act
2000.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1660]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000026" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000026"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Randerson" PimsId="5929" UID="13071962000065" xid="2139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000065">Baroness
Randerson:</Member> The skills and qualities required by members of the
Parades Commission are clearly  set out in the Parades
Commission Appointments Information Pack which may be viewed
at:</hs_para>
<hs_para UID="13071962000027" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000027">http://publicappointments.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/appointments/download/513f3523e4b05a42eb243393.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000081" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000081">Police:
Northern
Ireland</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000094" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000094">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Eames" PimsId="3066" UID="13071962000066" xid="1202" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000066">Lord
Eames</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000043" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000043">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what was the cost of transferring police
officers from the rest of the United Kingdom to assist the Police
Service of Northern Ireland during the Twelfth of July events; what
proportion of that cost was met by the devolved administrations; and
what proportion of the cost was met from other
sources.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1604]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000028" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000028"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Randerson" PimsId="5929" UID="13071962000067" xid="2139" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000067">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State, Wales Office (Baroness
Randerson):</Member> This is an operational matter for the Chief
Constable. Ministerial responsibility for public order mutual aid rests
with the Northern Ireland Executive Justice Minister David Ford
including how the costs of any request will be met. I understand that
it will take some weeks for final costs to be
audited.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question">

<?notus-xml column=158?><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000082" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000082">Schools:
Cycling</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000095" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000095">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Greaves" PimsId="3545" UID="13071962000068" xid="1111" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000068">Lord
Greaves</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000044" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000044">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government what discussions have taken place between
Ministers or officials from the Department for Transport and the
Department for Education about making Bikeability cycle training
available for all primary and secondary school-age
pupils.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1622]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000029" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000029"><Member ContinuationText="Lord Nash" PimsId="7004" UID="13071962000069" xid="2171" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000069">The
Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State for Schools (Lord
Nash):</Member> Informal discussions have taken place between officials
from the Department of Transport and the Department for Education about
the possibility of including Bikeability in the national
curriculum.</hs_para><hs_para UID="13071962000030" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000030">The
national curriculum focuses on the core essential knowledge that all
pupils need to succeed, whilst allowing teachers the freedom to design
a wider school curriculum which best meets the needs of their pupils.
Whilst Bikeability is not a compulsory part of the national curriculum,
schools are welcome to teach Bikeability cycle training as part of
their wider school curriculum and many already do
so.</hs_para><NewDebate BusinessType="Question"><hs_DebateHeading UID="13071962000083" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000083">Somaliland,
Puntland and
Somalia</hs_DebateHeading><hs_DebateType>Question</hs_DebateType></NewDebate><hs_TabledBy UID="13071962000096" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000096">Asked
by
<B><Member ContinuationText="Lord Boateng" PimsId="5772" UID="13071962000070" xid="2048" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000070">Lord
Boateng</Member></B></hs_TabledBy>
<hs_Question UID="13071962000045" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000045">To ask Her
Majesty’s Government, further to the Written Answer by Baroness
Warsi on 3 July (<I>WA 234</I>), what progress has been made following
the officials meeting convened by the Foreign and Commonwealth Office
on 24 June to safeguard the contribution of the role that remittances
play in supporting the economy and people of (1) Somaliland, (2)
Puntland, and (3)
Somalia.<hs_QuestionUIN>[HL1656]</hs_QuestionUIN></hs_Question><hs_para UID="13071962000031" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000031"><Member ContinuationText="Baroness Northover" PimsId="2142" UID="13071962000071" xid="1368" url="/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130719w0001.htm#13071962000071">Baroness
Northover:</Member> DFID continues to work closely with the Treasury,
the Serious Organised Crime Agency and the Foreign Office to assess the
situation and secure a commercial solution. These solutions should
reconcile the need for improved security in the international money
transfer system, with maintaining the access of migrant families to
accessible, affordable money transfer services. We will also work with
our aid partners to mitigate any negative consequences, although DFID
development programming in Somalia, which supports some of the poorest
and most vulnerable people there, will not be
affected.</hs_para></Body></Fragment></System><System type="Index"><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/Index/F40BCA22CDF95F0C3C8B3F22212C6D84D54C2B6B" __version__="1.2"><Index cdate="26" cday="Friday" cmonth="July" cyear="2013" date="19" day="Friday" issue="39" maxparts="1" month="July" part="1" price="" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="747" year="2013"><tocdate col="WS149">Friday 19 July 2013</tocdate><title>ALPHABETICAL
INDEX TO WRITTEN
STATEMENTS</title><level1 col="WS149">Energy: Shale
Gas</level1><level1 col="WS150">Taxation:
Shale Gas</level1><tocdate col="WS149">Friday 19
July 2013</tocdate><title>ALPHABETICAL INDEX TO WRITTEN
ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA153">Climate
Change</level1><level1 col="WA153">Education
Act
1996</level1><level1 col="WA153">Elections:
Northern Ireland
Assembly</level1><level1 col="WA154">Gaza</level1><level1 col="WA154">Government:
Ministerial
Visits</level1><level1 col="WA154">Israel
and
Palestine</level1><level1 col="WA155">Local
Enterprise
Partnerships</level1><level1 col="WA155">NHS
Leadership
Academy</level1><level1 col="WA156">Northern
Ireland Parades
Commission</level1><level1 col="WA157">Police:
Northern
Ireland</level1><level1 col="WA158">Schools:
Cycling</level1><level1 col="WA158">Somaliland,
Puntland and Somalia</level1><title>NUMERICAL INDEX
TO WRITTEN
ANSWERS</title><level1 col="WA155">[HL1413]</level1><level1 col="WA155">[HL1415]</level1><level1 col="WA153">[HL1483]</level1><level1 col="WA157">[HL1604]</level1><level1 col="WA158">[HL1622]</level1><level1 col="WA154">[HL1632]</level1><level1 col="WA153">[HL1634]</level1><level1 col="WA158">[HL1656]</level1><level1 col="WA157">[HL1658]</level1><level1 col="WA157">[HL1659]</level1><level1 col="WA157">[HL1660]</level1><level1 col="WA153">[HL1668]</level1><level1 col="WA154">[HL1670]</level1><level1 col="WA154">[HL1674]</level1></Index></Fragment></System><System type="Back_Cover"><?date 2013-07-19?><Fragment __lock__="0" __shareable__="false" __uri__="/files/documents/default/HOL/2013_2014/DailyParts/2013_07_19_PT_1/Cover/F95F0C3C8B3F22212C6D84D54C2B6BF40BCA22CD" __version__="1.2"><Contents cdate="26" cday="Friday" cmonth="July" cyear="2013" date="19" day="Friday" issue="39" maxparts="1" month="July" part="1" price="4@010c00" printing="daily" session="201314" volume="747" year="2013"><citicont1 col="981">Littering
from Vehicles Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="1006">Alan
Turing (Statutory Pardon) Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="1024">Clean
Neighbourhoods and Environment (Amendment) Bill [HL] <I>Second
Reading</I></citicont1><citicont1 col="WS 149">Written
Statements</citicont1><citicont1 col="WA 153">Written
Answers</citicont1></Contents></Fragment></System></House></HansardDoc>