<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Legislation SchemaVersion="1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation C:\development\projects\ActsToSchema\legislationSchema\schema\schemaLegislationBase-v1-0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:leg="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/legislation" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ukm="http://www.tso.co.uk/assets/namespace/metadata" xmlns:fo="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Format">
<ukm:Metadata>
<dc:title>Marriage (Approved Organisations) Bill</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>ISBN TO GO HERE</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Parliamentary Counsel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>17/5/2013</dc:date>
<ukm:BillMetadata>
<ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:DocumentCategory Value="Bill" />
<ukm:DocumentMainType Value="PublicBill" />
<ukm:DocumentStatus Value="final" />
</ukm:DocumentClassification>
<ukm:Number Value="Bill 27" />
<ukm:Parliament Value="55" />
<ukm:Session Value="3" />
<ukm:House Value="House of Lords" />
</ukm:BillMetadata>
</ukm:Metadata>
<Contents>
<Rubric TemplateVersion="4.2.002" xmlns="" /><Rubric xmlns="" /><ContentsTitle>Contents</ContentsTitle>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00005">
<ContentsNumber>1</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Marriages according to usages of approved organisations</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00010">
<ContentsNumber>2</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Consequential amendments</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsItem ContentRef="p00011">
<ContentsNumber>3</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Citation, commencement and extent</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsItem>
<ContentsSchedules>
<ContentsSchedule ContentRef="p00012">
<ContentsNumber>Schedule</ContentsNumber>
<ContentsTitle>Consequential amendments</ContentsTitle>
</ContentsSchedule>
</ContentsSchedules>
</Contents>
<Primary>
<PrimaryPrelims>
<Title><?start-line?>A
<?new-line?>Bill

<?new-line?>To
</Title>
<Number /><LongTitle><?start-line?><Para>
<Text>Amend the law on marriage to permit the Registrar General to permit certain <?new-line?>charitable organisations to solemnise marriages.<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
</Text>
</Para>
</LongTitle>
<DateOfEnactment><DateText /></DateOfEnactment>
<PrimaryPreamble>
<EnactingText>
<Para>
<Text>B<SmallCaps>e it enacted</SmallCaps> by the Queen’s most Excellent Majesty, by and with the advice and <?new-line?>consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in this present <?new-line?>Parliament assembled, and by the authority of the same, as follows:—</Text>
</Para>
</EnactingText>
</PrimaryPreamble>
</PrimaryPrelims>
<Body NumberFormat="default">
<P1group id="p00005">
<Title><?start-line?>Marriages according to usages of approved organisations</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>In the Marriage Act 1949, after section 47, insert the following section—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Marriages according to usages of approved organisations</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>47A</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2 id="p00006">
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Registrar General may by certificate approve organisations to <?new-line?>solemnise marriages according to their usages provided that any such <?new-line?>organisation—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>is a registered charity concerned with advancing or practising a <?new-line?>religion or belief, including a non-religious belief;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>does not possess or have the use of any registered place of <?new-line?>worship; and</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>c</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>appears to the Registrar General to be of good repute.</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2 id="p00007">
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In the certificate referred to in subsection <InternalLink id="i00001" Ref="p00006">(1)</InternalLink> the Registrar General shall <?new-line?>designate an officer of the organisation (“the principal officer”) to <?new-line?>appoint persons for stated periods of time to act as registering officers <?new-line?>on behalf of the organisation, and may impose such conditions as seem <?new-line?>to him or her to be desirable relative to the conduct of marriages by the <?new-line?>organisation and to the safe custody of marriage register books.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2 id="p00008">
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>The principal officer shall, within the prescribed time and in the <?new-line?>prescribed manner, certify the names and addresses of the persons so <?new-line?>appointed to the Registrar General and to the superintendent registrars <?new-line?>of the registration districts in which such persons live, together with <?new-line?>such other details as the Registrar General shall require.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A marriage shall not be solemnised according to the usages of an <?new-line?>approved organisation until duplicate marriage register books have </Text><?new-page?><?start-line?>  <Text>been supplied by the Registrar General under Part IV of this Act to the <?new-line?>registering officers appointed to act on behalf of the organisation.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>If the Registrar General is not satisfied with respect to any registering <?new-line?>officer of the approved organisation that sufficient security exists for <?new-line?>the safe custody of marriage register books, he or she may in his or her <?new-line?>discretion suspend the appointment of that registering officer.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A marriage to which this section applies shall be solemnised with open <?new-line?>doors in the presence of either—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a registrar of the registration district in which the marriage <?new-line?>takes place; or</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a registering officer appointed under subsection <InternalLink id="i00002" Ref="p00007">(2)</InternalLink> whose <?new-line?>name and address have been certified in accordance with <?new-line?>subsection <InternalLink id="i00003" Ref="p00008">(3)</InternalLink> and of two witnesses;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
<Text><?start-line?>and the persons to be married shall make the declarations and use the <?new-line?>form of words set out in subsection (3) or (3A) of section 44.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2 id="p00009">
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A marriage solemnised according to the usages of an approved <?new-line?>organisation shall not be valid unless there is produced to the <?new-line?>superintendent registrar, at the time when notice of marriage is given, <?new-line?>a certificate signed by the principal officer or a registering officer of the <?new-line?>approved organisation that each person giving notice of marriage is a <?new-line?>member of the said organisation.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>A certificate under subsection <InternalLink id="i00004" Ref="p00009">(7)</InternalLink> shall be for all purposes conclusive <?new-line?>evidence that any person to whom it relates is authorised to be married <?new-line?>according to the usages of the said organisation and the entry of the <?new-line?>marriage in a marriage register book under Part IV of this Act, or a <?new-line?>certified copy thereof made under the said Part IV, shall be conclusive <?new-line?>evidence of the production of such a certificate.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</BlockAmendment>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00010">
<Title><?start-line?>Consequential amendments</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>The Marriage Act 1949 shall have effect subject to the amendments specified in <?new-line?>the Schedule to this Act.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
<P1group id="p00011">
<Title><?start-line?>Citation, commencement and extent</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<P2>
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act extends to England and Wales.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act may be cited as the Marriage (Approved Organisations) Act 2013 and <?new-line?>together with the Marriage Acts 1949 to 1994 and the Marriage (Wales) Acts <?new-line?>1986 to 2010 may be cited as the Marriage Acts 1949 to 2013.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>This Act shall come into force at the end of the period of three months <?new-line?>beginning with the day on which it is passed.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</Body>
<?new-page?>
<Schedules>
<Schedule id="p00012" NumberFormat="default">
<Number><?start-line?>Schedule</Number>
<TitleBlock>
<Title><?start-line?>Consequential amendments</Title>
</TitleBlock>
<Reference>Section 2</Reference>
<ScheduleBody>
<P>
<Text><?start-line?>The following amendments are made to the Marriage Act 1949—</Text>
<P2 id="p00013">
<Pnumber>1</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 26 (marriages which may be solemnised on authority of <?new-line?>superintendent registrar’s certificate) in subsection (1) after paragraph (c) <?new-line?>there is inserted—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P3>
<Pnumber>ca</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>a marriage conducted under the auspices of an approved <?new-line?>organisation;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</BlockAmendment>
<AppendText>.</AppendText>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>2</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 35 (marriages in registration district in which neither party <?new-line?>resides) after “the Society of Friends” there is inserted “or of an approved <?new-line?>organisation”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>3</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 43 (appointment of authorised persons) in subsection (3) after “the <?new-line?>Society of Friends” there is inserted “or of an organisation authorised by the <?new-line?>Registrar General under section 47A”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>4</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 50 (person to whom certificate to be delivered), in subsection (1) <?new-line?>after paragraph (d) there is inserted—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P3>
<Pnumber>da</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>if the marriage is to be solemnised according to the usages of <?new-line?>an approved organisation, a registering officer of that <?new-line?>organisation</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</BlockAmendment>
<AppendText>.</AppendText>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>5</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>After section 52, the following section is inserted—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P1group>
<Title><?start-line?>Interpretation</Title>
<P1>
<Pnumber>52A</Pnumber>
<P1para>
<Text><?start-line?>In this Part of this Act “approved organisation” has the meaning <?new-line?>given to it in section 67.</Text>
</P1para>
</P1>
</P1group>
</BlockAmendment>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>6</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 53 (persons by whom marriages are to be registered), after <?new-line?>paragraph (b) there is inserted—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<P3>
<Pnumber>ba</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>in the case of a marriage solemnised according to the usages <?new-line?>of an approved organisation, a registering officer of that <?new-line?>organisation;</Text>
</P3para>
</P3>
</BlockAmendment>
<AppendText>.</AppendText>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>7</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 54 (provision of marriage register books by Registrar General), in <?new-line?>subsection (1) after the words “the Society of Friends,” there is inserted <?new-line?>“registering officer of every approved organisation”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>8</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 55 (manner of registration of marriages)—</Text>
<P3>
<Pnumber>a</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>in subsection (1) after the words “the Society of Friends” there is <?new-line?>inserted “or of an approved organisation”; and</Text>

</P3para></P3>
<P3>
<Pnumber>b</Pnumber>
<P3para>
<Text><?start-line?>in subsection (1)(b) after the words “the Society of Friends” there is <?new-line?>inserted “or of an approved organisation” and after the words “the <?new-line?>said Society” there is inserted “or organisation”.</Text>

</P3para></P3>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>9</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 57 (quarterly returns to be made to superintendent registrar), in <?new-line?>subsection (1) after the words “the Society of Friends” there is inserted “or of <?new-line?>an approved organisation”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<?new-page?><P2>
<Pnumber>10</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 59 (custody of register books) after the words “the Society of <?new-line?>Friends” there is inserted “or of an approved organisation”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>11</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 60 (filled register books) in subsection (1), paragraph (b), after the <?new-line?>words “registering officer of the Society of Friends” there is inserted “or of <?new-line?>an approved organisation”; after the words “members of the Society of <?new-line?>Friends” there is inserted “or of the said organisation”, and after the words <?new-line?>“the said Society” there is inserted “or organisation”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>12</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 63 (searches in register books) after the words “the Society of <?new-line?>Friends” there is inserted “or of an approved organisation”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>13</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 67 (interpretation of Part IV), there are inserted in the list of <?new-line?>definitions the following—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>“approved organisation” means an organisation approved by <?new-line?>the Registrar General under section 47A of this Act;” and</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>““registering officer of an approved organisation” means a <?new-line?>person whom the principal officer of the said organisation <?new-line?>certifies in writing under his or her hand to the Registrar <?new-line?>General to be a registering officer in England or Wales of that <?new-line?>organisation;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</BlockAmendment>
<AppendText>;</AppendText>
<Text><?start-line?>and in the definition of “superintendent registrar” after paragraph (b) <?new-line?>insert—</Text>
<BlockAmendment TargetClass="primary" Context="main" TargetSubClass="unknown" Format="double">
<UnorderedList Decoration="none" Class="Definition">
<ListItem>
<Para>
<OrderedList Decoration="parens" Type="roman">
<ListItem NumberOverride=" ba">
<Para>
<Text><?start-line?>in the case of a marriage registered by a registering <?new-line?>officer of an approved organisation, the superintendent <?new-line?>registrar of the registration district which is assigned by <?new-line?>the Registrar General to that registering officer;</Text>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</OrderedList>
</Para>
</ListItem>
</UnorderedList>
</BlockAmendment>
<AppendText>.</AppendText>
</P2para>
</P2>
<P2>
<Pnumber>14</Pnumber>
<P2para>
<Text><?start-line?>In section 75 (offences relating to solemnisation of marriages) in subsection <?new-line?>(1), paragraph (a), after the words “the Society of Friends” there is inserted <?new-line?>“or of an approved organisation”; and in subsection (2), paragraph (a), after <?new-line?>the words “the Society of Friends” there is inserted “or of an approved <?new-line?>organisation”.</Text>
</P2para>
</P2>
</P>
</ScheduleBody>
</Schedule>
</Schedules>
</Primary>
</Legislation>