<?xml version="1.0"?>
<amendments>
<header>
<billtitle>Online_Safety_(HLBill8(a))</billtitle>
<headertext>AMENDMENTS TO  BE  MOVED IN  COMMITTEE</headertext>
</header>
<clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
<proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 3, after &#8220;pornographic&#8221; insert &#8220;and violent&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 7, after &#8220;pornographic&#8221; insert &#8220;and violent&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 11, after &#8220;pornographic&#8221; insert &#8220;and violent&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 17, after &#8220;pornographic&#8221; insert &#8220;and violent&#8221;</quote>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>Clause 4</clausenumber>
<proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> Clause 4, leave out Clause 4 and insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Role of OFCOM</quote>
<quote>(1) It shall be the duty of OFCOM to set, and from time, to time to review and revise, standards for the&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) filtering of adult content in line with the standards set out in section 319 of the Communications Act 2003;</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) age verification policies to be used under section 1 of this Act.</IndentOne>
<quote>(2) The standards set out by OFCOM under this section must be contained in one or more codes.</quote>
<quote>(3) Before setting standards under subsection (1), OFCOM must publish, in such a manner as they think fit, a draft of the proposed code containing those standards.</quote>
<quote>(4) After publishing the draft code and before setting the standards, OFCOM must consult relevant persons and organisations.</quote>
<quote>(5) It shall be the duty of OFCOM themselves to establish procedures for the handling and resolution of complaints about the observance of standards set under this section.</quote>
<quote>(6) OFCOM must prepare a report for the Secretary of State about the operation of this Act&#8212;</quote>
<IndentOne>(a) every three years from the date of Royal Assent; and</IndentOne>
<IndentOne>(b) at the direction of the Secretary of State.&#8221;</IndentOne>
</text>
</Amendment>
<clausenumber>After Clause 4</clausenumber>
<proposer>BARONESS HOWE OF IDLICOTE</proposer>
<Amendment>
<Number>000</Number>
<text>
<quote><B>000:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
<quote> &#8220;Secretary of State duty to educate parents of children under 18 on online safety</quote>
<IndentOne>The Secretary of State must provide means of educating parents of children under the age of eighteen about online safety.&#8221;</IndentOne>
</text>
</Amendment>
</amendments>

