<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>23 October</Date>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>Counsellors and Psychotherapists (Regulation)</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>Bill to provide that the Health Professionals Council be the regulatory body for counsellors and psychotherapists; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>funding for local authorities: TEN MINUTE RULE MOTION</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That leave be given to bring in a Bill to establish a commission to identify the changes in the law necessary to provide for the differing requirements for funding of local authorities taking into account the varying demand for the services they provide; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>23</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>OPPOSITION DAY (8th ALLOTTED DAY)</OrderTitle>
      <so>9(3)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>Dealing with the past in Northern Ireland</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House notes the ongoing discussions in Northern Ireland chaired by Dr Richard Haass on a number of important issues including the legacy of the Troubles; recognises the deep sense of loss still felt by the innocent victims of violence and their continuing quest for truth and justice; acknowledges the valour and sacrifice of the men and women who served and continue to serve in the armed forces, the police and the prison service in Northern Ireland; and is resolved to ensure that those who engaged in or supported acts of terrorism will not succeed in rewriting the narrative of this troubled period in Northern Ireland’s history.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>Air passenger duty</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House recognises that the UK has the highest rate of air passenger duty (APD) in the world; believes that this is detrimental to attracting inward investment, encouraging exports, drawing more tourists to the UK and helping ordinary families to benefit from aviation; notes research carried out by PricewaterhouseCoopers and others stating that abolishing APD would not only pay for itself but would be a permanent economic boost to the UK economy and create tens of thousands of jobs; further believes that the abolition of this tax would be of benefit to all regions of the UK; further notes that it is the intention of the Prime Minister to review green taxes; and calls on the Government, as part of that review, to give high priority to the abolition of air passenger duty.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>PRESENTATION OF PUBLIC PETITIONS</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>Changes to the Probation Service (Mr Iain Wright)</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Child and adolescent inpatient mental health services</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>