<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>15 October</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>REGULATION OF THE PRIVATE RENTED SECTOR:TEN MINUTE RULE MOTION</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That leave be given to bring in a Bill to provide for the regulation of letting agents; to protect tenants’ deposits; to require the enforcement of environmental and energy-efficiency standards in private-sector rented accommodation; to amend the law on secure tenancies; to provide for fair rent to be applicable to all rented accommodation; to require landlords not to discriminate against people in receipt of state benefits; to require local authorities to establish a private rented sector office; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>23</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>ANTI-SOCIAL BEHAVIOUR, CRIME AND POLICING BILL: REPORT (DAY 2) AND THIRD READING</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>As amended in the Public Bill Committee, to be further considered</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <OrderTitle>DEEP SEA MINING BILL: WAYS AND MEANS</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, for the purposes of any Act resulting from the Deep Sea Mining Bill, it is expedient to authorise:</p>
         <p>(1) the imposition of charges in connection with licences granted as a result of the Act, and</p>
         <p>(2) the payment of sums into the Consolidated Fund.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>52(1)(A)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <OrderTitle>CIVIL AVIATION SAFETY</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House takes note of European Union Document No. 12864/13, a draft Commission Regulation (EU) No. .../… of XXX amending Regulation (EU) No. 965/2012 laying down technical requirements and administrative procedures related to air operations pursuant to Regulation (EC) No. 216/2008 of the European Parliament and of the Council; notes that the Government recognises the importance of managing crew fatigue to support civil aviation safety; supports the Government’s view that the measures will establish safety improvements across the European Union and maintain safety in the UK; and further supports the Government’s view that the measures respect subsidiarity principles and help to deliver a level playing field across the EU.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>119(11)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <OrderTitle>NATIONAL HEALTH SERVICE</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft National Health Service (Licence Exemptions, etc.) Regulations 2013, which were laid before this House on 4 July, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>118(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>PRESENTATION OF PUBLIC PETITIONS</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>Elections in Zimbabwe (Fiona Mactaggart)</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>Replacement of Blaxhall Post Box (Suffolk) (Dr Thérèse Coffey)</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>The Save Coniston GP Surgery campaign (Tim Farron)</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>The Save Hawkshead GP Surgery campaign (Tim Farron)</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Role of the Attorney General in reviewing legislation passed by the National Assembly for Wales</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>