<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>11 November</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>offender rehabilitation bill [lords]: SECOND READING</OrderTitle>
      <so>9(3)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>offender rehabilitation bill [lords]: programme</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the following provisions shall apply to the Offender Rehabilitation Bill [Lords]:</p>
         <p>(1) The Bill shall be committed to a Public Bill Committee.</p>
         <p>(2) Proceedings in the Public Bill Committee shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion on Tuesday 3 December 2013.</p>
         <p>(3) The Public Bill Committee shall have leave to sit twice on the first day on which it meets.</p>
         <p>(4) Proceedings on Consideration shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion one hour before the moment of interruption on the day on which those proceedings are commenced.</p>
         <p>(5) Proceedings on Third Reading shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion at the moment of interruption on that day.</p>
         <p>(6) Standing Order No. 83B (Programming committees) shall not apply to proceedings on Consideration and Third Reading.</p>
         <p>(7) Any other proceedings on the Bill (including any proceedings on consideration of any message from the Lords) may be programmed.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>83A</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>deferred divisions</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, at this day’s sitting, Standing Order No. 41A (Deferred divisions) shall not apply to the Motion on a Reasoned Opinion relating to the regulation of new psychoactive substances.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>PRESENTATION OF PUBLIC PETITIONS</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>Speed limit in Elterwater, Cumbria (Tim Farron)</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>Housing development off Hillside Close (Bozeat, Northamptonshire) (Mr Peter Bone)</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Lottery funded projects and feed-in-tariffs</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>