<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>22 October</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>descendants of deceased adopted people (access to information): TEN MINUTE RULE MOTION</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That leave be given to bring in a Bill to amend the Adoption and Children Act 2002 to allow access to information for the descendants of deceased adopted people; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>23</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>immigration bill: second reading</OrderTitle>
      <so> 9(3)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <OrderTitle>immigration bill: PROGRAMME</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the following provisions shall apply to the Immigration Bill:</p>
         <p>(1) The Bill shall be committed to a Public Bill Committee.</p>
         <p>(2) Proceedings in the Public Bill Committee shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion on Tuesday 19 November 2013.</p>
         <p>(3) The Public Bill Committee shall have leave to sit twice on the first day on which it meets.</p>
         <p>(4) Proceedings on Consideration shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion one hour before the moment of interruption on the day on which those proceedings are commenced.</p>
         <p>(5) Proceedings on Third Reading shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion at the moment of interruption on that day.</p>
         <p>(6) Standing Order No. 83B (Programming committees) shall not apply to proceedings on Consideration and Third Reading.</p>
         <p>(7) Any other proceedings on the Bill (including any proceedings on consideration of Lords Amendments or on any further messages from the Lords) may be programmed.</p>
      </Text>
      <so> 83A(7)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>DEFERRED DIVISIONS</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, at this day’s sitting, Standing Order No. 41A (Deferred divisions) shall not apply to the Motion in the name of Nicky Morgan relating to the Draft Budget 2014 and the Motion in the name of Mr David Gauke relating to Value Added Tax.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <OrderTitle>immigration bill: MONEY</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, for the purposes of any Act resulting from the Immigration Bill, it is expedient to authorise the payment out of money provided by Parliament of:</p>
         <p>(1) any expenditure incurred under or by virtue of the Act by the Secretary of State; and</p>
         <p>(2) any increase attributable to the Act in the sums payable under any other Act out of money so provided.</p>
      </Text>
      <so> 52(1)(a)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <OrderTitle>immigration bill: WAYS AND MEANS</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, for the purposes of any Act resulting from the Immigration Bill, it is expedient to authorise:</p>
         <p>(1) the imposition of an immigration health charge;</p>
         <p>(2) the charging of fees in respect of the exercise of functions in connection with immigration or nationality; and</p>
         <p>(3) the payment of sums into the Consolidated Fund.</p>
      </Text>
      <so> 52(1)(a)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <OrderTitle>DRAFT BUDGET 2014</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House takes note of European Union Document No. SEC (2013) 370, a Statement of estimates of the Commission for 2014 (Preparation of the 2014 Draft Budget); agrees with the Government that at a time of ongoing economic fragility in Europe and tight constraints on domestic public spending, it is essential that the European Union budget reflects the consolidation efforts of Member States to bring deficit and debt onto a more sustainable path; agrees that the Multi-Annual Financial Framework (MFF) agreement secured by the Prime Minister at the February European Council represents a good deal for taxpayers, delivering an unprecedented real-terms reduction of €35 billion on the current period in the seven year payment ceilings to €908.4 billion and a real-terms reduction of over three per cent in payment appropriations, and protecting the UK rebate; welcomes the fact that the 2014 Draft Budget respects the MFF agreement; notes that the Commission’s proposal sees a cash reduction in payments of around €4.5 billion compared to the current budget for 2013; and calls on the Government to continue its efforts to limit the size of the Budget by pressing for further savings, particularly in administration, in order to get the best deal for UK taxpayers.</p>
      </Text>
      <so> 119(11)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>7</Number>
      <OrderTitle>VALUE ADDED TAX</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the Value Added Tax (Education) Order 2013 (S.I., 2013, No. 1897), dated 30 July 2013, a copy of which was laid before this House on 30 July, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so> 118(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>8</Number>
      <OrderTitle>ESTABLISHMENT OF A european public prosecutor’s office</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House considers that the Draft Regulation on the establishment of a European Public Prosecutor’s Office (EPPO) (European Union Document No. 12558/13 and Addenda 1 and 2) does not comply with the principle of subsidiarity, for the reasons set out in the annex to Chapter One of the Fifteenth Report of the European Scrutiny Committee (HC 83-xv); and, in accordance with Article 6 of Protocol (No. 2) annexed to the EU Treaties on the application of the principle of subsidiarity and proportionality, instructs the Clerk of the House to forward this reasoned opinion to the Presidents of the European Institutions.</p>
      </Text>
      <so> 16(1)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>9</Number>
      <OrderTitle>DELEGATED LEGISLATION</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the motion in the name of Mr Andrew Lansley relating to the House of Commons Members’ Fund shall be treated as if it related to an instrument subject to the provisions of Standing Order No. 118 (Delegated Legislation Committees) in respect of which notice of a motion has been given that the instrument be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so> 9(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Misleading websites offering access to Government services</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>