<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Care_(HLBill1_VI(a))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZZRAA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZZRAA&#042;:</B> Clause 30, page 25, line 16, leave out &#8220;particular accommodation of that type&#8221; and insert &#8220;&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentTwo>(i) particular accommodation of that type;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) accommodation of the specified type in a particular location; or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) particular accommodation of that type in particular locations,&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZZRAB&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZZRAB&#042;:</B> Clause 30, page 25, line 19, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) &#8220;Location&#8221; includes a particular location in either the local authority&#8217;s area or in the area of another local authority.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZZSB&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZZSB&#042;:</B> Clause 33, page 27, line 34, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) There shall be no restriction in terms of type of provider placed on the services which can be purchased by direct payments.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZZADA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZZADA&#042;:</B> Clause 36, page 31, line 44, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Where the cost to the second authority of meeting the carer&#8217;s eligible needs is different from the cost to the first authority of doing so, the second authority must provide a written explanation of the difference to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the carer;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the adult needing care;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any other person to whom the carer asks the authority to provide an explanation.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZFC&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZFC&#042;:</B> After Clause 41, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Adult safeguarding access order: power of access</quote>
         <quote>(1) An authorised officer may apply to a justice of the peace for an order (an adult safeguarding access order) in relation to a person living in any premises within a local authority&#8217;s area.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The purposes of an adult safeguarding access order are&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to enable the authorised officer and any other person accompanying the officer to speak in private with a person suspected of being an adult at risk of abuse or neglect;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to enable the authorised officer to assess the mental capacity of a person suspected of being an adult at risk of abuse;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) to enable the authorised officer to ascertain whether that person is making decisions freely; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) to enable the authorised officer properly to assess whether the person is an adult at risk of abuse or neglect and to make a decision as required by section 41(2) on what, if any, action should be taken.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) When an adult safeguarding access order is in force, the authorised officer, a constable and any other specified person accompanying the officer in accordance with the order, may enter the premises specified in the order for the purposes set out in subsection (2).</quote>
         <quote>(4) The justice of the peace may make an adult safeguarding access order if satisfied that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the authorised officer has reasonable cause to suspect that a person is an adult who is experiencing or at risk of abuse or neglect;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) it is necessary for the authorised officer to gain access to the person in order to make whatever enquiries it thinks necessary and to make a decision as required by section 41(2) on what, if any, action should be taken;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) making an order is necessary in order to fulfil the purposes set out;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) exercising the power of access conferred by the order will not result in the person being at greater risk of abuse or neglect.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) An adult safeguarding access order must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) specify the premises to which it relates;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provide that the authorised officer may be accompanied by a constable;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) specify the period for which the order is to be in force.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) Other conditions may be attached to an adult safeguarding access order, for example&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) specifying restrictions on the time that the power of access conferred by the order may be exercised;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) providing for the authorised officer to be accompanied by another specified person;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) requiring notice of the order to be given to the occupier of the premises and to the person suspected of being an adult at risk of abuse.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) A constable accompanying the authorised officer may use reasonable force if necessary in order to fulfil the purposes of an adult safeguarding access order set out in subsection (2).</quote>
         <quote>(8) On entering the premises in accordance with an adult safeguarding access order, the authorised officer must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) state the object of the visit;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) produce evidence of the authorisation to enter the premises; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) provide an explanation to the occupier of the premises of how to complain about how the power of access has been exercised.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) In this section &#8220;an authorised officer&#8221; means a person authorised by a local authority for the purposes of this section, but regulations may set restrictions on the persons or categories of persons who may be authorised.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZFD&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZFD&#042;:</B> After Clause 41, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty to report adults at risk of abuse</quote>
         <quote>(1) If a relevant partner of a local authority has reasonable cause to suspect that the local authority would be under a duty to make enquiries under section 41, it must inform the local authority of that fact.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If the person that the relevant partner has reasonable cause to suspect would be the subject of enquiries under section 41, and appears to be within the area of a local authority other than the one of which it is a relevant partner, it must inform that other local authority.</quote>
         <quote>(3) If a local authority has reasonable cause to suspect that a person within its area at any time would be the subject of enquiries under section 41 and is living or proposing to live in the area of another local authority (including a local authority in Wales, Scotland or Northern Ireland), it must inform that other local authority.</quote>
         <quote>(4) In this section &#8220;relevant partner&#8221;, in relation to a local authority, means&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the local policing body and the chief officer of police for a police area any part of which falls within the area of the local authority;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any other local authority with which the authority agrees that it would be appropriate to co-operate under this section;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any provider of probation services that is required by arrangements under section 3(2) of the Offender Management Act 2007 to act as a relevant partner of the authority;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) any provider of regulated activities as listed in Schedule 1 to the Health and Social Care Act 2008 (Regulated Activities) Regulations 2010;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) a Local Health Board for an area any part of which falls within the area of the authority;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) an NHS trust providing services in the area of the authority;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) such person, or a person of such description, as regulations may specify.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZFE&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZFE&#042;:</B> After Clause 41, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Neglecting or ill-treating an adult at risk of abuse</quote>
         <IndentOne>Any person who wilfully causes or permits an adult to suffer, or inflicts physical pain or mental suffering upon an adult who has care and support needs, or having the care or custody of that adult, wilfully causes or permits the person or health of that adult to be injured, including through the neglect of their care and support or health needs, or wilfully causes or permits that person to be placed in a situation that endangers his or her person or health, is liable&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) on summary conviction, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 12 months or a fine not exceeding the statutory maximum or both;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) on conviction on indictment, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 5 years or a fine or both.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZFF&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZFF&#042;:</B> Schedule 2, page 97, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(e) social work-qualified staff from the establishing local authority&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZJ&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZJ&#042;:</B> Clause 43, page 36, line 22, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) An SAB is required to appoint a social work-qualified individual to supervise the carrying out of a review as stated.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>92ZK&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>92ZK&#042;:</B> After Clause 43, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty of candour</quote>
         <quote>(1) Local authorities must take reasonable steps to create an open and honest culture that enables employees to report reasonable suspicions of abuse and neglect of individuals in the care of the local authority or a provider commissioned by the local authority.</quote>
         <quote>(2) &#8220;Reasonable steps&#8221; include&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) ensuring that staff are aware of and trust processes open to them;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provision of advice about the process;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) review of procedures;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) regular communications to staff about the processes.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[In substitution for Amendment 106]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104ZBA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104ZBA&#042;:</B> Before Clause 66, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Initial funding assessment</quote>
         <IndentOne>Before enactment of Part 1, the Secretary of State must ask the Office for Budget Responsibility to complete by the end of 2014 a review of the funding of adult social care that assesses&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) the adequacy of current public funding of these services;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the proposals for funding the provisions in this Act; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the implications of the Act and its funding for the NHS over the next five years.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>105NA&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>105NA&#042;:</B> Clause 70, page 58, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A local authority must make contact with adults who have recently been certified sight-impaired or severely sight-impaired and who are ordinarily resident in its area.</quote>
         <quote>( ) Regulations may specify the period after the issue of a Certificate of Vision Impairment within which a local authority must make contact with a sight-impaired or severely sight-impaired adult and the form of such contact.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>