<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill59(e))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 6</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE EARL OF LISTOWEL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 6, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Looked after children: duty to provide information about support on returning home to care of parents or others with parental responsibility</quote>
         <quote>(1) Except in circumstances prescribed by regulations, a local authority must provide the information specified in subsection (2) to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any person who has contacted the authority to request information about &#8220;return home support services&#8221; for a looked after child returning home to the care of P; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) any P within the authority&#8217;s area, to whose care a looked after child has returned, who has contacted the authority to request any of the information specified in subsection (2).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) The information is&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) information about the return home support services available to people in the authority&#8217;s area;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) information about the authority&#8217;s duties under section 22(3A) of the Children Act 1989 (&#8220;return home support services&#8221;: personal budgets) and regulations made under it;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any other information prescribed by regulations.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 6, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Looked after children returning to care</quote>
         <quote>(1) Whenever a local authority decide that a looked after child should return to the care of P, the local authority must assess and monitor the support needs of the child and P for as long as is necessary to safeguard and promote the child&#8217;s welfare.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After carrying out an assessment of the support needs of a looked after child in accordance with subsection (1), the local authority must provide a child in care, and, in the case of formerly accommodated children, offer to provide, &#8220;return home support services&#8221; to meet identified the support needs for as long as is necessary to safeguard and promote the child&#8217;s welfare.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Whenever the local authority provide &#8220;return home support services&#8221; under subsection (2), they must prepare a personal budget if asked to do so by P or the child or (in prescribed circumstances) a person of a prescribed description.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The authority should prepare a &#8220;personal budget&#8221; if they identify an amount as available to secure return home support services that they have decided to provide, with a view to the recipient being involved in securing those services.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Regulations may make provision about personal budgets, in particular&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) about requests for personal budgets;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) about the amount of a personal budget;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) about the sources of the funds making up a personal budget;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) for payments (&#8220;direct payments&#8221;) representing all or part of a personal budget to be made to the recipient, or (in prescribed circumstances) a person of a prescribed description, in order to secure any return home support services to which the budget relates;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) about the description of the return home support services to which personal budgets and direct payments may (and may not) relate;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) for a personal budget or direct payment to cover the agreed cost of the return home support services to which the budget or payment relates;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) about when, how, to whom and on what conditions direct payments may (and may not) be made;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) about when direct payments may be required to be repaid and the recovery of unpaid sums;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(i) about conditions with which a person or body making direct payments must comply before, after or at the time of making a direct payment;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(j) about arrangements for providing information, advice or support in connection with personal budgets and direct payments.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) If the regulations include provision authorising direct payments, they must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) require the consent of the recipient, or (in prescribed circumstances) a person of a prescribed description, to be obtained before direct payments are made;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) require the authority to stop making direct payments where the required consent is withdrawn.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) Any return home support services secured by means of direct payments made by a local authority are to be treated as support services provided by the authority for all purposes, subject to any prescribed conditions or exceptions.</quote>
         <quote>(8) In this section &#8220;prescribed&#8221; means prescribed by regulations.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD MCCOLL OF DULWICH</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS BUTLER-SLOSS</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD CARLILE OF BERRIEW</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 9, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Child trafficking guardians for children who may have been victims of human trafficking</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 26A of the Children Act 1989 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;26B Child Trafficking Guardians for children who may have been victims of human trafficking</quote>
         <quote>(1) A child trafficking guardian shall be appointed to represent the best interests of each child who might be a victim of trafficking in human beings if the person who has parental responsibility for the child fulfils any of the conditions set out in subsection (3).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The child trafficking guardian shall have the following responsibilities to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) advocate that all decisions relating to the child are made in the child&#8217;s best interest and, where reasonably practicable and consistent with the child&#8217;s welfare after ascertaining the child&#8217;s wishes and feelings in relation to those decisions;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) advocate for the child to receive appropriate care, safe accommodation, medical treatment, including psychological assistance, education, translation and interpretation services;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) assist the child to access legal and other representation where necessary, including, where appropriate, to appoint and instruct the solicitor representing the child on all matters relevant to the interests of the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) consult with, advise and inform the child victim of the child&#8217;s legal rights;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) keep the child informed of all relevant immigration, criminal or compensation proceedings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) contribute to identification of a plan to safeguard and promote the long-term welfare of the child based on an individual assessment of that child&#8217;s best interests;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) provide a link between the child and various organisations who may provide services to the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) assist in establishing contact with the child&#8217;s family, where the child so wishes and it is in the child&#8217;s best interests;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(i) where appropriate liaise with an immigration officer handling the child&#8217;s case in conjunction with the child&#8217;s legal representative;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(j) accompany the child to all police interviews; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(k) accompany the child whenever the child moves to new accommodation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Subsection (1) shall apply if the person who has parental responsibility for the child&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is suspected of taking part in the trafficking of human beings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) has another conflict of interest with the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is not in contact with the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) is in a country outside the United Kingdom; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) is a local authority.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (1), a child trafficking guardian may be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an employee of a statutory body;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an employee of a recognised charitable organisation; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a volunteer for a recognised charitable organisation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) A person discharging duties as a child trafficking guardian shall not discharge any other statutory duties in relation to a child for whom they are providing assistance under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Where a child trafficking guardian is appointed under subsection (1), the authority of the child trafficking guardian in relation to the child shall be recognised by any relevant body.</quote>
         <quote>(7) In subsection (6), a &#8220;relevant body&#8221; means a person or organisation&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) which provides services to the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to which a child makes an application for services; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) to which the child needs access in relation to being a victim.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) The appropriate national authority&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall by order set out the arrangements for the appointment of a child trafficking guardian as soon as possible after a child is identified as a potential victim of trafficking in human beings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) shall by order set out requirements for the training courses to be completed before a person may discharge duties as a child trafficking guardian;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) shall by order set out the arrangements for the supervision of persons discharging duties as a child trafficking guardian;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) shall by order set out the arrangements for the provision of support services for persons discharging duties as a child trafficking guardian; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) shall by order designate organisations as a &#8220;recognised charitable organisation&#8221; for the purpose of this section.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) A person&#8217;s appointment as a child trafficking guardian for a particular child under this section shall come to an end if&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the child reaches the age of 18; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a durable solution for the child has been found based on an individual assessment of the best interests of the child.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(10) In this section, a child is considered to be a &#8220;potential victim of trafficking in human beings&#8221; when a referral has been made to a competent authority for a determination under the identification process required by Article 10 of the Trafficking Convention (Identification of Victims) and there has not been a conclusive determination that the individual is not such a victim.</quote>
         <quote>(11) For the purposes of subsection (10), there is a conclusive determination that an individual is not a victim of trafficking in human beings when, on completion of the identification process required by Article 10 of the Trafficking Convention, a competent authority concludes that the individual is or is not such a victim.</quote>
         <quote>(12) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;parental responsibility&#8221; has the same meaning as section 3 of this Act;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;competent authority&#8221; means a person who is a competent authority of the United Kingdom for the purposes of the Trafficking Convention;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;the Trafficking Convention&#8221; means the Council of Europe Convention on Action against Trafficking in Human Beings (done at Warsaw on 16 May 2005);</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;trafficking in human beings&#8221; has the same meaning as in the Trafficking Convention.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 11</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS BUTLER-SLOSS</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HUGHES OF STRETFORD</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 11, page 11, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2B) Involvement is any kind of direct or indirect involvement that promotes the welfare of the child; it shall not be taken to mean any particular division of a child&#8217;s time.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 21</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD RAMSBOTHAM</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 21, page 20, line 16, leave out subsection (5) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) Health care provision or social care provision which is educational for, or training of, a child or young person is to be treated as special educational provision (instead of health care provision or social care provision).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 26</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD RAMSBOTHAM</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 22, line 15, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) securing for children and young people with special educational needs but no EHC plan the education, health and care provision agreed under subsection (3)(a).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 22, line 18, leave out &#8220;have regard to&#8221; and insert &#8220;act in accordance with&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 22, line 19, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) ensure that, following operation of the dispute resolution procedures mentioned in subsection (3)(g), agreement between the partners is reached on the matters set out in subsection (3), and ensure that arrangements are in place, as set out in subsection (4), and then put into effect.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 22, line 32, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Where a clinical commissioning group, or the NHS Commissioning Board, is a partner commissioning body, the agreements and arrangements referred to in subsections (1) to (5) are not to be taken to be constrained by reference to what that group or Board has separately decided to be necessary for the purposes of its duty under section 3 or section 3B of the National Health Service Act 2006 as the case may be.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 22, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(10) Before making arrangements for the purposes of subsection (1), or before agreeing the matters set out in subsections (3) to (5) or any of them, the local authority, and its partner commissioning bodies, shall consult those persons and bodies specified in section 27(3).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 22, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(11) The arrangements made and the matters agreed following consultation under subsection (10) shall be published by the local authority and its partner commissioning bodies as prescribed by regulations.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 27</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 27, page 22, line 42, after &#8220;needs,&#8221; insert &#8220;including organisations that provide online or blended learning (or both),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 27, page 23, line 21, at end insert &#8220;including alternative and online providers&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 28</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 28, page 24, line 14, at end insert &#8220;including organisations that provide online or blended learning (or both)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 29</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 29, page 25, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) independent alternative education providers including providers of online or blended learning (or both)&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 29, page 25, line 17, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in the case of an alternative education provider, a member of the senior team.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 30</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 25, line 29, at end insert &#8220;including online and blended learning&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 26, line 2, after &#8220;received&#8221; insert &#8220;, including the use of alternative education providers and online educational tools,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 34</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 34, page 28, line 14, after &#8220;school&#8221; insert &#8220;, through the provision of alternative education including online or blended learning (or both),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 38</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 38, page 31, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) a provider of alternative educational provision including providers of online or blended learning (or both).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 39</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 39, page 32, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in the case of alternative education providers, a member of the senior team.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 41</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 41, page 33, line 34, after &#8220;institution&#8221; insert &#8220;, including providers of online or blended learning (or both),&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 42</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD RIX</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD LOW OF DALSTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HUGHES OF STRETFORD</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS SHARP OF GUILDFORD</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 42, page 34, line 10, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) If the plan specifies social care provision, the responsible local authority must secure the specified social care provision for the child or young person.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 43</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 43, page 34, line 24, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) a provider of alternative educational provision including online or blended learning (or both).&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 49</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 49, page 37, line 18, at end insert &#8220;, including online or blended learning provision (or both)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 57</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 57, page 43, line 29, at end insert &#8220;including those institutions that provide alternative educational provision and online or blended learning (or both)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 59</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 59, page 44, line 16, at end insert &#8220;that has been agreed to by the parent as being suitably provided and is therefore included in the EHC plan&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 59, page 44, line 30, after &#8220;institution&#8221; insert &#8220;, by an alternative education provider or in any place&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 62</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 62, page 45, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) alternative education providers including providers of online or blended learning (or both)&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 62, page 45, line 39, leave out from &#8220;provision&#8221; to end of line 40 and insert &#8220;that is requested by the pupil or student or the pupil or student&#8217;s parents (or both)&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 62, page 46, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in the case of alternative education providers, a member of the senior team&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 64</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 64, page 46, line 35, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) in the case of alternative education providers, a member of the senior team&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 67</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 67, page 48, line 33, at end insert &#8220;including providers of alternative educational provision including online and blended learning&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 69</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD RAMSBOTHAM</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 69, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Maintaining an EHC plan for detained young persons</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 562C(2) of the Apprenticeships, Skills, Children and Learning Act 2009, insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) The host local authority must make arrangements to secure special educational provision and health care provision in accordance with an EHC plan as agreed with the home local authority whilst the young person is detained in relevant youth accommodation.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Regulations may make provision about maintaining an EHC plan for a detained young person, in particular&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) how the host and home local authority determine the provisions of the EHC plan to be maintained whilst the young person is detained;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) about circumstances in which a host local authority must or may review an EHC plan or secure a re-assessment whilst the young person is detained;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) how the provisions of the EHC plan which the host and home local authority maintain are communicated to the young person and parent.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 70</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD RAMSBOTHAM</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 70, leave out Clause 70</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 73</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASSEY OF DARWEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 73, page 51, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;alternative education provision&#8221; means &#8220;education arranged by local authorities for pupils who, because of exclusion, illness or other reasons, would not otherwise receive suitable education; education arranged by schools for pupils on a fixed-period exclusion; and pupils being directed by schools to off-site provision to improve their behaviour and education provision can include online and blended learning.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 73, page 51, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Alternative education provider&#8221; means &#8220;an organisation that looks to provide education for those pupils who, because of exclusion, illness or other reasons, would not otherwise receive suitable education and this includes providers of online and blended learning.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 78</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE EARL OF LISTOWEL</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 78, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 4A</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Children&#8217;s centres</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Birth registration pilot scheme</quote>
         <IndentOne>Local authorities must establish a pilot scheme to trial the registration of births within children&#8217;s centres, and evaluate the effectiveness of the scheme to&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) identify and contact new families; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) enable children&#8217;s centres to reach more families, in particular those with children under the age of two, or who the local authority consider&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) hard to reach, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) vulnerable.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 78, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Information and data sharing</quote>
         <quote>(1) NHS trusts shall make arrangements to share with local authorities records of live births to parents resident in their area, to be used by the local authority for the purposes of identifying and contacting new families through children&#8217;s centres and any other early years outreach services it may operate.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State must, within a period of six months of the passing of this Act, bring forward regulations placing consequential requirements on trusts and local authorities in exercising their duty under subsection (1), including, but not limited to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the format of arrangements made;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the safeguarding of information;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the circumstances in which it would not be appropriate for a trust to provide information to local authorities;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the regularity of data transfers;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) timescales within which a local authority must contact new families made known to it; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) any further requirements the Secretary of State deems necessary.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>