<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill32_I(b))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 27, page 22, line 12, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) If the education and care provision referred to in subsection (1)(a) and (b) is deemed insufficient to meet the needs of children and young people under subsection (2), a local authority must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) publish these findings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) involve those consulted in subsection (3) in producing an action plan to revise the education and care provision referred to in subsection (1)(a) and (b);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) review and report on progress against its action plan;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) revise the local offer accordingly.</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Regulations must make provision about&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) criteria to be used by local authorities in assessing whether the education and care provision referred to in subsection (1)(a) and (b) is sufficient under subsection (2);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the information to be included in an authority&#8217;s action plan;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) how an authority is to involve children, young people and families in the production of, and assessment of progress against, its action plan;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) imposing time limits on implementing the revision of the education and care provision referred to in subsection (1)(a) and (b) deemed insufficient.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 47, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Change of residence</quote>
         <quote>(1) This section applies where&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a local authority (the &#8220;sending authority&#8221;) maintains an education, health and care plan for a child or young person, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) another local authority (the &#8220;receiving authority&#8221;) is notified by the child&#8217;s parent or the young person that they intend to move residence to the receiving authority&#8217;s area.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Where the sending authority is notified by the child&#8217;s parent or the young person that they intend to move residence it must provide the receiving authority with a copy of the education, health and care plan.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The receiving authority must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) review the child or young person&#8217;s education, health and care plan having regard to the need for continuity of provision, and the outcomes specified in the plan; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) provide the child&#8217;s parent or the young person with such information as it considers appropriate.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>