<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill32(s))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD MCCOLL OF DULWICH</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 9, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Child Trafficking Guardians for children who may have been victims of human trafficking</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Children Act 1989 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 26A insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;26B Child Trafficking Guardians for children who may have been victims of human trafficking</quote>
         <quote>(1) A child trafficking guardian shall be appointed to represent the best interests of each child who might be a victim of trafficking in human beings if the person who has parental responsibility for the child fulfils any of the conditions set out in subsection (3).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The child trafficking guardian shall have the following responsibilities to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) advocate that all decisions taken are in the child&#8217;s best interest;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) advocate for the child to receive appropriate care, accommodation, medical treatment, including psychological assistance, education, translation and interpretation services;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) advocate for the child&#8217;s access to legal and other representation where necessary;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) consult with, advise and keep the child victim informed of legal rights;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) where appropriate instruct the solicitor representing the child on all matters relevant to the interests of the child arising in the course of proceedings including possibilities for appeal;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(f) contribute to identification of a plan to safeguard and promote the long-term welfare of the child based on an individual assessment of that child&#8217;s best interests;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(g) keep the child informed of all relevant immigration, criminal or compensation proceedings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(h) provide a link between the child and various organisations who may provide services to the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(i) assist in establishing contact with the child&#8217;s family, where the child so wishes and it is in the child&#8217;s best interests;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(j) liaise with the UK Border Agency where appropriate;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(k) attend all police interviews with the child; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(l) accompany the child whenever the child moves to new accommodation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) Subsection (1) shall apply if the person who has parental responsibility for the child&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) is suspected of taking part in the trafficking of human beings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) has another conflict of interest with the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) is not in contact with the child;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) is in a country outside the United Kingdom; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) is a local authority.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (1), a child trafficking guardian may be&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an employee of a statutory body;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an employee of a recognised charitable organisation; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) a volunteer for a recognised charitable organisation.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) Where a child trafficking guardian is appointed under subsection (1), the authority of the child trafficking guardian in relation to the child shall be recognised by any relevant body.</quote>
         <quote>(6) In subsection (5), a &#8220;relevant body&#8221; means a person or organisation&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) which provides services to the child; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to which the child needs access in relation to being a victim.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) The appropriate national authority&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall by order set out the arrangements for the appointment of a child trafficking guardian as soon as possible after a child is identified as a potential victim of trafficking in human beings;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may make rules about the training courses to be completed before a person may discharge duties as a child trafficking guardian;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) shall by order set out the arrangements for the provision of support services for persons discharging duties as a child trafficking guardian; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) shall by order designate organisations as a &#8220;recognised charitable organisation&#8221; for the purposes of this section.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) In this section a child is considered to be a &#8220;potential victim of trafficking in human beings&#8221; when&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) there has been a conclusive determination that the individual is a victim of trafficking in human beings, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) there are reasonable grounds to believe that the individual is such a victim and there has not been a conclusive determination that the individual is not such a victim.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(9) For the purposes of sub-paragraph (8)(b) there are reasonable grounds to believe that an individual is a victim of trafficking in human beings if a competent authority has determined for the purposes of Article 10 of the Trafficking Convention (identification of victims) that there are such grounds.</quote>
         <quote>(10) For the purposes of sub-paragraph (8) there is a conclusive determination that an individual is or is not a victim of trafficking in human beings when, on completion of the identification process required by Article 10 of the Trafficking Convention, a competent authority concludes that the individual is or is not such a victim.</quote>
         <quote>(11) In this section&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;parental responsibility&#8221; has the same meaning as section 3 of this Act;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;competent authority&#8221; means a person who is a competent authority of the United Kingdom for the purposes of the Trafficking Convention;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;the Trafficking Convention&#8221; means the Council of Europe Convention on Action against Trafficking in Human Beings (done at Warsaw on 16 May 2005);</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;trafficking in human beings&#8221; has the same meaning as in the Trafficking Convention.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>