<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Children_and_Families_(Bill32(h))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, leave out line 9 and insert &#8220;satisfied that C ought to be placed for adoption&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 11, after &#8220;adopter&#8221; insert &#8220;after a matching process has been conducted&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 28, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Directions under subsection (1) shall be given in writing setting out the Secretary of State&#8217;s reasons which shall be in accordance with regulations.</quote>
         <quote>( ) A local authority to which directions have been given under subsection (1) may at any time&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) request the Secretary of State to review the directions,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) appeal against the Secretary of State&#8217;s decision to the High Court.</IndentOne>
         <quote>( ) The Secretary of State may at any time rescind directions given under subsection (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD STOREY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 3, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 3 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 4</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 3, line 2, after &#8220;asked&#8221; insert &#8220;at any time&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 6</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS BUTLER-SLOSS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 6, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Adoption and Children Act 2002 (Amendment)</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 98 of the Adoption and Children Act 2002 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Omit paragraph (a) of section 98(1) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(a) assisting</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) persons adopted before the appointed day,</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the descendants of persons adopted before the appointed day</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>who have attained the age of 18 to obtain information in relation to the adoption of the adopted person.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 8</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS HAMWEE</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 8, page 6, line 44, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the benefit to the child of an order under subsection (2),&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 21</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS BRINTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HOWE OF IDLICOTE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Special educational needs of severely bullied children</quote>
         <quote>(1) Schedule (Special educational needs of severely bullied children) has effect.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In this section and schedule (Special educational needs of severely bullied children)&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;bullying&#8221; is unwanted behaviour that causes distress or harm, involves an imbalance of power or strength between aggressor and victim, is unwarranted and commonly occurs repeatedly over time;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;severe bullying&#8221; is behaviour that affects children so severely that they suffer trauma and psychological damage, which can also result in them missing school for long periods of time;</quote>
         <quote>a &#8220;bullying incident&#8221; should be addressed as a child protection concern when there is reasonable cause to suspect that a child is suffering, or is likely to suffer, significant harm.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 22</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS BRINTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 22, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Data on the number of children and young people with special educational needs and disabilities</quote>
         <quote>(1) A local authority in England must publish information annually on the number of children and young people in its area who have special educational needs and disabilities.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Information under subsection (1) must be published by type of special educational need and disability.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 26</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD LOW OF DALSTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 26, page 20, line 41, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A local authority in England and its partner commissioning bodies must make arrangements (&#8220;joint commissioning arrangements&#8221;) about the education, health and care provision to be secured for disabled children and young people in their area.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 27</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WILKINS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 27, page 22, line 12, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The authority must consider the extent to which there is sufficient funding in place to deliver the provision referred to subsection (1)(a) to meet the special educational needs and social care needs of children and young people concerned.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 30</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WILKINS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 24, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) funding available by the authority for provision within subsection (2)&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD LOW OF DALSTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 24, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the provision within subsection (2) it expects to be available in its area at the time of publication for children and young people who have a disability under the Equality Act 2010&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 25, line 11, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A local authority&#8217;s local offer shall be subject to inspection by Ofsted and the Care Quality Commission.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>BARONESS BRINTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 30, page 25, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Regulations must make provision about the format in which a local offer will be published.</quote>
         <quote>( ) The format in which a local offer will be published must be of a format that&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) allows parents of children with special educational needs to make comparisons between different local authorities&#8217; local offers; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) presents information by type of special educational need.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 30</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WILKINS</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 30, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Minimum standards for the local offer</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State shall lay a draft of regulations setting out the minimum level of specific special educational provision, health care provision and social care provision that local authorities must provide as part of their local offer, and the regulations are not to be made unless they have been approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Once regulations under subsection (1) have been made, the Secretary of State must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) issue guidance to local authorities on how to meet these regulations, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) publish information on these regulations accessible to the families of children and young people with special educational needs on the Department&#8217;s website, and in any other way he sees fit.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 37</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD LOW OF DALSTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 37, page 30, line 20, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Any social care provision which the local authority considers to be necessary in order to meet the needs of the disabled person under section 2 of the Chronically Sick and Disabled Persons Act 1970.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 38</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 38, page 31, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(g) a provider of alternative educational provision including the provision of online learning and blended learning.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD LOW OF DALSTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 38, page 31, line 3, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) an institution of higher education which the young person has accepted an offer from&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 41</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 41, page 32, line 43, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) an educational institution that can provide alternative educational provision, including online learning and blended learning for both pre-16 and post-16 children with special educational needs.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 42</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD LOW OF DALSTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 42, page 33, line 21, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) If the plan specifies social care provision, the responsible local authority must secure the specified social care provision for the child or young person.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 49</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 49, page 36, line 29, at end insert &#8220;to, including alternative provision for online learning and blended learning&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 57</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 57, page 42, line 34, at end insert &#8220;including those institutions that provide alternative educational provision, especially online learning and blending learning&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 59</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 59, page 43, line 19, leave out &#8220;place in accordance with&#8221; and insert &#8220;provider of online learning or blended learning in accordance with the EHC plan that has been agreed by the parents as being a suitable provider and therefore included in&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 59, page 43, line 33, after &#8220;institution&#8221; insert &#8220;, alternative education provider, especially those organisations that provide online learning or blended learning&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 62</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 62, page 44, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(g) alternative education providers, including providers of online learning or blended learning.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD LOW OF DALSTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 62, page 45, line 2, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In using their best endeavours to meet special educational needs, the school or other institution must provide a graduated response using the School Action and School Action Plus stages.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 62, page 45, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) in the case of all types of alternative providers, a member of the senior management team.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 64</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 64, page 45, line 30, after &#8220;Academy&#8221; insert &#8220;, alternative provision provider including those organisations that provide online learning, blended learning&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 72</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS BRINTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 72, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Inspection and review of local authorities in England</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 136 of the Education and Inspections Act 2006 (inspection of local authorities in England), after subsection (4), insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) The Chief Inspector must inspect the performance by an authority in delivering and commissioning specialist support services for children with special educational needs.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Schedule 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS BRINTON</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS HOWE OF IDLICOTE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Schedule 3, insert the following new Schedule&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Schedule</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Special educational needs of severely bullied children</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>1 In this Schedule, children have a learning difficulty if they&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) have a significantly greater difficulty in learning than the majority of children of the same age;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) have a disability which prevents or hinders them from making use of educational facilities of a kind generally provided for children of the same age in schools within the area of the local authority; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) are under compulsory school age and fall within the definition in (a) or (b) or would do so if special educational provision was not made for them.</IndentOne>
         <quote>2 The Secretary of State must produce an anti-bullying strategy (and consequential Codes of Practice and Statutory Guidelines) for educational establishments on ways of preventing and protecting children from bullying and ensuring effective recovery programmes to counter the consequences of severe bullying.</quote>
         <quote>3 (1) It shall be the duty of the headteacher of the establishment that the child or young person attends to ensure that a full risk assessment is carried out locally in respect of any child or young person who is referred on the grounds that they are being severely bullied directly or indirectly at a school or in the community.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In conducting the assessment, the person assessing shall take into account the impact, frequency and the intensity of the bullying on the child or young person.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In assessing the needs of children or young persons in respect of severe bullying the welfare and recovery of the child or young person must be paramount.</quote>
         <quote>4 The Secretary of State shall have responsibility for ensuring that a multi-agency action plan is prepared by the relevant local authority and a case conference in conjunction with safeguarding agencies is convened in respect of any child or young person who is the subject of severe bullying.</quote>
         <quote>5 Children who are severely bullied are eligible for a temporary statement of Special Education Needs. The criteria for a temporary statement include but are not limited to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) school attendance at zero, or close to zero, for three months, including not attending and refusing to attend;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the child wanting to be in school or be educated or have friends but being too frightened to attend school;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) written evidence of occurrences or complaints of bullying, ostracism, or unresolved incidents;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) advice from General Practitioner; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) intervention by a child psychologist.</IndentOne>
         <quote>6 Indicators to measure improvement, demonstrating that the temporary statement can be drawn to a conclusion include but are not limited to&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) improved attendance at an alternative or at specialist provision for such children and a willingness to return to mainstream school;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a level of ability to study and concentrate at an alternative or at specialist provision for such children, and a willingness to return to mainstream school;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) motivation to learn at an alternative or at specialist provision for such children and a willingness to return to mainstream school;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) improvement in child or young person&#8217;s self-esteem at an alternative or at specialist provision for such children and a willingness to return to mainstream school; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) advice from the full range of professionals working with the child.</IndentOne>
         <quote>7 The Secretary of State must ensure that measures are put in place to enable strategic authorities to implement agreed action plans in respect of any child or young person who is being bullied.</quote>
         <quote>8 If a severely bullied child or young person is unable to go to school because of bullying alternative full time provision should be made available as soon as possible to prevent disruption to their education.</quote>
         <quote>9 In paragraph 7, strategic authorities may include central government, local authorities, educational establishments, social media providers, health service trusts and children&#8217;s services.</quote>
         <quote>10 The Department for Education, schools, and other relevant authorities (collectively the &#8220;authorities&#8221;) must keep a record of instances of severe bullying directly or indirectly in respect of any child or young person. The authorities must inform child safeguarding agencies and any other child protection bodies of any concerns about the nature of an individual child or young person who is being bullied.</quote>
         <quote>11 The Secretary of State must measure the impact of the implementation of any action plan in respect of any young person or child. Impact may include attendance at school, level and ability of the child or young person to concentrate, their achievement of learning targets and the wellbeing of that child or young person.</quote>
         <quote>12 (1) The Secretary of State must ensure that all relevant teachers, staff and volunteers receive core training on the consequences and causes of bullying and on prevention strategies.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Relevant teachers, staff and volunteers will be expected to teach pupils at appropriate times about bullying and its consequences.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Relevant teachers, staff and volunteers will be expected to work with all children, including the bullies, to address their behaviour.</quote>
         <quote>13 Local authorities must provide family support and interventions in respect of any child or young person who is assessed as being severely bullied or who is engaged in perpetrating severe bullying behaviour. A family must consent to any such intervention.</quote>
         <quote>14 The Secretary of State must ensure that all headteachers and school governors provide a safe learning environment for children at school such that they are free from harm, humiliation, intimidation, bullying or harassment.</quote>
         <quote>15 The Secretary of State must commission research into the effectiveness of anti-bullying strategies and produce guidelines on best practice.</quote>
         <quote>16 The Secretary of State must regulate and validate or otherwise any supplier of external training to schools on anti-bullying practice and strategy.</quote>
         <quote>17 The Secretary of State must agree a code of conduct with social media providers in respect of severe bullying of children and young persons to minimise the use of texts, e-mails, online social media sites, and other technology which could contribute to severe bullying.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 73</clausenumber>
   <proposer>THE COUNTESS OF MAR</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS MASHAM OF ILTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 73, page 50, line 40, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;alternative education provision&#8221; means education arranged by local authorities for pupils who, because of exclusion, illness or other reasons, would not otherwise receive suitable education; education arranged by schools for pupils on a fixed-period exclusion; and pupils being directed by schools to off-site provision to improve behaviour;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;alternative education provider&#8221; is an organisation that provides education for those pupils who, because of exclusion, illness or other reasons would not otherwise receive a suitable education;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;online learning&#8221; means the use of electronic media and information and communication technologies in education, including multimedia learning, technology-enhanced learning, computer-based instruction, computer-based training, computer-based assisted instruction, internet-based training, web-based training, online education, virtual education and virtual learning environments and learning platforms;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;blended learning&#8221; means &#8220;a formal education programme in which a student learns at least in part through online delivery of content and instruction as well as attending a &#8220;bricks and mortar&#8221; school structure.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 74</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS TYLER OF ENFIELD</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 74, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 74 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 75</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS TYLER OF ENFIELD</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 75, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 75 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 76</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS TYLER OF ENFIELD</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 76, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 76 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 78</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS BRINTON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 78, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Part 4A</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Protection of Children</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> Actions due to a belief of possession by spirits</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 1 of the Children and Young Persons Act 1993 (cruelty to persons under sixteen) is amended as follows&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 1(1) the words &#8220;and has responsibility for any child or young person under that age,&#8221; are omitted and for the word &#8220;him&#8221; is substituted &#8220;any child or young person under that age.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) In section 1(2), after paragraph (b) there is inserted&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) in subsection (1) of this section the meaning of &#8220;ill-treats&#8221; includes the communication by word or by action a belief that the child is possessed by evil spirits or has supernatural harmful powers&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) to the child concerned, or</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) to anyone connected to that child.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 79</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 79, page 52, line 16, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) raise public awareness of children&#8217;s rights by promoting knowledge of and respect for the rights of children;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>( ) initiate and intervene in legal proceedings, including proceedings under section 7 on the Human Rights Act 1998 where the Children&#8217;s Commissioner is not the victim or potential victim of the unlawful act to which the proceedings relate;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 85</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 85, page 55, line 40, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) after paragraph (b) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) the Children&#8217;s Commissioner&#8217;s assessment of the extent to which children in England enjoy&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the rights in the United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the rights of children in any other international treaty ratified by the United Kingdom; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) the rights of children in the law applicable in England&#8221;.&#8221;</IndentTwo>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 86</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS WALMSLEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 86, page 56, line 37, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) A child is within this subsection if he or she is detained in pursuance of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) an order made by a court, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) an order of recall made by the Secretary of State.</IndentOne>
         <quote>( ) A child is within this subsection if he or she has been identified by a professional as a potential victim of trafficking.</quote>
         <quote>( ) A child is within this subsection if he or she is a separated migrant child.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>