<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Energy_(Bill48_I(a))</billtitle>
      <headertext>AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
      <headertext>[Supplementary to the Marshalled List]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 3</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD O&#8217;NEILL OF CLACKMANNAN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2A&#042;:</B> After Clause 3, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Decarbonisation obligation</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State must bring forward regulations for a &#8220;decarbonisation obligation&#8221; within a year following enactment for the purposes of ensuring obligations under section 1(1) are met.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A decarbonisation obligation means the level of carbon intensity of electricity generation in the United Kingdom that a relevant supplier may not exceed in respect of the total kilowatt hours of electricity that it supplies to customers in England and Wales during that year.</quote>
         <quote>(3) In setting a decarbonisation order, the Secretary of State must first obtain and take account of advice from the Committee on Climate Change.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Under this section, a &#8220;relevant supplier&#8221; refers to electricity suppliers supplying electricity in the United Kingdom.</quote>
         <quote>(5) Section 4 makes further provision in relation to subsection (2).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 37</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD GRANTCHESTER</proposer>
   <clausetext>[In substitution for Amendment 50]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>50&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>50&#042;:</B> After Clause 37, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Strategy for electricity demand reduction</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State shall within 12 months of the passing of this Act publish a strategy setting out cost-effective policies for achieving a reduction in demand for electricity.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The strategy must include a target expressed in terrawatt hours for reducing electricity demand by 2020.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Secretary of State shall&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) implement the strategy; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) report to Parliament each year on progress.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 132</clausenumber>
   <proposer>BARONESS FINLAY OF LLANDAFF</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>104A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>104A&#042;:</B> After Clause 132, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Carbon monoxide detection</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Secretary of State may make regulations to ensure&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) any particular class of residential premises is fitted with an appropriate carbon monoxide alarm where any carbon burning appliance is in situ,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the supply, sale and fitting of a carbon monoxide alarm may be undertaken by any registered carbon burning appliance engineer, smart meter installer or by local authority fire and rescue service personnel.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) Regulations under this section shall be contained in a statutory instrument which shall be laid before Parliament and subject to annulment by resolution of either House of Parliament.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>