<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>European_Union_Referendum_(Bill63_II)</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>50</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>50:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 12, leave out subsection (6)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>50A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>50A&#042;:</B> Clause 1, page 1, line 14, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) No order shall be made under subsection (6) until the Secretary of State has prepared, published and laid before Parliament an assessment of the United Kingdom&#8217;s intended relationship with the European Union in the event of withdrawal from the European Union.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>51</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>51:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Enactment conditions</quote>
         <quote>(1) The outcome of the referendum shall not be acted upon until each House of Parliament passes by resolution a motion of consent that the referendum has produced a result which is definitive and beyond challenge.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The outcome of the referendum shall not be considered definitive unless 40 per cent of those registered to vote give assent in the referendum.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>52</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>52:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Count for votes cast</quote>
         <IndentOne>The count for votes cast in the referendum shall be carried out and declared separately for&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) Scotland;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) Wales;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) Northern Ireland; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) England.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[As an amendment to Amendment 52]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>53</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>53:</B> After Clause 1, line 8, at end insert &#8220;; and</quote>
         <IndentOne>(e) Gibraltar&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>54</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>54:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Announcement of the results</quote>
         <IndentOne>The declaration of the number of votes cast shall be made&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) in each counting area;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) in aggregate for each of England, Northern Ireland, Scotland, Wales and Gibraltar; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) in aggregate for the United Kingdom.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>55</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>55:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Definition of &#8220;United Kingdom&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(1) For the purposes of this Act, the United Kingdom comprises England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Subject to subsections (3) and (4), the Secretary of State may amend subsection (1) by order made by statutory instrument subject to approval by resolution of both Houses of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Notwithstanding any provisions of the Scotland Act 1998, the Government of Wales Acts 1998 and 2006 and the Northern Ireland Act 1998, the&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) Scottish Parliament relating to Scotland,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) Welsh Assembly relating to Wales, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the Northern Ireland Assembly relating to Northern Ireland,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>may authorise their presiding officer to forward a request, along with any relevant reports agreed to by the Parliament or Assembly, that the Secretary of State make an order under subsection (2) to amend subsection (1).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) No order shall be made under this section until the Secretary of State has laid before both Houses of Parliament a report setting out any opinion on his or her proposal to make such an order expressed by any of the Scottish Parliament, the Northern Ireland Assembly or the Welsh Assembly.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>56</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>56:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Enactment conditions</quote>
         <quote>(1) The outcome of the referendum shall not be acted upon until each House of Parliament passes by resolution a motion of consent that the referendum has produced a result which is definitive and beyond challenge.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The outcome of the referendum shall be not considered definitive unless 40 per cent of those registered to vote participate in the referendum.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>57</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>57:</B> Clause 2, page 1, line 18, leave out &#8220;parliamentary election in any constituency&#8221; and insert &#8220;local authority election in the United Kingdom&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>58</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>58:</B> Clause 2, page 1, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the persons who are at least 16 years old at the date of the referendum,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>59</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>59:</B> Clause 2, page 1, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;( ) the persons who, on the date of the referendum, would be entitled to vote in a parliamentary election in any constituency, but are not eligible to vote in a local authority election in the United Kingdom by reason of being resident in another country that is a member of the European Union,&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>60</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>60:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 1, leave out paragraph (c) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) citizens of the European Union resident in the United Kingdom&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>61</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>61:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(d) prisoners who are serving a sentence of less than two years&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) Provision shall be made so that all Britons resident abroad who are aged 16 or over on the date of the referendum shall be able to vote in the referendum in person or by post.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>62A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>62A&#042;:</B> Clause 2, page 2, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2) The Secretary of State may not make an order under section 1(3) until the Electoral Commission has informed the Secretary of State that every local authority has taken all reasonable steps to ensure that all of those entitled to vote under this section are accurately recorded on the electoral register.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>63</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>63:</B> After Clause 2, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendment of the Representation of the People Act 1985</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 1 of the Representation of the People Act 1985 (extension of the parliamentary franchise), after subsection (3), insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) For the purposes of voting in a referendum on the United Kingdom&#8217;s membership of the European Union, the conditions set out in subsection (3)(c) and (d) do not have to be met providing that the overseas elector resides in a country that is a member of the European Union at the date of the referendum.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 5, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The referendum shall take place by means of an all-postal vote ballot.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>64A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>64A&#042;:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 10, leave out subsections (2) and (3) and insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The referendum will be conducted in accordance with sections 101 to 110 of the Political Parties Elections and Referendums Act 2000.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>65</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>65:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 11, leave out &#8220;by order&#8221; and insert &#8220;introduce further legislation to Parliament to&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>65A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>65A&#042;:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 15, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3A) The Electoral Commission shall undertake a review of the conduct of the referendum and shall publish a report setting out the conclusions of the review no more than 12 months after the day or days on which the referendum is held.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>66</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>66:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 16, leave out subsection (4)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>67</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>67:</B> Clause 3, page 2, line 18, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(5) The Secretary of State shall, by order, make provision for the votes cast in England, Northern Ireland, Scotland and Wales, respectively, to be counted and declared separately.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausetext>[As an amendment to Amendment 67]</clausetext>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>68</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>68:</B> Clause 3, line 3, leave out &#8220;and Wales,&#8221; and insert &#8220;, Wales and Gibraltar,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>69</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>69:</B> After Clause 3, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Office for Public Information on the European Referendum</quote>
         <quote>(1) There shall be established an Office for Public Information on the European Referendum (&#8220;the Office&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Office shall be headed by a Commissioner for Public Information.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Commissioner shall be appointed with the approval of the Commissioner for Public Appointments.</quote>
         <quote>(4) It shall be the duty of the Commissioner for Public Information and the Office to inform the public ahead of the vote in the referendum of the advantages and disadvantages of the UK&#8217;s membership of the European Union.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The cost of the Office shall be met by Her Majesty&#8217;s Treasury.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>70</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>70:</B> After Clause 3, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Procedure for an order under section 3</quote>
         <quote>(1) Before making an order under section 3, the Secretary of State must consult&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Electoral Commission;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) local authorities;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) any officially established group formed to campaign on the referendum;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) any other people that appear relevant to the Secretary of State.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) If, following consultation under subsection (1), the Secretary of State proposes to make an order under section 3, the Secretary of State must lay before each House of Parliament a document which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) explains the proposals;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) sets them out in the form of a draft order; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) gives details of consultation under subsection (1).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) After laying such a document the Secretary of State may not make an order in the terms of the draft set out in subsection (2)(b) until a prescribed period of no less than 60 days from the day on which the document is laid has passed.</quote>
         <quote>(4) When the prescribed period in subsection (3) has expired, the Secretary of State may make an order in the terms of the draft in subsection (2)(b) if it is approved by a resolution of each House of Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(5) However, during the prescribed period in subsection (3), a committee of either House charged with reporting on the draft order may, at any time, recommend changes to the draft order, including that no further proceedings be taken in relation to the draft order.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Where a recommendation is made by a committee of either House under subsection (4) in relation to a draft order, no proceedings may be taken in relation to the draft order in that House under subsection (3) unless the recommendation is, in the same session, rejected by resolution of that House.</quote>
         <quote>(7) If, after the expiry of the 60-day period, the Secretary of State wishes to make an order consisting of a version of the draft order with material changes, he must lay before Parliament&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) a revised draft order; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a statement giving details of&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) any representations made under subsection (2)(a); and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the revisions proposed.</IndentTwo>
         <quote>(8) In calculating the period mentioned in subsection (3) no account is to be taken of any time during which&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) Parliament is dissolved or prorogued, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) either House is adjourned for more than four days.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>71</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>71:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Reporting</quote>
         <quote>(1) No order shall be made under section (Commencement) until&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) at least eighteen months have passed since the passing of this Act.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(2) A report under subsection (1)(c) must include an assessment of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the effect on the United Kingdom&#8217;s economy;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the effect on the rights of individuals within the UK;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the rights of European citizens living in the UK;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the rights of UK citizens living in another country that is a member of the European Union.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>72</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>72:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Assessment of future relationship with the European Union</quote>
         <IndentOne>No order shall be made under section (Commencement) until the Secretary of State has prepared, published and laid before Parliament an assessment of the United Kingdom&#8217;s intended relationship with the European Union in the event of withdrawal from the European Union.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>73</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>73:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Commencement</quote>
         <IndentOne>This Act shall come into force on a day appointed by the Secretary of State by order made by statutory instrument subject to approval by resolution of each House of Parliament.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Referendum condition</quote>
         <quote>(1) No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European union.</quote>
         <quote>(2) A report under subsection (1) must include an assessment of&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the effect on the United Kingdom&#8217;s economy;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) the effect on the rights of individuals within the UK;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) the rights of European citizens living in the UK;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the rights of UK citizens living in another country that is a member of the European Union.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74A&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74A&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on alternatives to membership of the European Union: Switzerland</quote>
         <IndentOne>No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union and instead seeking a special bilateral agreement with the European Union such as that negotiated between the European Union and Switzerland.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74B&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74B&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on alternatives to membership of the European Union: Norway</quote>
         <IndentOne>No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union and instead seeking a special bilateral agreement with the European Union such as that negotiated between the European Union and Norway.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74C&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74C&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on alternatives to membership of the European Union: the Commonwealth</quote>
         <IndentOne>No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union and instead seeking an enhanced free trade area with Commonwealth countries.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74D&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74D&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on alternatives to membership of the European Union: North America</quote>
         <IndentOne>No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union and instead seeking an enhanced free trade area with those countries signed up to the North American Free Trade Agreement.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74E&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74E&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on alternatives to membership of the European Union</quote>
         <quote>(1) No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union and instead seeking to make separate trading arrangements with countries determined in accordance with sub-section (2).</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Secretary of State shall, within six months of the passing of this Act, draw up and present to Parliament for approval a list of countries for the purposes of sub-section (1).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74F&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74F&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on alternatives to membership of the European Union: European Economic Area</quote>
         <IndentOne>No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union and instead seeking access to the European Union&#8217;s internal market under the European Economic Area Agreement.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74G&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74G&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Report on alternatives to membership of the European Union: European Free Trade Association</quote>
         <IndentOne>No order shall be made providing for a referendum to be held under this Act until the Secretary of State has published and laid before Parliament an evidence based assessment of the impact of the United Kingdom ceasing to be a member of the European Union and instead seeking to become a member of the European Free Trade Association.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74H&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74H&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Public information campaign</quote>
         <quote>(1) There shall be a public information campaign prior to the referendum which shall include material, available online and in print, summarising the meaning of the referendum question and an objective assessment by the Office for Budget Responsibility of the economic impact of the United Kingdom remaining within the European Union and of the United Kingdom leaving the European Union.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The print material prepared under subsection (1) shall be distributed, as far as is practicable, to all households in the United Kingdom.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>74J&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>74J&#042;:</B> After Clause 4, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Assistance available to designated organisations</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Electoral Commission shall designate two organisations to whom assistance is available in accordance with section 110 of the Political Parties Elections and Referendums Act 2000.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The Commission shall make to each designated organisation a grant of the same amount, which shall be an amount not exceeding £600,000 determined by the Commission.</quote>
         <quote>(3) The Commission shall specify a limit to the expenditure which each designated organisation may incur during the referendum period.</quote>
         <quote>(4) Any organisation planning to spend more than £10,000 on activities which might reasonably be expected to promote a &#8220;yes&#8221; or a &#8220;no&#8221; vote in the referendum must register with the Electoral Commission as a permitted participant for the referendum period.</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Electoral Commission shall set a limit to the amount spent by any single permitted participant in the referendum period.</quote>
         <quote>(6) The Electoral Commission shall set an aggregate limit for the total expenditure of permitted participants on each side who operate to a common plan.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>75</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>75:</B> Clause 6, page 3, line 4, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) The Secretary of State may by order made by statutory instrument subject to approval by both Houses of Parliament amend subsection (1) to omit the word &#8220;Scotland&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>76</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>76:</B> Clause 6, page 3, line 5, after &#8220;(Referendum&#8221; insert &#8220;and related provisions&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>