<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Financial_Services_Banking_Reform_(Bill54(i))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 4, page 17, line 15, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Full separation</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>142VA General requirement of separation</quote>
         <quote>(1) Where the members of any group include one or more ring-fenced bodies and one or more other bodies, the members of the group must, before the end of the period of five years beginning with the relevant commencement date, take steps to secure that there are no members of the group that are ring-fenced bodies.</quote>
         <quote>(2) If in the case of any group steps to secure that there are no members of the group that are ring-fenced bodies are not taken within the period specified in subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) at the end of that period the Part 4A permission of each member of the group that is a ring-fenced body shall be treated as having been cancelled to the extent that it relates to a core activity, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) after the end of that period the appropriate regulator must refuse to give any member of the group a Part 4A permission to carry on a core activity.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) At the end of the period specified in subsection (1)&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) section 142H, subsections (1)(b) and (4) to (7), and, in subsection (8), the definition of &#8220;specified&#8221;, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) sections 142K to 142V,</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>cease to have effect.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(4) In subsection (1) &#8220;the relevant commencement date&#8221; means the day appointed for the coming into force of section 4 of the Financial Services (Banking Reform) Act 2013 so far as it inserts this section.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 14, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Professional standards</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 65 of FSMA 2000 insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;65A Professional standards</quote>
         <quote>(1) The regulator will raise standards of professionalism in financial services by mandating a licensing regime based on training and competence.</quote>
         <quote>(2) This licensing regime must&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) apply to all approved persons exercising controlled functions, regardless of financial sector;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) specify minimum thresholds of competence including integrity, professional qualifications, continuous professional development and adherence to a recognised code of conduct and revised Banking Standards Rules;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) make provisions in connection with&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentTwo>(i) the granting of a licence;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(ii) the refusal of a licence;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iii) the withdrawal of a licence; and</IndentTwo>
         <IndentTwo>(iv) the revalidation of a licensed person of a prescribed description whenever the appropriate regulator sees fit, either as a condition of the person continuing to hold a licence or of the person&#8217;s licence being restored;</IndentTwo>
         <IndentOne>(d) be evidenced by individuals holding an annual validation of competence;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) include specific provision for a Senior Persons Regime in relation to activities involving the exercise of a significant influence over a controlled function under section 59 of the Act.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In section 59, for &#8220;authorised&#8221; substitute &#8220;licensed&#8221; throughout the section.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 15, page 28, line 11, at end insert &#8220;but excludes the provision of legal advice in taking decisions or participating in the taking of decisions&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 22, page 35, line 43, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(7) The rules of conduct made by the FCA or the PRA shall not require any person under section 64A who is a professional legal adviser to:</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) to answer any privileged question, </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) to provide any privileged information, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) to produce any privileged document.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) A &#8220;privileged question&#8221; is a question which the person would be entitled to refuse to answer on grounds of legal professional privilege in proceedings in the High Court.</quote>
         <quote>(9) &#8220;Privileged information&#8221; is information which the person would be entitled to refuse to provide on grounds of legal professional privilege in such proceedings.</quote>
         <quote>(10) A &#8220;privileged document&#8221; is a document which the person would be entitled to refuse to produce on grounds of legal professional privilege in such proceedings.</quote>
         <quote>(11) A person may not be required under section 64A to produce any excluded material (as defined by section 11 of the Police and Criminal Evidence Act 1984 (c. 60)).</quote>
         <quote>(12) In the application of this section to Scotland&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) subsections (7) to (11) do not have effect, but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a person under section 64A who is a professional legal adviser, may not be required under the rules of conduct made by the FCA or PRA to answer any question, provide any information or produce any document which he would be entitled, on grounds of legal privilege, to refuse to answer or (as the case may be) provide or produce.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(13) In this section, &#8220;legal professional privilege&#8221; means protection in legal proceedings from disclosure, by virtue of any rule of law relating to the confidentiality of communications; and &#8220;items subject to legal professional privilege&#8221; are&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) communications between a person who is a professional legal adviser, or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) communications made in connection with or in contemplation of legal proceedings and for the purposes of those proceedings.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(14) In this section, &#8220;professional legal adviser&#8221; means a barrister, advocate or solicitor.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Before Clause 114, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Duty of care</quote>
         <IndentOne>At all times when carrying out core activities, a ring-fenced body shall&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(a) be subject to a fiduciary duty towards its customers in the operation of core services; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) be subject to a duty of care towards its customers across the financial services sector.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 116, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Arrangements for consulting practitioners and consumers</quote>
         <IndentOne>After section 2L of FSMA 2000 (the PRA&#8217;s general duty to consult) insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <quote>&#8220;2LA PRA duty to consider representations from the FCA Consumer Panel</quote>
         <quote>(1) The PRA must consider and respond to representations made by the Consumer Panel established by the FCA under section 1Q of the Financial Services Act 2012.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The PRA must from time to time publish in such manner as it thinks fit responses to the representations.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 124, page 95, line 13, leave out paragraph (b)</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 127, page 95, line 36, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) No order may be made appointing a day for the coming into force of section 4 so far as it inserts section 142VA or FSMA 2000 unless&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) the day is later than that on which there is published the report of the review under section 142J of that Act containing a recommendation that section 4 of that Act should be brought into force to that extent, and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) a draft of the order has been laid before, and approved by a resolution of, each House of Parliament.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>