<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>National_Insurance_Contributions_(Bill65_I)</billtitle>
      <headertext>MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN GRAND COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext> The amendments have been marshalled in accordance with the Instruction of 14th January 2014, as follows&#8212;</headertext>
      <headertext>Clauses 1 to 3 Schedule 1 Clauses 4 to 15 Schedule 2 Clauses 16 to 21 </headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 1</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DAVIES OF OLDHAM</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Post implementation review</quote>
         <quote>(1) Her Majesty&#8217;s Revenue and Customs must, after one year, prepare a post implementation review of the employment allowance which the Minister shall lay before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The review must consider&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) what impact the employment allowance has had on the number of jobs;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) what impact the employment allowance has had on wage levels;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) overall take up of the employment allowance; </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(d) the geographical spread of businesses, charities and sports clubs taking up the employment allowance; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(e) the effectiveness of Her Majesty&#8217;s Revenue and Customs&#8217; strategy to promote the employment allowance.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2&#042;:</B> After Clause 1, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Administrative and compliance costs review</quote>
         <quote>(1) Her Majesty&#8217;s Revenue and Customs must, after six months of this Act coming into force, prepare a review which the Minister shall lay before Parliament.</quote>
         <quote>(2) The review must consider&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) whether there are any administrative or compliance costs associated with the employment allowance being reported by those applying for it; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) whether businesses, charities and sports clubs are having any problems in claiming the employment allowance.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 9</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DAVIES OF OLDHAM</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3&#042;:</B> Clause 9, page 10, line 39, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(13) The Treasury shall publish a review of the level of youth unemployment as at December 2013 and the effect on the level of youth unemployment if the amendments made in this section were required to be brought into force on 6 April 2014.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DAVIES OF OLDHAM</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 10, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 10 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 13</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DAVIES OF OLDHAM</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 13, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 13 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 14</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD DAVIES OF OLDHAM</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TUNNICLIFFE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 14, the above-named Lords give notice of their intention to oppose the Question that Clause 14 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>