<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Northern_Ireland_Miscellaneous_Provisions_(Bill58_I)</billtitle>
      <headertext>MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED IN COMMITTEE</headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 5</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD LEXDEN</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TRIMBLE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1:</B> After Clause 5, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Opposition status in the Northern Ireland Assembly</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Northern Ireland Assembly may, at any time after the passage of this Act, request that the Secretary of State introduce opposition status and rights for members of the Assembly, subject to the provisions of this section.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Within six months of receiving a request from the Northern Ireland Assembly, the Secretary of State shall, by regulation, introduce the following rights for Assembly members with opposition status&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) speaking rights;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) supply days; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(c) chairmanship and deputy chairmanship of the Public Accounts Committee, </IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>and shall make clear that these rights are to be allocated to members with opposition status in a manner that is proportionate to their relative number in the Assembly.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) It shall be for the Speaker of the Northern Ireland Assembly to determine what is proportionate under subsection (2) and to set this out in the Assembly&#8217;s Standing Orders.</quote>
         <quote>(4) For the purposes of this section, opposition status shall apply to any party with at least one seat in the Northern Ireland Assembly which is not a part of the Executive and which has notified the Speaker in writing of its desire to be accorded opposition status.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 6</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD MCAVOY</proposer>
   <proposer>BARONESS SMITH OF BASILDON</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2:</B> Clause 6, page 6, line 30, at beginning insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In Schedule 3 to the Northern Ireland Act 1998 (reserved matters), at the end of paragraph 1 insert &#8220;except such functions as are specified by the Secretary of State by order made by statutory instrument.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 6, lord Empey gives notice of his intention to oppose the Question that Clause 6 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD ALDERDICE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3:</B> Clause 10, page 9, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) Subsections (1) and (2) shall only enter into force after the remaining provisions of this section have been complied with.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State shall establish a body corporate called the Northern Ireland Civil Service Commission (&#8220;the Commission&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Commission must publish a set of principles to be applied for the purposes of recruiting persons on merit on the basis of fair and open competition.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Before publishing the set of principles (or any revision of it), the Commission must consult the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Northern Ireland Civil Service management authorities must comply with the recruitment principles.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 11</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD ALDERDICE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 11, lord Alderdice gives notice of his intention to oppose the Question that Clause 11 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 12</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 12, lord Empey gives notice of his intention to oppose the Question that Clause 12 stand part of the Bill.</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Before Clause 21</clausenumber>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>4&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>4&#042;:</B> Before Clause 21, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Civil forum</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Northern Ireland Act 1998 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After section 55 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;55A Civic forum: establishment</quote>
         <IndentOne>The First Minister and Deputy First Minister shall consult with the civil and voluntary sector within Northern Ireland in order to bring forward proposals to the Northern Ireland Assembly to give effect to a working and effective Civic Forum.&#8221;</IndentOne>
         <quote>(3) In section 56 (civic forum), after subsection (2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(2A) A motion for approval under subsection (2) shall be made no later than 1 April 2015.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 25</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD TRIMBLE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>5:</B> After Clause 25, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Election of the First Minister</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Northern Ireland Act 1998 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Omit sections 16A (appointment of First Minister, deputy First Minister and Northern Ireland Ministers following Assembly election, 16B (vacancies in the office of First Minister or deputy First Minister) and 16C (sections 16A and 16B: supplementary).</quote>
         <quote>(3) Before section 17 (Ministerial offices) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;A17 First Minister and deputy First Minister</quote>
         <quote>(1) Each Assembly shall, within a period of six weeks beginning with its first meeting, elect from among its members the First Minister and deputy First Minister.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Each candidate for either office must stand for election jointly with a candidate for the other office.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Two candidates standing jointly shall not be elected to the two offices without the support of a majority of the members voting in the election, a majority of the designated Nationalists voting and a majority of the designated Unionists voting.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The First Minister and deputy First Minister&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall not take up office until each of them has affirmed the terms of the pledge of office; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) subject to the provisions of this Part, shall hold office until the conclusion of the next election for First Minister and deputy First Minister.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The holder of the office of First Minister or deputy First Minister may by notice in writing to the Presiding Officer designate a Northern Ireland Minister to exercise the functions of that office&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) during any absence or incapacity of the holder; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) during any vacancy in that office arising otherwise than under subsection (7)(a);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>but a person shall not have power to act by virtue of paragraph (a) for a continuous period exceeding six weeks.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The First Minister or the deputy First Minister&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) may at any time resign by notice in writing to the Presiding Officer; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) shall cease to hold office if he or she ceases to be a member of the Assembly otherwise than by virtue of a dissolution.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) If either the First Minister or the deputy First Minister ceases to hold office at any time, whether by resignation or otherwise, the other&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall also cease to hold office at that time; but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may continue to exercise the functions of his or her office until the election required by subsection (8).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) Where the offices of the First Minister and the deputy First Minister become vacant at any time an election shall be held under this section to fill the vacancies within a period of six weeks beginning with that time.</quote>
         <quote>(9) Standing orders may make provision with respect to the holding of elections under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(10) In this Act &#8220;the pledge of office&#8221; means the pledge of office which, together with the code of conduct to which it refers, is set out in Annex A to Strand One of the Belfast Agreement (the text of which Annex is reproduced in Schedule 4).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>6:</B> After Clause 25, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Amendment of Crime and Courts Act 2013</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Crime and Courts Act 2013 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In section 61 (short title, commencement and extent), for subsection (18) substitute&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(18) Part 1 of and Schedules 1 to 4 to this Act extend to Northern Ireland.&#8221;</quote>
         <quote>(3) Omit Schedule 24 (the NCA: Northern Ireland).&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD LEXDEN</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD BEW</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD BLACK OF BRENTWOOD</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>7</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>7:</B> After Clause 25, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Defamation</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 17 of the Defamation Act 2013 (short title, extent and commencement) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (2), after &#8220;Wales&#8221; insert &#8220;and Northern Ireland&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TRIMBLE</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>8</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>8:</B> After Clause 25, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Junior Ministers</quote>
         <IndentOne>In section 19 of the Northern Ireland Act 1998 (junior Ministers), after subsection (1)(b), insert&#8212;</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>&#8220;(c) that any department exercising any of the functions specified in paragraph (b) shall do so under the direction and control of the junior Minister.&#8221;&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 28</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>9</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>9:</B> Clause 28, page 17, leave out line 40</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>