<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Northern_Ireland_Miscellaneous_Provisions_(Bill58_R_I)</billtitle>
      <headertext>MARSHALLED LIST OF AMENDMENTS TO BE MOVED ON REPORT</headertext>
      <headertext>[Amendments marked &#042; are new or have been altered]</headertext>
   </header>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 7</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD LEXDEN</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>1&#042;</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>1&#042;:</B> After Clause 7, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Opposition status in the Assembly</quote>
         <quote>(1) Schedule 6 of the Northern Ireland Act 1998 (standing orders: further provision) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) After paragraph 4(2) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) The standing orders shall include provision in relation to the allocation of the Chairmanship and Deputy Chairmanship of the Public Accounts Committee.&#8221;.</quote>
         <quote>(3) After paragraph 5 insert&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>&#8220;Opposition status</HeadingTwo>
         <quote>6 (1) The standing orders shall provide for official opposition status to be allocated to any party with at least one seat in the Assembly which is not a part of the Executive.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Official opposition status shall only be introduced under sub-paragraph (1) if approved by a cross community vote in the Assembly.</quote>
         <quote>(3) For the avoidance of doubt, it shall not be possible for the Assembly to revoke the official opposition status accorded to members under the provisions of this paragraph without the consent of the Secretary of State.&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>Clause 10</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD EMPEY</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD BEW</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>2:</B> Clause 10, page 9, line 7, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(3) Subsections (1) and (2) shall only enter into force after the remaining provisions of this section have been complied with.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The Secretary of State shall establish a body corporate called the Northern Ireland Civil Service Commission (&#8220;the Commission&#8221;).</quote>
         <quote>(5) The Commission must publish a set of principles to be applied for the purposes of recruiting persons on merit on the basis of fair and open competition.</quote>
         <quote>(6) Before publishing the set of principles (or any revision of it), the Commission must consult the Secretary of State.</quote>
         <quote>(7) Northern Ireland Civil Service management authorities must comply with the recruitment principles.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <clausenumber>After Clause 25</clausenumber>
   <proposer>LORD LEXDEN</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD LESTER OF HERNE HILL</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD BLACK OF BRENTWOOD</proposer>
   <proposer>LORD PANNICK</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>3:</B> After Clause 25, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Defamation</quote>
         <quote>(1) Section 17 of the Defamation Act 2013 (short title, extent and commencement) is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) In subsection (2), after &#8220;Wales&#8221; insert &#8220;and Northern Ireland&#8221;.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <proposer>LORD TRIMBLE</proposer>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>4:</B> After Clause 25, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Election of the First Minister</quote>
         <quote>(1) The Northern Ireland Act 1998 is amended as follows.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Omit sections 16A (appointment of First Minister, deputy First Minister and Northern Ireland Ministers following Assembly election, 16B (vacancies in the office of First Minister or deputy First Minister) and 16C (sections 16A and 16B: supplementary).</quote>
         <quote>(3) Before section 17 (Ministerial offices) insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;A17 First Minister and deputy First Minister</quote>
         <quote>(1) Each Assembly shall, within a period of six weeks beginning with its first meeting, elect from among its members the First Minister and deputy First Minister.</quote>
         <quote>(2) Each candidate for either office must stand for election jointly with a candidate for the other office.</quote>
         <quote>(3) Two candidates standing jointly shall not be elected to the two offices without the support of a majority of the members voting in the election, a majority of the designated Nationalists voting and a majority of the designated Unionists voting.</quote>
         <quote>(4) The First Minister and deputy First Minister&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall not take up office until each of them has affirmed the terms of the pledge of office; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) subject to the provisions of this Part, shall hold office until the conclusion of the next election for First Minister and deputy First Minister.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(5) The holder of the office of First Minister or deputy First Minister may by notice in writing to the Presiding Officer designate a Northern Ireland Minister to exercise the functions of that office&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) during any absence or incapacity of the holder; or</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) during any vacancy in that office arising otherwise than under subsection (7)(a);</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>but a person shall not have power to act by virtue of paragraph (a) for a continuous period exceeding six weeks.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(6) The First Minister or the deputy First Minister&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) may at any time resign by notice in writing to the Presiding Officer; and</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) shall cease to hold office if he or she ceases to be a member of the Assembly otherwise than by virtue of a dissolution.</IndentOne>
         <quote>(7) If either the First Minister or the deputy First Minister ceases to hold office at any time, whether by resignation or otherwise, the other&#8212;</quote>
         <IndentOne>(a) shall also cease to hold office at that time; but</IndentOne>
         <IndentOne>(b) may continue to exercise the functions of his or her office until the election required by subsection (8).</IndentOne>
         <quote>(8) Where the offices of the First Minister and the deputy First Minister become vacant at any time an election shall be held under this section to fill the vacancies within a period of six weeks beginning with that time.</quote>
         <quote>(9) Standing orders may make provision with respect to the holding of elections under this section.</quote>
         <quote>(10) In this Act &#8220;the pledge of office&#8221; means the pledge of office which, together with the code of conduct to which it refers, is set out in Annex A to Strand One of the Belfast Agreement (the text of which Annex is reproduced in Schedule 4).&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>