<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<amendments>
   <header>
      <billtitle>Transparency_of_Lobbying_Non-Party_Campaigning_and_Trade_Union_Administration_(Bill50_R(c))</billtitle>
   </header>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Schedule 1, page 53, line 1, leave out paragraph 3</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 6, page 4, line 27, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;(6A) A registered person who is aggrieved by the Registrar&#8217;s decision in terms of subsection (6) may appeal to the Tribunal against that decision.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 36, page 39, line 10, leave out from beginning to &#8220;the&#8221; in line 15</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 37, leave out Clause 37</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 38, page 43, line 11, after &#8220;If&#8221; insert &#8220;, following receipt of a formal and qualifying complaint,&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 38, page 44, leave out lines 4 and 5</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 38, page 45, line 37, at end insert&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;( ) In no circumstances will any document acquired under section 24ZH by the Certification Officer or his agents or by inspectors appointed under section 24ZI be made available by any means or in any form to any third party, and this prohibition includes disclosure to other government departments and agencies except where an issue of national security or serious criminal offence is involved.&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> Clause 39, page 46, line 15, leave out &#8220;24ZC&#8221; and insert &#8220;24ZA&#8221;</quote>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Clause 39, insert the following new Clause&#8212;</quote>
         <quote>&#8220;Commencement of Part</quote>
         <IndentOne>The provisions in this Part shall not come into force until the Secretary of State has placed in the Libraries of both Houses a review of the burden of regulatory responsibility that this Part will place on trade unions, including any necessary rule changes and their timeframe.&#8221;</IndentOne>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
   <Amendment>
      <Number>000</Number>
      <text>
         <quote>
            <B>000:</B> After Schedule 4, insert the following new Schedule&#8212;</quote>
         <HeadingTwo>Schedule</HeadingTwo>
         <HeadingTwo>Tax relief on donations</HeadingTwo>
         <quote> After Schedule 6 to the Political Parties, Elections and Referendums Act 2000, insert&#8212;</quote>
         <text>
            <quote>
               <B>000:</B> After Schedule 4, </quote>
            <HeadingTwo>Schedule 6A</HeadingTwo>
            <HeadingTwo>Tax relief on donations</HeadingTwo>
            <quote>1 To obtain tax relief under section 70A (Tax relief on donations), the conditions set out in paragraph 2 must be satisfied.</quote>
            <quote>2 (1) The individual who made the donation is a permissible donor.</quote>
            <quote>(2) The registered political party to which the donation is made is a party which, at the last general election preceding the donation, had at least two members elected to the House of Commons.</quote>
            <quote>(3) Conditions A to F in section 416 of the Income Tax Act 2007 (meaning of &#8220;qualifying donation&#8221;) would have been met if the donations had been made to a charity.</quote>
            <quote>(4) The donor has given a declaration in the manner specified by regulations made by the Commissioners for Her Majesty&#8217;s Revenue and Customs and containing any information and any statements required by regulations.</quote>
            <quote>3 Regulations made under paragraph 2(4) may provide for declarations&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) to have effect;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) to cease to have effect;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(c) to be treated as never having had effect,</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>in any circumstances and for any purposes specified by the regulations.</IndentOne>in any circumstances and for any purposes specified by the regulations.<quote>4 Regulations made under paragraph 2(4) are subject to annulment pursuant to a resolution of the House of Commons.</quote>
            <quote>5 Tax relief in relation to donations given by an individual must not exceed&#8212;</quote>
            <IndentOne>(a) £16 in the tax year 2014-2015;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(b) £32 in the tax year 2015-2016;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(c) £96 in the tax year 2016-2017;</IndentOne>
            <IndentOne>(d) an amount to be set in primary legislation by the Secretary of State in subsequent fiscal years.</IndentOne>
            <quote>6 Notwithstanding any other provisions of this Act, the amounts in paragraph 5 may only be amended by primary legislation.</quote>
            <quote>7 Tax relief shall not be given on higher rate income tax.</quote>
            <quote>8 The amount of tax relief (subject to paragraphs 5 and 6) shall be computed and allocated to the political party to which the donation was given as if that party was a charity to which Chapter 2 of Part 8 of the Income Tax Act 2007 applies.&#8221;&#8221;</quote>
         </text>
      </text>
   </Amendment>
</amendments>