<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>8 October</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>freedom of information (private healthcare companies): Ten Minute Rule Motion</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That leave be given to bring in a Bill to amend the Freedom of Information Act 2000 to apply to private healthcare companies; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>transparency of lobbying, non-party campaigning and trade union administration Bill: programme (No. 2) motion</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the Order of 3 September 2013 (Transparency of Lobbying, Non-Party Campaigning and Trade Union Administration Bill: Programme) be varied as follows:</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>For paragraph (6) substitute–</p>
         <p>“(6) Proceedings on Consideration–</p>
         <p>(a) shall be taken on the days shown in the first column of the following Table and in the order so shown, and</p>
         <p>(b) shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion at the times specified in the second column of the Table.</p>
         <p>Table</p>
      </Text>
      <so>83A(9)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <OrderTitle>transparency of lobbying, non-party campaigning and trade union administration Bill: report stage (day 1)</OrderTitle>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <OrderTitle>public bodies</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Public Bodies (Abolition of Victims’ Advisory Panel) Order 2013, which was laid before this House on 25 April 2013, in the last Session of Parliament, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>118(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <OrderTitle>representation of the people</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft European Parliamentary Elections (Amendment) Regulations 2013, which were laid before this House on 9 July, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>118(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <OrderTitle>social security</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Jobseeker’s Allowance (Domestic Violence) (Amendment) Regulations 2013, which were laid before this House on 8 July, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>118(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Government policy on Burma</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>