<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>9 October</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>CORONERS AND JUSTICE (AMENDMENT): Ten Minute Rule Motion</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That leave be given to bring in a Bill to amend section 62 of the Coroners and Justice Act 2009 so as to apply additionally to the possession of pornographic written material about children; to make consequential amendments to the Act; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>PRIVILEGE</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the Police Information Notice from Sussex Police addressed to the hon. Member for East Worthing and Shoreham, dated 4 September 2013, be referred to the Committee of Privileges.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <OrderTitle>transparency of lobbying, non-party campaigning and trade union administration Bill: REPORT STAGE (DAY 2) AND THIRD READING</OrderTitle>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <OrderTitle>CLIMATE AND ENERGY POLICIES IN 2030</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House takes note of European Union Document No. 8096/13, a Commission Green Paper: A 2030 framework for climate and energy policies; and further notes the Government’s support for an ambitious EU emissions reduction target for 2030, delivered in a cost-effective, flexible, technology-neutral way, supported by a robust, reformed emissions trading system, and underpinned by a global climate agreement in 2015.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>119(11)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <OrderTitle>DRAFT VOTING ELIGIBILITY (PRISONERS) BILL (JOINT COMMITTEE)</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, notwithstanding the Resolution of this House of 16 April, it be an instruction to the Joint Committee on the Draft Voting Eligibility (Prisoners) Bill that it should report on the draft Bill by 18 December 2013.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>9(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Mobile army surgical hospital and the humanitarian response capability</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>