<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>17 July</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Electoral Register (Access to Public Services): Ten Minute Rule Motion</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That leave be given to bring in a Bill to introduce a requirement that electoral registration be a condition of access to public services; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Opposition Day (5th Allotted Day)</OrderTitle>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>Deferred Divisions</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, at this day’s sitting, Standing Order No. 41A (Deferred divisions) shall not apply to the Motion in the name of Greg Clark relating to the Multiannual Financial Framework, 2014–2020.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>Business of the House</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, at this day’s sitting, the Motion in the name of the Prime Minister relating to Trident Alternatives Review may be proceeded with, though opposed, until 10 o’clock or for three hours, whichever is the later.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Multiannual Financial Framework, 2014–2020</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House takes note of European Union Documents No. 8041/13, draft Amending Budget No. 2 to the General Budget 2013: general statement of revenue: statement of expenditure by section: Section III: Commission, No. 11295/13, a draft Council Regulation laying down the Multiannual Financial Framework for the years 2014–2020, No. 11298/13, a draft Inter-Institutional Agreement between the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission on budgetary discipline, cooperation in budgetary matters and on sound financial management, and No. 11307/13, a draft Council Regulation laying down the Multiannual Financial Framework for the years 2014–2020 and Inter-Institutional Agreement between the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission on budgetary discipline, cooperation in budgetary matters and on sound financial management: Draft Declarations; agrees with the Government that at a time of ongoing economic fragility in Europe and tight constraints on domestic public spending, the MFF agreement reached, which delivers a reduction of €35 billion on the current period in the seven year payment ceilings to €908.4 billion, a real-terms reduction of over three per cent in payment appropriations, represents a good deal for taxpayers; welcomes the Government’s successful defence of the UK abatement, noting that UK contributions to the EU budget have risen in recent years due to the 2005 decision to give away parts of the abatement, shares the Government’s disappointment at the Council Decision to agree an additional €7.3 billion in 2013 in draft Amending Budget No. 2 and welcomes the Government’s opposition to that decision, reflecting as it does the weaknesses in the 2007-13 deal.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Trident Alternatives Review</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House has considered the Trident Alternatives Review.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Defence</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Armed Forces Act (Court Martial) (Amendment) Rules 2013, which were laid before this House on 17 June, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Defence</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Armed Forces (Retrial for Serious Offences) Order 2013, which was laid before this House on 17 June, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>7</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Companies</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Companies Act 2006 (Strategic Report and Directors’ Report) Regulations 2013, which were laid before this House on 10 June, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>8</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Companies</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Large and Medium-sized Companies and Groups (Accounts and Reports) (Amendment) Regulations 2013, which were laid before this House on 24 June, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>9</Number>
      <OrderTitle>Companies</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Companies and Partnerships (Accounts and Audit) Regulations 2013, which were laid before this House on 24 June, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>PRESENTATION OF PUBLIC PETITIONS</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>Proposed closure of Post Office at Lupus Street (London, SW1) (Mark Field)</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>Closure of Barclays Bank (Marston Green) (Mrs Caroline Spelman)</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>Installation of a controlled crossing on Ashby Road (Daventry) (Chris Heaton-Harris)</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Government policy on selection and allocation of organs for transplant</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>