<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<op>
   <Date>3 September</Date>
   <Item>
      <Number>1</Number>
      <OrderTitle>young apprenticeships: Ten Minute Rule Motion</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That leave be given to bring in a Bill to provide for young apprenticeships for 14 to 16 year olds; and for connected purposes.</p>
      </Text>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>2</Number>
      <OrderTitle>transparency of lobbying, non-party campaigning and trade union administration Bill: Second Reading</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House affirms its belief in the need for a Bill on lobbying; declines to give a Second Reading to a Bill which requires further pre-legislative scrutiny and consultation; and considers that a Special Committee of the House should be set up with the remit of producing an improved Bill to be presented to the House within six months.</p>
      </Text>
      <Text>
         <p>That this House affirms its belief in the need for greater transparency in the lobbying industry and in British politics, and considers that there should be a universal register of all professional lobbyists backed by a code of conduct and sanctions, clear rules on third party campaigning, and real reform to get the big money out of politics; but declines to give a Second Reading to the Transparency of Lobbying, Third Party Campaigning and Trade Union Administration Bill because the proposals on lobbying cover only a tiny minority of the industry and will make lobbying less transparent, and the proposals on third party campaigning amount to a gag on charities and campaigners who have a democratic right to participate in important debates in the run up to elections; and strongly believes that the publication of such a Bill should have been preceded by a full process of pre-legislative scrutiny and consultation with affected parties.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>9(3)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>3</Number>
      <OrderTitle>transparency of lobbying, non-party campaigning and trade union administration Bill: programme</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the following provisions shall apply to the Transparency of Lobbying, Non-Party Campaigning and Trade Union Administration Bill:</p>
         <p>(1) The Bill shall be committed to a Committee of the whole House.</p>
         <p>(2) Proceedings in the Committee of the whole House shall be completed in three days.</p>
         <p>(3) The proceedings shall be taken on the days shown in the first column of the following Table and in the order so shown.</p>
         <p>(4) The proceedings shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion at the times specified in the second column of the Table.</p>
         <p>Table</p>
         <p>(5) Any proceedings on Consideration and proceedings on Third Reading shall be taken in two days in accordance with the following provisions of this Order.</p>
         <p>(6) Any proceedings on Consideration shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion one hour before the moment of interruption on the second day.</p>
         <p>(7) Proceedings on Third Reading shall (so far as not previously concluded) be brought to a conclusion at the moment of interruption on the second day.</p>
         <p>(8) Standing Order No. 83B (Programming committees) shall not apply to the proceedings on the Bill in Committee of the whole House, to any proceedings on Consideration or to proceedings on Third Reading.</p>
         <p>(9) Any other proceedings on the Bill (including any proceedings on Consideration of Lords Amendments or on any further messages from the Lords) may be programmed.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>83A(7)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>4</Number>
      <OrderTitle>transparency of lobbying, non-party campaigning and trade union administration Bill: money</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, for the purposes of any Act resulting from the Transparency of Lobbying, Non-Party Campaigning and Trade Union Administration Bill, it is expedient to authorise the payment out of money provided by Parliament of:</p>
         <p>(1) any expenditure incurred by a Minister of the Crown under or by virtue of that Act, and</p>
         <p>(2) any increase attributable to the Act in the sums payable under any other Act out of money so provided.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>52(1)(a)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>5</Number>
      <OrderTitle>transparency of lobbying, non-party campaigning and trade union administration Bill: ways and means</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, for the purposes of any Act resulting from the Transparency of Lobbying, Non-Party Campaigning and Trade Union Administration Bill, it is expedient to authorise:</p>
         <p>(1) the charging of fees under this Act in connection with a register of lobbyists, and</p>
         <p>(2) the payment of sums into the Consolidated Fund.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>52(1)(a)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>6</Number>
      <OrderTitle>public bodies</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft Public Bodies (Merger of the Gambling Commission and the National Lottery Commission) Order 2013, which was laid before this House on 25 March, in the last Session of Parliament, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>118(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>7</Number>
      <OrderTitle>national health service</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That the draft National Health Service (Licensing and Pricing) Regulations 2013, which were laid before this House on 4 June, be approved.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>118(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <Number>8</Number>
      <OrderTitle>BUSINESS OF THE HOUSE (11 SEPTEMBER)</OrderTitle>
      <Text>
         <p>That, at the sitting on Wednesday 11 September, notwithstanding Standing Order No. 20 (Time for taking private business), the Private Business set down by the Chairman of Ways and Means may be entered upon at any hour, and may then be proceeded with, though opposed, for three hours, after which the Speaker shall interrupt the business.</p>
      </Text>
      <so>9(6)</so>
   </Item>
   <Item>
      <OrderTitle>ADJOURNMENT</OrderTitle>
      <DebateTitle>Baroness Thatcher’s legacy</DebateTitle>
      <so>9(7)</so>
   </Item>
</op>